<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>DEX on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/dex/</link>
        <description>Recent content in DEX on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/dex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Staying Ahead of the Curve: the shift from Liquidity Mining to Liquidity Shaping</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/maverick-liquidity-shaping/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/maverick-liquidity-shaping/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Staying Ahead of the Curve: the shift from Liquidity Mining to Liquidity Shaping" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been four months since Maverick is out, and a few days since the MAV token joined the fray. Yet, most of DeFi is still scratching its head regarding how Maverick delivers 2-3x the capital efficiency of its top competitor, Uniswap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the time was right for a deep dive into the innovations brought by the model and the new paradigm it fosters regarding liquidity management: &lt;strong&gt;liquidity shaping&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovations-on-dex-more-like-tools-for-lp-to-express-themselves&#34;&gt;Innovations on DEX? More like tools for LP to express themselves
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, a decentralized exchange can innovate at two levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The liquidity structure&lt;/strong&gt;: the options offered to liquidity providers to design the supply activity that best matches their thesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And/or &lt;strong&gt;the incentivization model&lt;/strong&gt;: the tools and modalities enabling DAOs &amp;amp; projects to incentivize customized or not liquidity structures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most new DEX being released recycle an existing infrastructure and focus on innovating on only one dimension - usually the incentivization model - as seen recently with the wave of Solidly/Velodrome forks - &lt;strong&gt;[ve(3,3), the logical next step after veCRV?](&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2023/solidly-velodrome-template.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2023/solidly-velodrome-template.md&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are, however, a few critical moments in the industry when a new DEX was released and provided &lt;strong&gt;critical innovation on both fronts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/uniswap-v2/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V1/V2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; established a solid infrastructure for &lt;code&gt;x*y=k&lt;/code&gt; pools &amp;amp; basic incentivization model: 30 bps fees auto compounded &amp;amp; the possibility of having Liquidity Mining programs on the staked LP tokens (ERC20).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve&lt;/strong&gt; provided an innovative and efficient liquidity model for pegged assets (stableswap) while pioneering a ve/gauge-based model for liquidity provider incentivization introducing a revenue capture at the token level (admin fee).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/uniswap-v3/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;UniswapV3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; delivered the tools to manage a more advanced liquidity structure harnessing concentrated liquidity efficiently and providing more flexibility fee-wise (1, 5, 30, 100 bps fees, not auto-compounded)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally came &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/maverick-v2/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maverick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which goes even further than UniswapV3 in the customization of the liquidity structure it provides, offers streamlined position management (native rebalancing) and an unprecedented level of control regarding incentivization options, marking the birth of a new paradigm: liquidity shaping.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each core innovations &lt;strong&gt;enable more expressivity for LPs: they get access to increasingly refined and customized tools enabling even the most intricate thesis to find a proper medium to be expressed onchain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, before diving into the depth of liquidity shaping, some pointers on Maverick are necessary. Indeed, to fully understand the impact of liquidity shaping on Maverick, you first need to master its liquidity structures and their consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mavericks-liquidity-structures&#34;&gt;MAVERICK&amp;rsquo;S LIQUIDITY STRUCTURES
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, one of Maverick&amp;rsquo;s critical innovations is its liquidity structures, enabling the exchange to reach an unprecedented level of capital efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maverick offers four options to LP that could be regrouped into two categories for simplicity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The static mode is similar to a UNIv3 liquidity providing across a custom range, with &lt;strong&gt;immensely more flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And three dynamic modes offer &lt;strong&gt;various flavors of rebalancing to LP&lt;/strong&gt; to optimize further their earning: left (follows price to the left), right (follows price to the right), and both (follows price both ways).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-mavericks-static-mode-is-a-game-changer&#34;&gt;Why Maverick&amp;rsquo;s Static Mode is a game changer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many still have to understand how much of an improvement Maverick&amp;rsquo;s static mode is over UNIv3, so let us focus on it for a minute. Here&amp;rsquo;s a quick table recapping the main difference to get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Item&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Uniswap v3&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Maverick Static Pools&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supply liquidity in an arbitrary custom range, even potentially only with one token&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Support an uneven liquidity distribution within that range&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supports customized fees and width&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4 fees tiers, 1 width&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Near-infinite fee/width tiers&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supports the creation of ERC-20-wrapped LP tokens to ease LP onboarding &amp;amp; incentivization&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ (Boosted Pools)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supports natively the distribution of rewards (Liquidity Mining)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supports natively the weighted &amp;amp; customized distribution of rewards to LP (Liquidity Shaping)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like UniswapV3, Maverick supports supplying liquidity in &lt;strong&gt;an arbitrary custom range,&lt;/strong&gt; even potentially only with one token, for instance, an LP on ETH/USDC from $2000 to $2400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the current price is below $2000 (at the time of writing: $1900), the LP will be supplied purely with ETH and progressively rebalances to USDC as the price moves upwards, ending entirely in USDC at $2400.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/eth-lp-univ3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;eth-lp-univ3.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what about LPs that have an even more refined thesis? What about the LP that sees ETH in that range for a week but mainly in the $2150-2250 area? Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be nice for him to be able to express this thesis through the liquidity structure he chooses? It is precisely what Maverick enables:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/eth-lp-mav.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;eth-lp-mav.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the screenshot above, you see a distribution from $2000 to $2400 on the ETH/USDC pair; however, &lt;strong&gt;unlike Uniswap, which necessarily distributes liquidity evenly across the range, Maverick enables LPs to choose&lt;/strong&gt;. To better fit our LP thesis, most of the liquidity is concentrated over the three ticks covering the $2150-2250 price zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maximizing-the-expressivity-offered-to-lps&#34;&gt;Maximizing the expressivity offered to LPs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The expressivity offered to LP on Maverick is virtually infinite. I expect to see some interesting use cases emerge soon, especially for the protocols that will harness Maverick from the get-go (&amp;ldquo;Maverick-native&amp;rdquo; protocols). For instance, y&lt;strong&gt;ou could envision Maverick as a price stabilization mechanism for a stablecoin or a pegged asset&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming the stablecoin project controls some liquidity, it could supply it in very expressive ways in times of need to constraint the price range. Here&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;buy wall&amp;rdquo; liquidity structure on LUSD: the whole liquidity of this LP is supplied on a single tick, the first one where LUSD is worth below 1.00 USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/mav-buy-wall.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mav-buy-wall.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a current price &amp;gt;1.00 USDC, this LP is supplied 100% in USDC and acts like a buying reserve: if the price of LUSD falls, the LP will rebalance. Such positions are promising, as they can exert buy/sell pressure helping to better constrain peg assets within narrower ranges, which massively reduces the cost of their liquidity incentivization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-about-the-dynamic-modes&#34;&gt;What about the dynamic modes?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maverick dynamic modes offer a convenient and easy solution for LPs who maximize their exposure to market prices to maximize the volume processed. All three modes essentially harness the same structure but give different options to LP:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the price just one way (left or right) - there are tons of pairs where it makes a lot of sense, like wstETH/ETH (wstETH being &amp;ldquo;up-only&amp;rdquo; against ETH thanks to the staking yield)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the price both ways, a good match for LP looking to maximize adequate liquidity and fees collected at the expense of increased IL risk on the principal. It&amp;rsquo;s particularly suited for stable and pegged asset pairs, but not only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/mav-both.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mav-both.gif&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key thing to understand here is that &lt;strong&gt;Maverick delivers native rebalancing to its LP&lt;/strong&gt;, and here again, it goes above and beyond what preceded in terms of customization options. &amp;ldquo;Native&amp;rdquo; is the keyword here, meaning the rebalancing can be &lt;strong&gt;done cleverly and gas-efficiently&lt;/strong&gt;. While this is not new by itself, here again, the devil lies in the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Curve, LPs have no options: their liquidity is concentrated, but all LPs of a given pair are under the same regime. It eases the management, but kills the expressivity. With Uniswap, LPs can dynamically rebalance their position using third-party tools like Arrakis; it comes with sizable trust assumptions, potential fees, and hefty gas costs. It allows more expressivity but requires more active management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there are some limits to Maverick&amp;rsquo;s liquidity rebalancing, based on a TWAP and with some delays to avoid manipulations, it remains a crucial tool to help LPs maximize the time effectively spent in range / in the current price tick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mavericks-incentivization-model-liquidity-shaping&#34;&gt;MAVERICK&amp;rsquo;S INCENTIVIZATION MODEL: LIQUIDITY SHAPING
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a better understanding of the first fundamental innovation brought by Maverick - the unprecedented expressivity offered to LP in the design and management of their position - we can now explore Maverick&amp;rsquo;s second leg: its novel incentivization model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story here is both short and long. &lt;strong&gt;In short, Maverick provides the same level of customization at the incentivization layer as at the pool creation level.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads us to a longer story, with examples to be more explicit. Replicating most existing liquidity structures and incentivization models on Maverick is possible. But what&amp;rsquo;s even more interesting are the new ones previously never tried because they were not technically feasible before Maverick: it&amp;rsquo;s time to explore and experiment!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dynamic-contract-triggered-buysell-walls&#34;&gt;Dynamic contract-triggered buy/sell walls
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember the example from earlier about the stablecoin project posting liquidity as a buying wall to constrain the price? &lt;strong&gt;The project does not even needs its liquidity to do it&lt;/strong&gt;, as the same process can be replicated with a boosted pool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project creates a boosted pool where all the liquidity is distributed on one tick below the price like above.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The project supplies incentives to the boosted pool for the duration of its choice &amp;amp; apes will do the rest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This whole process can be automated and triggered entirely through smart contracts, meaning another contract could dynamically manage the incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-case-of-cvxcrvcrv&#34;&gt;The case of cvxCRV/CRV
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s study another checkmate case, the one of cvxCRV. Indeed, the cvxCRV/CRV Curve pool is the absolute worst offender:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It harnesses a &lt;strong&gt;a regular structure, absolutely sub-optimal for an asset trading in a constrained range like cvxCRV&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It harnesses a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;dumb&amp;rdquo; liquidity mining model where all LPs are paid equally&lt;/strong&gt;, leading to cvxCRV deposits, which make 75% of the pool, earning 75% of the rewards - while being close to useless liquidity-wise (as there are already too much cvxCRV in that pool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;so-what-can-be-done-better&#34;&gt;So what can be done better?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, the concentration could be finetuned much more at the liquidity structure level. cvxCRV is a &amp;ldquo;one-way asset&amp;rdquo;: you can wrap CRV to cvxCRV 1:1 through the Convex contracts, but converting cvxCRV to CRV is done on a DEX at a discount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=&amp;gt; This means cvxCRV has a price ceiling against CRV: in no world, cvxCRV could be worth &amp;gt;1 CRV, and the current price is around 0.95 CRV per cvxCRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==&amp;gt; The ideal structure for such a pool could be &lt;strong&gt;a concentration going from 1cvxCRV = 0.9 CRV to 1 cvxCRV = 0.99 CRV, offering vastly superior liquidity efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, for the incentivization layer, massive gains are to be made with a switch. Instead of paying all LPs equally while the pool is massively unbalanced, why not focus on those who bring the most value to the pool, aka the CRV component?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;=&amp;gt; I&amp;rsquo;d go with two joint pools to best cover that pair incentivize-wise: &lt;strong&gt;first, a static LP over ten bins&lt;/strong&gt; centered around the current price - it provides room for the price to express itself with sufficient liquidity &amp;amp; this structure is already &amp;gt;100x more efficient than the existing Curve V2 pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;==&amp;gt; For the nail in the coffin, we can &lt;strong&gt;add a one-tick left-right pool one top to maximize liquidity efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The details of this example help you understand that if you take this pool to Maverick, the compounded effect of the superior liquidity structure with a vastly more efficient incentivization model leads to results from a different league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/curve-cvxcrv-crv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-cvxcrv-crv.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently $54M TVL in Curve cvxCRV/CRV pool for a daily volume of around $300k daily (0.5% utilization). With a base incentive of 12% CRV, ~&lt;strong&gt;$6M of CRV tokens are expanded yearly to maintain this liquidity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Maverick, a ~$500K  properly structured pool&lt;/strong&gt; ($250k static broad range + $250k left-right) &lt;strong&gt;would be sufficient to consistently process the $300k daily volume&lt;/strong&gt; with better prices than on Curve. Assuming the same incentivization intensity, &lt;strong&gt;it would cost $60k a year to maintain&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;proto-liquidity-shaping-with-bunni&#34;&gt;Proto Liquidity Shaping with Bunni?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope that, at this point, you get a better sense of why liquidity shaping is genuinely revolutionary, as it will allow another order-of-magnitude leap regarding the efficiency of both the liquidity structures and the incentivization models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are earlier, less complete iterations on such a concept, provided by the liquidity manager built on top of UniswapV3 that allows incentivization on a customized range, for instance, rewards for LUSD/USDC LP, but only for the LUSD = 0.999 USDC to LUSD = 1.01 USDC range. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bunni.pro/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bunni&lt;/a&gt; is a good example of such services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those could be described as &amp;ldquo;proto liquidity shaping,&amp;rdquo; as they enable to force a specific price range but cannot apply different weights to each tick in that range: they are limited by the Uniswap V3 pool model that offers less flexibility than Maverick. In the end, both are quite complimentary as Bunni can be used to force a wide range, which can be further refined with a uneven static Maverick pool &amp;amp; finally maintained uber liquid at current price with a left-right on Maverick too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mav-token&#34;&gt;MAV TOKEN
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With clear perspectives on both the novel pool structure and incentivization model and their consequences, we&amp;rsquo;re now ready to add the last piece of a puzzle, one you&amp;rsquo;re likely more familiar with, but here too, there are key differences: the MAV token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released just a few weeks ago, the MAV token has been airdropped to early liquidity providers and protocol users. The initial airdrop is just &lt;strong&gt;the first of many&lt;/strong&gt;, and more are planned, for LPs, but also protocols harnessing Maverick or building on top of it. For more details on the intended distribution, check this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/maverick-protocol/maverick-ecosystem-incentive-program-95cf76dbfa5e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maverick Ecosystem Incentive Program&lt;/a&gt; article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As readers of this blog, I imagine you are extensively familiar with the veCRV model and its implications. If not, you&amp;rsquo;ve got some reading to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV wars: understanding the race to accumulate power to influence Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vemav--liquidity-directing-voting-vote-directed-liquidity-shaping&#34;&gt;veMAV &amp;amp; Liquidity Directing Voting (vote-directed liquidity shaping)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/vemav.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;vemav&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the MAV token is sequential, currently in phase 1, where users can claim their drop, LP MAV, or lock it to obtain veMAV. &lt;strong&gt;Stage 2 will introduce Maverick&amp;rsquo;s Liquidity Directing Voting and mark the true beginning of the MAV races.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main difference here is, of course, the expressivity enabled by Maverick that will also impact the tokenomics: unlike on veCRV or veBAL, where projects allocate liquidity to a whole pool, here, with Maverick, &lt;strong&gt;protocols will be able to target their voting power to a specific part of the AMM distribution&lt;/strong&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll find more information on veMAV here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/maverick-protocol/introducing-maverick-protocols-voting-escrow-model-c29a60120339&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Introducing Maverick Protocol&amp;rsquo;s Voting-Escrow Model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maverick--vemav-x-chain-strategy&#34;&gt;Maverick &amp;amp; veMAV X-chain strategy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another critical thing to note with the MAV token is that it implements &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://layerzero.gitbook.io/docs/evm-guides/layerzero-omnichain-contracts/oft&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Layer Zero&amp;rsquo;s Omnichain Fungible Token (OFT) standard&lt;/a&gt;, greatly facilitating cross-chain operations. It enables MAV to exist natively on every chain and should ease the operational overhard for the team to launch the gauge system on a new network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not seem much at first glance, but it could make a massive difference. Indeed, Curve and Balancer have been slow to export their full gauge model to networks other than the mainnet they initially operate on. &lt;strong&gt;I expect Maverick to move much more quickly&lt;/strong&gt;, and the early empirical data validate it. In ~3 months of existence, Maverick has already launched two chains apart from mainnet: zkSync and BSC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;another-main-difference-with-vecrv&#34;&gt;Another main difference with veCRV
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;veMAV implements several other changes compared to a base veCRV model, and I invite you to identify them all. Here are some other ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The veMAV per MAV weighting is not linear here, even if it still favors max lockers (4 years); the min lock of 1 week gives one veMAV/MAV, while max locking gives 5veMAV/MAV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no linear decay&lt;/strong&gt; like on veCRV - which is a significant UX improvement. It could also have very positive consequences for veMAV liquid wrappers, making it easier to keep close to the peg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet there are still incentives to stay committed. Indeed, The veMAV/MAV ratio is computed with the formula &lt;code&gt;1.5^(lock end - contract launch)&lt;/code&gt;. With the lock end as the main parameter, veMAV lockers who want to maximize their power must extend their lock frequently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding wrappers, several existing projects have already expressed their intention of building on top of Maverick or veMAV, including Paladin, SpiralDAO, and StakeDAO. The MAV wars will be vicious, so read the fine print before locking your MAV somewhere else than in the veMAV contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forward-outlook--parting-words&#34;&gt;Forward outlook &amp;amp; parting words
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Maverick is currently live on mainnet, zkSync, and BSC. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to remark on how much it dominates the volume on zkSync, even with a fraction of its competitor TVL:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/zksync-dex-volume.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;zksync-dex-volume.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/liquidity-shaping-maverick/zksync-dex-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;zksync-dex-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mainnet, most of the success has been found with ETH-LSDs pairs (wstETH, swETH, etc.) and stablecoins. Maverick&amp;rsquo;s efficient liquidity structure is highly competitive with Curve, Uniswap, and Balancer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On volatile tokens, LPs are a bit shy still, just like it took a few months for people to get used to the novelty brought in by Uniswap V3. Interestingly, LPs are experimenting more on zkSync, especially on pairs such as ETH/USDC, thanks to the lowered gas costs, leading to an overall capital efficiency even more significant than on mainnet, here are the stats for today (July 06 2023):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniswap V3 - mainnet: 0.23&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick - mainnet: 0.3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick - zkSync: 0.93&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-started-with-maverick-as-a-user&#34;&gt;Getting started with Maverick as a user
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a learning curve for Maverick, as understanding how to structure liquidity properly can be intimidating because of all the options provided. Yet more options mean more expressivity and, thus, more efficiency and returns when adequately harnessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To make the most of Maverick as a user and discover the protocol in an environment with low fees, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend supplying your first LPs on zkSync&lt;/strong&gt; - as it will enable you to modify them at a low cost if needed. Like most new DeFi products, the best way to master it is to use it and see it behaves in various market conditions, so get at it: you might also be double-dipping on airdrops so that it can be quite a rewarding experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to check out the Boosted Pools, which - in addition to their incentives - have a pre-defined liquidity configuration, making them more accessible to LPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-managers-its-time-to-wake-up&#34;&gt;Liquidity Managers, it&amp;rsquo;s time to wake up!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the project side, &lt;strong&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s an absolute necessity for liquidity managers to understand and master Maverick&lt;/strong&gt;, as it&amp;rsquo;s by far the venue delivering the most liquidity efficiency. I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to help them in the process, since it has become a specialty of mine. Feel free to reach out if you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss how your project could harness liquidity shaping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: In case you missed the news, I&amp;rsquo;ve been advising the Maverick team since last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2023/maverickxtokenbrice.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Announcement: TokenBrice 🤝 Maverick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will be interesting to see how the next few months of the DEX wars will unfold; with Maverick already consistently in the top 5 of Ethereum DEXes by volume processed, I think it&amp;rsquo;s no stretch to envision it breaking into the top 3 by the end of year latest as the veMAV gauges will be released.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you better understand the paradigm shift that lies with the transition from liquidity mining / basic ve(3,3) to Maverick&amp;rsquo;s powerhouse implementing vote-directed liquidity shaping. Feel free to follow the events live, monitoring onchain data like as OGs do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>ve(3,3), the logical next step after veCRV?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/solidly-velodrome-fork/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/solidly-velodrome-fork/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/solidly-velodrome-template/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post ve(3,3), the logical next step after veCRV?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Solidly/Velodrome forks have been popping up like mushrooms, especially across the popular layer 2 like Arbitrum or zkSync. Solidly is now the top #3 forked protocol in DeFi and one of the rare cases where the forks (such as Velodrome) are the market leaders. At first glance, it could seem like just another fork hype train, like when we had the Uni/Sushi fork season, Olympus fork season, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And indeed, it’s overblown: an absurd amount of such DEXes are launching weekly, and 95% of them won’t be relevant six months from now. However, like with most of such hype trains, there is deep down, below the fluff, an actual fundamental innovation in how decentralized exchanges are designed that is worth looking into.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this article will dive deep into the Solidly and Velodrome models to understand why they became a standard fork template. With that said, we’ll be in an excellent position to ponder the next steps for these DEXes and what this market might look like in a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s get right to it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article assumes a minimal understanding of decentralized finance and a thorough understanding of the veCRV model. If you need a refresher, check: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md%22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV Wars: understanding the race to accumulate power to influence Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-ve33-dexes&#34;&gt;Introduction to ve(3,3) DEXes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into how Solidly built on top and tried to improve the veCRV model, let’s take a step back to consider the scope first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;amm-structure-vs-incentivization-layer&#34;&gt;AMM Structure VS Incentivization Layer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, to grasp the ve(3,3) DEXes story, we need to distinguish between two layers that are equally important for a decentralized exchange:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The liquidity structure layer&lt;/strong&gt;: the various AMM models used to sustain liquidity, such as UNIv2’s x*y=k or Curve’s stableswap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The incentivization layer&lt;/strong&gt;: fees + all other incentives directed to the liquidity provider, including token emissions (such as in the CRV model).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at the end of the day, 1 – the liquidity structure – is the heart of the game, the second layer – incentives – is crucial in attracting and sustaining sufficient liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curve innovated on both. While the models we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss today harnessed it, they &lt;strong&gt;focus entirely on improving the incentivization layer&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed at the current stage, most of ve(3,3) DEXes harnessing the Solidly or Velodrome model only offer two well-known liquidity structure types: x*y=k &amp;amp; stableswap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Depending on the DEXes, those two liquidity models are called correlated/volatile or stable/volatile.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let’s talk about what was so interesting about Andre’s Cronje original Solidly and what insights we can draw from its failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;andre-cronjes-solidly-innovations&#34;&gt;Andre Cronje’s Solidly Innovations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Introduced in early 2022 on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://andrecronje.medium.com/ve-3-3-44466eaa088b&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cronje’s medium&lt;/a&gt;, the crucial part of Solidly’s vision was a significant improvement in the utility for lockers. On Curve, lockers are committed for four years with non-transferable vote-escrowed tokens. While it’s great for the long-term incentives alignment of all the participants of the Curve ecosystem, it also creates a sizable barrier to entry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus came ve(3,3), with at its core &lt;strong&gt;the veNFT&lt;/strong&gt;. While veCRV are illiquid, veSOLID positions are represented by the veNFT, enabling their transfer or OTC sale/purchase. It helps make locking less scary. To further incentivize it, Cronje introduced “&lt;strong&gt;anti-dilutive rebases&lt;/strong&gt;”, a concept drawn from Ampleforth/Olympus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here is simple: since the Curve/Solidly DEX model emits tokens weekly to liquidity providers, vetokens holders are constantly diluted. They must keep increasing their position even to maintain their current vote share. To compensate for this, veSOLID holders receive a weekly rebase proportional to the weekly emissions under the Solidly model. This allows them to maintain their voting share even if no new tokens are locked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from these changes, Solidly inherited most of the Curve model, including &lt;strong&gt;the LP boost&lt;/strong&gt; feature, enabling vetokens holders to earn boosted yields on their liquidity position. This feature has real consequences since it pretty much “calls for a Convex.” Indeed, the logical conclusion of such a feature is one/a few actors seizing significant amounts of vetokens and providing their LP boost to depositors for a fee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presence/absence of this feature is the critical difference between the Solidly and Velodrome models, so we’ll touch back on it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there one last critical twist to the voter incentives model. On Curve, LP get half of the trading fees collected + CRV emissions, while voters have no exposure to the fees of the pool they are voting on. It can lead to situation where voters are voting for pools just for the bribes, even if the pool provides no volume to the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Solidly, the LPs are only rewarded with SOLID emission, and the LP fees are redirected to the voters of the pool. Thus, as a veSOLID holder, to optimize your earnings, you are incentivized to consider the volume on the pool you are voting on, and not just the bribes. This leads to a better alignment of the incentives of the main participants of the protocol (swapper, liquidity provider, veHolder)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solidly also innovated on the launch strategy, with &lt;strong&gt;an airdrop targeted at protocols&lt;/strong&gt;, depending on their onchain activity on Fantom, where Solidly was. Together, all those innovations and the hype led to a massive amount of liquidity quickly attracted to the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Solidly’s initial implementation had a few key weaknesses, including an aggressively steep decline in emissions and fully permissionless gauge creation that allowed any pools to receive SOLID rewards. It was gamable, so it was gamed. Soon, tokens were created for the sole purpose of farming SOLID, and the price quickly spiraled, along with the TVL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/solidly-velodrome-template/solidly-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;cover-image&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The TVL disappeared as quickly as it came, and Solidly became a part of history for most. But those who followed the events closely knew that Solidly’s failure did not come from a weakness in the ve(3,3) model but more of &lt;strong&gt;an overlooked detail of its implementation&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that while Solidly was no more, ve(3,3) would likely resurface. And it did, a few months later, on another chain made by another team: enter Velodrome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;velodromes-refinements-to-the-solidly-model&#34;&gt;Velodrome’s refinements to the Solidly model
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/velodrome-v2/optimism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Velodrome&lt;/a&gt; harnessed the Solidly model and fixed the issue with emissions by implementing a &lt;strong&gt;whitelist for gauges&lt;/strong&gt;, helping to avoid the situation where rewards are allocated to made-up tokens, as seen on Solidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velodrome went far beyond a mere fork, though, and implemented further improvements; among them were a more sustainable emissions model and &lt;strong&gt;removing the LP boost feature&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning there is no preferential treatment for veVELO holders in terms of yield. Velodrome also streamlines the experience for first-time LPs who might be confused with the yield range you see on DEXes with LP boost implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the technical features, a large part of Velodrome’s success is due to the &lt;strong&gt;team’s execution and care for the business development strategies&lt;/strong&gt;, an essential part of the ve(3,3) model. Built on Optimism, Velodrome found its PMF as the chain liquidity layer. Thanks to its model, sustaining liquidity on Velodrome is much more cost-effective for projects than, say, on Uniswap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Solidly, &lt;strong&gt;Velodrome airdropped several protocols with a veVELO NFT,&lt;/strong&gt; no strings attached, which helped immensely to attract the initial voting and bribing activity. The protocol found a good fit, mostly with other protocols emitting stablecoins or ETH liquid stake derivatives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/solidly-velodrome-template/defiwars-velodrome.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defiwars-velodrome&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost a year, and the activity has sustained, thanks to careful and progressive adjustments of the &lt;strong&gt;OP incentives allocated on the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, known as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@VelodromeFi/tour-de-op-updates-631268181baa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Tour de OP&lt;/a&gt;. Most of them are used to incentivize two behaviors essential to sustain the flywheel:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bribes from protocols, incentivized by OP bribes matching.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locking of veVELO, incentivized by an OP lock bonus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bribe matching is further increased for projects which lock veVELO or deploy sizeable amounts of protocol-owned liquidity to the exchange, helping further amplify the reinforcing effect: those who want to build liquidity sustained over the long term on Velodrome have been given solid reasons to buy VELO, lock and vote, bribe, and supply POL, &lt;strong&gt;ideally all at once&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads to Velodrome topping the protocols TVL charts on Optimism and processing about 30% of the total volume of the chain vs 50% for Uniswap, which has roughly ¼ of Velodrome’s TVL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/solidly-velodrome-template/optimism-volume.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;optimism-DEX-volume&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, why such a spread between the both? Simple: Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s Volume/TVL ratio is ~9x above Velodrome right now because the liquidity on Uniswap is much more concentrated and thus more efficient. But it’s about to change as Velodrome V2 is arriving soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introducing-velodrome-v2&#34;&gt;Introducing Velodrome V2
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Uniswap had a headstart with concentrated liquidity, it will change rapidly. The v3 license &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.uniswap.org/contracts/v3/guides/governance/liscense-modifications&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;expired on April 1st 2023&lt;/a&gt;, meaning the model is now much easier to re-implement. Many DEXes, including Solidly/Velodrome forks, intend to harness this. Still, to keep this article focused, we’ll only cover what is announced for Velodrome V2, expected in the next few weeks/months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Velodrome V2 will not just mark &lt;strong&gt;the introduction of UNI-v3 style of LP on the DEX&lt;/strong&gt; but also significant UX/UI improvements, a relayer to ease the management of veNFT, artwork for the veNFT, and much more. Check the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@VelodromeFi/velodrome-the-road-ah-43488531bb0e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;V2 announcement article&lt;/a&gt; for details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you understand the benefits of the Solidly and Velodrome models. While I mention the myriad of forks in the introduction, I’ve stayed on course with this article. I guess this calls for a follow-up where I comb through their main forks and the modifications they implement into the template: stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Importance of Business Development&lt;/strong&gt; | ve(3,3), just like Curve, are protocols for protocols. The team&amp;rsquo;s professionalism and ability to efficiently prioritize and executive on BD is a sizable success factor of the DEX over the long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of the launch/airdrop/top racers rooster&lt;/strong&gt; | Even if BD is done well, a given ve(3,3) DEX is only as good as its top racers. Yes, you want them bribing, voting, and driving awareness, but not only. The quality of the liquidity driven to the DEX also matters (volume/TVL ratio).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LP Boost and its consequences&lt;/strong&gt; | If a ve(3,3) implements LP boost, it calls for Convex-like protocols. The success of the ve(3,3) will be impacted by how much and how well its Convex-likes do. To follow the key stats on the various wrappers and main veTokens holders, check - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiwars.xyz/wars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiWars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ve(3,3) + Liquidity Concentration&lt;/strong&gt; | While ve(3,3) is a significant innovation for the incentives layer of the DEX, it currently harnesses sub-par liquidity structures. Properly matching the ve(3,3) incentives model with an efficient UNIv3-style liquidity structure will help further improve the effectiveness of the flywheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Announcement: TokenBrice 🤝 Maverick</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/maverick-x-tokenbrice/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/maverick-x-tokenbrice/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/maverick-x-tokenbrice-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Announcement: TokenBrice 🤝 Maverick" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is more of a personal announcement: I wanted to let you know what I am up to and what&amp;rsquo;s happening with Maverick. So let&amp;rsquo;s not beat around the bush: I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to announce that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m supporting the Maverick team as an advisor, helping with the growth strategy, tokenomics, and business development.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storytime&#34;&gt;Storytime
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like me, you must be over-saturated with DEXes. If you follow DeFi closely, you&amp;rsquo;ve seen several of these launches daily. Yet most still adopt fundamental liquidity structures: x*y=k for volatile pairs and stableswap, and focus on innovating on the tokenomics instead: the now famous ve(3,3) DEXes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a DEX that would innovate at the fundamental level&lt;/strong&gt; for a while, so in May last year, when Bob reached out to let me know about Maverick, I was all ears. I quickly realized Maverick could reshape how we envision liquidity in DeFi and help further improve its efficiency. So I’m glad to announce my involvement today: Maverick is already live, growing quickly, and poised for even exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we dive into what makes Maverick so interesting, we need to take a step back and consider the broader context of liquidity in DeFi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-structuring-deep-dive&#34;&gt;Liquidity Structuring Deep Dive
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the beginning, there was Uniswap&lt;/strong&gt;, and its ease of use for liquidity providers led people to believe it was a trivial activity. Yet, any liquidity-providing activity on a DEX involves two decisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picking a pair (or more) of tokens (ex: ETH/USDC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Forming price assumptions regarding one/both tokens (🐂, 🐻, or 🦀)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second decision is &lt;strong&gt;often implicit&lt;/strong&gt;, like with UniswapV2, where you get no option but only one choice: 50/50, meaning that your optimal scenario is both tokens going sideways in price with a large trading volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Uniswap V3 emerged, the second assumption was suddenly more explicit to DeFi users thanks to concentrated liquidity. However, V3 added complexity to the liquidity provider experience and active management. It &lt;strong&gt;mainly caters to power-users who can afford frequent rebalancing&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;require external tooling&lt;/strong&gt; to be harnessed effectively by LPs, the liquidity manager – Arrakis, Bunni, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-unique-about-maverick&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s unique about Maverick?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Maverick is the spiritual descendant of UniV3 and CurveV2. It offers infinite flexibility in the design of liquidity-providing position, similar to Uniswap V3, but with streamlined and autonomous execution, just like on Curve. Indeed, LPs on Maverick can decide to redistribute their liquidity to follow the price in one or both directions. &lt;strong&gt;If needed, the rebalancing is done at the DEX level, ensuring gas efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt; Maverick also supports “static pools” that are range-bound too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This feature makes Maverick a fantastic fit for pegged assets, especially those that are not continually trading precisely at the peg&lt;/strong&gt; and so underserved by the usual liquidity structures, such as a LUSD/USDC pair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve stableswap, which optimizes liquidity for a 1/1 price, is not ideal when LUSD is overpeg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniswap v3, where LPs usually end up super concentrated around the current market price, which is efficient, but also quickly through them out of range as the price move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/mav-both.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mav-mode-both&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Maverick, such a pair can be harnessed optimally by each LP, depending on their actual goal. &lt;strong&gt;It enables each LP to craft an automatically adjusting position that enforces a strategy fitting his assumptions and needs&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are some examples of goals &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; liquidity structure matching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎚️ | Looking for a safe yield with minimal risk? A static LP might be preferable, as the outcomes are predictable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐂/🐻 | Thinking LUSD is currently over/undervalued: you can supply directional liquidity and earn extra if your assumption verifies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🦀 | Want to bet on volume with prices going sideways? You can simply focus your liquidity a few bins around the price and activate the &lt;strong&gt;left-right mode&lt;/strong&gt; to constantly rebalance the current price, thus maximizing the available liquidity and fees collected but also the potential impermanent loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, Maverick has found &lt;strong&gt;a beast of a product/market fit on pools like wstETH/ETH&lt;/strong&gt;, often averaging over 100% daily utilization rate. Here’s today, for instance (4/20):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve: TVL = $1.5B, Volume =$34M, Utilization = 2,26%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick: TVL = $10.6M, Volume =$10.45M, &lt;strong&gt;Utilization = 98,5%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/mav-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Maverick Top Pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launched just a few weeks ago on the Ethereum mainnet, Maverick is already seeing an impressive volume and unprecedented liquidity utilization rate, especially on pegged asset pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maverick was also launched on zkSync, its first L2, a few days ago. As more staple DeFi projects roll out service there, Maverick will have many opportunities to demonstrate the superior efficiency its liquidity designs can offer to LPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited about the next steps: as a DeFi Strategist at Liquity, the release of Maverick felt like early Christmas to me; I think it&amp;rsquo;s just getting started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll contribute to Maverick as an advisor, meaning that my main focus remains my commitment to immutable protocols, especially Liquity, helping them grow through various onchain and offchain activities. I’m confident Maverick will quickly prove to be a decisive tool in achieving that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just hearing about Maverick? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mav.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/mavprotocol&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;join the Discord server.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/money-god-meme.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to cover an essential topic for Ethereum and other blockchains and often misunderstood: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; assets&lt;/strong&gt;, which track the price of a reference asset. Before looking at the different approaches to producing such an asset, we&amp;rsquo;ll first start with a higher level of analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are such assets needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are they used for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we want to standardize non-native Ethereum assets on this chain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these foundations are established, we will have all the tools to &lt;strong&gt;figure out the different methods and what is at stake&lt;/strong&gt;.. I will conclude with a more detailed analysis of a project that seems to me very relevant and innovative : the RAI of Reflexer Labs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already familiar with the different pegging mechanisms, you can jump &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34; &gt;directly to the section on Reflexer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assets-standardization-on-the-ethereums-blockchain&#34;&gt;Assets standardization on the Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s blockchain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volume of issuance and use of pegged-assets has exploded last year, but before we look at what they are actually used for, let&amp;rsquo;s understand why. The simplest use case is to produce a stable asset, most often indexed to the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, &lt;strong&gt;the method used at a high level is tokenization&lt;/strong&gt;: we represent an asset that comes from another chain / world on Ethereum, such as wBTC (corresponding to 1 BTC on the Bitcoin chain) or USDC (corresponding to 1 USD in Circle&amp;rsquo;s bank account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;addresses one of the most common concerns for the general public: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cryptos are volatile assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;the rise of stablecoins has gone hand in hand with the rise of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;, why? According to me, there are many reasons, the main ones being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrowings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable assets can be very productive in DeFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-borrowings-mostly-in-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Why are borrowings mostly in stablecoins?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The money markets allow their users to borrow assets using other assets as collateral. The most frequent use case corresponds to the following pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user deposits a volatile asset, such as ETH, wBTC or LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He uses it as collateral to &lt;strong&gt;borrow a stable asset, like USDC or DAI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so? To put it simply, few people are fond of the risks associated with price changes. &lt;strong&gt;Borrowing an asset, if you then mobilize it, is like shorting it&lt;/strong&gt;. No problem with stablecoins - in theory - but the reality is quite different with a non-stable asset: if the price goes down, good for you: the debt will only be cheaper to repay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the other way around, the scenario can be frightening since &lt;strong&gt;you can end up with a debt that increases&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you borrow 1000 UNI when one UNI is worth $20. You sell them for another token, for example stablecoins. So here you are with $20,000 DAI that you mobilize in DeFi for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You hold your debt for several months and now you want to pay it off. Except that one UNI is now worth $30 and you no longer have any: you have to buy some back on the markets to pay off the debt and close the position. &lt;strong&gt;The debt is always paid in the borrowed asset&lt;/strong&gt;: you therefore owe 1,000 UNIs at $30 per unit or 30,000 DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am ignoring the loan interest&amp;rsquo;s here for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake. In reality you should pay back slightly more UNI, according to the interest rate and the length of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yield-farming-with-stable-assets&#34;&gt;Yield-farming with stable-assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the first point understood, the second one makes perfect sense.: &lt;strong&gt;a lot of people are borrowing stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;, so that means that on the other side of the market people are lending them out, for attractive interest rates considering the demand. For example, on Aave, one of the main money markets, there has been &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity crunch in stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; almost since the launch of v2. Depositors enjoy an average annualized return of about 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is quite similar elsewhere with differences due to the specificities of each money market. Nevertheless, the liquidity crisis on stablecoins goes far beyond Aave: it potentially extends to the whole DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;there is no shortage of opportunities to produce a return with stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about loans here, but it is also possible to bring liquidity to stablecoin pairs and even combine the two approaches to increase returns with a product like Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/curve-yield-pool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-yield-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explosion-of-the-pegged-assets-use-in-2020&#34;&gt;Explosion of the pegged-assets use in 2020
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, we have seen a real explosion in the issuance and use of pegged-assets in 2020. On the one hand, more and more projects are being launched to propose &lt;strong&gt;new asset types or new approaches to represent them&lt;/strong&gt;. On the other hand, the scenarios for using these pegged-assets are multiplying thanks to the growth of Curve money markets, vaults like those offered by Yearn or Harvest, and other even more complex DeFi products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name but one, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://alchemix.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alchemix&lt;/a&gt;, a new synthetic asset service that allows &lt;strong&gt;loans secured by your future return&lt;/strong&gt;. Let me explain: with Alchemix, everything starts with a stable asset that produces a return. They chose the yDAI to start with (DAI productive thanks to the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user starts by depositing yDAI. He can then &lt;strong&gt;give up his future return&lt;/strong&gt; to borrow up to 50% of the deposited value. His loan is &lt;strong&gt;reimbursed automatically thanks to the interest generated by the yDAI&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, since he has access to 50% of the deposited value immediately (borrowed in alUSD), he can put it to work to increase the return of the entire strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of product allows for an interesting across time arbitrage and leads to an even greater demand for stablecoins: at the launch of Alchemix, deposits in the yDAI vault took off up to the maximum capacity available for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about stablecoins so far, but a similar scenario has played out on other pegged-assets like tokenized BTC on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/stablecoin-growth.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stablecoin-growth-ethereum-messari&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the impressive growth of DeFi, we can only expect the demand for this type of asset to grow ever faster. So let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the different approaches used to produce them to understand their trade-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-different-methods-to-produce-pegged-assets&#34;&gt;The different methods to produce pegged-assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, the vast majority of this demand for stable assets is being addressed with solutions based on a 1:1 match requiring trust. Thus, it is &lt;strong&gt;mostly USDT ($38.5B issued) and USDC ($9.4B) that are leading the way&lt;/strong&gt;, well ahead of DAI ($2.7B). The same goes for Bitcoin, without going into detail, all the most used solutions require trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pegged-assets&amp;quot; are assets that follow the price of another via a mechanism called &amp;ldquo;pegging&amp;rdquo;. Therefore, the &amp;ldquo;peg&amp;rdquo; is the value that the asset must maintain, for example $1 for stablecoins that follow the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growing variety of approaches are being explored to produce a pegged-asset with less compromise. They are generally grouped into large families that correspond to the main method used to maintain the peg. However, as these approaches develop, the boundaries between them become blurred as several projects explore &lt;strong&gt;hybrid approaches mixing several elements of each&lt;/strong&gt;. We will start from the simplest to understand and progressively go to the most complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-a-trusted-third-party-11-ratio&#34;&gt;Using a trusted third party (1:1 ratio)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The peg is easily maintained and rather stable. The system is solvent at all times (-&amp;gt; 1 USD in the bank for 1 USDC issued for example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; The system requires a central trusted intermediary - the issuing organization. This same organization relies on another intermediary, the bank where the USD are deposited. In addition, the presence of a trusted intermediary creates a risk: is it reliable? transparent? The risk goes beyond image, it can also be legal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has already been detailed enough, so I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to the more complex methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins-produced-by-over-collateralization-maker-dai&#34;&gt;Stablecoins produced by over-collateralization: Maker DAI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The system no longer involves a central trusted intermediary (at least initially) &amp;amp; still manages to more or less maintain the peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; It will require &lt;strong&gt;always more $ collateral than $ (DAI) produced (over-collateralization)&lt;/strong&gt;. Governance risks. Risks at the liquidation level, carried out by third parties. The system is as trustless as its most used collateral. Maker now accepts censorable collateral (wBTC, USDC, etc.) which reintroduces a trust risk into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before algorithmic stablecoins, MakerDAO is a pioneer when thinking about how to &lt;strong&gt;produce a stable asset with less trust needed in the system than 1:1 approaches&lt;/strong&gt;. Maker is a more complex service because beyond the DAI - the stablecoin issued by the system, it also allows its users to use different assets to borrow (technically mint) DAIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it recreates risks and dangers to maintain the peg of the DAI. Many improvements have been proposed and implemented since the beginning, which allows DAI to be much more stable now than in its early days. Nevertheless, the scaling of DAI has come with additional compromises in terms of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-innovative-approaches&#34;&gt;More innovative approaches
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the approaches are more diversified - I group them into two families: the algorithmic approaches already well studied on my blog and the hybrid approaches. Both are based on an essential concept to understand: the &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; of these systems is a smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-smart-contract-as-central-bank&#34;&gt;A smart contract as &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use the words &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; because it evokes the essential concept here: the body that issues money and implements the monetary policy of the system is a smart contract. This allows for great transparency and visibility on the actions related to monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the systems presented below, you really need to understand this: &lt;strong&gt;the decisions to create or destroy new stablecoins are &amp;ldquo;taken&amp;rdquo; by a smart contract&lt;/strong&gt; - it alone has this ability to issue (and destroy / burn in some systems) tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say that the smart contract takes &amp;ldquo;decisions&amp;rdquo;, I must explain myself : &lt;strong&gt;to be more precise, one could say that it reacts to the evolution of various measurable parameters&lt;/strong&gt;. The decisions of the smart contract are therefore transparent and predictable. A change in the rules governing it is possible but only via a governance vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most often, the main parameter taken into account is simply &lt;strong&gt;the price of the stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, in early algorithmic systems like Basis (BAC is the stablecoin), the rules are simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If BAC &amp;gt; $1, then the system issues and distributes new BAC to try to bring the price back towards $1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When BAC &amp;lt; $1 the system destroys BAC to create upward pressure. The destruction is not direct but voluntary: the actors in the system are encouraged to burn their BAC for a coupon (BAB) corresponding to 1 BAC + premium, which they can collect only when BAC has a sustained price above the dollar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more background on this &amp;ldquo;smart contract central bank&amp;rdquo; idea, you can read my first article on algorithmic stablecoins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;L&amp;rsquo;état et le futur des stablecoins algorithmiques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;algorithmic-approaches&#34;&gt;Algorithmic approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; This makes systems without a central trust intermediary possible and thus opens the way to truly trustless pegged-assets. Community governance possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; Sustained peg loss or difficulty maintaining peg. Possible governance attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I analyze the main approaches to produce algorithmic stablecoins in a dedicated article :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖ L&amp;rsquo;histoire de deux modèles de seigneuriage : Basis contre ESD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, projects like ESD, DSD, or Basis Cash were the pioneers of algorithmic stablecoins. However, all of these systems are now in a bit of an abyss: &lt;strong&gt;their stablecoins have been worth well under a dollar for a long time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/bac-90days.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bac-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their users are looking forward to a V2 that will bring stablecoin back to the dollar like the messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hybrid-approaches&#34;&gt;Hybrid approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The best of both worlds?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages / Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; A new potentially central and  intermediate point of trust appears in the system. You what happened next&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the current limitations of first generation algorithmic stablecoins, another approach has successfully emerged: the hybrid approach.  These are intrinsically algorithmic systems that &lt;strong&gt;include nonetheless a reserve in stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. (different from the system) used to maintain the peg: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://samkazemian.medium.com/frax-v2-algorithmic-market-operations-b84521ed7133&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pioneer in this field is Frax. With Frax, &lt;strong&gt;when FRAX trades above the dollar the system itself sells some to accumulate USDC&lt;/strong&gt;. This helps to bring the price down while building up a reserve of stablecoins not exposed to the system itself. Thus, if FRAX is trading &lt;strong&gt;below the dollar, the system can buy FRAX directly&lt;/strong&gt; on the market (using its stock of USDC) to bring the price back down to $1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/frax-price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;frax-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this approach has the &lt;strong&gt;merit of efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; (FRAX has maintained its peg very well since launch), it reintroduces a trusted intermediary into the mechanism. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not a bank like with Tether, but it&amp;rsquo;s still necessary trust in the system. What happens if the USDC balance of Frax is seized or frozen: could the system survive it? For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, yes it is technically (and legally) possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remain very high-level on FRAX and describe the system mostly as it was in the beginning. Many integrations have been implemented or are being considered, such as the ability to mint FRAX directly into the FRAX-Tornado anonymity set (directly into TornadoCash) to offer a potentially more confidential stablecoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34;&gt;Focus on Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s RAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To finish this article, which I hope will be instructive, I suggest to analyze an innovative system: Reflexer RAI. It is a similar approach to MakerDAO, in the sense that the stable asset is produced by over-collateralization. Nevertheless, it brings many improvements over the Maker model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trustless collateral&lt;/strong&gt;: Until now, RAI only accepts ETH as collateral. This means that 100% of the collaterals in the system are not censurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond the dollar&lt;/strong&gt;: the asset produced by the system does not follow the dollar (which is not really stable itself). The price of the RAI is determined by a consensus established by the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Money God&lt;/strong&gt; : just like algorithmic stablecoins, the system reacts to different observed parameters. However, just like MakerDAO, here it is the users themselves who directly hit the RAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance&lt;/strong&gt; : the token of the Reflexer system (FLX), which will be distributed to the users, is intended to be used to progressively decentralize the governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t panic if you don&amp;rsquo;t immediately understand why this system is innovative and significant, we will explore each of these points in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;censorship-resistant-collateral&#34;&gt;Censorship-resistant collateral
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initially, MakerDAO only accepted Ether as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;. With the first significant update of the system - the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/whitepaper/White%20Paper%20-The%20Maker%20Protocol_%20MakerDAO%E2%80%99s%20Multi-Collateral%20Dai%20%28MCD%29%20System-FINAL-%20021720.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Multi Collateral DAI&lt;/a&gt; - more tokens became usable as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community was perplexed by this decision, especially because of the choice of accepted tokens. Thus, BAT was one of the first new collateral while LINK, a token with volume and liquidity already far superior to BAT at the time, only arrived much later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond this &lt;strong&gt;difficult to understand valuation&lt;/strong&gt;, the crux of the problem is that &lt;strong&gt;many collaterals now accepted are censorable&lt;/strong&gt;: wBTC, RenBTC, USDC, TUSD, etc. This reduces the trustlessness of MakerDAO since at different times up to 50% of all DAIs were minted from censorable collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure is now reduced, but the concern remains. Furthermore, the addition of a special USDC vault was criticized during Black Thursday for helping DAI regain its peg - but it also made MakerDAO even more dependent on such collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Reflexer also fits in as &lt;strong&gt;a reaction to this &amp;ldquo;drift&amp;rdquo; of MakerDAO&lt;/strong&gt;: for now, only ETH is accepted to open a vault. I will be surprised if the team or the DAO vote to accept censorable collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-the-us-dollar&#34;&gt;Beyond the US Dollar
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Reflexer goes much further than DAI in its quest for stability. Indeed, the dollar itself does not have a stable value, because of the continuous production of new units which leads to inflation: thus $10,000 in 1950 is equivalent in purchasing power to almost $110,000 in 2021 (3.42% inflation per year on average over the period).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An asset that is intended to be stable must therefore go beyond the limitations of the dollar and this is precisely what RAI does&lt;/strong&gt;: it does not follow the price of the dollar. The price of RAI is determined by pure social consensus: the system takes into account the observed price of the ETH/RAI pair (market price) as well as an internal price target (redemption rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are often gaps between the two, which creates an incentive to beat the RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/reflexer-spread.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;reflexer-spread&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore, RAI is obviously not a stablecoin, It is not a pegged-asset either&lt;/strong&gt;. There are not enough words to describe RAI accurately, but let me try. RAI is an abstraction on the ETH which is intended to be more stable than the ETH, while maintaining its trustlessness (with time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-hail-the-money-god&#34;&gt;All Hail the Money God
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Money God&amp;rdquo; is the term used to refer to the set of rules that govern the Reflexer system. The memetic potential is also enormous. To remain quite synthetic, the Money God is lenient towards those who follow a perennial and long-term logic on the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the distribution mechanism of the Reflexer token, FLX, was recently modified to better align incentives (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;). The essence of the change is to better compensate those who perpetuate the system, i.e.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit ETH to mint RAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the RAI minted + the equivalent in ETH in the liquidity pool on Uniswap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of March 8, 100% of FLX is being distributed to those who follow this scenario. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/stefanionescu/e66204be990f4bc113a022341cb39186&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The history of FLX retroactive distribution strategies is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-de-governance-plan&#34;&gt;The De-Governance Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the important technical innovation on Reflexer, barely explored here, I particularly appreciate &lt;strong&gt;their approach to governance and decentralization of the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, as described by Stefan one of its architects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The principle of “ungovernance” comes from our desire to progressively remove human control from the RAI system, thus making it socially scalable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has established &lt;strong&gt;a plan with concrete and dated goals&lt;/strong&gt; to achieve this end. The first step is to make the system&amp;rsquo;s liquidation and taxation mechanisms &amp;ldquo;governance minimized&amp;rdquo; - only a few parameters will remain changeable via governance (voting of FLX holders) from this point on. The target date is April 17, 2022, a little over a year after the initial launch of RAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each step, the scenario is similar: a critical mechanism of the system is &amp;ldquo;governance-minimized&amp;rdquo; before it is put back under the full control of FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the details of this plan here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following and waiting for Reflexer for over a year, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally tell you about it, and please forgive me for the delay: I wanted to put it in context to make sure everyone grasps the innovation brought by this protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article &lt;strong&gt;does not constitute investment advice&lt;/strong&gt;. I have no credentials in this area: they do not yet exist for DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am discussing the mechanics of several protocols and what they allow for or envision in the future. Even if I mention tokens, ditto: I discuss their utility or tokenomics but &lt;strong&gt;never their relevance as an investment&lt;/strong&gt;. On this topic, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helps you better understand the rise of pegged-assets on Ethereum - it is essential. It&amp;rsquo;s also critical to understand the different trade-off sets associated with each approach: they are all potentially more or less relevant, depending on your situation and needs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whether you are convinced by Reflexer or not, I strongly encourage you to dig into this system, just as I regularly invite you to explore the workings of Aave, Curve or Unslashed. All four are very relevant and innovative systems: understanding them in depth will allow you to internalize many essential things  to understand decentralized finance in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/money-markets-risk/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/money-markets-risk/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/cover.gif" alt="Featured image of post Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Money markets are at the heart of DeFi. From a high-level perspective, yes, they simply enable the borrowing and lending of various assets. Yet &lt;strong&gt;those functions are like the two primitive verbs of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; at the base of pretty much all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three major money markets right now in DeFi: Aave, Compound &amp;amp; Cream. Yet all the following services use them, one way or another: Yearn Finance, Curve Finance, Alpha Finance, Harvest Finance, DeFiSaver, Saffron, 88MPH, Idle Finance, etc. To put it simply - &lt;strong&gt;money markets are one of the root-level of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money markets are amazing - simple yet very intricate. In this article, I try to provide a framework and some clues to assess the risk at different levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To dive more into the service layer currently being built on top of money markets, feel free to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-risk-scoring-is-broken&#34;&gt;I/ Risk Scoring is Broken
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the risk analysis framework, let&amp;rsquo;s quickly discuss the current leading solution used to evaluate risk in DeFi: Consensys CodeFi DeFiScore.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeFiScore is undisputedly compromised since it&amp;rsquo;s still giving DAI a higher rate on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/compound-v3/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; even with the oracle failure on the Compound side and the arrival of the Safety Module on Aave&amp;rsquo;s side:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consensys CodeFi team was notified a few days ago&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, acknowledged the issue&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but yet &lt;strong&gt;refused any immediate to update the website even with just notice or disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, one of their members proposed a 500 USDC bounty open for anyone willing to update the formula&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It has yet to be claimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that quantitative approaches so far have failed. They must achieve both sustainability (if the formula stays consistent it allows historical comparisons) and adaptability (yet the risk parameters are always evolving): it&amp;rsquo;s not an easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not delve into the depths of risk scoring, as there is a dedicated article exploring what a decent DeFi-native risk scoring system looks like coming out shortly on this blog (hint: it does not exist yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-appreciating-the-safety-of-a-money-market&#34;&gt;II/ Appreciating the Safety of a Money Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s painful to hear, but since quantitative analysis is unhelpful, you have to resort to a qualitative approaches for each project. The good news is there aren&amp;rsquo;t many money markets in DeFi worth looking at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cream / Iron Bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these, you have to look at them holistically. I propose an approach that is &lt;strong&gt;purely mine&lt;/strong&gt;, using &lt;strong&gt;8 different dimensions all critical to the safety of assets&lt;/strong&gt; committed to the money market analyzed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocol access &amp;amp; permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oracles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidation mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collateral listing &amp;amp; risk analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded insurance ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native token risk management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community &amp;amp; Ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what we have today is essentially a comprehensive framework you can use to assess the safety of a given money market. Feel free to challenge me on any item. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessary Disclaimer: This is not investment advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost no one is qualified to assess risks in DeFi: even &amp;ldquo;institutions&amp;rdquo; doing it like the DeFiscore are way off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is intended to help you better understand and appreciate the risk &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;by yourself&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the most reliable way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iia-protocol-access--permissions&#34;&gt;II.A/ Protocol Access &amp;amp; Permissions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the very base level, you want to know who can update the protocol core parameters (-&amp;gt; the contracts), and the different limits associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, there&amp;rsquo;s usually a &lt;strong&gt;timelock&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that any significant change only applies after a set duration. For the administrative functions of the protocol, you need to make sure that they are &lt;strong&gt;community-owned&lt;/strong&gt;, which usually means &lt;strong&gt;governed by a multisig&lt;/strong&gt; of designed community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section also includes everything related to &lt;strong&gt;the &amp;ldquo;opsec&amp;rdquo; of the wallets/people&lt;/strong&gt; governing the multisig. &amp;ldquo;Opsec&amp;rdquo; is short for &amp;ldquo;operations security&amp;rdquo; - it&amp;rsquo;s about the safety of everything digital interfaces related to the holders of these keys. Can they be hacked? Impersonated? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a matter is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;CRITICAL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as we saw recently with the CEO of Nexus Mutual: his laptop was compromised, allowing the hacker to submit a fraudulent transaction on top of a real transaction he signed.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have yet to see significant attacks based on social engineering in DeFi but expect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency on the decisions of the protocol is key too: we address it below in the community &amp;amp; DAO section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on mature money markets like Aave or Compound. Newer projects might be less decentralized, and that can be a good thing - you might want some control and rollback options for a newer project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-protocol-accesses--decentralization&#34;&gt;Assessing the protocol accesses &amp;amp; decentralization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Assess on a protocol/team-basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Potentially all funds deposited on the market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Not yet 🤞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to evalutating opsec and decentralization plan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChrisBlec&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chris Blec&lt;/a&gt; is your guy. He&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising on opsec, and produced many helpful contributions on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/13S7NRk1girTdQMajnVdU5JRlVO5BG_uJKhTO2Ef10b0/edit?usp=sharing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;summarized overview of the situation for the main DeFi projects here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to wrap this up, here are some good questions to ask to assess the safety of a money market at the protocol &amp;amp; permission level:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who can update the contracts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they have a credible opsec?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any drain function in the contracts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do the administrative functions do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How decentralized is the process to create a new lending market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iib-oracles&#34;&gt;II.B/ Oracles
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the oracles are the source for &amp;ldquo;outside truths&amp;rdquo;. &lt;strong&gt;Blockchains are only aware of themselves&lt;/strong&gt;, so for Ethereum, the price of ETH in dollars (or any other token) is technically an &amp;ldquo;outside truth&amp;rdquo; you need to bring on-chain in a &lt;strong&gt;safe and verifiable manner&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s precisely what oracles do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s essential, as the &lt;strong&gt;perceived price&lt;/strong&gt; delivered by the oracle is the &lt;strong&gt;source of truth for the protocol&amp;rsquo;s liquidation decisions&lt;/strong&gt;. If the oracle says DAI is worth 1.30, then you are liquidated even if your DAI-borrowing position was safe on a $1 DAI and DAI is still actually worth $1 on the markets: the oracle is the source of truth. It happened already with Compound, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a theoretical concern.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news here is that the answer is quite simple: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/chainlink-oracles/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ChainLink&lt;/a&gt; is widely recognized as the most credible decentralized oracle solution, so any money market not using at least partly their price feeds is gambling with its users&amp;rsquo; money, as Compound did with significant lossses. It seems like the situation has not improved - despite the failure Compound still uses the same centralized oracle (Coinbase) and a proposal suggesting a switch to ChainLink was refused. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-oracles&#34;&gt;Assessing oracles
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Significant (most impacting sub-theme to date).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: market-based, potentially whole markets can be drained/affected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, on Compound.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can assess the oracles for a money market with the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the source of truth for prices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How reliable is that source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any history of abusive liquidation (stemming from oracle issues)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iic-liquidation-mechanisms&#34;&gt;II.C/ Liquidation Mechanisms
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The liquidation mechanisms are critical too, but they only happen once a liquidation can be triggered - which depends on the price the oracle returns. So the &lt;strong&gt;liquidation mechanism cannot make up for a faulty oracle&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to first understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, different money markets handle liquidations differently. They have different delays, fees, and restrictions with their liquidations. For instance, the Maker oracle/liquidation (internal system) has a one-hour delay to prevent flash liquidations during unsustained flash crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, liquidation is not sudden neither an all-or-nothing event. There are several buffers to your positions, for instance on Aave, every token has a &lt;strong&gt;maximum loan to value&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;liquidation threshold&lt;/strong&gt;at least slightly higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with USDC as collateral, for instance, there is a 5% spread between the two - the max LTV is 80% (&lt;em&gt;max $8000 worth borrowed from a 10 000 USDC collateral&lt;/em&gt;), while the liquidation threshold is 85% (&lt;em&gt;= liquidation if collateral value &amp;lt; $8500&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/aave-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave USDC collateral parameters&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gives borrowers using USDC as collateral another 5% margin so that even if the oracle reports $0.97 no abusive liquidations would occur. The situation is similar in other money markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-liquidation-mechanisms&#34;&gt;Assessing liquidation mechanisms
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Mostly depends on the collateral price action - a flash crash could trigger a chain of liquidations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Significant (the money market can be potentially undercollateralized)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, on Maker where there were issues and delays with liquidations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some questions to ask yourself to assess the liquidation mechanisms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When liquidations are triggered; what is the flow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any additional delay?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the liquidation fees?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another massive subtopic here: the &lt;strong&gt;liquidations do not happen magically&lt;/strong&gt; - they are triggered by other users. So the incentives need to be on point there too so that liquidations do happen when needed and promptly. This topic is even more complex now in an age of high gas costs (liquidation profits vs gas costs of the tx). Skipping it for digestibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iid-collateral-listing--risk-analysis&#34;&gt;II.D/ Collateral Listing &amp;amp; Risk Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alright, now that we have a money market getting reliable prices and liquidating when needed, we can start looking at the tokens accepted as collateral and what is the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessing a token&amp;rsquo;s health and overall safety is &lt;strong&gt;one of the most complex tasks nowadays in DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; because figuring out the whole ecosystem around a token can be tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the SNX token, for instance, a major ERC-20 token. It&amp;rsquo;s usable as collateral on Aave, but with quite a low maximum loan to value ratio (to be raised soon?) at 15%. Other ERC-20 tokens like LINK are in the 60-75% range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without diving too much into the details, this has to do with what you can do with each token and &lt;strong&gt;SNX usage as collateral on the Synthetix platform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s risk parameters are conservative enough to essentially &amp;ldquo;front-run&amp;rdquo; Synthetix itself in the chain of liquidations if a black swan event was to happen &lt;/span&gt;on Synthetix. It seems wise: a money market should not want to take higher exposition on a given token than the native platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at it is the other way around: assess the overall &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo; of the latest tokens added as collateral on the platform: are they liquid? Credibly decentralized? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also look at the overall collateral usage for any suspicious mismatch, like on Cream where almost a third of the deposits are FTT tokens (FTX exchange).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/cream.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cream&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-collateral-listing-strategy&#34;&gt;Assessing the collateral listing strategy
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Depends on the collateral listing strategy risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: If a dangerous token is accepted as collateral, the money market can potentially ends-up undercollateralized or even drained. For instance, Cream accepts COVER as collateral. The token suffered three infinite mint attacks already, exposing Cream to further risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; some tokens got minted to infinity, like COVER&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But they were used as collateral on a money market yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t expand more on this topic since Aave&amp;rsquo;s risk documentation is very well done - check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.aave.com/risk/asset-risk/risk-parameters&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the risk parameters section&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are the collateral listing decisions made?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What risk framework is used for collateral?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the money market adapting to the changing circumstances of the tokens it lists?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iie-safety-module&#34;&gt;II.E/ Safety Module
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if the risk is known at every level, &lt;strong&gt;insurance is never an option and never supernumerary&lt;/strong&gt;. The first layer of defense is of course the platform-level if there is any compensation module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that there is! Aave pioneered the field &amp;amp; even Compound has a reserve now. The second good news is that assessing the usefulness of this module is dead simple: it&amp;rsquo;s a simple ratio between the total $ value of the borrows made on the money market and the total $ that can be mobilized by the safety module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aave has roughly 2B in the Safety Module, of which up to 30% can be seized if needed = 600M. It covers both the V1 &amp;amp; V2 of the protocol. If the 30% on the slashing of the Safety Module is not sufficient, the safety module can mint additional AAVE tokens. Such a scenario is accounted for by neither Compound nor Cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/aave-safety-module.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave&amp;rsquo;s Safety Module&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of insurance, money markets can also have reserves. Compound is the pioneer here, with about $10M in reseve&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Aave also has a reserve system that was recently launched, but I excluded it from the analysis considering the limited balance.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking at the available numbers, here are our quick maths:
&lt;code&gt;Safety Ratio = USD value of insurance / Total borrow on the money market&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🛡 Aave =  53%&lt;/strong&gt; | $1.765 B (600M can be mobilized) in the Safety Module for $1.1B borrowed accross V1+V2 ($572M V1, $437M V2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🕯 Compound = 0.24%&lt;/strong&gt; | $4.3B borrowed on a $10M safety capital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💀 Cream = 0%&lt;/strong&gt; | As far as I know, Cream has no or highly limited (low amounts) native insurance module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ Note: While Compound currently has no safety module, the team/DAO is currently sitting on a large COMP reserve that could be used to that end&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The maths were done on Feb 17 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;evaluating-the-native-insurance-module&#34;&gt;Evaluating the native insurance module
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-null, but not as relevant here. The SM is here to provide compensations in case of failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Depositors know they can get slashed if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Aave&amp;rsquo;s pioneering the field. The slashing launched weeks ago. So far no events required Aave to harness the safety module, but it&amp;rsquo;s great to know it&amp;rsquo;s here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a sense of how protecting the native safety and insurance modules are, here are some decent questions to ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any native insurance module covering the platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the withdrawal delays &amp;amp; safeguards?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the coverage ratio (USD TVL exposed / USD TVL of Safety Module)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iif-expanded-insurance-ecosystem&#34;&gt;II.F/ Expanded Insurance Ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of the native insurance system of the money market, depositors and borrowers can &lt;strong&gt;cover their positions through a third party insurance service&lt;/strong&gt; like Nexus Mutual or Unslashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;most widely covered risk is the one of a technical failure of smart contracts&lt;/span&gt;. You will find covers for pretty much any widely used contract there is. Yet, &lt;strong&gt;smart contract failures are not the only event that can lead to a loss of funds on a money market&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Robert Leshner the CEO of Compound can factually state the following&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; while the protocol recently suffered 90M of abusive liquidations because of faulty oracles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compound has been operating for close to 2 years with ZERO smart contract bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It creates a false sense of security many are falling for, just like the period of operation of the protocol. Notice how I left it out of these 8 criteria? It&amp;rsquo;s because it has close to zero relevance despite services like DeFiScore giving it an absurdly important weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m careful when I talk about &amp;ldquo;90M of abusive liquidations because of faulty oracles&amp;rdquo; but to be explicit - it affected negatively potentially any DAI borrower back then that might have gotten liquidated wrongly - losing a part of their deposit with &lt;strong&gt;no recourse and no compensation&lt;/strong&gt; since Compound operated as intended (smart-contract wise).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of risks of smart contract failures, please consider the following list of non-exhaustive other risks that can result in a loss of fund:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure or manipulation of an oracle,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An issue with the smart contract of a token used collateral (such as infinite mint),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A stablecoin used as collateral or borrowing asset on the market lose its peg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The device or wallet of the admin of a not-so-decentralized service is compromised&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issues or delays with liquidations, meaning the money market can potentially no longer meet its collateralization requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most insurance services are unhelpful with all these risks but for the risks of smart contract failures. The market for other types of risk is barely getting started thanks to Unslashed Finance now providing &lt;strong&gt;coverage for the risk of stablecoins losing their peg&lt;/strong&gt; or custodian risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/defiprime-insurance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Defiprime insurance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the different approaches for DeFi insurance, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiprime.com/comparing-insurance-like-solutions-in-defi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this piece from DeFi Rate&lt;/a&gt;. However please keep in mind the &lt;strong&gt;massive bias here&lt;/strong&gt;: it was written more than two years ago by Hugh Karp, founder of Nexus Mutual. However, it&amp;rsquo;s still factual enough and insightful to understand the different models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;understanding-insurances-and-the-risk-they-truly-cover&#34;&gt;Understanding insurances and the risk they truly cover
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🎯Object&lt;/strong&gt;: Smart Contract Failure + stablecoin loss of peg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💰Utility&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides compensation if a failure is observed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt;: Nexus Mutual, one of the oldest insurance options already paid out on several situations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the topic of extended insurances, you will want to look at services such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unslashed.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Unslashed Finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nexusmutual.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nexus Mutual&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.coverprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cover Protocol&lt;/a&gt; and the plans they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the options available through the ecosystem to cover a position on the money market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their pricing and reliability (paid out already?)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iig-native-token-risk-management&#34;&gt;II.G/ Native Token Risk Management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discussed quite a bit about the various tokens used as collateral, but there is one you need to watch extra carefully: the &lt;strong&gt;native token of the money market&lt;/strong&gt;. So that&amp;rsquo;s the COMP token on Compound, AAVE on Aave, and CREAM on Cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The maximum Loan to Value (max LTV) dictates the borrowing power of collaterals. A 50% max LTV means one can borrow up to half to the dollar value of the collateral deposited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first layer is of course to make sure that there is no fool play: &lt;strong&gt;the money market must be neutral and not favor its own token&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems obvious, but it&amp;rsquo;s not a given. Cream allows an excessive 75% max LTV on CREAM, one of the highest of the whole protocol - as high as some stablecoins. Compound itself gives COMP a permissive 60% max LTV while Aave is more conservative at 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the money market is healthy and the token well designed - people should be bullish on it, meaning some of them use it as collateral to long it - aka depositing AAVE on Aave to long AAVE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, despite the permissive LTV, COMP&amp;rsquo;s and CREAM&amp;rsquo;s longs are rarer than AAVE&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-how-a-money-market-manage-its-native-token-risks&#34;&gt;Assessing how a money market manage its native token risks
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s an all or nothing event: the money market can play with fire on its native token for months with no consequences before the situation eventually blow up and the token + the money market crumble together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: The loss can potentially be system-wide (whole money market affected).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Not yet. But Cream is already way beyond any reasonable max LTV figure on the CREAM token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are some considerations worth exploring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the health of the native token of the platform: token contract, liquidity, integrations, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the native token usage on the protocol &amp;amp; assess the health of its market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ownership, distribution, and Gini coefficient of the governance token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve focused on the money market themselves. Yet, they are community-driven &amp;amp; governed projects, so their community &amp;amp; integration within the ecosystem are an essential part of the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iih-community--ecosystem&#34;&gt;II.H/ Community &amp;amp; Ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, communities are essential. It&amp;rsquo;s not a &amp;ldquo;nice-to-have&amp;rdquo; to make the protocol more attractive, it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;core feature&lt;/strong&gt; and I assess it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On such a topic, again, no metrics will help you just by themselves. The gist is to get a sense of how dynamic the community is. It usually translates into its core components: the DAO, the Discord, and the overall presence in the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of a healthy community is &lt;strong&gt;widespread support and usage across the ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, with many services and products built &amp;ldquo;on top of&amp;rdquo; the protocol examined. Here despite Compound&amp;rsquo;s lead being the first mover, Aave is also now a prime choice for any new protocol building a new financial primitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, teams can purposely foster such an environment simply by having members accessible and involved in the space. Besides, Aave has an &lt;strong&gt;ecosystem grants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:15&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; initiative helping to fund projects built on top of Aave such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/firp-apwine.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine offering fixed yields&lt;/a&gt;. Other community-related initiatives are a healthy tell, such as hackathons, AMAs, livestreams, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again here - make sure to &lt;strong&gt;assess the quality, not the quantity&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to rush out all the initiatives listed above. But doing it right, in a way that makes sense for the community and pushes it forward is much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make this a case against Compound, but here again, it&amp;rsquo;s so obvious. While Compound community fundings are quite limited the grants program just launched&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:16&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, its founder Robert Leshner is an active venture capital investor, with the Robot Ventures funds&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:17&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/robovc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Robovc&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-community--dao-of-a-money-market&#34;&gt;Assessing the community &amp;amp; DAO of a money market
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: The community is the most important feature of all for the long-term success of the money market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Long-term risk. If a money market loses the community favors, it&amp;rsquo;s not gonna be a dramatic event but more of slow and painful threading into irrelevance for the given market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, with Compound - they lost their top of mind position and preference for several reasons, such as their lack of support for the ecosystem, the DAI Market Oracle issue &amp;amp; the team reaction to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some questions and clues to help you assess this last yet essential part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the DAO-level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it work to submit a proposal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are they reviewed and improved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the delay between the vote and the execution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any proposal that was ignored or not implemented for a long time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core team members:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they legit? Involved in the space? Giving back? Advising?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background-check: any involvement with a scam? What were they doing before?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present-check: on top of their involvement with the money market, what are they doing? Any potential conflict of interest?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation &amp;amp; support: how hard is it to build on top of this money market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the services built on top of the money market? Are they widely used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they communicating clearly on risk parameters? Do they have non-technical/non-dev risk-focused documentation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-a-note-on-defi-tribalism&#34;&gt;III/ A note on DeFi Tribalism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring such a topic was insanely insightful for me, at so many levels. I remain quite surprised by the tribalism of the space: apart from Aave, gathering the information presented in this article was not a trivial task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the question I asked and the observations I shared, I&amp;rsquo;ve been the target of personal attacks from founders of some of the teams mentioned in this article. Others were quite misleading and selective in their answers. I received no answers from both Cream &amp;amp; Compound official accounts or teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such attitudes gave me even more will to push this article forward. &lt;strong&gt;Beyond the technicalities of each protocol, I think the attitude of the founding team is essential too&lt;/strong&gt;. On this front, there is a protocol that stands an order of magnitude above any other: surprise surprise, it also happens to be the most technically sound, secure, integrated, and exciting, and interesting. 👻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iiia-limitations-of-this-risk-assessment-approach&#34;&gt;III.A/ Limitations of this risk assessment approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I anticipate strong reactions already, so let me add a few more topics not addressed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While we went quite deep, we did not discuss the tokenization process: the process used by the protocol to represent the assets deposited. On this front, &lt;strong&gt;both Compound and Cream are using an archaic approach&lt;/strong&gt; that was topped on all fronts by Aave with the first release of the aTokens in early 2020.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:18&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Aave V2 further improved the tokenization process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cream by itself is a small market, but &lt;strong&gt;through the Iron Bank other protocols can borrow from Cream&lt;/strong&gt;. Assessing the risk on such a market is even harder - and it was excluded from this analysis. To learn more about the real risk already posed and manifested by such an approach, you can check the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rekt.news/alpha-finance-rekt/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;latest Rekt on Alpha Homora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While MakerDAO provides a service functionally equivalent to lending, the process is significantly different since each borrower is minting DAI. So for the sake of simplicity, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly excluded MakerDAO from this analysis, but for a few meaningful examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no affiliation whatsoever with the Aave, Compound, Cream, or any other money market. However, I do own AAVE tokens (that I purchased myself on the markets) and stake them in the Safety Module. All the content hosted on my blog is made accessible for free - I am the sole editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you get a better grasp of the scope of risks in money markets. I want to stress again that it&amp;rsquo;s non-exhaustive, nor absolute truth but I do firmly believe provides clear and useful contributions to make sure risks in DeFi are broadly understood, better than what currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not agree with this statement, feel free to challenge me. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m eager for facts disproving my observations: it would mean DeFi is safer than I thought.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder: this blog is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/hello-world.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;one of the few websites of the space not pillaging your data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; through the usage of Google Analytics and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-notes--references&#34;&gt;IV. Notes &amp;amp; References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find additional information on each fact, event or figure mentioned in the article through the footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the get go, the formula used was abitrary, suffered dozens of obvious flaws and was rigged in favor of Compound through the ridiculous importance given to the time of operations. In my humble opinion, the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiScore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s main goal was Consensys&amp;rsquo; promotion. If at least, they had done the work&amp;hellip;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pinged them on Twitter and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1360296967939772423?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;suggested many obvious improvements&lt;/a&gt; anyone with some DeFi experience could have provided.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack, one of their engineer recognized that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jack_clancy93/status/1360304560846364672?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the case of Compound DAI score &amp;gt; Aave is not defensible.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to him if you want to claim the 500 USDC bounty! &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jack_clancy93/status/1360305374033682436?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here is the tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this attack or any other in the DeFi space, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rekt.news/nxm-hugh-speaks-out/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check the Rekt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/49657/oracle-exploit-sees-100-million-liquidated-on-compound&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info about the 89M DAI oracle abitrage on Compound here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the attack occuring several weeks ago because of their reliance on Coinbase centralized oracles, it seems like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChainLinkGod/status/1362132404484198401?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the situation has not been fixed yet&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MakerDAO team published a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.makerdao.com/the-market-collapse-of-march-12-2020-how-it-impacted-makerdao/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;write-up&lt;/a&gt; after the events explaining what happened.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cover is an insurance protocol unable to secure their own token contract and liquidity mining program. They got attaked three times already. Here are &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coingape.com/cover-becomes-latest-defi-protocol-to-get-exploited-price-crashes-by-77-within-an-hour/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;some info on the last one&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each cToken stores reserves (insurance), there&amp;rsquo;s $9.4m (and growing by over $100k/day) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358566161361821696&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are around $450K worth of tokens collected in the reserve as of now: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.aave.com/risk/asset-risk/risk-parameters#reserve-factor&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s reserve factor documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compound is also sitting on a 4 million COMP (roughly $1.8b) chest that could be allocated for insurance &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358569634618867714?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes he&amp;rsquo;s factual since the contract never failed so far. However for less technically-savy people, it can read like Compound never suffered any loss, which is not the case. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358566161361821696?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.nexusmutual.io/claim-assessment&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;claims and payouts on Nexus Mutual here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:15&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first round of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/aave/aave-ecosystem-grants-88260ede1485&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave Ecosystem grants started about a year ago&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:16&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal for Compound Ecopsystem Grants was &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/governance/proposals/30&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;executed two months ago&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:17&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://robvc.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RoboVC&lt;/a&gt;: It funded several services harnessing Compound (like InstaDapp or Multis) &amp;amp; Compound itself.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:18&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case for aTokens&amp;rsquo; technical superiority could be the topic on an article by itself but here is the gist of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simpler&lt;/strong&gt;: aTokens maintain a 1:1 ratio against the base asset while cTokens have an increasing exchange rate against their base assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier accounting &amp;amp; integrations&lt;/strong&gt;: aTokens 1:1 correspondence makes them much easier to interact with - there is no need to fetch any additional data. With Compound, any service interacting with cTokens needs to fetch the corresponding the cToken/BaseToken exchange rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic and understandable interest&lt;/strong&gt;: both a &amp;amp; c tokens accrue interest dynamically. However, here again, because of aTokens&amp;rsquo; more elegant and straightforward design, the experience is more fluid with aTokens (deposit, reassured by 1:1 correspondence, number go up)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More potent integrations&lt;/strong&gt;: aToken allows for novel use cases, especially if you take into account the other features of Aave. For instance, there is a Yearn vault harnessing aLINK to borrow USDC from users&amp;rsquo; deposits to farm with them and settle the income for more aLINK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🍷 Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/fixed-interest-rate-protocol-firp-apwine/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/fixed-interest-rate-protocol-firp-apwine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/pac-man.png" alt="Featured image of post 🍷 Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process. As DeFi is developing faster than ever, with now more than $ 50 billion of total value locked across all protocols, &lt;strong&gt;the yield offering is diversifying&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our topic today strikes at the heart of this trend, with a solution offering a potentially instant payout for deposits on DeFi protocols like Yearn or Aave: APWine. Before we get to this point however, we need to place back some context on money markets and FIRPs in general since they are still novel types of products for most DeFi users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;money-market--pacman&#34;&gt;Money Market = PacMan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/pac-man.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;the interest bearing stablecoin pacman-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tranching, insurance, and FIRPs are essentially like &lt;strong&gt;abstraction-layers built on top of a money market&lt;/strong&gt; to provide additional features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔪 Tranching&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ better separation of the different type of risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🛡 Insurance&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ coverage against technical failures (&amp;amp; more!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 FIRPs&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ &amp;ldquo;coverage&amp;rdquo; against variations of APY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they are interesting as a features by themselves, what fascinates me is what happens &lt;strong&gt;when/if they are integrated at the base level&lt;/strong&gt;. It would enable other protocols to harness these features. For instance, Harvest could offer a &amp;ldquo;de-risked&amp;rdquo; USDC vault &amp;amp; essentially bringing the whole DeFi to another level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, DeFi&amp;rsquo;s different value set is not only a benefit for transparency and audibility: it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;also at least &lt;ins&gt;an order of magnitude&lt;/ins&gt; more efficient&lt;/strong&gt; than the dying patchwork of finance it&amp;rsquo;s bound to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-interest-rate-protocols-firps&#34;&gt;Fixed Interest Rate Protocols (FIRPs)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s define what Fixed Interest Rate Protocols are and what are their role within the broader ecosystem of decentralized finance on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With DeFi, the goal for most is &lt;strong&gt;to produce yields from a given asset.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually one of the easiest ways to achieve this will be to lend it for instance, for a return. Doing so means assuming several layers of risk you can insure yourself against (-&amp;gt; Unslashed) or simply avoid taking with tranching (-&amp;gt; Saffron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re super responsible and try to insure &amp;amp; further protect your deposits, you are left with one sizable issue: &lt;strong&gt;the base return produced by the asset is usually volatile&lt;/strong&gt;, making the pricing of the whole package (lended deposit + insurance + tranching) hard to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/coingecko-report.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coingecko-crypto-2020-report&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://assets.coingecko.com/reports/2020-Year-End-Report/CoinGecko-2020-Report.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;full report here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely where FIRPs get a chance to shine: &lt;strong&gt;since they make the interest predictable, FIRPs help promote a more responsible attitude&lt;/strong&gt; for the whole space - by making it easier to use all the meta-structure now available to protect deposits on money markets or DeFi asset managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article addresses fixed interest rate protocols only. For a broader perspective on risk management for DeFi deposits, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/risk-tranching.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read my introduction piece touching on insurance, tranching and FIRPs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In there, we addressed how insurance, tranching, and fixed interest might eventually be integrated natively into money-markets, enabling to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/risk-tranching.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;envision &amp;ldquo;risk-free&amp;rdquo; interest bearing stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, this article assume a minimal understanding of the topic. If something is still unclear, please refer to the previous article ☝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apwine-fixed-yield-sauternes-&#34;&gt;APWine: Fixed-yield Sauternes 🍷
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So with the hell of an intro and without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into today&amp;rsquo;s matter: &lt;strong&gt;understanding what FIRPs are and what they bring to the table through the lense of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🍷 Even better, it&amp;rsquo;s wine-themed and Frenchies are involved - what&amp;rsquo;s not to love already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-difference-between-apwine-and-88mph&#34;&gt;The difference between APWine and 88MPH
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a high-level perspective, both projects could be described as FIRPs, yet they achieve this result through different means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With 88MPH, the yield of your deposits are fixed thanks to a secondary prediction market built for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With APWine, you can lock your assets for a month for instance to instantly earn the yield.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to be more explicit, both are not interchangeable nor operating on the same time frame: with 88MPH, the income becomes &lt;strong&gt;predictable but it&amp;rsquo;s still an iterative process&lt;/strong&gt;. With APWine, the income becomes &lt;strong&gt;predictable &amp;amp; instantly delivered&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means different tradeoffs on the risk management side. With 88MPH, the yield is calculated algorithmically - there&amp;rsquo;s always a buyer, which is neat for convenience, but also means the protocol can accrue debt if there is a mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposite is true for APWine: since it&amp;rsquo;s market-based, no mismatch can occur (-&amp;gt; no protocol debt), but it means there can be demand/offer issues (such as heavy discount on FYTs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/apwine.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;apwine-deposit-process&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apwine-instant-payday&#34;&gt;APWine: Instant Payday?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With APWine, the logic is quite straightforward. It all starts by depositing a token earning some yield, such as a stablecoin deposited on Aave or a Yearn vault token onto the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of each period, users receive FYT (Future Yield Tokens) representing their yields for the period. &lt;strong&gt;The FYT are standard ERC-20 tokens&lt;/strong&gt; that will be tradable shortly after launch on APWine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deposit is locked for the period, however users can withdraw early with a fee, by burning their FYT tokens. The slashing is deactivated for the beta period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the yield is instantly available and usable, APWine should provide ample opportunities for both hedging and arbitraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After several weeks of testnet, APWine is coming to mainet! The beta will start in a couple of weeks with a first period starting on March 1st for 30 days. The APW token and liquidity mining should could shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.medium.com/our-beta-is-live-on-the-ethereum-mainnet-3860491a365c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More information on APWine beta &amp;amp; launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next-for-apwine&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next for APWine?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the short term, I&amp;rsquo;ll be following closely the upcoming launch of the platform next week. Several upcoming releases have already been announced such as the arrival of more services and pools on the platform and the release of the APW token and its associated liquidity mining plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like always though, what gets me really excited is the endgame!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-endgame-a-yield-hedging-protocol&#34;&gt;The Endgame: a yield hedging protocol
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we envision the end-game here, first we need to see if the idea works and &lt;strong&gt;if there is a real fit.&lt;/strong&gt; In the APWine case, &lt;strong&gt;success will be measured by looking at the health of the markets for FYT tokens&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to settle at parity with expected yields, but if users can really get an &lt;strong&gt;instant payday even with a 20% fee&lt;/strong&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving this means having really liquid FYT markets, which is perfectly doable especially if there is a liquidity mining plan in APW token to bootstrap them. Regarding the APW token itself, diving in the FAQ will give you a bit more insight into what the team envisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each future expiration, 10% of the generated yield is shared between all APW token holders (percentage subject to change in the future based on the market demand). The token will also enable them to participate in the governance mechanisms of APWine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/faq&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ApWine FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on top of the usual governance right of the protocol, it seems like there is already a revenue stream considered for the APW token, on top of any potential liquidity mining plan involving an APW-based pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French being the language of DeFi, it was about time we got some fine wine-makers involved in the yield brewing process! If you are interested in the protocol, you can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.medium.com/our-beta-is-live-on-the-ethereum-mainnet-3860491a365c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read more about the beta here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be following closely as I&amp;rsquo;m having &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zo0B64swtPI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a chat with Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the persons involved with APWine next week (in French).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Volume begets fees: how are the main decentralized exchanges capturing value?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/decentralized-exchange-value-capture/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/decentralized-exchange-value-capture/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Volume begets fees: how are the main decentralized exchanges capturing value?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve shared my perspective on many DeFi protocols on this blog, but recently I realized I&amp;rsquo;ve never gone back to the basics: the DEXs. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what we will do today, tackling the topic mostly by looking at value capture mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMM-based DEXs like Uniswap, Curve or SushiSwap all grew tremendously both in available liquidity and volume this year, and so did the fees they collected. To put it simply: &lt;strong&gt;these DEXs now are the main fee-collectors there are in crypto, right after the Bitcoin and Ethereum network themselves&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/fees.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crypto-fees&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite an impressive achievement! So today we&amp;rsquo;ll look at this yummy cake and understand how it&amp;rsquo;s split. What&amp;rsquo;s the different approaches? What is their token used for / how do they establish their incentive model? And then how will the arrival of layer 2 impact all of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-automated-market-maker-amms&#34;&gt;The rise of Automated Market Maker (AMMs)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the discussions around automated market makers (AMMs) lately, I wanted, as usual, to take a step back and consider the current state of the market, the position of the main players and what&amp;rsquo;s coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss AMMs but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the technical details of the bonding curves to others. Instead, we will address the topic from a value capture and tokenomics perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rise and development of AMMs fundamentally changed the market&lt;/strong&gt;. Before their dominion, order-book based approaches were still widely used. One of the main merits of AMMs is to change the logic of the service, as it becomes &lt;strong&gt;peer to contract&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need for a matching order on the other side, thanks to the bonding curve, there&amp;rsquo;s always one (within pool liquidity &amp;amp; slippage limits).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the key factors that enabled them to grow as they streamlined everything related to token exchanges: from the act of swapping itself, but also liquidity providing and even things like fetching a price for assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have our beautiful DEX-commissions-cake, now let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the main services&amp;rsquo; value capture mechanism to better understand their main differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the sake of the simplicity of this article, we won&amp;rsquo;t address Balancer and Bancor models. It might be a good follow-up piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;value-capture-mechanisms-in-discovery-mode&#34;&gt;Value capture mechanisms in discovery mode
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the different iterations and releases of the main DEXs, their value capture mechanisms evolved. Initially, there was not necessarily a token and a share of the exchange collected fee captured by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uniswap-the-need-for-liquidity&#34;&gt;Uniswap: The need for liquidity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in the first days of the AMM, the main concern was liquidity - still very scarce back then: Uniswap had no token and no need for it to pioneer the AMM-front. The initial and still current fee distribution infrastructure matches this requirement: a &lt;strong&gt;30 bps fee (0.3%) is taken on every trade and distributed to the liquidity providers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a perfect fit to start as you have a liquidity chicken and egg problem to begin with: sufficient liquidity will enable swaps without too much slippage, driving volume (if there&amp;rsquo;s need for the given token/market) and therefore revenues for LP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is currently no fee or value capture at the token-level but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;ready to be implemented&lt;/strong&gt; if the DAO was to decide it - the V2 of the protocol shipped last year includes a &lt;code&gt;Protocol fee&lt;/code&gt; feature.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sushiswap-value-capture-to-the-token&#34;&gt;SushiSwap: Value capture to the token
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the early days, one of the core changes of SushiSwap was a slight reduction of this fee to 25 bps to &lt;strong&gt;redirect the 5 bps left to SUSHI stakers.&lt;/strong&gt; This enables SUSHI stakers to get a share of the fees collected on all pairs, instead of liquidity-pair based distribution only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the initial distribution phase, there were several adjustments made but the mechanism is roughly the same. Onsen introduced a rotational reward system onboard relevant new pools. More importantly for the tokenomics, ⅔ of the SUSHI rewards earned through liquidity mining are now vested over a 6 months period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/sushi-onsen.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sushiswap-onsen&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vesting reduces the incentives for &amp;ldquo;mercenary liquidity&amp;rdquo;, especially for liquidity managed by a vault for instance &amp;amp; helps to &lt;strong&gt;make sure that large liquidity providers are also SUSHI holders at all time&lt;/strong&gt; (even up to 6 months after they&amp;rsquo;re done farming), better aligning interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this split, SushiSwap distributes a 0.25% fee for each swap to LP, just like Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s 0.30%. On top of this fee, another 0.05% fee is collected on each swap in form of LP tokens, and settled for SUSHI distributed to the stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improvements brought by Sushi are relevant, yet in my eyes the real game-changer is the Curve model, so let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-peek-at-the-endgame-curve-finance--crv&#34;&gt;A peek at the endgame? Curve Finance &amp;amp; CRV
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve&amp;rsquo;s model is slightly more complex than the previous but results in an ever better alignment of incentives between the platform users and the token holders. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of the CRV token, liquidity providers on Curve have been earning CRV tokens on top of their usual commissions (if they stake). And just like SushiSwap, Curve&amp;rsquo;s introduced a form of value capture at the CRV-token level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/curve-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the model is more intricate so let&amp;rsquo;s discuss each part and see how they interact with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-tutorial--the-timelock&#34;&gt;1/ Tutorial : The Timelock
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make use of CRV tokens within Curve, the first choice one has to make is the length of its commitment. The base unit is veCRV, a time-weighted locked CRV enabled for governance. To be explicit: &lt;strong&gt;to be eligible for the fees collected and other features discussed below, you need to lock your CRV token for at least 1 year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism is quite straightforward, you can lock for 1 to 4 years. 4 years will give you 1 veCRV per CRV, decreasing linearly to 0.25 veCRV per CRV for a one year period. As said before, veCRV is the base unit of the system - so it will determine how much fees as well as boosting and governance power you have access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-level-up-zone--your-share-of-the-fees&#34;&gt;2/ Level-up Zone : Your share of the fees
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Staking and locking CRV tokens in the DAO is enough to be eligible for a share of the fees collected on Curve, yet it&amp;rsquo;s only the first step of the journey. The commissions are collected frequently and settled for 3pool LP tokens. The mechanism recently kicked off and started distributing rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the effective return fluctuates as it&amp;rsquo;s tied to Curve&amp;rsquo;s exchange volume and the CRV token acquisition price. At the time of writing, it&amp;rsquo;s around &lt;strong&gt;$0.29 yearly for 1 vecRV.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To describe the next layer of the Curve&amp;rsquo;s onion, I love to use a metaphor inspired from online role-playing games. Indeed, there are three types of realms fitting to describe the next three steps for Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvE (Player vs Environment)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you face only AI-controlled monsters (mobs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvP (vs Players)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you fight against other players in a set environment (arena/battlefield)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RvR (Realm vs Realm)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you fight against other players potentially everywhere (faction-based)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll use this frame of reference to analyze the next three layers of the Curve&amp;rsquo;s onion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-curves-pve---boosting-crv-rewards&#34;&gt;3/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvE - Boosting CRV rewards
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, liquidity providers can stake their LP tokens to earn CRV on top of their usual commissions. But they can also &lt;strong&gt;use their veCRV tokens to boost&lt;/strong&gt; one or several of their pools, increasing the CRV earned up to 2.5 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, one needs an amount of veCRV proportionate to the $value of the liquidity providing position boosted. The effective cost (in veCRV) to have the maximum boost is not the same for each pool - creating a first layer of incentives/arbitrages games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/crv-boost.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve CRV boosting&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting mechanism enabling a better alignment of incentive: &lt;strong&gt;large and efficient CRV earners are also significant veCRV holders&lt;/strong&gt; (-&amp;gt; locked for 1-4 years) so they have a fair amount of skin in the game. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s just the first &amp;amp; friendliest layer of Curve&amp;rsquo;s meta game. Let&amp;rsquo;s go deeper into the onion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-curves-pvp---the-gauge-weights-game&#34;&gt;4/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvP - The Gauge Weight&amp;rsquo;s Game
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If pool-boosting is PvE, the gauge-weights are Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvP arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gauge-weights are a bit similar to boosting, but &lt;strong&gt;at the platform-level&lt;/strong&gt;. veCRV holders can vote to &lt;strong&gt;decide the share of newly minted CRV allocated to each pool&lt;/strong&gt;. Additional restrictions apply here to prevent the manipulation of the votes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The VeCRV needs to be locked with at least 7 days left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gauge weight voting can only be changed by users every 10 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It enables the incentivization of new pools, theoretically without impulse needed from the Curve team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-curves-rvr---governance--inter-protocol-gov&#34;&gt;5/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s RvR - Governance &amp;amp; inter-protocol gov
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last layer of the onion lies with Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance: veCRV holders can vote on the DAO proposal and with at least 2 500 veCRV, you can submit a proposal to the DAO. So, to recap, once you hold veCRV, you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earn a share of the fees collected by the exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can boost your own CRV streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Through gauges, influence future CRV emission on curve pools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally with the governance, you have a say in the key parameters of the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While 1&amp;amp;2 is what is of interest to most-end users, &lt;strong&gt;items 3&amp;amp;4 can be incredibly valuable for other dApps, DeFi projects and protocol politicians&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, the possibilities are virtually endless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For instance, imagine a project introducing a new stablecoin. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be neat for them to have governance power within Curve to eventually include it in a boosted Curve pool?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even deeper into the onion, already &lt;strong&gt;successful DeFi projects with treasury can allocate a part of it to the CRV token to harness the benefits from all 4 items&lt;/strong&gt; - 1&amp;amp;2 to boost their treasury income streams and 3&amp;amp;4 to make their platform or service more attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another layer deeper: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://crv.ape.tax&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s yveCRV vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It offers better returns on CRV than staking yourself (~1.3x), but depositors renounce boosting and voting capacity in favor of Yearn - which can then use this extra boosting/voting capacity to enhance the yield of its vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final level of depth: imagine a crypto/DeFi PR-like service a couple years from now. I expect them to be able to &lt;strong&gt;supply other projects with proposition power&lt;/strong&gt; on the main DAOs like Curve or Aave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-next-steps-for-curve&#34;&gt;6/ Next Steps for Curve
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have to consider one last dimension on Curve, as it&amp;rsquo;s not just any DEX. Indeed, from the get-go Curve specialized into the &lt;strong&gt;swaps of pegged-assets&lt;/strong&gt; and optimized for it. It started with stablecoins only, but we now also have BTC and ETH representations too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the growing available liquidity, the team is now harnessing DeFi synergies (with Synthetix) to offer swaps between the different pegged assets listed on Curve, such as DAI -&amp;gt; wBTC or USDT -&amp;gt; EURS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides incredible value as it covers markets that are currently not broadly available elsewhere (EURS) and enables a minimization of slippage for large trades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay concise, Uniswap and Sushiswap&amp;rsquo;s bonding curves are well suited to &lt;strong&gt;support many small or average swaps, especially on large pools&lt;/strong&gt; with a low slippage. However, they are less optimal for large orders as slippage increases in proportion to the share of liquidity of the pool required by the trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A service like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps you streamline this process &amp;amp; optimize your swap further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-outlook-l2--its-incentives&#34;&gt;Future outlook: L2 &amp;amp; its incentives
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To wrap up this article, let&amp;rsquo;s not forget about the upcoming tectonic shift for the Ethereum space: the increasing availability of layer 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, we saw the value transacted on AMM explode to the detriment of order-book based approaches. They streamlined the whole experience and made tons of sense for layer 1 so we can reasonably expect them to pave the way for L2 decentralized trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loopring is already delivering live in production an AMM on L2:&lt;/strong&gt; a zk-Sync based L2 DEX with various incentives for liquidity providers. Curve has been working with Zk-Sync too, so we can reasonnably expect them to ship a live L2 product this year considering the latest developments with Zk-Sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/loopring.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Loopring V2 Stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Synthetix recently rolled their Optimism L2 mainnet and the force seems strong around a Uniswap x Optimism rollout. Jokingly the other day I was saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthetix Optimism L2 is Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s testnet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising to see Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s L2 implementation rolling out within weeks or months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re at it, what about tokoenomics x L2? I expect to see &lt;strong&gt;LP incentives too migrating to L2&lt;/strong&gt;, as it&amp;rsquo;s already the case with Loopring. Synthetic too quickstarted its current limited L2 (minting/burning only) with SNX incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services that do not already have a token might have an edge here as they can incentive the L2 directly. On the other hand, the protocols that heavily incentivized their L1 already might lack firepower to match the incentives offered by projects with &amp;ldquo;L2-native&amp;rdquo; tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be fascinating to watch the releases of the different layer 2 and how they impact the protocols usage and tokenomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/defi-france-live-16.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-france-live-16&#34;
	
	
&gt;
🇫🇷 If you understand spoken French:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to meet 0xMaki to discuss the topic &lt;strong&gt;in French&lt;/strong&gt; this Monday on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JT8N7-gqTjA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi France&amp;rsquo;s YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes--references&#34;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more info in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/docs/v2/advanced-topics/fees/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2 Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A concept &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;[https://newsletter.banklesshq.com/p/the-life-of-a-protocol-politician&#34; &gt;first theorized in the Bankless newsletter&lt;/a&gt;referring to a person or entity specializing in gaining influence over diverse decentralized protocols &amp;amp; then offering on-the-tap access to this influence as a service.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
