<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>RealT on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/realt/</link>
        <description>Recent content in RealT on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/realt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How DeFi can pay for your lunches</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;This tactic was first published in the Bankless newsletter and written with advice and support from Ryan.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link to the original publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Crypto Natives,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that guy &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurashin/2016/01/07/this-man-has-been-living-on-bitcoin-for-3-years/#3c9a747a2697&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;who tried to live on Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; in 2013?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living bankless was harder back then. No one accepted it. Lots of friction. But people kept saying that one day every Starbucks would accept Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it didn’t stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because the guy in that story is now &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fortune.com/2019/12/11/crypto-crown-prince-olaf-carlson-wee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a mega-millionaire&lt;/a&gt; much the result of…not spending his Bitcoin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that teach us? It teaches to not to spend our BTC &amp;amp; ETH! Who wants to end up like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/news/bitcoin-pizza-day-celebrating-20-million-pizza-order/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bitcoin pizza guy&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s time to check in again. New tools like stablecoins and DeFi protocols are now make going bankless easier…and even…better than a bank?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice&lt;/a&gt; to share his story. He’s uses an Ethereum address, a few protocols, and a wallet + visa card combo to get passive DeFi income to pay for his lunches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/paying.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;paying-lunch-with-DAI-from-DeFi&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Above—&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1225773317598187527?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;watch Brice pay for French cheese&lt;/a&gt; the bankless way)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he plans to do a whole lot more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re closer than ever to the dream of a crypto money system yet hardy anyone’s talking about it. They will. The next 10 yrs is where crypto becomes useful in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the decade we go bankless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-RSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🙏Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;—earn &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;high yields&lt;/a&gt; on deposits &amp;amp; borrow at the best possible rate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tactics-tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TACTICS TUESDAY:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tactic-26-how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactic #26:&lt;/strong&gt; How DeFi can pay for your lunches
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brice tells us his system for earning daily DAI to pay for expenses like lunch. He uses an Ethereum address as his bank, DAI as his stablecoin &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-a-dai-saving-account&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;and savings account&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tokenized real-estate&lt;/a&gt; to generate passive income, and a smart-contract wallet plus &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visa card&lt;/a&gt; for spending. Learn about his 5 DAI per day portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal: &lt;em&gt;Generate a stable return in DAI to cover for living expenses.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skill: &lt;em&gt;Intermediate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effort: &lt;em&gt;An hour or two a week, sometimes less&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROI: &lt;em&gt;9-12% annual if fully passive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;⚠️&lt;strong&gt;RSA’s note on risk&lt;/strong&gt;: In this bankless frontier Brice is taking on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-assess-the-risk-of-lending&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;many risks&lt;/a&gt;—to name a few: failure of DAI, failure of protocols like aDAI, failure of smart-contract wallet, variable interest rates, failure of the entire Ethereum protocol. He could lose all or a portion of his funds in a worse case. The passive income opportunities he mentions should be adjusted for these risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest post:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice Berdah&lt;/a&gt;, Community at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; DeFiFrance Co-Organizer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My relationship with money has always been ambiguous. As a teen, I was your usual &amp;ldquo;get money it’s spent that day&amp;rdquo; kind of guy—I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thinking or strategic about it, just looking forward to enjoying what money enables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-masterplan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The masterplan&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I grew up and started earning money on my own, I began thinking more and more about money and personal finance. Shortly after my first proper job, I was already doing math on my expenses, my income, and how long I would need to work and save in order to not have to work anymore. The dream of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly, this turned into a basic plan with two arbitrary choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would aim to acquire $1.5M. I assumed this capital would earn 5% / year landing me around $75K/year of interest before taxes—enough to sustain my lifestyle if not too excessive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I’d get there by the time I&amp;rsquo;m 35 (giving 20-30 good years to do my things)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was obviously and predictably a failure&lt;/strong&gt;. Between the start of my plan at 21 years old and now (I’m 28), I was barely able to save a fraction of the required amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-did-my-plan-fail&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did my plan fail?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I was learning about decentralised finance, I took some time to reflect on the back-then current failure of my masterplan. Here are the main reasons I identified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I did not define steps to reach the end goal&lt;/strong&gt;: I wanted to jump straight from no passive income to full passive income, without planing any intermediary step to make it more realistic and achievable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had little to no discipline&lt;/strong&gt; when it came to taming my expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I overlooked the &amp;ldquo;details&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. I had little to no idea of how I was actually going to produce a stable and consistent 5% return on such capital. I just assumed it would be attainable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-decentralised-finance&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter decentralised finance&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s jump to the current situation! I followed the development of the DeFi ecosystem very closely, thanks to my job at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DeFi-France/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;different meetups&lt;/a&gt; I co-organise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I used DeFi out of curiosity: the amount I engaged was marginal—most of my net worth was still in ETH/ERC-20 tokens. Like most, I was both curious and perplexed—is this magic internet money experiment really working?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-aha-moment&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My &amp;ldquo;Aha!&amp;rdquo; moment&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started seriously using more DeFi services, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/markets&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; bZx and then later the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://oasis.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dai Saving Rate&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;. It was awesome and magical, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t what lit the spark for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic spark came from a piece a tokenised real estate I bought on Ethereum using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;. You may already know RealT—it’s a platform for tokenized real-estate. You own property tokens and receive &lt;strong&gt;daily rental payments in DAI.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this? It got my mind racing. This was how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st day of rent:&lt;/strong&gt; oh okay, this thing is real. &lt;em&gt;By this point, I started discussing RealT with other people in the scene.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of first week:&lt;/strong&gt; now I was checking my wallet balance every morning—seeing the list of rent paid was exhilarating but left me craving more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of first month:&lt;/strong&gt; at first I spent the DAI almost immediately using my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith Visa card&lt;/a&gt;. It was so tempting—the DAI sitting there in my wallet, accumulating every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After first month:&lt;/strong&gt; as the idea of daily DAI became a reality to me, I started rethinking about my masterplan: how much DAI do I need per day to live solely on that? How much capital would it represent? (&lt;em&gt;Hint: way less than $1.5M)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Above: a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1223641685898465282?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi Milkshake&lt;/a&gt; I bought with my daily DAI passive income using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visa card&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dai-per-day-as-a-framework&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAI per day as a framework&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What happened there? Why would RealT have this impact on me while Compound did not? (Huge respect for all the projects mentioned in this post, please keep going!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the answer is more straightforward than what people expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to download movies or buy them to watch them. At some point, Netflix offered us streaming and 99% of us never looked back—&lt;strong&gt;I expect the same thing to happen with money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;money-that-empowers-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money that empowers people&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, daily DAI streaming is a paradigm shift that enables most of us to instantly become much smarter and efficient in the way we relate and manage our assets. It’s empowering to the individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? The concept of DAI per day reinforces two powerful ideas: first, streaming money and second, using DAI as the base monetary reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is streaming money a paradigm shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes it easy to break down significant objectives in small chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no wait time between the first initial investment and the first payout. Payouts are available instantly—and spendable anywhere that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;accepts Visa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is DAI a paradigm shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI is a stablecoin—you don’t have to hoard it or worry about daily value lose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI is at a bridge: easy to spend in the real world but also a hop away from all other Ethereum-based assets (including passive income assets like RealT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As DeFi grows sources of DAI/day are becoming more numerous and attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the tokens used for payouts are more diverse (consider liquidity pools). Bringing everything back in DAI/day gives you exhaustive visibility over all your crypto-passive income sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;that-daily-dai-lifestyle&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That Daily Dai Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough context, let&amp;rsquo;s get practical: what can we do today with these shiny new financial levers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to my masterplan to give it a second try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, instead of going straight for full financial independence, I decided to aim for something more practical. For me, it was straightforward: I have three lunches in London every week, costing me around $30 per week on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means I need roughly &lt;strong&gt;4.3 DAI per day&lt;/strong&gt; to pay for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I could also skip lunch, but I decided to have it for free thanks to DeFi!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet but getting close: according to my revised plan, I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting free lunches by the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-a-5-dai-per-day-portfolio&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting with a 5 DAI per day portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am currently exploring different possibilities in my portfolio, so let&amp;rsquo;s consider a simple one: one that nets you 5 DAI per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you can expect if you want a simple passive DAI strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8-9% APR with DAI: for instance, locking your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-a-dai-saving-account&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DAI in the DSR&lt;/a&gt; is at 8%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9-12.5% APR with income assets: but with a higher risk, using RealT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s if you want to set it and forget about it. There are other opportunities with additional earning opportunities. For instance, if you own a RealT asset, you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to sell at a premium on Uniswap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits from their liquidity incentive program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s keep this simple and passive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll stick with the Dai Saving Rate—the safest way to produce DAI interests right now—and RealT—a more risky bet that can offer higher returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much in assets values is required for 5 Daily DAI at the below rates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
![earning-table](/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/earning-table.png)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;going-farther&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going farther&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this is a simple framework to get started it suffers from some limits. For instance, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to generate 100 DAI/day from this approach, RealT will not cut it. You&amp;rsquo;ll run into issues of liquidity (not enough estate available) or systemic risk (you&amp;rsquo;d be owning a sizeable share of ALL RealT estates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my current understanding, I intend to maintain a similar strategy up to roughly 10 DAI/day. My current portfolio also includes aDAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I blast through the 10 DAI/day, this year, that is if the plan stands, I will be diversifying more and more. I think liquidity pools &amp;amp; staking (SNX, for instance) can be a way to go. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar enough with these topics &amp;amp; haven&amp;rsquo;t started committing serious amounts of money to it—so I&amp;rsquo;m not the best one to talk about it right now: maybe in a few months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder how this looks in practice? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/tokenbrice.eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;See for yourself at tokenbrice.eth.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
![zerion-preview](/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/wallet.png)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Above: see Brice’s DAI earnings &amp;amp; spending in real-time—&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.zerion.io/0x030de46c333dfd602442a103919412a7987d0ac7/lend?utm_campaign=aw&amp;amp;utm_medium=header_button&amp;amp;utm_source=landing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;plug tokenbrice.eth into Zerion&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-on-projections&#34;&gt;** On projections…**
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allow me to loop back to my masterplan. While the DAI per day approach is fantastic it has one main downside: it makes yearly projections harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a minute now and try to guess how much daily DAI you need to produce 50k DAI per year? Did you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How close were you to 137, the actual answer? Most people tend to overestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while DAI/day is my base, I also look at two other levels to not lose track of the big picture: the DAI per month and the DAI per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;going-bankless-in-the-real-world&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going bankless in the real world&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you found value in this tactic—my goal is practical DeFi: demonstrating what you can do harnessing DeFi today. This post was written down &amp;amp; translated adaptation of my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DeFi-France/events/268374027/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;last talk at DeFi France.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late last year &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://slideslive.com/38920018/living-on-defi-how-i-survive-argentinas-50-inflation&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mariano Conti’s talk&lt;/a&gt; sent an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/straddling-two-worlds-crypto-and&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;electro-shock to the crypto world&lt;/a&gt;: he reminded us that DeFi is already used for very real situations, such as avoiding losing 50% of your net worth to inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the perfect demonstration of someone living in the real world using the opportunities offered by DeFi. My goal was to provide the European version of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mariano survived inflation using DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, on the opposite, want to live my best life, thanks to DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the magic: &lt;strong&gt;both of us are acting in our own best interest and in doing so, we are supporting the development of a fairer &amp;amp; more accessible financial system for all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a clear illustration of how fast the industry is evolving: hop on &amp;amp; enjoy the ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;author-blub&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author Blub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice Berdah&lt;/a&gt; is the community manager at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; and co-organizer of DeFi France. He’s an active crypto user and leader in the grassroots movement for decentralized finance in the EU.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;action-steps&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action steps&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the passive income opportunities in DeFi and what are the risks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a Visa card for daily DAI spending (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; if in EU or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-your-first-crypto-visa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;other options&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless&lt;/a&gt;. $12 / mo. Includes &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/archive?utm_source=menu-dropdown&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;archive access&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/welcome-to-the-inner-circle-wave&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Inner Circle&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/the-deal-sheet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Deals&lt;/a&gt;—[(pay w/ crypto)](&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Free coffees ☕, thanks to DeFi</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/free-coffees-thanks-to-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/free-coffees-thanks-to-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Free coffees ☕, thanks to DeFi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overview of the passive income-earning opportunities enabled by decentralised finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it feels like the world of money is upside down: while the returns offered by banks keep getting lower (if not negative!), innovative techs enabled the emergence of an alternative financial system that is already delivering incredible value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it short: Ethereum created money on steroids while regular finance simply fails at delivering anything else than surface-level innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the money you have sitting at the bank has barely seen a one-digit interest rate for years, the yearly return enabled by decentralised finance frequently prints 2 digits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this situation even be real? It seems like decentralised finance (DeFi) is still a little too intimidating for outsiders. Or more like used to! After reading this, you’ll have no excuse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t want you scratching your head at the fifth line, so let’s clear the air on DeFi before we go on. Decentralised Finance is a term used to refer to the nascent &amp;amp; novel new financial ecosystem, built on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this parallel finance ecosystem, thousands of users from around the globe borrow, lend and exchange tokens with one another. They do so using uncensorable and unstoppable services, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.exchange/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-coffees-thanks-to-strangers-from-theinternet&#34;&gt;Free coffees, thanks to strangers from the Internet
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fully harnessing the capabilities of Ethereum, those new financial services are able to (potentially) operate in a decentralised, trustless and transparent manner — making the system &lt;strong&gt;more accessible and inclusive&lt;/strong&gt; overall (no credit check!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key aspect of DeFi is its composability, often referred as “money lego”: projects built using Ethereum’s DeFi follow standards (such as ERC-20 for basic token definitions) enabling “permission-less interoperability” — it’s possible to integrate any project one with the other, without even requiring the help of its creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are curious about the topic, you’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/defifrance/DeFi-Onboarding-Guide-a0713cfe5d844ff28bc829006625b118&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exhaustive DeFi onboarding guide&lt;/a&gt; here that introduces many articles, podcasts and videos to learn more about DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know DeFi can be a lot, so I develop a very practical approach to it: &lt;strong&gt;we’ll talk only about LIVE, working services&lt;/strong&gt; that have been paying interests to their users for several months at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;earning-returns-on-a-stablecoin&#34;&gt;Earning returns on a stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ A stablecoin (such as DAI) is a token with stable value. It&amp;rsquo;s usually achieved by tracking the value of a stable asset, like the dollar: 1 DAI = $1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decentralised finance ecosystem is structuring itself as a more credible alternative every day. Strong &amp;amp; resilient services emerged as basic tools used by most:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt;: Borrow against ETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/da/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DAI&lt;/a&gt;: Avoid price volatility &amp;amp; earn interest (Dai Saving Rate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.exchange/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt;: tokens exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound Finance&lt;/a&gt;: borrow or lend &amp;amp; earn interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other services exist to produce a passive income thanks to Ethereum, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fulcrum.trade/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;bZx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of these new services, you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have your assets in $ — &lt;strong&gt;DAI is a cryptocurrency tracking the price of $1&lt;/strong&gt; — so that you’re &lt;strong&gt;not exposed to the markets’ volatility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earn a &lt;strong&gt;5–8% yearly return&lt;/strong&gt;, on that $: your DAI will either be lent or locked directly in the Maker system (Dai Saving Rate) to help stabilize the price of DAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-a-wallet-earning-5-daiday-looklike&#34;&gt;How does a wallet earning 5 DAI/day look like?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To keep it simple here, we’re considering only 3 investments strategy matching different risk profiles, using only two different services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/5DAI.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Dai Saving Rate is arguably the safest way to earn a return on your DAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The risk is minimal because you’re not lending your money to anyone. To keep it short, you lock your DAI in the Maker system, and the system pays you a premium because you’re helping DAI to maintain its peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;🖊 Edit: Please note that the earning rates presented for specific protocols are no longer accurate. However, similar results can still be achieved with alternative methods.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/defiscore.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;👆 DeFiscore is a community project offering a comprehensive rating of the risks associated with different lending protocols. What you see above is an overview of their ranking of DAI lending opportunities.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;👆&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;DeFiscore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is a community project offering a comprehensive rating of the risks associated with different lending protocols. What you see above is an overview of their ranking of DAI lending opportunities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the other solution used, RealT, is a &lt;strong&gt;little more novel and risky&lt;/strong&gt;. RealT tokenises real estate on Ethereum &amp;amp; allow anyone to become an owner. If you own a share of RealT estate, you’ll receive &lt;strong&gt;your share of the rent, paid in DAI, daily&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ Since RealT tokens are securities, you will have to through a KYC to purchase them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the level of risk is higher with RealT than Maker, RealT does have one advantage — so far, the returns are stable. On the other hand, Maker’s DSR rate is still changing quite often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Nov 18 2019)&lt;/em&gt; DSR  Launched at 2%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(3 Jan)&lt;/em&gt; 4 %&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(8 Jan)&lt;/em&gt; 6 %&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(26 Jan 2020)&lt;/em&gt; 7.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(4 Feb)&lt;/em&gt; 8.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(9 Feb)&lt;/em&gt; 7.5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-dai-tocoffees&#34;&gt;From DAI to coffees
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a clearer picture as to how we can generate a passive income using cryptocurrencies, you might wonder: what about the coffees?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thanks to Monolith (disclaimer: I work there) it’s easy as ABC. We provide you with a non-custodial Ethereum wallet, paired with a Visa Debit Card. You can go from DAI in your wallet to a €/£ balance ready to be spent on your card in 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was step 1. We’ve shared recently about a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/monolith_web3/status/1223597132952887302?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;significant upcoming update&lt;/a&gt;, that will let you exchange tokens and access decentralised lending services straight from your Monolith app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;before-you-jumpin&#34;&gt;Before you jump in
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are seriously considering investing amounts close to those presented in the table above, &lt;strong&gt;please ensure that you know the basics&lt;/strong&gt;: such as using &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/monolith/5-rules-you-need-to-know-to-stay-safe-on-ethereum-2447244cdcb3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;securing&lt;/a&gt; an Ethereum wallet, understanding threats and choosing an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/monolith/the-usability-of-security-the-choice-of-a-contract-wallet-1e32f92ea9a1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;appropriate security model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You do not need an account on any exchange to use DeFi.&lt;/strong&gt; It is much safer to access DeFi services directly from your wallet. Using a centralised service generates additional risks for your assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to make the jump? Deploy your first contract wallet today and order your Visa debit card &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.app.link/ETH-IS-MONEY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;with the Monolith app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/card.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.app.link/ETH-IS-MONEY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🆓 &lt;strong&gt;Get your Monolith card for free&lt;/strong&gt; | 🇪🇺 Shipping to 31 countries in Europe | 💸 Spend DAI in a flash with minimal fees | 🔐 Advanced security model | 💱 Built-in DEX Aggregator (soon)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article represents my personal view only — and is written free of any professional affiliation. Facts &amp;amp; data are sourced as much as possible, but my views are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does not constitute an offer to sell, a solicitation of an offer to buy, or a recommendation of any cryptocurrency, digital token, investment, security or any other product or service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Furthermore, nothing in this article is intended to provide legal or investment advice and nothing in this article should be construed as a recommendation to buy, sell, or hold any cryptocurrency, digital token, investment or security, or to engage in any investment strategy or financial transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
