<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>👩‍🔧 Projects on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/-projects/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 👩‍🔧 Projects on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/-projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Introducing my next step: contributing to a DeFi mastermind geared to support trustless and unstoppable DeFi: The DeFi Collective</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-collective/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-collective/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/defi-collective/twitter_banner.png" alt="Featured image of post Introducing my next step: contributing to a DeFi mastermind geared to support trustless and unstoppable DeFi: The DeFi Collective" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deficollective.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Proudly introducting The DeFi Collective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Historically, financial systems have been mismanaged by states, corrupted by entrenched private interests, and unable to deliver an equitable, fair, and transparent baseline to enable unfettered value exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over five years ago, I discovered the (back then) nascent decentralized finance ecosystem and was promptly convinced it embodies a credible attempt to deliver a neutral value exchange layer, freed from the influence of states and able to resist the corruption attempts of private actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the Ethereum network provides a neutral ledger, enabling users to transact in a purely peer-to-peer fashion. Its ability to support smart contracts allows for the creation of various protocols for more advanced use cases — some of which can approach the network&amp;rsquo;s resilience level, such as Uniswap, a financial primitive providing infrastructure for the permissionless exchange of any token that will operate as long as the Ethereum network synchronizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, I progressively became more engaged and committed to upholding and delivering on this vision:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2018, I started to write and share about DeFi on various mediums, and eventually launched this blog a couple of years later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In late 2019, with friends, we launched &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/defi_fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi France&lt;/a&gt; to nurture a supportive environment to broaden adoption and involvement in DeFi amongst the French-speaking communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2020, I started to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@DeFiFrance/featured&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;host live shows in French&lt;/a&gt; to document the most relevant DeFi protocols and deepen the users’ comprehension of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, in 2022, I joined the Liquity team, to help grow the adoption of LUSD, a critical piece of infrastructure in my perspective, as it remains the most resilient stablecoin available to date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/defi-collective/tokenbrice-metamorphosis.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;tokenbrice-metamorphosis-timeline&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;proudly-introducing-the-defi-collective&#34;&gt;Proudly introducing The DeFi Collective
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s time to introduce my latest commitment to help the DeFi ecosystem deliver on its initial promises: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DeFiCollective_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The DeFi Collective&lt;/a&gt;. The DeFi Collective attempts to solve a structural imbalance that could ultimately lead DeFi to fail to deliver on its core values. DeFi suffers from an inherent tension between delivering on its base values and the concessions some think are needed for growth and adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most widely adopted protocols are rarely the most resilient, and we at the Collective believe it stems from an incentive misalignment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teams who tightly control their protocol (usually through multisigs) and harness aggressive tokenomics models tend to have more firepower to attract capital and promote themselves than those who value security and sturdiness above all else. We picture the Collective as a critical resource in reverting this imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-nonprofit-association-to-support-the-sturdiest-defi-protocols&#34;&gt;A nonprofit association to support the sturdiest DeFi protocols
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How? It’s straightforward; you’ll see that the &lt;strong&gt;DeFi Collective delivers a competitive edge, allocated only to the highest-quality DeFi protocols.&lt;/strong&gt; Protocols that ensure open, transparent, and resilient public infrastructures will receive the support of the DeFi Collective, free of charge and without conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeFi Collective is a Swiss nonprofit association incorporated in Zug, bound by its status to use its resources to support the most resilient and relevant DeFi protocols. What does this entail? The Collective will clarify and publish its “protocol guidelines” shortly after launch: any protocol that matches them is eligible for its support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what kind of support are we talking about? About all the critical expertise a protocol needs to harness to grow and thrive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Awareness and education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrations and networking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Legal &amp;amp; self-policing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Collective is &lt;strong&gt;a group of experts that cannot be hired; instead, it self-appoints on protocols that match its demanding guidelines.&lt;/strong&gt; Embodied by the ants, The Collective intends to demonstrate that social coordination is paramount. Together, ants will build an ever-growing colony, acting as an organic mesh network nurturing an ecosystem where trustless DeFi can thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ants-like-and-harness-liquidity-driving-tokens&#34;&gt;Ants like and harness liquidity-driving tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To deliver on its vision, The Collective received support from top-notch teams that align with it, including Liquity, Maverick, CatInaBox, Diva, DYAD, Zero &amp;amp; Retro. &lt;strong&gt;It enables the Collective to be self-sustainable from day one, and able to direct and sustain over $25M of assets in liquidity pools of relevant DEXes across various layers,&lt;/strong&gt; including mainnet, Optimism, Arbitrum, zkSync, Polygon zkEVM &amp;amp; more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the Collective controls sizable liquidity-driving positions, including veVELO, vlLIQ, vlAURA, veRAM, veZERO, veRETRO &amp;amp; more, and manages treasuries on all the networks mentioned above, to support the liquidity of relevant tokens through liquidity-driving votes and liquidity-providing activities. The Collective adheres to extremely risk-averse treasury management practices intended to preserve and grow its capital in a manner that is synergistic with its goals and vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-liquidity-management&#34;&gt;Beyond Liquidity Management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquidity management and support is a critical area of expertise for the Collective that I will champion, along with governance-related activities to increase the adoption of the tokens from the supported protocols across the broader DeFi ecosystem. However, the DeFi Collective is an adventure much bigger than myself, and I am blessed with the support of two equally critical founding board members – Nils Bundi and Florian Prantl, who deliver on their expertise in their respective areas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/nils-bundi-6246b998/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nils Bundis&lt;/a&gt; is a DeFi protocol architect and developer with a background in financial engineering. As an experienced DeFi builder, he knows the challenges of building “truly decentralized” protocols. Apart from the technical depth, Nils will also support the Collective with his expertise in the operational requirements, ensuring secure and trusted DeFi services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/floowp_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Floria Prantl&lt;/a&gt; is a lawyer and policy specialist with a background in advising DeFi and CeFi projects, navigating the legal and regulatory pitfalls in setting up and expanding their services. He also brings valuable experience advocating with authorities for progressive and balanced regulations. At the Collective, he particularly lends his expertise to operational compliance, offering guidance to supported protocols and contributing to the Collective&amp;rsquo;s self-policing, networking, and other vital initiatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their skills and knowledge will help the Collective to conduct research, establish and promote self-policing guidelines, and entertain any other relevant activities deemed necessary to deliver on &lt;strong&gt;its vision of supporting the existing resilient and DeFi-aligned protocols and foster an ecosystem where protocol builders have increased incentives to walk the path of sturdiness, immutability, and resilience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-streamlined-infrastructure-kept-in-check&#34;&gt;A streamlined infrastructure, kept in check
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All board members and contributors to the Collective are capped to a commitment accounting for at max 50% of their working hours. This policy was designed to keep the structure in check and avoid situations where the preservation/growth of the structure is given more priority than achieving its end goals, which is often seen in public institutions and associations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contributors have agreed to compensation well below the market rate for their efforts. Boardmembers are not compensated for their activity. This enables the Collective to minimize its starting expenses and aggressively compounds its earnings to grow its onchain treasuries, giving it more means to deliver on its vision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The DeFi Collective is now my main focus and commitment&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that I will sadly no longer be able to contribute directly to Liquity as a team member. It was not an easy decision to make. Still, it was necessary to enable me to keep focusing on my areas of expertise (liquidity management and governance) and keep growing them. As one of the most resilient lending infrastructures available, the Liquity protocol matches the Collective guidelines and will be part of the supported protocols amongst several others to be introduced shortly. The Collective will thus be able to support Liquity’s growth and expansion with liquidity-management-related activities and help LUSD get more broadly supported across DeFi protocols and L2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;follow-the-ants-and-get-involved-with-the-colony&#34;&gt;Follow the ants and get involved with the colony
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do you resonate with the Collective’s vision and want to make a difference in DeFi? You can shape the Collective: let us know about your unique expertise to assist the collective as a contributor or a friend, or get actively involved to join as a member – all of this is happening on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/KFhE3tpGsM&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Collective Discord&lt;/a&gt;: a place to be!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep in touch with The DeFi Collective, you can also &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DeFiCollective_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;follow us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, where we will update the community with our news, including the upcoming first Collective Live Session I’ll be hosting: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/NsaQNpC65C?event=1164186718375772261&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;join us Thursday, October 19, at 7 PM GMT+2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the Collective:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deficollective.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi Collective website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://deficollective.org/blog/the-defi-collective-introduction/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Introducing the DeFi Collective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Announcement: TokenBrice 🤝 Maverick</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/maverick-x-tokenbrice/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/maverick-x-tokenbrice/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/maverick-x-tokenbrice-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Announcement: TokenBrice 🤝 Maverick" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post is more of a personal announcement: I wanted to let you know what I am up to and what&amp;rsquo;s happening with Maverick. So let&amp;rsquo;s not beat around the bush: I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to announce that &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m supporting the Maverick team as an advisor, helping with the growth strategy, tokenomics, and business development.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;storytime&#34;&gt;Storytime
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like me, you must be over-saturated with DEXes. If you follow DeFi closely, you&amp;rsquo;ve seen several of these launches daily. Yet most still adopt fundamental liquidity structures: x*y=k for volatile pairs and stableswap, and focus on innovating on the tokenomics instead: the now famous ve(3,3) DEXes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a DEX that would innovate at the fundamental level&lt;/strong&gt; for a while, so in May last year, when Bob reached out to let me know about Maverick, I was all ears. I quickly realized Maverick could reshape how we envision liquidity in DeFi and help further improve its efficiency. So I’m glad to announce my involvement today: Maverick is already live, growing quickly, and poised for even exponential growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we dive into what makes Maverick so interesting, we need to take a step back and consider the broader context of liquidity in DeFi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-structuring-deep-dive&#34;&gt;Liquidity Structuring Deep Dive
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the beginning, there was Uniswap&lt;/strong&gt;, and its ease of use for liquidity providers led people to believe it was a trivial activity. Yet, any liquidity-providing activity on a DEX involves two decisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Picking a pair (or more) of tokens (ex: ETH/USDC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Forming price assumptions regarding one/both tokens (🐂, 🐻, or 🦀)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second decision is &lt;strong&gt;often implicit&lt;/strong&gt;, like with UniswapV2, where you get no option but only one choice: 50/50, meaning that your optimal scenario is both tokens going sideways in price with a large trading volume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Uniswap V3 emerged, the second assumption was suddenly more explicit to DeFi users thanks to concentrated liquidity. However, V3 added complexity to the liquidity provider experience and active management. It &lt;strong&gt;mainly caters to power-users who can afford frequent rebalancing&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;require external tooling&lt;/strong&gt; to be harnessed effectively by LPs, the liquidity manager – Arrakis, Bunni, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-unique-about-maverick&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s unique about Maverick?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, Maverick is the spiritual descendant of UniV3 and CurveV2. It offers infinite flexibility in the design of liquidity-providing position, similar to Uniswap V3, but with streamlined and autonomous execution, just like on Curve. Indeed, LPs on Maverick can decide to redistribute their liquidity to follow the price in one or both directions. &lt;strong&gt;If needed, the rebalancing is done at the DEX level, ensuring gas efficiency.&lt;/strong&gt; Maverick also supports “static pools” that are range-bound too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This feature makes Maverick a fantastic fit for pegged assets, especially those that are not continually trading precisely at the peg&lt;/strong&gt; and so underserved by the usual liquidity structures, such as a LUSD/USDC pair:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve stableswap, which optimizes liquidity for a 1/1 price, is not ideal when LUSD is overpeg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniswap v3, where LPs usually end up super concentrated around the current market price, which is efficient, but also quickly through them out of range as the price move&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/mav-both.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mav-mode-both&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Maverick, such a pair can be harnessed optimally by each LP, depending on their actual goal. &lt;strong&gt;It enables each LP to craft an automatically adjusting position that enforces a strategy fitting his assumptions and needs&lt;/strong&gt;. Here are some examples of goals &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; liquidity structure matching:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🎚️ | Looking for a safe yield with minimal risk? A static LP might be preferable, as the outcomes are predictable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐂/🐻 | Thinking LUSD is currently over/undervalued: you can supply directional liquidity and earn extra if your assumption verifies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🦀 | Want to bet on volume with prices going sideways? You can simply focus your liquidity a few bins around the price and activate the &lt;strong&gt;left-right mode&lt;/strong&gt; to constantly rebalance the current price, thus maximizing the available liquidity and fees collected but also the potential impermanent loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, Maverick has found &lt;strong&gt;a beast of a product/market fit on pools like wstETH/ETH&lt;/strong&gt;, often averaging over 100% daily utilization rate. Here’s today, for instance (4/20):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve: TVL = $1.5B, Volume =$34M, Utilization = 2,26%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick: TVL = $10.6M, Volume =$10.45M, &lt;strong&gt;Utilization = 98,5%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/maverickxtokenbrice/mav-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Maverick Top Pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Launched just a few weeks ago on the Ethereum mainnet, Maverick is already seeing an impressive volume and unprecedented liquidity utilization rate, especially on pegged asset pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maverick was also launched on zkSync, its first L2, a few days ago. As more staple DeFi projects roll out service there, Maverick will have many opportunities to demonstrate the superior efficiency its liquidity designs can offer to LPs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited about the next steps: as a DeFi Strategist at Liquity, the release of Maverick felt like early Christmas to me; I think it&amp;rsquo;s just getting started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll contribute to Maverick as an advisor, meaning that my main focus remains my commitment to immutable protocols, especially Liquity, helping them grow through various onchain and offchain activities. I’m confident Maverick will quickly prove to be a decisive tool in achieving that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just hearing about Maverick? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mav.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/mavprotocol&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;join the Discord server.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/jr-strategist/jr-strategist-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a Junior DeFi Strategist to join me on my daily DeFi adventures, learn and grow. The fundamental missions are governance proposals, liquidity management, business development, and partnerships, but the scope is quite flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique opportunity for a passionate DeFi curious to jumpstart his/her career in crypto. Be the first hire for a community-led effort to cater governance-minimized and immutable protocols to achieve the mission of DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be working closely with me and learn my tactics to successfully grow liquidity and utility for immutable DeFi projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-activities&#34;&gt;Your activities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek and find new partnership opportunities for DeFi projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with other DeFi protocols and DAOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write governance proposals, and support proposals submitted by third parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage strategies enforced on the various liquidity-driver tokens owned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize Protocol Owned Liquidity strategies across main net and L2s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and tweet about partnerships and liquidity opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-experience-and-skills&#34;&gt;Your experience and skills
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive DeFi on chain track record - who cares about diplomas? Show me a wallet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively involved in DeFi, owning some key governance tokens, knowledgeable about the main models (Liquity, Curve, Aave, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of DEXs like Curve, Uniswap, Balancer and voting protocols I.e.  Convex, Aura as well as ve(3,3) models like e.g. Velodrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well versed in the differences of cvxCRV, yCRV, sdCRV, uCRV, and aCRV
Solid understanding of the top DeFi protocols and good overview of the promising newcomers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re already active on various governance forums or DeFi-related Discords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written and spoken English proficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work independently as well as team up with your peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-can-offer&#34;&gt;What I can offer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exciting part time position (~50%) with a monthly retainer in FIAT (for the beginning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive a community-led initiative (more to be announced soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be part of a top notch and proven DeFi team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work remotely (ideally in Europe or US timezone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forms.gle/6qaXgkczuhiaqNTV6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Please apply via this form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back in touch shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
