<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Votium on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/votium/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Votium on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/votium/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Subtles nuances with great consequences: a cross analysis of Curve and Velodrome</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/crv-vs-velo/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/crv-vs-velo/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Subtles nuances with great consequences: a cross analysis of Curve and Velodrome" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to address Velodrome/Aerodrome, a genuine success story in DeFi. I’ve covered DEXes extensively on this blog, especially Curve: this article will compare the two models and explain how Velodrome improved on the veCRV template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, let me start with a disclaimer: there are two core components to a DEX that everyone needs to be aware of to understand what follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The liquidity structures it provides (x*y=k, stableswap, CL, stableswap-NG, curve V2, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The incentives model, which for a DEX is synonymous with its tokenomics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post focuses on the latter, the core of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/velodrome-v2/optimism&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Velodrome&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s innovation. This post assumes basic familiarity with Curve’s veCRV tokenomics; if not, I urge you to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/fr/crv-wars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read my previous writing about it&lt;/a&gt;, posted three years ago but still helpful to understand the model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vecrvvevelo-fees-collection--distribution&#34;&gt;A/ veCRV/veVELO Fees Collection &amp;amp; Distribution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fee collection and redistribution are the lifelines of a decentralized exchange. Here, simplicity is usually good, as the DEX segment leader Uniswap is still operating under an extremely simple yet brutally efficient model, where 100% of the collected money goes to the liquidity providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the launch of its CRV token in August 2020, Curve explored an alternative path, where 50% of the fees collected on a given pair go to liquidity providers and the remaining 50% to the “DAO” (admin fees), meaning the veCRV holders. Curve introduced the concept of “liquidity gauges,” where locked token holders (veCRV) can direct emissions to be received by liquidity providers, creating an incentive baseline independent of the volume processed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velodrome launched two years later, at the end of May 2022, and explored yet another split, inspired by a previous project iterating on the Curve model: Solidly. Here, &lt;strong&gt;LPs get no exposure to the fees collected on the pairs they provide liquidity for and are fully incentivized by token emissions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core difference between veCRV and veVELO lies in how they handle the fees collected at the DEX/DAO level, where we observe differences in the amount of fees collected and their distribution model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive into the nuances of this topic: they are key to understanding the pros and cons of each mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a1-amount-of-fees-distributed-velo--2-x-curve&#34;&gt;A.1/ Amount of fees distributed: VELO = 2 x Curve
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve and Velodrome operate under the same base logic: every week, a given amount of CRV/VELO tokens are emitted and distributed to liquidity providers. Each pool has an associated gauge for which veCRV/veVELO holders can vote, and the weekly budget allocation follows the proportion of the “gauge vote”: if a gauge receives 1% of the total veCRV/veVELO vote, 1% of all the emissions produced that week will be directed to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These emissions are essentially the main cost for the DEX: the price paid to attract and retain liquidity. What matters then is what comes on the other side of the balance sheet – the revenues: in our case, it’s the fees collected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Curve, revenues stem from the “admin fees” of each pool, which are usually set at 50%. This means the fees collected on a given pool are split 50/50 between the LP and the DAO/veCRV holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/curve-revenues.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-revenues&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Velodrome, it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward: liquidity providers get no exposure to the fees collected on the pool they supply; they are incentivized through $VELO emissions only, meaning that the DAO/veVELO holders get 100% of the fees generated on the DEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this core difference already has a massive impact, the following one is even more meaningful as it pertains to how those fees are distributed to veCRV/veVELO holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a2-model-for-the-distribution-of-fees-a-fairer-and-more-efficient-approach&#34;&gt;A.2/ Model for the distribution of fees: a fairer and more efficient approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve harnesses a model that could be described as &lt;strong&gt;a fee mutualization system&lt;/strong&gt;: the fees veCRV holders receive depend only on the amount of veCRV they control. Without getting too technical, those fees are collected in the various tokens involved in the pool (such as USDC/USDT/DAI for the 3pool), and every week, harvested, swapped for 3pool LP token, and then made available for claiming to veCRV holders – as you can see, this means somewhat of an infrastructure to operate, the cost of which scale with the number of pools on the Curve DEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Velodrome provides a superior model on all dimensions, as it achieves better DEX/LP/token holder alignment without any infrastructure required. Let’s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;Velodrome connects gauge-voting activity with fee distribution&lt;/strong&gt;. Here, the amount of veVELO one controls matters, but even more important is which pool one votes for since the &lt;strong&gt;voters are exposed to the fees collected on the pairs they vote for only.&lt;/strong&gt; They collect the fees as such (i.e., a voter of the ETH/USDC pool gets ETH and USDC), meaning the infrastructure required is much more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velodrome ties fee distribution to the gauge-voting activity: veVELO holders receive the fees collected on the pool they vote ONLY, paid as such every week. It enables the better alignment of veVELO holders with the best interest of Velodrome as a DEX compared to Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This simple twist creates an interesting voting flywheel. High-volume pairs collect lots of fees, meaning high incentives for voters. This leads to many votes, which direct sensible emissions to the pair, attracting more liquidity providers, enabling more volume processing, etc., until an equilibrium point is reached. This means that high-volume pairs sustain themselves without bribes or a benevolent profit-minimizer whale-voter needed, which is not the case with Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/velodrome-revenues.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;velodrome-revenues&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Velodrome Revenues Overview - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.com/0xkhmer/velodrome&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source: 0xkhmer dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/aerodrome-revenues.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;aerodrome-revenues&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Aerodrome Revenues Overview - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.com/0xkhmer/aerodrome&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source: 0xkhmer dashboard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a3-what-it-means-in-practice&#34;&gt;A.3/ What it means in practice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough with the explainer; let’s illustrate by considering the case of a veCRV/veVELO voter, who decided to vote for a pair processing minimal volume (the situation is common).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A significant veCRV holder votes for a pool processing a marginal amount of volume compared to its TVL, either to collect a bribe or because he wants to support the tokens involved in the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His voting activity is detrimental to Curve as a DEX because he directs emissions where they are unnecessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He receives the same amount of 3CRV as a more Curve-aligned voter with an equivalent veCRV bag trying to direct incentives to maximize volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now on Velodrome:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A significant veVELO holder votes for a pool processing a marginal amount of volume compared to its TVL, either to collect a bribe or because he wants to support the tokens involved in the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His voting activity is detrimental to Velodrome as a DEX because he directs emissions where they are unnecessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He receives a marginal amount of fees since the pool he is voting for is processing a marginal volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is the same in reverse for voting on a high-volume pool that would be of interest to the DEX:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Curve, this DEX-aligned voter will receive the same amount of 3CRV as anyone holding the same bag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On Velodrome, this DEX-aligned voter will be well rewarded, as he will be a majority voter on a high-volume pair: an ideal situation to maximize fees earned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On both sides, bribes are paid to voters and can lead to situations where votes are directed to pools that are not optimal in terms of volume processed. However, on Curve, there is no penalty for doing so. On Velodrome, bribers of such pools compete with high-volume pools offering attractive APR to voters, with or without bribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same thing, from another angle: on Curve, the cost of bribes depends only on the value of CRV emissions. On Velodrome, the baseline price a project must pay to gather votes depends on the total bribes + fees collected on other pools. This means that high-volume pools push the cost of bribes upward, entertaining yet another flywheel in the flywheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding the above means understanding the core difference between the Curve and Velodrome models. However, to get the full picture, more elements must be considered. Let’s discuss the LP boost now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;b-lp-boosts--its-impact-on-the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;B/ LP boosts &amp;amp; its impact on the ecosystem
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;LP boost, as it is called, is a Curve-specific feature. Many protocols forking the veCRV tokenomics, such as Balancer with its veBAL, also use it. It enables veCRV holders to earn more CRV rewards on their LP, factoring in several elements, including the size of their veCRV bag and the size of their various LPs. Thus, with appropriate veCRV ownership, an LP can get an “LP Boost” of up to 2.5x compared to the base emission rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b1-lp-boost-explained&#34;&gt;B.1/ LP Boost explained
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To maximize the boost obtained, up to 2.5x maximal, one must:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Own as much veCRV as possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have LP positions in as many pools as possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a proportionate/balanced amount of TVL in those various pools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simply put, LP Boost is a rugged game from the get-go&lt;/strong&gt;. It is not designed to benefit individual veCRV holders over their LP but to attract meta-protocol, such as Convex, who can achieve 1+2+3 consistently. &lt;strong&gt;The growth of Convex is not a success story; it is by design (Curve’s design)&lt;/strong&gt;. If it were not for Convex, another similar protocol would own most of the veCRV supply. We observed similar patterns with other protocols that adopted LP Boost: Balancer has Aura. Convex and Aura control &amp;gt; 50% of the veCRV/veBAL supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velodrome and Aerodrome completely avoid the possibility of a new protocol to gobble up the supply by not having any boosting mechanism. As we’ve seen with Curve, Convex emerged and captured most of the supply; now, all LPs are earning with a boost, and none are benefiting from any disproportionate amount of CRV. The system has converged to everyone earning about the same effective boost, or in Velodrome/Aerodrome’s case, no boost since the future outcome would’ve been LPs earning the same effective boost. The other fact remains that since Convex has a majority of CRV locked, they control the future governance of CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;b2-consequences-of-lp-boost&#34;&gt;B.2/ Consequences of LP Boost
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The existence of the LP-Boost calls for a Convex-like layer on top of the DEX; there is no avoiding it. At this point, some could think: &amp;ldquo;So you have a protocol gobbling most of your emissions and locking them forever; what&amp;rsquo;s the problem?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple: it&amp;rsquo;s simply inefficient design since those meta-layers provide features that could be delivered less convoluted at the base level (by the DEX itself) and without the fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curve needs Convex and the bribe marketplace: Votium, Warden, and Hidden Hands. But also the auto-compounder/vote delegation manager: Airforce Union, Concentrator, etc. You end up with dozens of protocols taking some fees here and there to deliver something that Velodrome manages to pack in natively. This makes the experience more complex for the users, who must know about these dozens of protocols and their subtleties to make the most of Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, remember how, while discussing the fee distribution, we mentioned that Curve required a much more dense infrastructure to operate? Well, imagine the mess that veCRV+LP Boost is in the backend. There is a reason why both Curve and Balancer are taking ages to ship on a new L2, and often with partial functionality (such as no LP boost, surprise surprise.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;seamlessly-expanding-beyond-what-curve-offers&#34;&gt;Seamlessly expanding beyond what Curve offers
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On Velodrome, the bribe marketplace is built-in: projects can post their bribes directly on the Velodrome frontend, and voters can check available bribes and vote in the same place. New features keep being delivered and added to the same interface used by all participants: LPs, projects, and tokenholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;velodrome-relays&#34;&gt;Velodrome Relays
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;They go from quality-of-life / gas-saving upgrades, such as the “auto-max-lock”, saving lockers for those who wish to remain max-locked to maximize their gauge-voting power the hassle of doing it manually, to much more extensive features, like Relay, a veVELO position management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/relay.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;velodrome-relay&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a tool catering to projects using Velodrome to grow liquidity on their pairs. It enables them to set up their voting and bribing strategy and implement it automatically: no need to submit weekly transactions anymore. Relay has another benefit, since currently, the strategy available is a veVELO-maxi one, compounding all fees &amp;amp; bribes collected into VELO and relocking it to maximize voting power: it creates a sizeable VELO sink, directly indexed on the fees distributed by the exchange. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/VelodromeFi/status/1762908204894445834&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Almost 1/5 of all veVELO are already there&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Relay feature matures, more strategies will be available to its users, including some that compound all the fees and bribes earned into veVELO but, for instance, make them claimable in ETH or USDC. It will prove very convenient for veVELO holders that are not looking to support a project in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;venft-tokenized-locked-positions&#34;&gt;veNFT: Tokenized locked positions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Velodrome has other neat innovations packed in, such as the still under-appreciated veNFT: with Curve, veCRV is non-transferable, making their management painful. Velodrome can achieve the same alignment but enables transferability: veVELO positions are represented by a veNFT that can be transferred. There is no way of redeeming a given veNFT for the underlying VELO tokens apart from waiting for the lock to expire. However, it eases the management of such a position by enabling its transfer. There is also &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decode.market/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an OTC market for veVELO veNFTs&lt;/a&gt;, where holders can sell their position to interested buyers at a fluctuating discount compared to the value of underlying VELO tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-deep-understanding-of-the-nature-of-the-game&#34;&gt;A deep understanding of the nature of the game
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exchanges like Curve or Velodrome are a particular product type in the DeFi landscape. In regular business terms, &lt;strong&gt;they could be described as B2B2C: Business to Business to Consumer&lt;/strong&gt;. They are B2B because their first customers are other projects – the various protocols looking for liquidity. If they successfully service this market, the projects they onboard to their DEX will do the B2C work for them, as their liquidity pools present opportunities to their respective token holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that regard, I feel like Curve utterly failed. With its pyramid of solutions nested on top of one another, Curve is particularly unfriendly to onboard for projects. They wanna bribe? All right, decide between veCRV or vlCVX bribes on Bribe.crv, Votium, Warden, or StakeDAO. Do they want to manage their own CRV? Fine, just pick between veCRV, aCRV, cvxCRV, sdCRV, vlCVX, uCRV, etc. While this myriad of options might ravish Curve-enthusiasts, it turns, in my perspective, into a negative quality for the B2B side of things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, the experience with Velodrome is seamless: one place where everything happens, one option for each – without needing to compare between half a dozen cryptic and sometimes misleading alternatives. Coupled with the previous characteristics of the veCRV games discussed before, especially the LP Boost, it makes the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/farewell-glc/#the-case-of-the-crv-wars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve ecosystem particularly unfriendly to new entrants&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;who would want to enter a race rigged in favor of the first entrants three years after it began&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/crv-vs-velo/tour-de-op.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;tour-de-op&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the Velodrome BD efforts are remarkable; the team is broadly available to help onboard new projects, and several programs are designed to make the experience as simple and compelling for new entrants, regrouped under the “Tour de OP” umbrella, which includes a bribe matching program, lock bonuses and vote boosting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parting-words&#34;&gt;PARTING WORDS
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you might have seen, both Velodrome &amp;amp; Aerodrome have attracted much attention lately, thanks to their token seeing positive momentum: I think it&amp;rsquo;s well deserved. The release of Slipstream, Velodrome’s implementation of Concentrated Liquidity, will increase the volume processed per unit of TVL, unlocking the flywheel&amp;rsquo;s next growth phase. Aerodrome, Velodrome’s fork on the Base network, has seen spectacular growth since it launched six months ago, further demonstrating the model&amp;rsquo;s viability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the longer term, the Velodrome team is starting to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@VelodromeFi/velodrome-the-metadex-48e4af1ef9a4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;refer to Velo as a &amp;ldquo;MetaDEX&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, hinting at Velodrome becoming the base liquidity hub not just of Optimism but for the whole Superchain: all chains built on the OP stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time will tell, but Velodrome is already a resounding success on Optimism, so managing a cross-chain DEX properly would be a game changer. This is especially true considering how much Curve &amp;amp; Balancer has failed there—not because they did not try, but simply because their convoluted infrastructure with LP boost makes cross-chain deployment painful (Hello AuraFinance distributing AURA on chains where&amp;hellip; there is no liquidity for $AURA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: I’m addressing the DEX part of the product suite here, which is the complete product for Velodrome but not for Curve, which now has crvUSD and Llamalend. Still, even with crvUSD included, Aerodrome is now collecting and redistributing more fees than Curve, all of this while being present on one chain only vs 13 for Curve. While Curve-DEX has been sub-par for a while, the team has repeatedly proven innovative and able to bounce back. crvUSD revenues have already flipped those of Curve-DEX, and who knows what Llamalend could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game on: let’s wait and see.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>⚔ Advanced CRV warfare: analysis of protocols built on top of Curve and Convex </title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/crv-wars-l2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/crv-wars-l2/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/curve-wars-l2-cover-tokenbrice.png" alt="Featured image of post ⚔ Advanced CRV warfare: analysis of protocols built on top of Curve and Convex " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game and the fight around CRV and CVX tokens have changed in scope since my last article describing the original Curve Wars, now almost primitive. The infrastructure around Curve has become much denser with the arrival of Convex of course, but also Votium, Union Llama Airforce, Concentrator, CCRV, Lendflare, Warden, and many other protocols still in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To assume a strategic position on CRV or CVX, one must now be able to support an investment of several tens of millions of dollars. Thus, the race to accumulate CVX and CRV has become primarily a game for DAOs or whales. More specifically, DAOs seem to prefer CVX to CRV, which represents a more favorable trade-off:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boosts LP Curve&lt;/strong&gt;: ability to build liquidity via votes on Curve gauges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yields&lt;/strong&gt;: 4-5% in cvxCRV + potential bribe yields if capacity is not used (or the protocol also use bribes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: CVX can be used to its maximum capacity by committing 16 weeks + 3 days (vlCVX) while CRV requires up to 4 years of commitment (1 CRV = veCRV).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to extract the utility of CRV, CVX is a credible and more flexible alternative, which is why most DAOs focus on this token. Convex Finance has become a &amp;ldquo;functional L2&amp;rdquo; of Curve: a second layer that brings new features and a different set of tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Convex is not the only project that tried to realize this vision: there was also Yearn, which has now capitulated: Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Curve vaults are essentially through Convex, which is now more profitable. Since then, many projects are trying to offer a synergistic brick with the Curve/Convex behemoth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crv-or-cvx&#34;&gt;CRV or CVX?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t go back to the basics of the separation between the two tokens here, that&amp;rsquo;s a matter for an entire article if you&amp;rsquo;re new to the subject: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md%22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV wars: understanding the race to accumulate the ability to influence the Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be kept in mind that despite the computable equivalence between CVX and CRV (1vl CVX controls about 4.8 veCRV - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.xyz/Marcov/Convex-Finance&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;), the two tokens have different tradeoffs as described above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balance between CRV and CVX tends to hold, despite frequent swings: lately, the pendulum seems to swing more towards CVX. Nevertheless I think there is still room for other approaches that start from the source (CRV) and they are starting to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paladin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.warden.vote/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Warden&lt;/a&gt; is proposing a protocol that helps liquidity providers on Curve maximize their returns and perhaps achieve the desirable 2.5x bonus by borrowing the capacity of veCRV tokens (provided by others) paid directly in CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are so many other subtleties and interactions to keep in mind in order to understand the relevance of the strategies deployed by the different projects, DAOs and protocols to win the Curve Wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why this article proposes to review the CRV and CVX wars &lt;strong&gt;by visualizing and detailing the whole ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; that has developed around these two protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;curves-functional-layer-2&#34;&gt;Curve&amp;rsquo;s functional layer 2
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about &amp;ldquo;functional L2&amp;rdquo;, or simply Curve or Convex L2. This is an image to describe this trend of multiplication of supports used to interact with Curve/Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful not to confuse the term with &amp;ldquo;true L2s&amp;rdquo; / scaling L2s: the term in its original sense to describe a new chain that inherits the security of its parent while allowing for higher transaction throughput and more moderate costs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we start with Curve&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Functional L2s&lt;/strong&gt;, then Convex&amp;rsquo;s (itself a Curve L2), then borrowing services to leverage the many sources of return offered by the entire Curve ecosystem, and we&amp;rsquo;ll finish with the CRV/CVX protocol-whales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a dense and colorful adventure, but as is often the case with my articles, I&amp;rsquo;m offering you a summary of my research on the subject: enjoy your reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To lose you on the way, I propose you this map which summarizes the main actors of the Curve/Convex ecosystem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/curve-convex-l2-map-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve/Convex L2 map&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;convex-finance-curve-by-the-slice&#34;&gt;Convex Finance: Curve by the slice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex is the first functional L2 of Curve; other projects preceded it (yveCRV and sdveCRV) but they were not as synergistic with Curve and therefore only marginally successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Convex provides access to maximized and liquid CRV token returns through cvxCRV. The ability to govern and vote on the Curve gauges corresponding to the underlying veCRV tokens is redirected to the owners of vlCVX. Convex thus provides easy access to the Curve ecosystem (for veCRV owners).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Convex controls a large amount of vlCVX, the centralization of voting power on gauges is avoided by offering this capability to the highest bidder through Votium (bribes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convex is now basic, so I won&amp;rsquo;t detail it further here. My previous article on CRV Warfare went into more depth on the model and the contributions of Convex: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md%22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV Warfare: Understanding the race to accumulate the ability to influence Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;warden-of-paladin-curve-on-steroids&#34;&gt;Warden of Paladin: Curve on steroids?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.warden.vote/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Warden&lt;/a&gt; is another possible path for Curve LPs, which offers a different set of tradeoffs to Convex. Warden does not directly control veCRVs, but instead offers to rent the boosting capacity of LP Curve from veCRVs owned by others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rental is paid directly in CRVs and by the week. It comes from veCRV owners who make it available, for the price and duration of their choice. The deal is concluded through the delegation of the corresponding veCRVs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/warden-veboost.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;LP Ve boost rental on Warden&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warden thus returns to the LP Curve boost game. On Convex, most pools are boosted between 1.5 and 1.7x via Convex. Having your own stock of veCRV, increased by a Warden loan, allows you to reach 2x or even 2.5x maximum on certain pools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Warden even offers a handy calculator to visualize the amount of veCRV needed to reach a given multiplier:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/warden-calc.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Warden Calculator&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warden is therefore a credible alternative for protocols, DAOs and large carriers who would like to optimize their LP Curve in a perspective of maximizing the obtained CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;l2-convex&#34;&gt;L2 Convex
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex is not yet one year old (May 2021) but given the preponderant place that the service already occupies, abstractions built on top of it were quick to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;votium-convex-vote-auction&#34;&gt;Votium: Convex vote auction
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Convex protocol concentrates the largest amount of veCRVs owned by a single entity. Nevertheless, the voting capacity corresponding to the veCRVs owned by Convex (obtained thanks to the cvxCRV) is distributed among all the owners of the CVX token that &amp;ldquo;vote lock&amp;rdquo; it (vlCVX) for 16 weeks + 7 days).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via snapshot, they can mobilize their voting power directly on the Curve pool gauge of their choice. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://votium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Votium&lt;/a&gt; is an additional layer built on top of this feature: Votium allows any project to allocate a budget to support a given Curve gauge. At the end of the round, the vlCVX owners who voted on this gauge share the rewards, according to their voting power: these are the famous bribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/votium-bribes.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Votium bribes&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the impressive amount of veCRVs controlled by Convex, Votium has quickly emerged as &lt;strong&gt;an essential tool to establish and sustain a presence on Curve&lt;/strong&gt;: consistent bribes on Votium can quickly make a Curve pool very attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We detail below the example of Frax Finance which offers around $5-7M of bribes each round; this allows to maintain attractive returns on the Frax/3CRV pool despite the massive dilution (the pool contains almost $3B of assets), and this without issuing their own token (FXS) for liquidity mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;llama-airforce-union-shared-management-of-vlcvx&#34;&gt;Llama Airforce Union: shared management of vlCVX
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bribes offered on Votium are very attractive: this allows vlCVX to reach a return &lt;strong&gt;of about 40% APR - most of which (90%) comes from the bribes&lt;/strong&gt;. However, managing your own vlCVX position has several constraints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gas costs&lt;/strong&gt;, to lock in your vlCVX, but also to harvest the bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although it is possible to delegate, this leads to a dispersion of the rewards (paid in a dozen different tokens -&amp;gt; gas fees). So small and medium vlCVX holders generally prefer to concentrate their vote on a given project: more practical, but it implies not forgetting to &lt;strong&gt;vote at each round&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Llama Airforce Union proposes to remedy these two main limitations, for the happiness of small holders as well as those who prefer a &lt;strong&gt;100% passive management of their vlCVX&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is simple: the Union pools the management of vlCVX. The only action required from the users is the delegation of their vlCVX voting power to the Union contract. Thereafter, the Union takes care of everything:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In each round, the Union takes care of claiming all the obtained bribes, and sells them for cvxCRV (=mutualization/immense reduction of the impact of transaction fees).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The obtained cvxCRV are then deposited in the Pounder, which stakes them with Convex and composes the yield automatically (uCRV).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Union thus offers a relevant alternative for CVX owners who intend to maintain and compound their position over the long term. As always, don&amp;rsquo;t forget to pay attention to the fees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas fees are passed on and distributed to all Union users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A fee of 2% of the total bribes received is also charged in each round.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/llama-airforce-union.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Llama Air Force Union&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This TVL only takes into account the yields of the bribes compounded into cvxCRVs by the Union (uCRV). The vlCVX are not taken into account since they are simply delegated to the Union (about 2.5M CVX).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Union has been a rapid success. The project originated from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://llama.airforce/#/convex/flyer&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Llama Airforce&lt;/a&gt;, an already well-known source of information within the Curve/Convex ecosystem, which no doubt contributed to its adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;concentrator-aladdindao&#34;&gt;Concentrator (AladdinDAO)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://concentrator.aladdin.club/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Concentrator&lt;/a&gt; is a bit like the Union, but this time for liquidity providers. Thus the Concentrator proposes to manage LP Curve for its depositors: the rewards (CRV, CVX and potential other tokens) are automatically sold for cvxCRV and automatically composed (staking on Convex) via the aCRV wrapper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal is interesting and rather synergistic with Curve and Convex: it&amp;rsquo;s a bit unfortunate to see that CVX are sold for the moment, but explained by the lack of available wrapper for vlCVX. The service offered by Concentrator is therefore rather relevant for &lt;strong&gt;small and medium sized carriers who want to use their LP Curve to maximize their CRV&lt;/strong&gt; token exposure in an efficient way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;congruent-ccrv-curveconvex-flywheel-optimization&#34;&gt;Congruent CCRV: Curve/Convex flywheel optimization
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the current limitations of Convex (or feature for some) is that despite the fairly dense liquidity in the cvxCRV/CRV Curve pool, it is often unbalanced. CvxCRV is liquid against CRV, but rarely at 1:1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ccrv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CCRV&lt;/a&gt; is therefore designed as a mechanism to help rebalance this pool, using both Curve and Convex. The principle is quite simple if you understand the mechanisms of Curve and Convex:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/ccrv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CCRV.finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of the cCRV token, backed by 1 cvxCRV. The protocol stakes all the cvxCRVs deposited to back cCRVs in Convex, in order to obtain a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creation of the Curve 3CRV pool: CRV, cvxCRV and cCRV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bribes on the 3CRV pool to help it grow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism will launch with an initial allocation of 1M CRV (provided by Congruent DAO). This will airdrop 1M cCRV (via bribes) over the first few weeks of the token&amp;rsquo;s existence to help it launch quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the launch plan seems pretty solid, the sustainability of the mechanism still seems uncertain. The addition of fees could allow the CCRV protocol to have its own liquidity (and therefore return in CRV, CVX and 3 pool) which could fuel the bribes while reducing their effective cost in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;cCRV is not yet launched but is intended to be a &lt;strong&gt;new optimization of the flywheel Curve/Convex&lt;/strong&gt;. Interestingly, cCRV is being developed by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://congruent.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Congruent&lt;/a&gt;, a DAO that develops &amp;ldquo;Governance as a Service&amp;rdquo; (GaaS) products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bent-the-convex-of-convex&#34;&gt;Bent: the Convex of Convex?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.bentfinance.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bent&lt;/a&gt; is a true L2 Convex / L3 of Curve. The main question that arises with this project is whether there is anything to gain by going down to this level of depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concretely, Bent works like Convex works for Curve: Bent allows you to stake Curve LP tokens: they are then staked in Convex (by Bent), and you benefit from an additional return paid with their native token - BENT, in exchange for fees collected by Bent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/bentfinance-fees.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Bentfinance-fees&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you may notice, the fee structure is almost identical to Convex. Finally, just as Convex created its own representation of CRV (cvxCRV), Bent creates its representation of CVX, the bentCVX. This can also be locked (weBENT) exactly like CVX-&amp;gt;vlCVX, for 8 weeks to get an additional yield corresponding to the bribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every two weeks (Curve gauge round), weBENT holders vote on Snapshot to allocate their voting capacity on the gauges of their choice. The votes of the weBENT holders are echoed via the CVX owned by BentFinance, themselves echoed in CRV vote by Convex: two levels of depth!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/bentCVX-lock.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bentCVX-lock.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-relevant-abstraction&#34;&gt;A relevant abstraction?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I said when discussing Bent, the question here is not whether the model is relevant since Convex is living proof of that. Nevertheless, Convex is not a zero-sum game compared to Curve, since the protocol has brought new features that did not exist with just Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farm with LP Curve optimized, without having veCRV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Liquid Locking&amp;rdquo; (⚠ cvxCRV/CRV exchange rate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And the third point which is a bit of a consequence of the other two: Convex is now the biggest veCRV owner, and can therefore offer the bribe service (via Votium) with the most potential while being the most convenient (delegation, no need to claim every week, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I detail the contributions of Convex, it is obviously to ask the question: what does Bent bring &lt;strong&gt;functionally&lt;/strong&gt; compared to Convex?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farming option with LP Curve without owning a veCRV even more optimized than Convex, but all the outperformance comes from the BENT emissions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A less restrictive locking of CVX than direct locking via vlCVX (8 weeks at Bent, 16 weeks + 7 days at Convex)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, the third element is still missing to make Bent an interesting option, a mechanism that would create a real added value compared to Curve/Convex, in addition to farm optimization and a reduction of constraints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I would be dishonest if I did not add one last point: the security and durability of the protocol. Indeed, Bent Finance has been attacked by an insider in December 2021 for several weeks. The attack was made possible by the fact that at that time, Bent&amp;rsquo;s contracts were not secured by a multisig: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://halborn.com/explained-the-bent-finance-hack-december-2021/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more information here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conic-finance-cnc--collective-liquidity-management-on-curveconvex&#34;&gt;Conic Finance (CNC) 🚧: collective liquidity management on Curve/Convex.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 reports a protocol not yet launched&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to Bent, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ConicFinance&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Conic&lt;/a&gt; offers an additional abstraction from Curve LPs staked on Convex. However I think that this time the model has relevance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conic introduces the concept of &amp;ldquo;omnipools&amp;rdquo;, which would simplify the management for Curve LPs by going back to the primitive level: here, it is directly the tokens that are deposited (e.g. USDC or DAI). The Conic omnipools will then distribute the tokens on different LP Curve positions which are then staked on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The depositors receive their CRV, CVX and CNC tokens from Conic. In a similar way to CVX, the CNC can be &amp;ldquo;vote locked&amp;rdquo; to :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in bi-weekly gauge votes that determine the distribution of Curve pools by assets accepted on Conic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote on the whitelist and blacklist of accepted Curve pools (and thus eligible for gauges)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in the vote to decide which assets are supported on Conic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And any other governance decisions, including the potential activation of fees for the service (initially there will be none).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conic&amp;rsquo;s approach thus seems relevant and could be described as pooled asset management. It is a model reminiscent of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokemak.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Tokemak&lt;/a&gt; and goes one step further than Curve/Convex which remains at the level of governance determination of incitations. Here, governance votes will result in the actual movement of assets between different Curve pools. If the protocol manages to attract sufficient liquidity, it could become a major player in the Curve Wars, potentially with its own bribe system in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/conic-finance-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;conic-finance-en&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project has just been unveiled and the approach being considered for launch is also interesting. Part of the CNC supply will be airdropped to vlCVX owners. For the rest, it will be distributed with community fundraising, liquidity mining on CNC/ETH and to depositors on Conic. To learn more, there is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ConicFinance/conic-finance-pre-launch-announcement-7b9f485f59f2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;only one article available for now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;borrowing-services-with-lp-curveconvex-tokens-as-collateral&#34;&gt;Borrowing services with LP Curve/Convex tokens as collateral
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At this point, you may start to get saturated just by mentioning a new potential wrapper on CRV, CVX or even cvxCRV: this is probably normal. Most of the protocols involved in the Curve Wars develop synergies directly at the token level, which remains the most direct. But we should not forget two other important types of actors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocols offering a synergistic service with the Curve/Convex LP, such as using it as collateral.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocols / DAOs that have large amounts of CVX and CRV and can use them to develop a strategic position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before going to the whales and their strategies, I offer you two last analyses of protocols that allow you to borrow from an LP Curve position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lendflare-lft&#34;&gt;Lendflare (LFT)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lendflare.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lendflare&lt;/a&gt; allows Curve LPs to borrow from their position an asset that follows the same peg, for example a DAI borrow with the LP 3pool token (USDC/DAI/USDT) as collateral. This limitation avoids liquidations due to price changes between assets: with Lendflare as long as a borrower pays back his debt on or before the due date he is not liquidated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The critical point, as with any money market, is to attract enough depositors to make borrowing as cheap as possible and therefore competitive. Lendflare follows the logic of Curve&amp;rsquo;s boosts: users who bring in cash (USDC, DAI, ETH or wBTC) to facilitate borrowing are rewarded with the LFT token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like on Curve, here they can also benefit from a multiplier of up to 2.5x by locking in a quantity of LFT (veLFT) proportional to the deposit. There is even a very dense diagram that summarizes everything and will make you appreciate the special care I put into my home-made infographics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/lendflare.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;LendFlare&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol is still in the midst of deployment, although the borrowing functionality is already available. An initial sale (IDO) of the LFT token is underway, and an airdrop is also being discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curvance-cve-&#34;&gt;Curvance (CVE) 🚧
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curvance tackles the same problem but with a different approach. Here the protocol is not interested in Curve LPs as collateral, but rather &amp;ldquo;wrapped assets&amp;rdquo; in general like cvxCRV, bveCVX (Badger) or yvBOOST (Yearn). To enable the borrowing of stablecoins with these assets as collateral, they plan to isolate the risk by relying on Fuse pools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the CVE token will be distributed to liquidity providers and a veCVE-like system is envisioned with a new subtlety: yet another wrap, a liquid version of the veCVE, the cveCVE that gives access to the veCVE&amp;rsquo;s yield but delegates governance capabilities to the DAO. Again, boosts, gauges, and even potentially bribes are envisioned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the curious, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.curvance.com/cve/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;documentation is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;daos-whales-in-cvx&#34;&gt;DAOs whales in CVX
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, to finish this overview of the Curve/Convex ecosystem, we should not forget to look directly at the tokens - and in particular the DAOs that have large amounts of CRV or CVX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For CRV, there is not yet a clear dashboard summarizing the situation to my knowledge. For CVX on the other hand, there is a site for that: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Daocvx.com&#34; &gt;daocvx.com&lt;/a&gt;. The protocols we will detail now do not have any synergy built natively with Curve or Convex, but they have a lot of CVX and use them to improve their competitive position in the CRV war.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/daocvx.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;daocvx.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you dig through the list on your own, we&amp;rsquo;ll just detail two: Frax and Badger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frax-finance-dominating-the-curve-gauge-game&#34;&gt;Frax Finance: Dominating the Curve Gauge Game
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frax has a long-standing strategy of dominating the Curve Gauge game to help drive FRAX adoption. It was one of the first DAOs to gain a consistent position in CVX; it is now the DAO with the &lt;strong&gt;largest position with over 2.1M CVX&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frax is also known to be the most aggressive project with bribes and frequently offers the largest Votium bribe for its FRAX/3crv pool. In the last round (14), Frax&amp;rsquo;s bribe was about &lt;strong&gt;40% of the total value of all bribes&lt;/strong&gt; paid in that round ($6.5M / $16.2).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason Frax can afford to be so aggressive is that their vlCVX position reduces the effective cost of these bribes: thanks to their own votes, the protocol is able to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/tx/0x090777069299e6e292363c6131b5cc5b463d598a7f89d3c7207148c0497587f8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;recover&lt;/a&gt; a significant portion of the FXS used in each round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this strategy, the FRAX/3CRV pool is able to &lt;strong&gt;maintain a CRV issuance rate almost five times higher than the 3pool, for a similar total liquidity&lt;/strong&gt; (3pool: $3.3B, FRAX: $2.7B).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;badger-a-small-corner-for-bitcoin&#34;&gt;Badger: a small corner for Bitcoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning, Badger has focused on optimizing farming with BTC on Ethereum. Initially, before Convex, Badger worked closely with Yearn, but with the launch of Convex and its rapid dominance, Badge&amp;rsquo;s position has evolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Frax, Badger did not buy its CVX. Instead, Badger is developing a model similar to Convex&amp;rsquo;s to accumulate CRV under control; the bveCVX vault. It offers a similar return to direct locking on Convex, but includes itself in the Badger ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the bveCVX scales contribute to Badger&amp;rsquo;s internal boost system that is effective on most vaults. In addition, in each round the BadgerDAO uses the corresponding bveCVX voting power to support the Curve pools supported in Badger, which are essentially pools that involve one or more variants of wBTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/curve-wars-l2/bvecvx.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bvecvx.png&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than acquiring its position in CVX, Badger is able to obtain control of CVX tokens thanks to incentives - so it&amp;rsquo;s a sort of CVX rental. There is also a Curve bveCVX/CVX pool to allow early exit from the vault. There are now almost 1.7M CVX in the vault, so the strategy has proven itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-daos&#34;&gt;Other DAOs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I focused on two projects that develop two very distinct strategies to accumulate CVX and weigh in on the Curve Wars. As you can see on the graph above, there are many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a protocol develops a substantial position on CVX (say &amp;gt;300K CVX), it benefits directly from its tokens, especially in terms of liquidity. Nevertheless it doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there: large CVX owners are in a strategic position and will also be courted very soon for different partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can already see the mechanics at work, with the discussion around a potential 4pool (USDC/USDT/FRAX/UST), made possible thanks to the combined influences of Frax, Luna, Redacted and Olympus. The CVX protocols-whales thus become interfaces for the Curve Wars, it remains to be seen who will be able to make them the best offer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>⚔ CRV wars: understanding the race to accumulate power to influence Curve Finance protocol</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/crv-wars/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/crv-wars/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/curve-wars-cover-tokenbrice.png" alt="Featured image of post ⚔ CRV wars: understanding the race to accumulate power to influence Curve Finance protocol" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the early days of Curve Finance and the launch of the CRV token, we have been waiting, contemplating and assuming what the CRV war could bring. Now, with the launch of Convex, then Bribe.crv and finally Votium, everything is accelerating: VeCRV votes can now be bought! So let&amp;rsquo;s see how this impacts Curve and DeFi as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first glance, the question is quite simple and straightforward:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve is the largest decentralized DeFi exchange in terms of total value deposited.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CRV token provides access to 1/ a share of the fees collected 2/ &lt;strong&gt;a voting power to influence the issuance of future CRVs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;=&amp;gt; Having control over a large CRV voting power makes it &lt;strong&gt;much easier to develop a Curve pool&lt;/strong&gt;, since it offers the possibility to vote for large CRV returns on the pool in question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, as often in DeFi, everything is not so simple and the devil is in the details. To understand the stakes of the CRV war, you need to have &lt;strong&gt;a good understanding of the different tools built on it&lt;/strong&gt;. This will allow you to judge the relevance of the strategies deployed by the different projects that seek to influence Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;convex-and-the-vecrv-separation&#34;&gt;Convex and the VeCRV separation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before analyzing the battlefields - i.e. the different tools used in this CRV war - we need to look more deeply at one in particular: Convex. I&amp;rsquo;ve already talked about it on this blog, explaining &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/defi-flywheel.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the flywheel dimension of Convex with the CvxCRV&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactions of Convex with Curve go far beyond the CvxCRV, which is only one element.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, &lt;strong&gt;one could describe Convex as a separation between governance and returns on VeCRV&lt;/strong&gt; by amplifying each of the elements on a separate token. Let me explain:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cvxcrv--vecrv-yield&#34;&gt;CvxCRV = VeCRV-yield++
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CvxCRV corresponds to a VeCRV owned by Convex. They are locked in forever, but the liquidity available on CvxCRV/CRV allows depositors to close out their position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In terms of governance, CvxCRV loses all its capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; : VeCRV owner can vote on gauges (CRV issue) and governance votes. A CvxCRV owner has no other benefit than the return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, &lt;strong&gt;the return is amplified compared to a simple possession of VeCRV&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return in 3pool token - the share of fees collected on Curve - exactly like VeCRV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return in CRV (10% of all CRV farmed by Convex shared between all CvxCRV stakers)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Virtually the same yield in CVX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potential airdrops like Ellipsis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CvxCRV corresponds to a simple compromise compared to VeCRV: governance capabilities are lost (-&amp;gt; vlCVX) but in return the performance is greatly amplified and diversified.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vlcvx--vecrv-gov&#34;&gt;vlCVX = VeCRV-gov++
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the other end of the spectrum, Convex offers another interesting abstraction from Curve. It is its native CVX token. Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;each CVX corresponds to a VeCRV&lt;/strong&gt; voting capability (which comes from CvxCRV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mobilize it, the depositor must &amp;ldquo;vote lock&amp;rdquo; his CVX in vlCVX. They are locked for 16 weeks + 3 days and so provide access to governance capacity. Currently, vlCVX is by far the most economically efficient way to accrue Curve voting capacity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Price
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Voting power
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;VeCRV-vote/$
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Commitment
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;VeCRV
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;$2.42
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;1 veCRV
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;0.41
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4 years
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;vlCVX
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;$8.2
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;12,75 VeCRV
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;1.55
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;16 weeks + 3 days
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the increased profitability of CVX to influence Curve, the commitment is also less than on VeCRV. For the comparison table, I assumed a 4-year lock on CRV. The difference is even more in favor of vlCVX for shorter commitments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vlCVX does have one drawback: after the initial 16 weeks of lock-in, penalties are applied to depositors if the tokens remain inactive for more than 4 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to further analyze the returns offered by the delegation of CVX and the associated vote buying, feel free to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@portiadog/convex-finance-1cc6c9c1c733&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read this article&lt;/a&gt; which offers more detailed calculations :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/bribes-rewards.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bribes-rewards&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bribes-a-not-so-clean-separation&#34;&gt;Bribes: a not so clean separation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The situation was clear, but it did not remain so for long. Indeed, it should first be noted that vlCVX is not without returns: &lt;strong&gt;vlCVX owners share 6% of all CRVs farmed by Convex, in the form of CvxCRV&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, this is potentially not the only return for which vlCVX owners are eligible. Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;governance capacity can also offer a substantial return via bribe mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt; (vote buying).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different projects offer incentives for voting on the gauge of a given Pool Curve. For example, Alchemix offers rewards in ALCX, its native token, which can be claimed each week by all those who used their VeCRV to vote to increase the CRV allocation of the AlUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the long run, it is not impossible that the initial separation planned by Convex is not the most honest. Currently, the yield on cvxCRV is about 60% while it is only 15% on CVX. Nevertheless, &lt;strong&gt;when you add the bribes into the equation, it is not impossible that the yield on vlCVX is much higher than on cvxCRV.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-battlefields&#34;&gt;The battlefields
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Bribes&amp;rdquo; services are an essential part of the Curve governance equation. However, before digging into them, we need to recall the basic path (veCRV) that defines the framework for all its variants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VeCRV is obtained by locking CRV for up to 4 years. The longer the lock, the closer the VeCRV/CRV ratio is to 1. &lt;strong&gt;The lock gradually depletes over time as does the voting capacity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why vaults built on VeCRV operate on a 4-year perpetual locking logic: in order to preserve a voting capacity that is always as close to the maximum possible, &lt;strong&gt;they &amp;ldquo;refresh&amp;rdquo; the locking frequently.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/vecrv-ecosystem-tokenbrice.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;vecrv-ecosystem-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bribe-v0--direct-incentive-on-pools&#34;&gt;Bribe v0 : direct incentive on pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we talk about bribes, it is worth remembering there is a primitive form that has been available since the early days of Curve: additional incentives (on top of CRVs) for liquidity providers. Synthetix pioneered this with the SNX liquidity mining program on the sUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Direct incentives can be combined with bribes, and are even recommended. We will see below how MIM, for example, obtained much more activity by sharing its budget between incentives and bribes (after an initial phase without bribes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bribecrv-by-cronje-with-vecrv&#34;&gt;Bribe.crv by Cronje [with veCRV]
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the &amp;ldquo;bribes&amp;rdquo; are purchases of VeCRV votes. They are paid by the week, generally on Friday (the day the votes are taken into account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just as there are several systems for interacting with VeCRV, there are also several mechanisms for bribes. So we start with the one that was available first: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://bribe.crv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://bribe.crv.finance/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic unit is the VeCRV. Bribe.crv is a simple interface that summarizes the different offers and allows to collect its bribes. Voting is done directly on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a somewhat timid start, the service is being used more and more and many projects are now proposing bribes. The returns in the first few weeks have been excellent, it remains to be seen if they will last. For example, I got &lt;strong&gt;about 10% return on my VeCRV (/ current price) in 5 weeks&lt;/strong&gt; by voting for the MIM pool and receiving SPELL tokens in bribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll come back to the results below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;votium-with-vlcvx&#34;&gt;Votium [with vlCVX]
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The alternative available is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://votium.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Votium&lt;/a&gt;. Here, the basic unit is the vlCVX, so the two services are not competitors but complementary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Votium is more recent so the available bribes are more limited. On the other hand, &lt;strong&gt;Votium already controls an impressive voting power: about 8M CVX or more than 102M VeCRV&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system is potentially more passive than with bribe.crv since depositors can delegate to Votium who will take care of voting each week for them and collect the corresponding bribes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with an active delegation, a depositor can at any time take back control and vote for a given pool, directly on snapshot (-&amp;gt; no gas cost). The system is therefore more flexible than bribe.crv in this respect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other services to handle bribes are also in development with a release in the near future. So far the bribe game has focused mainly on CRV, but &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.paladin.vote/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Paladin&lt;/a&gt;, for example, intends to offer a similar mechanism with other protocols as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;putting-it-into-practice-tactics-and-results&#34;&gt;Putting it into practice: tactics and results
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conceptual bases are a bit heavy on this subject, but it is essential to understand them. To make it more explicit, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the practical side with concrete examples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-spellmim-case&#34;&gt;The Spell/MIM case
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://abracadabra.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abracadabra&lt;/a&gt; is a Maker service. Various assets are accepted as collateral, including productive assets such as xSUSHI or cvx3pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as Maker produces DAI, Abracadabra produces a stablecoin (on the dollar) called MIM. The liquidity available on MIM, as well as the opportunity for returns, is therefore a key factor in the platform&amp;rsquo;s success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why Abracadabra has progressively gone through all forms of direct or indirect bribes on Curve :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It started with a SPELL incentive (governance token) on the Curve/MIM pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When bribe.crv arrived, &lt;strong&gt;a portion of that incentive was reallocated to bribe&lt;/strong&gt; - thus distributed to veCRV owners who vote for the MIM gauge.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now, with the arrival of vlCVX, the team is considering reallocating the budget through this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few weeks, the MIM pool has exploded on Curve, at all levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV yields were really good in some weeks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This has attracted liquidity and volume, slightly reducing the yield but increasing the ability to boost the pool&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a result of this momentum, MIM is now the fifth largest pool curve in terms of volume, with a nice volume/TVL ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/crv-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the pool is now well balanced and rather dense (&amp;gt; $700M total liquidity).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example of Abracadabra is extremely instructive, as it demonstrates the relevance of the abstractions built on VeCRV: &lt;strong&gt;without increasing its total budget, Abracadabra has been able to attract much more liquidity than at the time of the simple direct incentive in SPELL.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You therefore understand that DeFi projects that take advantage of the veCRV, cvxCRV and vlCVX mechanisms have an undeniable advantage (&lt;strong&gt;economic AND political&lt;/strong&gt;) over those who have not yet grasped all their subtleties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sdvecrv-vs-cvxcrv&#34;&gt;sdveCRV VS cvxCRV
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;I now consider understanding Curve and the ability to effectively influence its governance to be an essential and required capability in most DeFi projects, especially for stablecoin projects.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No need to take my word for it though, let&amp;rsquo;s compare in practice two approaches implemented by projects with similar issues: liquidity strategies on cvxCRV (from Convex) and sdveCRV (from StakeDAO) - two abstractions built on veCRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the situations are similar, there are some important differences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start by recalling that Convex controls more than 30 times the amount of CRV controlled by Stake (102M vs 3M).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Furthermore, sdveCRV has serious problems with its peg: 1 sdveCRV ~= 0.5 CRV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/sdvecrv-peg.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sdvecrv-peg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sdvecrv-liquidity-plan-total-misunderstanding-and-abject-failure&#34;&gt;sdveCRV liquidity plan: total misunderstanding and abject failure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the analysis. Initially the liquidity of sdveCRV was against ETH just like Yearn. Since Convex, the Stake team is trying to react to make sdveCRV more attractive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the team clearly did not take the time to analyze the situation and rushed into what turned out to be &lt;strong&gt;one of the biggest governance failures ever seen on Curve&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After creating an anemic sdveCRV/CRV pool via the Curve Factory, a vote was taken to add the gauge control (= CRV incentives). Not only was &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dao.curve.fi/vote/ownership/83&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the vote overwhelmingly rejected&lt;/a&gt; but also &lt;strong&gt;the sdveCRV pool is set up in an aberrant and absolutely dangerous way for depositors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the factor A (amplification parameter) of the pool is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/factory/34&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;set to 200&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; a correct value for assets that follow the same peg, but &lt;strong&gt;delusional if one asset is worth twice the other&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/sdvecrv-mim-crv-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sdvecrv-mim-crv-pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To give you an idea, even the aforementioned absolutely massive MIM pool (7000x the liquidity of the sdveCRV pool) has not yet reached 200 of A factor (119 currently, increasing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, not only did Stake fail to solve its liquidity problem on sdveCRV, but &lt;strong&gt;such a course of events clearly raises the question of the Stake team&amp;rsquo;s understanding of the intricacies of Curve/Convex&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get sdveCRV back to peg and develop its liquidity, they will need a lot of effort, in order:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review the pool parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct incentives in SDT on the pool?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these steps are completed, the team would then have a chance to get the CRV gauge on this pool, but not before. So the current situation looks like a costly dead end: &lt;strong&gt;no way out unless the SDT board is heated (even more)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cvxcrv-liquidity-plan-immediate-take-off&#34;&gt;cvxCRV liquidity plan: immediate take-off
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the contrary, the liquidity plan on cvxCRV demonstrates how effective the process can be. Initially (and still today), the main pool for cvxCRV is on Sushiswap, against CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This situation does not really make sense: &lt;strong&gt;Sushi is far from optimal for optimizing liquidity across assets that follow the same peg&lt;/strong&gt;. So when Curve launched factory pools (V2), the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/factory/22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cvxCRV/CRV pool&lt;/a&gt; was one of the first to emerge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note here the A Factor at 50 - while cvxCRV holds its peg much better than sdveCRV&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/crv-wars/cvxcrv-pool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;cvxcrv-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without any incentive from Convex or Curve, the pool has already seen significant volume flow through DEX aggregators like Paraswap. Soon, there was a vote to add the CRV gauge which passed - and this pool is now farmable directly through Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pool remains slightly unbalanced (there is so much to do with CRVs, which are becoming increasingly rare&amp;hellip;) but it already brings a competitive alternative to the SLP cvxCRV/CRV pool with still a fraction of its liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article has helped you grasp the intricacies of the extended veCRV ecosystem and their implications for the CRV battle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before concluding, I would like to remind you that as usual the alpha is in the nooks and crannies. If you have understood this article, feel free to export the liquidity strategy analysis to other projects: I am sure it will be instructive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tell you often, but it will never be enough: not only Curve is the most important DEX in DeFi but it is also &lt;strong&gt;the most advanced protocol in terms of governance and tokenomics by far compared to anything else&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if you have no interest in Curve/Convex, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand these protocols in order to properly consider what&amp;rsquo;s going on in DeFi&amp;hellip; Hopefully this article will help you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
