<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Curve on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/curve/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Curve on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/curve/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Behind the scene of the decentralization theater: a study of the inalterability of DeFi protocols</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/unstoppable-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/unstoppable-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/unstoppable-defi-tokenbrice-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Behind the scene of the decentralization theater: a study of the inalterability of DeFi protocols" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decentralized finance has allowed the emergence of autonomous protocols whose functionalities are ensured by smart contracts that are sometimes immutable. It enables individuals from all over the world to use financial services that are at the same time sovereign, accessible, and more efficient and resilient than those available in traditional finance. It&amp;rsquo;s the lovely story that newcomers are told to lull them to sleep: the reality is much more nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;a handful of protocols fit this reality,&lt;/strong&gt; but most are far from being up to par. When the bulls are out, interest in the resilience of the protocols is generally shallow: the only thing that matters is price appreciation. But the bears have made a comeback, and thankfully it means a renewed interest in these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent implosion of the Luna ecosystem and its associated stablecoin, UST, will hopefully serve as a wake-up call for some. It was, unfortunately, a &lt;strong&gt;perfectly avoidable&lt;/strong&gt; disaster. The model used for this stablecoin and its flaws were already known, with many previous instances covered on this blog: BAC, MIC, ESD, DSD, etc. (at the application level on Ethereum rather than the protocol level, but with the same fundamental problems). They all had the same end: an endless spiral that brought them closer to absolute 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of this event, many investors have become aware that not all stablecoins are created equal and seek to learn more about the resilience of the many stablecoins available on the market and the robustness of different DeFi protocols in general. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;m seizing this exceptional moment to discuss this essential topic for the sustainability of DeFi; it has been a passion of mine for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, last year I already proposed to you an exhaustive analysis of the risks incurred on the borrowing services in DeFi and how to evaluate them. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is still relevant and a highly recommended read for any informed investor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough with the introduction. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the point and define the term &amp;ldquo;unstoppable&amp;rdquo; and what it implies in concrete terms at a protocol level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-unstoppable-defi-protocol&#34;&gt;What is an unstoppable DeFi protocol?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, we can call &lt;strong&gt;a DeFi protocol unstoppable &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when its essential functions are provided by smart contracts that are not modifiable, and it does not require external intervention to subsist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this relatively straightforward definition, I must add many notes and clarifications to cover the diversity of DeFi protocols and their use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-third-party-protocol-dependencies&#34;&gt;⚠️ Third-party protocol dependencies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, it is infrequent that a protocol does everything by itself. More often than not, a given protocol relies on various third-party protocols. Of course, the most common and well-known case is the oracle - the source of prices for assets - a critical component for borrowing services in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dependence-on-oracles-like-chainlink&#34;&gt;Dependence on oracles like ChainLink
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this regard, the most widely used oracle is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/chainlink-oracles/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ChainLink&lt;/a&gt;. Although technically robust, the industry recently got a reminder, thanks to Chris Blec and a few other actors concerned about the resilience of the service: ChainLink&amp;rsquo;s oracles are susceptible to manipulation or censorship. The riskiest attack vector seems to be &lt;strong&gt;the 3/20 multisig&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows the price source for a given asset to be changed immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concretely, if three people synchronize among these 20, they could change the ETH/USD oracle, for example, for an in-house oracle that returns a price of $1, and almost all DeFi loans would be liquidated in the process. However, it seems rather unlikely that people on or close to the ChainLink team would carry out such an attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant risk seems to be an &lt;strong&gt;attack by an external actor&lt;/strong&gt; who would like to harm the whole of DeFi. Indeed, with such a permissive multisig, it would be &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to identify three or more members of this multisig, kidnap them and threaten them to change a price source of ChainLink. It is the famous &amp;ldquo;🔧 wrench attack.&amp;rdquo; No matter how secure the smart contracts are, if they are administered by a multisig, they are vulnerable to this type of attack that goes through the people behind the protocols rather than the code directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem here is not the existence of this multisig, which is necessary to update and improve the services that ChainLink provides, but its setting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3/20 is extraordinarily permissive&lt;/strong&gt; and riskier from a 🔧 wrench attack point of view than 3/6, for example (which would have fewer potential targets to perform the attack). A more reasonable number aligned with what is usually done for 20 signers in total would be something between 8 and 12 signers required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No timelock&lt;/strong&gt;: so changes are immediate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚠️ Update - May 27&lt;/strong&gt;: On May 23rd (5 days after the publication of this article), the Multisig setup has been updated to a 4/9, which makes a 🔧 wrench attack harder to perform; there is still no timelock&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dependence-on-other-protocols-that-are-less-resilient-than-the-base-protocol&#34;&gt;Dependence on other protocols that are less resilient than the base protocol
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the fascinating elements in DeFi is &lt;strong&gt;composability&lt;/strong&gt;: protocols integrate and use each other. While this allows for the emergence of synergies and innovative use cases, it also comes with additional risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail, as we will come back to it later, we will take as an example PoolTogether, one of the most resilient protocols of the DeFi and quasi-unstoppable. The quasi comes from its external dependencies and, more precisely, the sources of yields used: Compound or Aave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the smart contracts of PoolTogether are immutable except for the part that manages the price allocation (v4). Still, the funds are deployed in protocols powered by smart contracts that can be altered (such as adding a new collateral, a necessary feature but also a potential attack vector&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The general rule is that a protocol is as resilient as the weakest link in its composability chain&lt;/strong&gt;. This rule is not absolute, as it is still possible to mitigate or contain the exposure taken with integrations, for example, by implementing redundancy, as we will see below in the detailed assesments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-access-to-protocols-the-question-of-websites-front-end&#34;&gt;⚠️ Access to protocols: the question of websites (front-end)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this topic, there are two key questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the access point to the protocol (= the website/front-end) resilient / can it be censored, for example, by a state actor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the site secure? Can a malicious actor attack it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-of-censorship-of-the-front-end&#34;&gt;Risk of censorship of the front-end
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, I must start by reminding you of a fundamental point: a DeFi service exists thanks to a set of smart contracts. It is &lt;strong&gt;entirely possible to interact with any DeFi service by going directly through the contracts&lt;/strong&gt; - and thus, even if their site were to be inaccessible. Of course, not all DeFi users have the technical skills required to interact with smart contracts directly, which is why &lt;strong&gt;the front-end issue remains essential&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, protocols that maximize their resilience need to think about it. Two main approaches are possible and can be combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a protocol can have &lt;strong&gt;multiple access points&lt;/strong&gt; that allow access to its service: if one of them were inaccessible, others would remain online, thus causing only minor inconvenience to the service users. For example, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt; can be used through the main app.aave.com site, but also through tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://instadapp.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;InstaDapp&lt;/a&gt; and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, most of these sites are still hosted by &lt;strong&gt;centralized services&lt;/strong&gt; that could all be censored simultaneously: it&amp;rsquo;s more work, but it&amp;rsquo;s technically possible. To overcome this limitation, another option is available: having one or more &lt;strong&gt;sites hosted via a decentralized solution like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in terms of front-end resilience, the most original, elegant, and efficient approach deployed to date is probably the one of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; protocol. Indeed, Liquity does not have an official website for its application deployed and managed directly by the team. Instead, the team provides &lt;strong&gt;a kit to deploy a front-end&lt;/strong&gt; of Liquity, usable by all. Because of this approach, the project now has &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/frontend&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a myriad of different sites to use its service&lt;/a&gt;, some of which are hosted on IPFS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/liquity-frontend.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;some-liquity-frontends&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;security-risks-of-front-end&#34;&gt;Security risks of front-end
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, one should not forget that a front-end remains a website. Even if it is not censored, &lt;strong&gt;it may be susceptible to attacks&lt;/strong&gt; of varying degrees of severity: the websites of the decentralized exchange SpiritSwap and QuickSwap, for example, have recently &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/QuickswapDEX/status/1525306033400188928?s=20&amp;amp;t=UKpcM2Gu6nZ9Kgl65kmp3w&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;suffered from such a scenario&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack vector is linked to the service&amp;rsquo;s domain name manager (GoDaddy). Other types of attacks are possible: for example, code injections through a third-party service that the site integrates, as we recently saw on EtherScan, as an advertising tracker they use was compromised (CoinZilla).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ℹ-limitations-of-unstoppable-protocols&#34;&gt;ℹ️ Limitations of unstoppable protocols
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unstoppable protocols cannot cover all use cases. Indeed, depending on the complexity of a protocol, it is sometimes impossible to avoid any dependency on another protocol that is itself at least partially censurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, one must keep in mind the counterpart that comes with the immutability of the smart contracts of unstoppable protocols: &lt;strong&gt;an update of these is technically impossible&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, when an unstoppable protocol needs to evolve, there is only one possible path: deploy a new version of the protocol (with its new set of immutable contracts) and encourage the &lt;strong&gt;migration&lt;/strong&gt; of its users to it. This is, for example, what Uniswap has done twice, with the migration to version 2 in May 2020 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and then again one year later with the release of Uniswap v3 in May 2021 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/UNIv2-migration-tool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;UNIv2-migration-tool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the differences between the versions, the protocol may also offer a tool to facilitate migration, as was the case for UNIv1⇒UNIv2. However, it was impossible for UNIv2⇒UNIv3 mainly because of the introduction of liquidity concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be exhaustive on the cost/benefit analysis of immutable contracts, don&amp;rsquo;t forget that they make 🔧 wrench attacks impossible and may also be of interest from a legal perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-spectrum-of-resilience&#34;&gt;The Spectrum of Resilience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve established the definition of &amp;ldquo;unstoppable&amp;rdquo; with all the necessary precisions, I propose to move directly to the analysis. Before digging into the relevant protocols, let me offer you a spectrum that highlights different levels of resilience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/resilience-spectrum-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-spectrum-resilience-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailing centralized or &amp;ldquo;DINO&amp;rdquo; (Decentralized in Name Only) protocols, decentralized in name only, is not very insightful, so I will let you dig for yourself. Instead, let&amp;rsquo;s look at protocols on the more exciting end of the spectrum: to the right of MakerDAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis-of-the-most-resilient-dex&#34;&gt;Analysis of the most resilient DEX
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we get to the resilience of Uniswap and Curve, we need to recall a few crucial things about decentralized exchanges. Specifically, they have two types of users who assume pretty different levels of risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who exchange tokens through the DEX. These users bear the risks linked to the DEX smart contracts for the time of the swap only (as well as those related to unlimited &amp;ldquo;approve&amp;rdquo; if the DEX contract is compromised and is not immutable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity providers are exposed as long as their position is maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Uniswap as on Curve, &lt;strong&gt;the contracts relating to the two situations are immutable&lt;/strong&gt;. It is technically impossible to envisage a &amp;ldquo;rug&amp;rdquo; of the liquidity providers, which is not the case for all DEXs: such an attack was possible on SushiSwap once because of their migration function. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that DEXs relying on an Automated Market Maker such as Uniswap or Curve do &lt;strong&gt;not need an oracle to work&lt;/strong&gt;, which significantly reduces their dependency on potentially censorable third-party services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, even if the contracts are immutable, the risk is not zero for the liquidity providers who assume all the risks related to the tokens involved in the pair. The general rule here is similar to that of the composability chain: &lt;strong&gt;a given LP position is as risky as its most dangerous token&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The front-end issue for DEX is less critical since many access points exist. The most competent users go through a decentralized exchange aggregator, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;uniswap&#34;&gt;Uniswap
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contracts core functions are completely immutable on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt; v1, v2 and v3. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/uniswap-v2/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2&lt;/a&gt; release markededthe introduction of an administrative fee the governance can decided to turn on&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (= to the protocol), as already seen on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the case is straightforward. If there is indeed a governance, the good news (less for UNI holders) is that what it can do is very limited. &lt;strong&gt;No seizure or migration of funds is possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Apart from the fee, it manages matters such as deploying Uniswap on a new chain, adding a new tier of fees (1bps for stablecoins), or using the protocol&amp;rsquo;s treasury &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, for example, to fund liquidity mining campaigns or to distribute UNI to friendly people who ask for it, without any limit or accounting &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curve-finance&#34;&gt;Curve Finance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve Finance&lt;/a&gt; is another example of resilient DEX with an equally exciting approach. Again, the essential functions are provided by immutable contracts. Nevertheless, Curve also has an &amp;ldquo;Emergency DAO&amp;rdquo; whose members are elected by the governance. This Emergency DAO can &amp;ldquo;kill&amp;rdquo; a pool (only if pools that are younger than 2 months old and not factory pools): all functions except withdrawal are disabled. It prevents further loss of funds if a problem emerges with Curve&amp;rsquo;s contracts. The Emergency DAO can also kill a gauge - that is the reward contract handling CRV (and potentially other token) rewards. Killed gauges can then be resurrected by the main DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Uniswap, Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance is centered around the management of CRV token issuance and management. However, the model is much more refined here; I invite you to read my previous articles on the subject to better understand it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV War: Understanding the race to accumulate the ability to influence the Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2022/crv-wars-l2.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ Advanced CRV Wars: Analysis of Protocols Built on Curve and Convex &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Uniswap, participation in Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance requires locking CRV tokens ( ⇒veCRV) for up to four years for those who want to maximize their influence. Thus, it protects the governance from different types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the governance also manages a whitelist of smart contracts authorized to interact with the veCRV contract &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: such decisions are consequential for liquidity providers on Curve and CRV owners in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance is one of the most fascinating to follow in DeFi. To help it make more informed decisions, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://substack.com/profile/66151946-crypto-risk-assessments&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a newsletter offering risk assesments of the various protocols that require a gauge&lt;/a&gt; has been set up. I highly recommend reading it; it&amp;rsquo;s an excellent source for perfecting one&amp;rsquo;s understanding of risk in DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-depth-analysis-of-other-notable-protocols&#34;&gt;In-depth analysis of other notable protocols
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to decentralized exchanges, other types of protocols get as close as possible to the most resilient end of the spectrum. Nevertheless, the use cases of the protocols we will detail now are more complex and cannot be served, to my knowledge, without dependencies on other more or less censorable services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquity&#34;&gt;Liquity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; is a dogged project that aims to create the most resilient borrowing system and stablecoin while maintaining an economically efficient system for borrowers. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into too much detail about this protocol here, I invite you to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read the dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s focus on the points relevant to our topic of the day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquity&amp;rsquo;s code is entirely immutable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquity has no governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nevertheless, like any borrowing service, Liquity depends on an oracle (ETH price in USD). Here, ChainLink is used, but a backup system is also in place. Calculations are made to determine if the data provided by ChainLink is deemed reliable. If it is not, the system automatically switches to a secondary price source as long as it is needed: the Tellor oracle. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, as I mentioned above, Liquity also has an interesting approach to maximizing front-end decentralization.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this approach, Liquity is the most resilient borrowing protocol available on Ethereum, allowing LUSD to sweep the title of the most robust and decentralized stablecoin.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pooltogether&#34;&gt;PoolTogether
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is a fascinating protocol that explores a new concept: &amp;ldquo;no-loss&amp;rdquo;. Concretely, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/pool-together-v5/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is a prize-linked savings account where the player takes no financial risk on his principal: the game relies entirely on the yield produced by the principal. It redistributes it to the different players according to their luck at the draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/pooltogether.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pooltogether&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this protocol, I invite you once again to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/pool-together.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read the dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the resilience of the protocol. Here, the main issue is &lt;strong&gt;the initial source of yield, which is external&lt;/strong&gt;: it comes from services like Aave or Compound, which are not unstoppable. Thus, a PoolTogether player assumes this risk on his entire deposit: the principal and the yield generated (before it is collected and redirected).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this third-party dependency, the PoolTogetger protocol is remarkably resilient. Indeed, on the PoolTogether side, &lt;strong&gt;contracts are as immutable as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically, they are all immutable (so a given pool cannot change its source of yield), except for the prize distribution part, which only affects the yields generated. Indeed, the prize distribution model can change following a governance vote (mainnet) or a multisig operation (Avalanche/Polygon), which is necessary because cross-chain governance is not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point is fascinating and unique in DeFi: PoolTogether is a no-loss prize-linked savings account. This (financial) design principle also manifests itself in smart contracts. A player cannot lose his principal, excluding a problem with Aave/Compound or a critical bug in the PoolTogether contracts. The code itself guarantees this; only the return is potentially at risk. Even if the entire PoolTogether team suffers a 🔧 wrench attack or PoolTogether&amp;rsquo;s governance turns hostile. So &lt;strong&gt;the promise of no loss is upheld at the smart-contract level&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also nuances and differences between V3 and V4 of the protocol as far as risks are concerned. The best thing is to carefully read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.pooltogether.com/security/risks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trustlessfi-&#34;&gt;TrustlessFi 🏗️
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trustless.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trustless&lt;/a&gt; is a protocol that I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated with lately. It&amp;rsquo;s not live yet, but I think the approach has a lot of merits. To describe it very simply, &lt;strong&gt;TrustlessFi is like Liquity and Reflexer having a child together on zkSync&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the goal is, as with Liquity, to create a protocol that will eventually be as unstoppable as possible, and the associated stablecoin (HUE) will inherit this property. Other mechanisms are similar to Liquity, such as ETH as the only collateral, immediate liquidations, or decentralization of the front-end (with a community validation mechanism this time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the governance side, we have here an approach similar to the Reflexer/RAI de-governance plan but more engaging: 4 phases are envisaged, and at each stage, the control of the Foundation and the community decreases making the protocol more and more immutable. These &lt;strong&gt;phases will be implemented in the code of the contracts themselves&lt;/strong&gt;: it is possible to delay the transition to a new phase by 45 days up to three times if necessary, but it is impossible to cancel this transition altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mechanism similar to Maker-MCD&amp;rsquo;s Dai Saving Rate allows participation in the system without necessarily needing to generate debt. HUE owners will be able to stake it to get a return from the interest rates paid by the borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are also some fascinating new features, such as that Troves/CDPs will be tokenized as NFTs, allowing their transfer. Another example is the deployment of HUE liquidity in Uniswap v3 (HUE/ETH), managed by the protocol. At the oracle level, we would also have an unstoppable price source using Uniswap v3, but this undoubtedly comes with increased manipulation risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the approach is going in the right direction. Still, there are many new concepts in this protocol, so it is not easy to anticipate the result once it is available in production for the time being &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-and-last-clarifications&#34;&gt;Conclusion and last clarifications
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope that this definite article can serve as a reference for all those who have essential questions about the resilience of DeFi protocols. As usual, rather than delivering assesments as is, I have tried to detail as much as possible the methodology and reasoning so that you can study for yourself the resilience of any protocol not mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go deeper, I warmly invite you to read an article I published last year, which perfectly complements this one, focused on money markets. It proposes a method of analysis to evaluate the different potential risks they imply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that such a precise analysis of such a critical subject could arouse more or less positive emotions. Please know that, as always, my intention is only &lt;strong&gt;to inform as many DeFians as possible on matters that I consider essential for DeFi in general.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My educational and pedagogical actions in DeFi have no other purpose than maximizing the resilience and relevance of decentralized finance over the long term. I hope that developers or promoters of protocols to the left of my suggested resilience spectrum will also understand and recognize this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 A huge thank you to all the proofreaders and contributors who participated in the development of this article:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proofreading and clarity of expression: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical and factual proofreading: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.radjaidjah.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Taz&lt;/a&gt; from DeFi France, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MTorgin&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MTorgin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention throughout this article the unstoppability of some DeFi protocols: we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the immutability of smart contract code here. The order of transactions on Ethereum can still be manipulated (⇒ MEV), and miners keep an essential role (until the transition to PoS). The contractual unstoppability discussed in this article thus has infrastructural limits.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChainLink provided more info &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.chain.link/docs/using-chainlink-reference-contracts/#updates-to-proxy-and-aggregator-contracts&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;in their documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the multisig contract can be checked &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/0x21f73d42eb58ba49ddb685dc29d3bf5c0f0373ca#readProxyContract&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;directly on EtherScan here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/chainlink-multisig-updated.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;chainlink-multisig-updated&#34;
	
	
&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/analysis-of-xsushis-incident/6335&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Analysis of the incident&lt;/a&gt; on Aave&amp;rsquo;s governance forum.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/blog/launch-uniswap-v2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2 launch announcement&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/blog/uniswap-v3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Announcement of the launch of Uniswap V3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infamous migrator function, also present in many SushiSwap fork. More information on this dreaded feature in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rugdoc.io/education/migrator/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this dedicated Rugdoc article&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.uniswap.org/t/i-think-it-is-necessary-for-uniswap-concurrently-to-turn-on-the-fee-switch-and-liquidity-mining-incentive/15645&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the latest discussions on the subject&lt;/a&gt; on the Uniswap governance forum.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entirely in UNI token, this treasury is quite volatile. Nevertheless, more than 227M UNI is still available today, or about $1.1B. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://openorgs.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenOrgs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the infamous 005 &amp;ldquo;DeFi Education Fund&amp;rdquo; vote; read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.uniswap.org/t/governance-proposal-005-defi-education-fund/12963&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the related topic on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; for more context.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three at present: Yearn Finance (yveCRV), Convex (cvxCRV) and StakeDAO (sdCRV).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/price-oracles-in-liquity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a clear introduction to the oracle management system on Liquity&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/liquity-runs-on-decentralized-frontends&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;on the technical and incentive model for Liquity front-end operators&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already seen, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to have &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2022/tokenbrice-liquity.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;joined the Liquity team very recently&lt;/a&gt;. I mention Liquity in this article because it is a relevant and instructive example of resilient protocol, independent of my professional commitments.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the alpha is for those who dig in and read footnotes carefully as well as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trustlessfi.notion.site/Trustless-4be753d947b040a89a46998eca90b2c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/defi-vs-inflation-tokenbrice-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation is more than ever at the center of discussions and concerns: no one understands much about it, no economist has really anticipated it, but we all have an opinion about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we leave economics and politics aside to focus on what matters for your wallet: in decentralized finance, all kinds of protocols are developed, and a good part of them &lt;strong&gt;provide credible and innovative tools to preserve and develop the purchasing power of a portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;, even when the macroeconomic context is most uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to evaluate strategies involving different assets and protocols, all with the same goal: to preserve and develop the effective purchasing power of a given portfolio. Nevertheless, we have to start with the basics, level 0: what is inflation and why should we, DeFians, care about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover image was made by a generous anonymous contributor and features the majestic &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/valkyre/created&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Valkyr-E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;α-tutorial-understanding-the-impact-of-inflation-on-a-crypto-portfolio&#34;&gt;α/ Tutorial: Understanding the impact of inflation on a crypto portfolio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t venture into the details of inflation for fiat currencies here, but the basic concept is known to anyone familiar with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the term: here is how the INSEE (Institut National de la Statistique et des Études Économiques) defines inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation is the loss of purchasing power of money that results in a general and lasting increase in prices. It must be distinguished from the increase in the cost of living. The loss of value of money is a phenomenon that hits the national economy as a whole (households, businesses, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just remember that, &lt;strong&gt;just like in DeFi where each token is associated with a protocol and potentially even an ecosystem, each fiat currency is also based on an economy as well as a set of rules&lt;/strong&gt; (legal system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-macro-point-of-view-scale--country&#34;&gt;Inflation, macro point of view (scale = country)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation corresponds to the production of new money, the important thing is not so much the quantity of money created, but more &lt;strong&gt;what is done with&lt;/strong&gt;. We all understand this rather well with two caricatural examples at each extreme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country A issues a large amount of money in order to invest massively in its transport infrastructure and its energy supply (= long-term investments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here, inflation can be controlled because the new money issued is used to finance investments that develop the country&amp;rsquo;s economic potential in the long run (-&amp;gt; compensation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country B issues a large amount of money to finance an emergency plan to compensate for the foreseeable consequences of previous pseudo-sanitary measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second scenario, the new money is used to cover a &amp;ldquo;current expense&amp;rdquo; of the government. The personal equivalent would be to go into debt every day to pay for lunch. This is obviously unsustainable in the long run. In this scenario, inflation can only be massive as a large amount of new money is issued, while the economic potential of the country in question stagnates or deteriorates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluating-future-inflation&#34;&gt;Evaluating future inflation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough about the macro, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our scale, with things we know well. Here is the evolution of the M1 money supply on the dollar, this allows us to visualize its &amp;ldquo;marketcap&amp;rdquo; in a way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/USD-m1-supply.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;USD M1 Supply&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we only look at M1 for simplicity but the trend is similar on M2 and M3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested here in the dollar which, although challenged, remains the fiduciary currency that sets the tone. As you can see, the curve has been going vertical since the beginning of the Covid crisis. The curve is now much scarier than the worst shitcoins I have ever seen. Doubt it? Consider the same information, presented in this light:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dollar has been around since 1914. 20% of all dollars in circulation were created in 2020. At the current rate, the total amount of dollars in circulation doubles about every 4-5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare with crypto, many are concerned about inflation / new token issuance on Curve Finance (CRV). The 4 year issuance curve looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/crv-release-schedule.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-release-schedule&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no economist, but I know my shitcoins. The official US inflation figure we are given is 7.5% per year. Like unemployment figures, it&amp;rsquo;s a highly political metric that&amp;rsquo;s hard to really appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7.5% figure may seem high, but it is still low when compared to the unprecedented money creation to deal with Covid. So I expect to see this inflation rise further, or else to be sustained over an extended period of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So inflation is here, at 7.5% minimum for several years at least. Enough with boomers&amp;rsquo; macro, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the range of tools that the DeFi offers us to face it and overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-beating-inflation-with-classic-stablecoin-returns&#34;&gt;I/ Beating inflation with &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; stablecoin returns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first approach is as always the simplest, &lt;strong&gt;the brute force method&lt;/strong&gt;: an inflation of 7.5% means that USD left as is will lose 7.5% of their value over the year. The point here is to find a source of return higher than inflation: the difference between the two is the effective return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inflation at 7.5% on the USD, I think it is prudent to make sure to &lt;strong&gt;reach at least 1.5x this figure in yield&lt;/strong&gt; to really consider yourself inflation-proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the game is simple and the rules fairly easy to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with a position in a given stablecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to make it productive, without assuming IL risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a return that exceeds the inflation figure, once the gas costs have been amortized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-stablecoin-deposit&#34;&gt;Simple stablecoin deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we would aim for &lt;strong&gt;a 10.875% annual return on stablecoin $ at the very least&lt;/strong&gt;. With recent declines and yield compression this is increasingly difficult, but still findable even with a single stablecoin deposit without IL risk. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coindix.com/?kind=stable&amp;amp;sort=-apy&amp;amp;chain=ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Coindix&lt;/a&gt; can help you find the vault of your dreams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/coindix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coindix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, &lt;strong&gt;not all vaults are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;! For example, we see nice returns on Bancor on the screenshot: don&amp;rsquo;t forget to consider the volatility of these returns as well as the fees in gas to deploy the position (a Bancor LP is notoriously more expensive than a Yearn deposit for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention it here only to forget it just as quickly afterwards: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.anchorprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Anchor protocol&lt;/a&gt; also offers you a &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; return close to 20% on UST stablecoin. Such a guaranteed rate does not come, of course, without serious compromises that raise real questions about the sustainability of this whole ecosystem (Terra/Luna).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;provision-of-liquidity--time-commitment&#34;&gt;Provision of liquidity + time commitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still in dollars, but a bit riskier, we can consider different types of commitments, with very controlled / no IL risks. For example, a liquidity provision between FRAX and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/DAI LP opportunities on Frax&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax Finance&lt;/a&gt;, the prime rate (x1) is just our minimum target, but it is possible to reach up to x5 with two types of commitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X3 by locking LP tokens for 3 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X2 by using your veFXS (much harder to reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective return on a position locked in for three years corresponds to about 3 times our minimum target, thus offering a credible protection against the loss of value due to the consequences of inflation, but you still have to be able to assume the three-year commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is taken here on DAI, but the situation is similar on the other major stablecoins; for example, here are the FRAX/USDC pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/USDC LP opportunities&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex for Frax is coming (optimizing Frax LP farming via Convex), if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own veFXS, it&amp;rsquo;s probably pertinent to wait until the service is released to make a decision with all the cards in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenizing-and-speculating-on-future-yields&#34;&gt;Tokenizing and speculating on future yields
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To beat that famous 10% return on the dollar, there are still many other options. I present you one last one here to help you consider the other possible strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, we rely on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol that allows the tokenization of future yields on productive assets. The principle is both simple and complex: depositing an asset on APWine allows to separate its future yield (FYT: Future Yield Token) from the underlying principal (PT: Principal Token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, different strategies are possible, such as immediately selling the future yield (FYT) in order to increase the quantity of the productive principal. Such a tool enables better risk management considering the volatily of yields observed in DeFi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and still well above the 10% requirement: let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on the aUSDT vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apwine-USDT-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine aUSDT vault&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automatically exclude the PT/FYT pool which is more complex to understand and has much higher risks than the PT/Underlying offering a 44% return in APW anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the strategy is simple, but you have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the important gas costs linked to the use of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;. To implement the strategy using USDT in the wallet, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit a part of them on Aave (I&amp;rsquo;d recommend 55% of the total maximum for this specific strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit the aUSDT obtained in 1 on APWine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow (x2) + Deposit the PT and Underlying (USDT) tokens as liquidity providing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Stake of the LPs PT/Underlying tokens to obtain the return in APW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget also the gas fees related to the APW claims + unwinding of the position at the end of the period (or before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore better to wait for a day when the transactions clear under 30 gwei so as not to suffer too much from the gas costs on such a strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage here, compared to Frax for example, is that &lt;strong&gt;the position is much more liquid&lt;/strong&gt;. APWine works with an epoch logic that lasts 90 days. Thus, to more easily amortize the costs in gas it is preferable to deploy the strategy at the beginning of the epoch: this is also when the returns are generally the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third winelisting (where the next tokens supported on APWine are decided) has just ended, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apw-winelisting3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine - Winelisting 3&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APWine is still a young protocol, but the governance is dynamic. The next step is approaching: as on Curve, it will soon be the veAPW holders (locked APW) that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.apwine.fi/t/apgp-2-enable-gauges-for-apw-rewards/171&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;will decide on emissions&lt;/a&gt; for each given vault. A redistribution of the cards is to be expected, plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-hedged-productive-positions-with-various-alternative-stablecoins&#34;&gt;II/ Hedged productive positions with various &amp;ldquo;alternative&amp;rdquo; stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have stayed for now on the dollar, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to begin with. Although dollar stablecoins are still largely dominant, there are now &lt;strong&gt;many stablecoins based on other fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt; such as EUR, JPY (Japanese Yen), CHF (Swiss Franc), KRW (Korean Won) or even CAD (Canadian Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the few centralized stablecoins (EURS or EURT), this market is mostly covered by protocols that offer to create synthetic stablecoins backed by other stablecoins. This is the case for example with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jarvis Network&lt;/a&gt;, which uses USDC to collateralize different types of stablecoins: jEUR, jCHF, jKRW, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-deposit&#34;&gt;Single deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yield opportunities with no/low IL for such stablecoins are still quite rare, and usually found on Curve: providing liquidity against other stablecoins based on the same fiat currency, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/curve-chf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CHF pool on Curve Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few stablecoins have lucrative single deposit options jEUR, jCHF, jJPY. They are based on the corresponding Curve pools, with additional incentives offered by Jarvis and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via Jarvis (also available farmed by Harvest), it is also possible to generate a return without IL on jCAD and jJPY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiatafiatb-liquidity-providing&#34;&gt;FiatA/FiatB Liquidity Providing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a slightly different approach, more risky, but also potentially more protective against inflation: providing liquidity on two stablecoins representing two different fiat currencies, for example EURT/3pool (USD) still on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, especially for smaller portfolios, many alternative stablecoins are available on Polygon or Avalanche, with a fairly dense ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarvis offers jCHF-USDC, jEUR-USDC or jCAD-USDC pools with returns above 20%. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beefy.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Beefy.Finance&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to automatically compose the returns obtained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/harvest-jarvis-2-stables.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Network Jarvis jFIAT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: depending on your base asset (e.g. USDC), exposure to EUR (or other currencies) can be lucrative or costly - depending on the evolution of the USDC/EUR exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the more adventurous among you, you should know that APWine is also available on Polygon and already supports several Jarvis tokens, such as the MooJarvis_4eur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity contribution on Curve (4eur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed by Beefy Finance (moo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which compounds return that Jarvis offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the addition of tokens voted during winelisting 3 will open new doors with the upcoming arrival on APWine/Polygon of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooKyber_USDC-jEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooMai_USDC-MAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forex-borrowing&#34;&gt;Forex Borrowing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if liquidations don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, know that a Fuse pool on Polygon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://polygon.market.xyz/pool/7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool7 - Jarvis Forex Market&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to use different jFiat as collateral as well as to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/fuse-pool7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Fuse pool 7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a service, almost anything is possible, here are some examples to inspire you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long USD + short EUR = MAI in collateral, borrow jEUR then sell jEUR and potentially loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short GBP via CHF = jCHF in collateral, borrow jGBP then sell and potential loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also note that the productive stablecoins m2CAD and m2JPY are available as collateral while keeping their yield: they can be interesting for more traditional leverage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding your balance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than just one magic position, what I like about Jarvis stablecoins is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;diversify easily into different types of fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to the low transaction fees on Polygon, it is quite possible to mix several different currencies and positions to make a coherent whole and well protected against its local inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a European (= spending €):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in stable productive € without IL, for example MooJarvis_4eur (+APWine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in jEUR/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% in stable productive dollar (e.g. aUSDT APWine strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Diversification: 15% jCHF/USDC + 15% jGBP/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject of &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; stablecoins, you should know that there are also a few that track gold or silver - they can be relevant from this perspective too. For example XAUT (with Pool Curve XAUT/3crv). Gold and silver remain &lt;del&gt;barbaric&lt;/del&gt; boomers&amp;rsquo; relics, personally I see very little interest in them for a competent DeFian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-inflation-resistant-stablecoins&#34;&gt;III/ Inflation resistant stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beating inflation is nice. Hedging it? Even better. But &lt;strong&gt;why not just abstract it&lt;/strong&gt;, using products that are naturally resistant to it? There are still very few stablecoins that are not tracking fiat currencies, but the supply is growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-the-first-dollar-free-stablecoin&#34;&gt;RAI, the first dollar-free stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast, the very first &amp;ldquo;unpegged stablecoin.&amp;rdquo; Launched at a value of Pi in USD (3.14) in 2021, it has been moving between 3.02 and 3.06 almost since its launch. Given its recent arrival (just over a year), it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how RAI will perform in a period of prolonged inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, diversifying a portion of your stablecoins into RAI may be an attractive option. In addition, there are different return options available on RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple deposit without IL risk: Idle Finance deposits your RAI in Fuse/Aave to optimize the native return + incentives in FLX from Reflexer + incentives in IDLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle-0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Additional FLX incentives for RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By assuming IL risk via liquidity provision on Curve vs. 3pool, a better return is possible. The crvRAI can then be staked directly on Curve or via Convex or Yearn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is based on a mechanism inspired by Maker MCD but with many modifications to make it possible. To understand how it works, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Signals that the mentioned protocol is still under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-inflation-resistant-stablecoin-the-frax-fpi&#34;&gt;🚧 An inflation-resistant stablecoin? The FRAX FPI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Frax Price Index is a new protocol that should arrive soon within the Frax ecosystem. The goal is to offer a new stablecoin, which would follow the CPI (Consumer Price Index) to protect against inflation. Just like Frax, &lt;strong&gt;the system is based on two tokens&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stable - Frax Price Index (FPI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the governance token - Frax Price Index Share (FPIS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/frax-price-index/inflation-hedge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax documentation&lt;/a&gt; offers some information about the upcoming token. &lt;strong&gt;An airdrop of FPIS is planned&lt;/strong&gt; for veFXS or cvxFXS holders. Thus, the protocol will be independent of FRAX/FXS, although a value capture mechanism to FXS is planned beyond the initial airdrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to project solely on a mere design, but it is clear that a stablecoin that would maintain its value despite inflation is a very desirable product. &lt;strong&gt;There are several questions as to whether the peg on FPI can be maintained&lt;/strong&gt;: to keep its equilibrium, people will have to take the opposite trade to FPI, i.e. &amp;ldquo;short inflation&amp;rdquo;. However, in the current context of galloping inflation, it is hard to imagine who could assume such a position and massive incentives might be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the arrival of the FPI is imminent. Traces of the token &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/token/0xdb68c6264e9d0f8a6df1fa5a89f205da38698d15&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FPIS on EtherScan&lt;/a&gt; can be found as early as early March. I look forward to seeing the Frax team&amp;rsquo;s proposed design to address these consequential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-inflation-resistance--degen--volt&#34;&gt;🚧 Inflation resistance + degen = VOLT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI, there is another project I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely, waiting for a long time and holding high hopes for. The high-level concept is very simple: an Abracadabra-like product that would not be a walking security loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Abracadabra allows borrowing from various productive collaterals, which makes the service desirable. Nevertheless, the infrastructure is close to a hack and the actions of the team members make Abracadabra a second or third grade money market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here, with Volt, is to cover the same vertical using a proven infrastructure: the base offered by Reflexer (RAI). Three main changes are expected on this model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Reflexer, which only accepts ETH as collateral, Volt will diversify the available options, notably with productive collateral such as wstETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of VOLT, the system&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, will be indexed to Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI. The Reflexer infrastructure will be reused (PID controller adapted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Volt team is also working in collaboration with Fuse and Olympus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow Volt, as always, the alpha lives on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dGhvDmCNGr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I describe here the initial design of Volt Protocol, which has since evolved. The vision of creating a borrowing service with an inflation-proof stablecoin remains, but the technical choices have evolved. Read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/volt-protocol/whitepaper/blob/main/volt.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper available here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-beating-inflation-with-returns-on-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;IV/ Beating inflation with returns on volatile assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a world where nothing holds and value leaks, what&amp;rsquo;s left? How about good, proven DeFi assets backed by protocols with massive, recurring revenues shared directly with their holders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few of them, very few. We will detail them one by one, as well as the different options available on them to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-the-origin-and-the-end&#34;&gt;ETH: the origin and the end
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is of course ETH, which has many different sources of return - just like stablecoins, there is nothing to stop you from diversifying your ETH exposure with several sources of return, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH staked with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lido.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lido Finance &lt;/a&gt;(low yield, but a priori the safest) [~5%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rocketpool.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rETH&lt;/a&gt; on Curve (more innovative, more lucrative, more risky) [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vault covered call options on ETH via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stakedao&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ribbon.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ribbon Finance&lt;/a&gt; [~25%, risks!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-chain liquidity on a Bridge, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cbridge.celer.network/#/liquidity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celer&lt;/a&gt; [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A position balanced in this way tracks/exceeds inflation slightly with the returns obtained on ETH. The profitability of the position over the long term depends of course mainly on the average entry price on ETH and its evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crv-cvx-and-fxs-the-three-fates-of-the-defi&#34;&gt;CRV, CVX, and FXS: The three Fates of the DeFi?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Romans, the Fates are three goddesses who govern the lives of humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clotho weaves the thread of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lachesis unwinds it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atropos cuts it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi also knows these Fates: three protocols that play a critical role in the survival and growth of potentially any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in addition to ETH, there are several DeFi projects that have already proven themselves, control substantial revenue streams, and offer a truly relevant service in a macro context of prolonged inflation; I see three essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve Finance - CRV&lt;/strong&gt;: the mother of all yields in DeFi + peg machine and liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convex Finance - CVX&lt;/strong&gt;: an option on CRV, which controls almost 50% of all locked CRVs and adds real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frax Finance - FXS&lt;/strong&gt;: innovative stable project, native DeFi, very productive via AMOs + arrival of FPI + Frax has a big position on CVX &amp;amp; some other protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being tokens backed by key protocols in DeFi, there is no shortage of return options on these three tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV -&amp;gt; Deposit on Convex in CvxCRV then stake or LP cvxCRV/CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVX -&amp;gt; Locked vote on Convex in vlCVX -&amp;gt; Return in cvxCRV + bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FXS -&amp;gt; Direct deposit on Frax (veFXS) or management via Convex (cvxFXS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-promising-tokens&#34;&gt;Other promising tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still other projects that have not yet reached the profitability of Curve or Convex but represent credible bets. In a world where inflation is here to stay, the tools that will allow us to protect ourselves from it can become very popular: I propose you some other theses related to what has been already mentioned in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apwinefi-apw-betting-on-the-advanced-defi-infrastructure&#34;&gt;APWine.fi (APW): betting on the advanced DeFi infrastructure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When inflation goes up, everyone is looking for yield. Let them run behind the %, and instead target the pick sellers in this gold rush. This is the main thesis behind a bet on APW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the article already, APWine offers interesting products to bet on the evolution of yields or even realize a future yield immediately. As DeFi develops, the demand for a product like APWine will keep growing. Will it be APWine, or another one? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the APWine Wars coming up, it&amp;rsquo;s not a stretch to envision bribes similar to what we see on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflexer-flx-a-bet-on-degovernance&#34;&gt;Reflexer (FLX): a bet on degovernance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the very interesting technical approach, Reflexer also innovates on another level. Indeed, since the launch of the protocol, the team has presented a &amp;ldquo;De-governance Plan&amp;rdquo; aiming at progressively minimizing the team&amp;rsquo;s control over the protocol through two main means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of everything that can be automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management by FLX holders for situations still requiring manual analysis/decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;Reflexer now exceeds RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The Money God League is a set of projects building using the Reflexer infrastructure, with the support of the team. So it seems quite natural to consider an airdrop of the governance token of these new projects, including VOLT, to FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last tip: the stakers of the FLX/ETH LP in the Reflexer Safety Module are the last resort to guarantee the solvency of the protocol. If I were to consider an airdrop to thank the Reflexer community, I would probably target them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looksrare-looks-bet-on-nfts&#34;&gt;LooksRare (LOOKS): bet on NFTs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of LOOKS as an option on the NFT market. In fact, LooksRare is the first NFT marketplace that shares revenue. This translates into &lt;strong&gt;an ETH yield for stakers on LOOKS that reached 3 digits sustained during the first few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/looks-eth-farm.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ETH yields on LOOKS staking&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, trading volume has dropped and the ETH yield with it, but &lt;strong&gt;the staking LOOKS is still one of the biggest ETH yields out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with these three suggestions, but of course there are other options - you be the judge. For example, the QI Wars have started and the protocol has good traction. Be careful, however, not to fall into the trap of thinking that all protocols that adopt the ve + bribes model will be as successful as Curve and Convex. ve tokenomics will multiply: it&amp;rsquo;s about making the right choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-and-happy-harvesting-&#34;&gt;Good luck and happy harvesting 🚜
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be tempted to apologize for the length of this article, but I remain confident that it&amp;rsquo;s worth a read and will be informative even for the most knowledgeable DeFians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have considered other useful strategies or protocols for protecting against inflation, please feel free to suggest them to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further reading, here are some recommended related articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-wars/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Curve Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Reflexer RAI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, for the practice, which remains ESSENTIAL, your best bet to warm up is to try with small amounts on inexpensive sidechains/L2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The APWine protocol on Polygon to familiarize yourself with these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting jFIAT / Liquidity contribution on Curve + farming to discover Jarvis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long/short on Forex with jFiats + Fuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: I have invested in APWine pre-sale and I am a big user of the protocol. I am a user and frequent holder of almost all the protocols mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice, I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing my research to help you do yours!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt; for their careful proofreading and their suggestions to help improve this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🌽 Defi money markets cookbook</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/money-market-recipes/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/money-market-recipes/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/money-market-recipes-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post 🌽 Defi money markets cookbook" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this blog, I frequently discuss about money markets and assets market in DeFi. Basically, they allow you to &lt;strong&gt;loan and borrow tokens&lt;/strong&gt;. These two actions have become like &lt;strong&gt;deFi verbs&lt;/strong&gt;: they are used directly or indirectly in almost every strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while it is crucial to understand the protocols you are using and especially &lt;strong&gt;the different &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;money market risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Today, I would like to focus on the why and the how:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which strategies can be implemented using money markets?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can they be deployed in practice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re going to break down different &amp;ldquo;recipes&amp;rdquo; to take advantage of the money markets. Take these recipes as &lt;strong&gt;inspiration to develop your own strategies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice: I am not authorized to dispense it. Rather than mechanically reproducing the strategies presented as examples, I invite you to try to understand the approach.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;leveraged-bets-on-a-money-market-via-the-market-itself&#34;&gt;Leveraged bets on a money market via the market itself
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every money markets have an associated token, for example the AAVE token for Aave. It is generally used for the governance of the protocol and sometimes also allows to capture part of the value it generates. With this strategy, we will &lt;strong&gt;use a money market to borrow assets that will then be used to gain exposure to the native token of the desired platform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙ Condition:&lt;/strong&gt; Optimism about the future of a given money market. It&amp;rsquo;s native token in this scenario is expected to appreciate in line with the growth of the market over the medium/long term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📅 Time horizon:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 - 24 months. ~3 months is a recommended minimum so that gas fees and borrowing costs don&amp;rsquo;t impact the returns of the strategy too much.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 Expected result&lt;/strong&gt;: the acquired token appreciates, which allows to pay back the debt (+ possible interest) at term by reselling part of the initial position. Once the debt is repaid, part of the acquired tokens can be kept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🃏 Bonus / Facilitator:&lt;/strong&gt; If the token in question can produce a return (e.g. AAVE in the Safety Module), this will allow the debt to be repaid even faster or to accumulate &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; tokens if the scenario of its price appreciation is verified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although this strategy is quite basic, it is one of my favorites. I recently shared with you on Twitter an example of how to put it into practice, which we will detail here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the concerned protocol is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://liquity.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; and the implementation of the strategy is quite simple, but has two variations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-exposure-to-the-native-token&#34;&gt;Direct exposure to the native token
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Either by directly exposing yourself to the LQTY token, which is of course more risky:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/mm-long-token-tokenbrice-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mm-long-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit ETH on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; via one of the frontends, they will serve as collateral for the position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrow LUSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swap LUSD (via ParaSwap for the best rate!) for LQTY, the native token of Liquity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stake LQTY, which generates LUSD and some ETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually repayment of debt (2) via LUSD yield (4) and resale of some of the LQTY acquired in step 3 after price appreciation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or more conservatively, with a strategy using Liquity to borrow LUSDs and make them productive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exposure-mainly-in-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Exposure mainly in stablecoins
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/mm-long-tokenbrice-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mm-long-token-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit ETH on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; via one of the frontends, they will serve as collateral for the position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrow LUSD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stake LUSD via either the Stability Pool (-&amp;gt; LQTY + ETH) or the LUSD pool on Curve Finance (-&amp;gt; Native + LQTY + CRV).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eventually repayment of debt (2) via yield (3)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn Finance also offers a LUSD vault that automatically manages the position on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investing-time-rather-than-money&#34;&gt;Investing time rather than money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alchemix arrival has opened up new perspectives in terms of strategy. On Alchemix, the debt repays itself over time. Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;the collateral used (yDAI) is a stablecoin that produces a return (via Yearn)&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus with the current conditions the loan is self-repaying in three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suggest a simple strategy to take advantage of Alchemix to make a profit. The main drawback is that &lt;strong&gt;only half of the amount of DAI initially placed in Alchemix can be borrowed in AlUSD&lt;/strong&gt; and then invested.
Nevertheless, as this strategy is based on stablecoins, it does not - (⚠ oracles) - involve any price risk and therefore does not require daily monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙ Condition:&lt;/strong&gt; DAI that will be locked in for ~3 years. Only half of the deposited amount is mobilizable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📅 Time horizon:&lt;/strong&gt; ~3 years (depends on DAI return rate on Yearn).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 Expected result&lt;/strong&gt;: In 3 years, the AlUSD debt is fully repaid and the DAI initially mobilized on Alchemix are free again. It remains to be seen what happened with the investment made with the borrowed AlUSD: it all depends on the choices made, I do not predict the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🃏 Bonus / Facilitator:&lt;/strong&gt; Use the borrowed AlUSD to invest in a token that can produce a return. This allows you to make a compound investment or even pay off Alchemix debt faster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-alcx-via-alchemix&#34;&gt;Long ALCX via Alchemix
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To illustrate the concept, I propose another simple strategy which is equivalent to long Alchemix via its token ALCX :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/alchemix-investment-tokenbrice-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;alchemix-investment-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit DAI as collateral on Alchemix. Alchemix deploys it on Yearn Finance to generate a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrow up to 50% of the initial value deposited in AlUSD, a stablecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invest the AlUSD in the desired token. Here for the example it is ALCX the native governance token of Alchemix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stake the acquired token to produce a return&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The repayment of the debt in AlUSD contracted on Alchemix is done automatically with time. It is possible to repay in advance thanks to the generated returns (4).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;putting-a-hodl-collateral-to-work-over-the-long-term&#34;&gt;Putting a &amp;ldquo;hodl&amp;rdquo; collateral to work over the long term
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I came to DeFi several years ago with a simple ambition: I wanted to put my Ethers to work. At the time it was not an easy task but nowadays there are many very interesting solutions. I will focus on one of them, Aave, for two reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave has launched &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity mining&lt;/strong&gt; program paid in StkAave&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (Aave V2 - Mainnet).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave is accessible on the &lt;strong&gt;sidechain Polygon&lt;/strong&gt; where the low fees allow to deploy DeFi strategies efficiently even with small capital. There is also a liquidity mining program there, in MATIC &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this strategy as accessible as possible, we will develop the example on the Polygon sidechain. It is therefore possible to use any of the tokens supported as collateral on the Aave/Polygon market: MATIC, AAVE, wETH, wBTC, USDC, and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to&#34;&gt;How-to
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategy is to &lt;strong&gt;produce returns through the borrowing of stablecoins used to provide liquidity on the Curve exchange service&lt;/strong&gt;. With the liquidity mining program on Aave, every step of the process is potentially lucrative at least in MATIC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙ Condition:&lt;/strong&gt; Having tokens accepted as collateral on Aave, and bring them back to Polygon for example using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wallet.matic.network/bridge/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the POS bridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📅 Time horizon:&lt;/strong&gt; Short / medium term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 Expected outcome:&lt;/strong&gt; Returns in MATIC, stablecoins and ETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🃏 Bonus / Facilitator:/&lt;/strong&gt;. Prospective: mining CRV &amp;amp; potential leverage when LP Curve Polygon tokens are accepted as collateral on Aave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;putting-eth-to-work-on-polygon&#34;&gt;Putting ETH to work on Polygon
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To illustrate this strategy, I start with the assumption of generating a return from ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/polygon-aave-curve-eth-farming-tokenbrice-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;polygon-aave-curve-eth-farming-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH deposit as collateral on Aave/Polygon (+native +MATIC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrowing stablecoins (-APR +MATIC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit and staking of stablecoins on Curve/Polygon (+natif +MATIC)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that Curve LP Polygon tokens are being considered for potential addition as collateral in the Aave market. We can also expect potential CRV rewards on Polygon LP positions if the DAO decides to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is possible to implement this strategy by keeping the tokens used as collateral on the L1 Aave in order to benefit from the mining of StkAAVE. It will be necessary to migrate the borrowed stablecoins from the Ethereum network to Polygon using for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wallet.matic.network/bridge/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Matic&amp;rsquo;s POS bridge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;protect-yourself-against-the-price-risk-of-the--farming-in-&#34;&gt;Protect yourself against the price risk of the $: farming in €.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, everything is done in dollars. It makes sense, everyone knows, but for a European user it is a significant additional  risk. Indeed, if your ambition is to generate enough to live on with DeFi, then this means your output will eventually be in Euro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/eur-usd-1y.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;eur-usd-1y&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a European farmer, it may therefore be &lt;strong&gt;interesting to have a DeFi exposure in € to avoid this risk&lt;/strong&gt;. At the moment, there are simply no Euro borrowing options other than &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mimo.capital/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mimo Capital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This service allows you to borrow PAR from ETH, wBTC or USDC. The MIMO governance token is also distributed to owners of active vaults as well as to liquidity providers on the PAR/ETH and PAR/USDC Balancer pools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the protocol is still recent and the PAR token is not yet supported in the ecosystem, as a collateral on Aave or in a Curve pool for example. So the situation is not yet ideal but it has the merit to exist!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other DeFi-€ solutions are in development. MakerDAO, for example, has mentioned a Euro-DAI, while Jarvis Network is working on a synthetic stablecoin €, the jEUR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-1&#34;&gt;How-to
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To farm natively in Euros, the best option is still what you can do with EURS. Since the launch of the pool on Curve, there are many options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚙ Condition:&lt;/strong&gt; Owning EURS / sEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;📅 Time horizon:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 month - years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 Expected result:&lt;/strong&gt; Growing a capital in Euro-stable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🃏 Bonus / Enabler:&lt;/strong&gt; Owning VeCRVs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-recipes/EURS-farming-tokenbrice-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;EURS-farming-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;pool Curve&lt;/strong&gt; directly offers an attractive yield in CRV even when it is not boosted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To automatically sell the farmed CRVs to compound the return, a vault is ideal. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yearn.finance&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn&lt;/a&gt; offers a vault on EURS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Farming is also possible via the EURS vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;StakeDAO&lt;/a&gt;, in order to accumulate SDT as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest&lt;/a&gt; also offers a vault that makes up the bulk of the returns while paying in FARM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope these different recipes will inspire you. Make sure you are &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;aware of the different money market risks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, used for all these strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The liquidity mining program StkAAVE was launched on Mars 26 following a governance vote. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AaveAave/status/1386753673104134155?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More info here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polygon sponsors a liquidity mining program in MATIC, both on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.polygon.technology/defiforall-kicking-off-l2-defi-summer-with-40-million-usd-in-liquidity-mining-rewards-from-4937d7c6e287&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.polygon.technology/continuing-scalability-defi-summer-with-5-million-usd-in-liquidity-mining-rewards-from-polygon-e73a76c5a8ad?gi=9a7b7e130606&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Volume begets fees: how are the main decentralized exchanges capturing value?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/decentralized-exchange-value-capture/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/decentralized-exchange-value-capture/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Volume begets fees: how are the main decentralized exchanges capturing value?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve shared my perspective on many DeFi protocols on this blog, but recently I realized I&amp;rsquo;ve never gone back to the basics: the DEXs. That&amp;rsquo;s precisely what we will do today, tackling the topic mostly by looking at value capture mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AMM-based DEXs like Uniswap, Curve or SushiSwap all grew tremendously both in available liquidity and volume this year, and so did the fees they collected. To put it simply: &lt;strong&gt;these DEXs now are the main fee-collectors there are in crypto, right after the Bitcoin and Ethereum network themselves&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/fees.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crypto-fees&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite an impressive achievement! So today we&amp;rsquo;ll look at this yummy cake and understand how it&amp;rsquo;s split. What&amp;rsquo;s the different approaches? What is their token used for / how do they establish their incentive model? And then how will the arrival of layer 2 impact all of that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-automated-market-maker-amms&#34;&gt;The rise of Automated Market Maker (AMMs)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With all the discussions around automated market makers (AMMs) lately, I wanted, as usual, to take a step back and consider the current state of the market, the position of the main players and what&amp;rsquo;s coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss AMMs but I&amp;rsquo;ll leave the technical details of the bonding curves to others. Instead, we will address the topic from a value capture and tokenomics perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rise and development of AMMs fundamentally changed the market&lt;/strong&gt;. Before their dominion, order-book based approaches were still widely used. One of the main merits of AMMs is to change the logic of the service, as it becomes &lt;strong&gt;peer to contract&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need for a matching order on the other side, thanks to the bonding curve, there&amp;rsquo;s always one (within pool liquidity &amp;amp; slippage limits).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s one of the key factors that enabled them to grow as they streamlined everything related to token exchanges: from the act of swapping itself, but also liquidity providing and even things like fetching a price for assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we have our beautiful DEX-commissions-cake, now let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the main services&amp;rsquo; value capture mechanism to better understand their main differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the sake of the simplicity of this article, we won&amp;rsquo;t address Balancer and Bancor models. It might be a good follow-up piece.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;value-capture-mechanisms-in-discovery-mode&#34;&gt;Value capture mechanisms in discovery mode
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the different iterations and releases of the main DEXs, their value capture mechanisms evolved. Initially, there was not necessarily a token and a share of the exchange collected fee captured by it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uniswap-the-need-for-liquidity&#34;&gt;Uniswap: The need for liquidity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in the first days of the AMM, the main concern was liquidity - still very scarce back then: Uniswap had no token and no need for it to pioneer the AMM-front. The initial and still current fee distribution infrastructure matches this requirement: a &lt;strong&gt;30 bps fee (0.3%) is taken on every trade and distributed to the liquidity providers&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a perfect fit to start as you have a liquidity chicken and egg problem to begin with: sufficient liquidity will enable swaps without too much slippage, driving volume (if there&amp;rsquo;s need for the given token/market) and therefore revenues for LP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is currently no fee or value capture at the token-level but it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;ready to be implemented&lt;/strong&gt; if the DAO was to decide it - the V2 of the protocol shipped last year includes a &lt;code&gt;Protocol fee&lt;/code&gt; feature.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sushiswap-value-capture-to-the-token&#34;&gt;SushiSwap: Value capture to the token
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the early days, one of the core changes of SushiSwap was a slight reduction of this fee to 25 bps to &lt;strong&gt;redirect the 5 bps left to SUSHI stakers.&lt;/strong&gt; This enables SUSHI stakers to get a share of the fees collected on all pairs, instead of liquidity-pair based distribution only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the initial distribution phase, there were several adjustments made but the mechanism is roughly the same. Onsen introduced a rotational reward system onboard relevant new pools. More importantly for the tokenomics, ⅔ of the SUSHI rewards earned through liquidity mining are now vested over a 6 months period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/sushi-onsen.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sushiswap-onsen&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This vesting reduces the incentives for &amp;ldquo;mercenary liquidity&amp;rdquo;, especially for liquidity managed by a vault for instance &amp;amp; helps to &lt;strong&gt;make sure that large liquidity providers are also SUSHI holders at all time&lt;/strong&gt; (even up to 6 months after they&amp;rsquo;re done farming), better aligning interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To achieve this split, SushiSwap distributes a 0.25% fee for each swap to LP, just like Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s 0.30%. On top of this fee, another 0.05% fee is collected on each swap in form of LP tokens, and settled for SUSHI distributed to the stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The improvements brought by Sushi are relevant, yet in my eyes the real game-changer is the Curve model, so let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-peek-at-the-endgame-curve-finance--crv&#34;&gt;A peek at the endgame? Curve Finance &amp;amp; CRV
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve&amp;rsquo;s model is slightly more complex than the previous but results in an ever better alignment of incentives between the platform users and the token holders. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of the CRV token, liquidity providers on Curve have been earning CRV tokens on top of their usual commissions (if they stake). And just like SushiSwap, Curve&amp;rsquo;s introduced a form of value capture at the CRV-token level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/curve-pools.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the model is more intricate so let&amp;rsquo;s discuss each part and see how they interact with one another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-tutorial--the-timelock&#34;&gt;1/ Tutorial : The Timelock
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make use of CRV tokens within Curve, the first choice one has to make is the length of its commitment. The base unit is veCRV, a time-weighted locked CRV enabled for governance. To be explicit: &lt;strong&gt;to be eligible for the fees collected and other features discussed below, you need to lock your CRV token for at least 1 year.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mechanism is quite straightforward, you can lock for 1 to 4 years. 4 years will give you 1 veCRV per CRV, decreasing linearly to 0.25 veCRV per CRV for a one year period. As said before, veCRV is the base unit of the system - so it will determine how much fees as well as boosting and governance power you have access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-level-up-zone--your-share-of-the-fees&#34;&gt;2/ Level-up Zone : Your share of the fees
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Staking and locking CRV tokens in the DAO is enough to be eligible for a share of the fees collected on Curve, yet it&amp;rsquo;s only the first step of the journey. The commissions are collected frequently and settled for 3pool LP tokens. The mechanism recently kicked off and started distributing rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that the effective return fluctuates as it&amp;rsquo;s tied to Curve&amp;rsquo;s exchange volume and the CRV token acquisition price. At the time of writing, it&amp;rsquo;s around &lt;strong&gt;$0.29 yearly for 1 vecRV.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To describe the next layer of the Curve&amp;rsquo;s onion, I love to use a metaphor inspired from online role-playing games. Indeed, there are three types of realms fitting to describe the next three steps for Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvE (Player vs Environment)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you face only AI-controlled monsters (mobs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PvP (vs Players)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you fight against other players in a set environment (arena/battlefield)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RvR (Realm vs Realm)&lt;/strong&gt;: where you fight against other players potentially everywhere (faction-based)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll use this frame of reference to analyze the next three layers of the Curve&amp;rsquo;s onion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-curves-pve---boosting-crv-rewards&#34;&gt;3/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvE - Boosting CRV rewards
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned earlier, liquidity providers can stake their LP tokens to earn CRV on top of their usual commissions. But they can also &lt;strong&gt;use their veCRV tokens to boost&lt;/strong&gt; one or several of their pools, increasing the CRV earned up to 2.5 times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, one needs an amount of veCRV proportionate to the $value of the liquidity providing position boosted. The effective cost (in veCRV) to have the maximum boost is not the same for each pool - creating a first layer of incentives/arbitrages games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/crv-boost.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve CRV boosting&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting mechanism enabling a better alignment of incentive: &lt;strong&gt;large and efficient CRV earners are also significant veCRV holders&lt;/strong&gt; (-&amp;gt; locked for 1-4 years) so they have a fair amount of skin in the game. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s just the first &amp;amp; friendliest layer of Curve&amp;rsquo;s meta game. Let&amp;rsquo;s go deeper into the onion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-curves-pvp---the-gauge-weights-game&#34;&gt;4/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvP - The Gauge Weight&amp;rsquo;s Game
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If pool-boosting is PvE, the gauge-weights are Curve&amp;rsquo;s PvP arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gauge-weights are a bit similar to boosting, but &lt;strong&gt;at the platform-level&lt;/strong&gt;. veCRV holders can vote to &lt;strong&gt;decide the share of newly minted CRV allocated to each pool&lt;/strong&gt;. Additional restrictions apply here to prevent the manipulation of the votes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The VeCRV needs to be locked with at least 7 days left.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The gauge weight voting can only be changed by users every 10 days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It enables the incentivization of new pools, theoretically without impulse needed from the Curve team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-curves-rvr---governance--inter-protocol-gov&#34;&gt;5/ Curve&amp;rsquo;s RvR - Governance &amp;amp; inter-protocol gov
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The last layer of the onion lies with Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance: veCRV holders can vote on the DAO proposal and with at least 2 500 veCRV, you can submit a proposal to the DAO. So, to recap, once you hold veCRV, you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earn a share of the fees collected by the exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can boost your own CRV streams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Through gauges, influence future CRV emission on curve pools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally with the governance, you have a say in the key parameters of the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While 1&amp;amp;2 is what is of interest to most-end users, &lt;strong&gt;items 3&amp;amp;4 can be incredibly valuable for other dApps, DeFi projects and protocol politicians&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here, the possibilities are virtually endless:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For instance, imagine a project introducing a new stablecoin. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be neat for them to have governance power within Curve to eventually include it in a boosted Curve pool?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even deeper into the onion, already &lt;strong&gt;successful DeFi projects with treasury can allocate a part of it to the CRV token to harness the benefits from all 4 items&lt;/strong&gt; - 1&amp;amp;2 to boost their treasury income streams and 3&amp;amp;4 to make their platform or service more attractive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Another layer deeper: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://crv.ape.tax&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s yveCRV vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. It offers better returns on CRV than staking yourself (~1.3x), but depositors renounce boosting and voting capacity in favor of Yearn - which can then use this extra boosting/voting capacity to enhance the yield of its vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final level of depth: imagine a crypto/DeFi PR-like service a couple years from now. I expect them to be able to &lt;strong&gt;supply other projects with proposition power&lt;/strong&gt; on the main DAOs like Curve or Aave.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-next-steps-for-curve&#34;&gt;6/ Next Steps for Curve
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, we have to consider one last dimension on Curve, as it&amp;rsquo;s not just any DEX. Indeed, from the get-go Curve specialized into the &lt;strong&gt;swaps of pegged-assets&lt;/strong&gt; and optimized for it. It started with stablecoins only, but we now also have BTC and ETH representations too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the growing available liquidity, the team is now harnessing DeFi synergies (with Synthetix) to offer swaps between the different pegged assets listed on Curve, such as DAI -&amp;gt; wBTC or USDT -&amp;gt; EURS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides incredible value as it covers markets that are currently not broadly available elsewhere (EURS) and enables a minimization of slippage for large trades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To stay concise, Uniswap and Sushiswap&amp;rsquo;s bonding curves are well suited to &lt;strong&gt;support many small or average swaps, especially on large pools&lt;/strong&gt; with a low slippage. However, they are less optimal for large orders as slippage increases in proportion to the share of liquidity of the pool required by the trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A service like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; helps you streamline this process &amp;amp; optimize your swap further.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-outlook-l2--its-incentives&#34;&gt;Future outlook: L2 &amp;amp; its incentives
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To wrap up this article, let&amp;rsquo;s not forget about the upcoming tectonic shift for the Ethereum space: the increasing availability of layer 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, we saw the value transacted on AMM explode to the detriment of order-book based approaches. They streamlined the whole experience and made tons of sense for layer 1 so we can reasonably expect them to pave the way for L2 decentralized trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loopring is already delivering live in production an AMM on L2:&lt;/strong&gt; a zk-Sync based L2 DEX with various incentives for liquidity providers. Curve has been working with Zk-Sync too, so we can reasonnably expect them to ship a live L2 product this year considering the latest developments with Zk-Sync.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/loopring.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Loopring V2 Stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Synthetix recently rolled their Optimism L2 mainnet and the force seems strong around a Uniswap x Optimism rollout. Jokingly the other day I was saying:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Synthetix Optimism L2 is Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s testnet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprising to see Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s L2 implementation rolling out within weeks or months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re at it, what about tokoenomics x L2? I expect to see &lt;strong&gt;LP incentives too migrating to L2&lt;/strong&gt;, as it&amp;rsquo;s already the case with Loopring. Synthetic too quickstarted its current limited L2 (minting/burning only) with SNX incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services that do not already have a token might have an edge here as they can incentive the L2 directly. On the other hand, the protocols that heavily incentivized their L1 already might lack firepower to match the incentives offered by projects with &amp;ldquo;L2-native&amp;rdquo; tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to be fascinating to watch the releases of the different layer 2 and how they impact the protocols usage and tokenomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/dex-value-capture/defi-france-live-16.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-france-live-16&#34;
	
	
&gt;
🇫🇷 If you understand spoken French:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to meet 0xMaki to discuss the topic &lt;strong&gt;in French&lt;/strong&gt; this Monday on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JT8N7-gqTjA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi France&amp;rsquo;s YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes--references&#34;&gt;Notes &amp;amp; References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find more info in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/docs/v2/advanced-topics/fees/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2 Documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A concept &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;[https://newsletter.banklesshq.com/p/the-life-of-a-protocol-politician&#34; &gt;first theorized in the Bankless newsletter&lt;/a&gt;referring to a person or entity specializing in gaining influence over diverse decentralized protocols &amp;amp; then offering on-the-tap access to this influence as a service.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/y-among-us.gif" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn Finance has been making headlines lately with the announcement of &lt;strong&gt;several acquisitions&lt;/strong&gt; like Pickle Finance or SushiSwap. The Yearn team has joined its development forces with five other DeFi projects already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To grasp what&amp;rsquo;s happening, we&amp;rsquo;ll look back at the main events since September and how each of the different sub-projects is now working to achieve a shared goal. While Yearn is still relatively new, there are already many chapters to its story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to better understand the latest events - the merger spree, let&amp;rsquo;s first quickly consider the three phases of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development and how they led to today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beginnings of Yearn with the fair launch of the YFI token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How YFI&amp;rsquo;s launch became a template with the waifus (forks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of the Yearn Ecosystem: Yearn beyond the vaults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-backstory-launch-waifus--the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Backstory: Launch, waifus &amp;amp; the ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last June, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s token launch was a unique moment, initiating what is now called a &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Essentially, the &lt;strong&gt;YFI token was distributed over a week to users&lt;/strong&gt; depositing to several pools related to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s products. Feel free to check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my first story on Yearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more about this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It translated into a growing awareness for the project, a rapid price appreciation of the token, and attracted involved DeFi users to contribute to Yearn through the DAO&amp;rsquo;s discussions. The launch was so successful that it actually became a template replicated more or less successfully by many other projects: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-waifus.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s waifus (forks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, Yearn was focusing on its own products, the main ones being the vaults enabling streamlined implementations of farming strategies. The vaults too grew beyond Yearn to become a product offered by many DeFi services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direction was not exactly clear back then. Indeed, there were many products being worked on, such as yBorrow, ySwap, yinsure, or the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/43292/eminence-finance-exploit-leads-to-degen-soul-searching&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Eminence exploit&lt;/a&gt;. However, the core product, the vaults saw little improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last few months, the vision for Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development evolved. Instead of an inward-facing plan focused on the ecosystem, the Yearn team started to look outward. At the same moment, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s DAO was structuring its processes and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/yip-54-formalize-operations-funding/7956&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;formalized operations fundings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads to the current merger phase - joining development efforts with other DeFi projects on relevant areas of expertise. Token-wise, nothing is changed, each project keeps its own token and sovereignty over it. So let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-mergers&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Mergers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the context set, let&amp;rsquo;s now look at the different projects joining forces with Yearn and how they contribute to add value to the offering. We&amp;rsquo;ll consider them as they happened, in their chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Some of these mergers are still pending a token holder vote to be validated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A NFT was made to immortalize this moment of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s history: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:90731:0xac6d5c44c7a089101c53735211b12f5f722c7688&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yAmong us, by Cryptouf - available on Rarible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pickle-finance-1124&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance (11/24)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: PICKLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;symbiotic relationship&amp;rdquo; with Pickle Finance was the first to be introduced on November 24. The idea is to merge the efforts of the two projects currently offering similar products. Pickle will now deliver an &lt;strong&gt;incentive mechanism on top of the Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; through gauges, similar to Curve&amp;rsquo;s current model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By joining forces, it creates additional options for Yearn vaults depositors while securing the assets deposited in the Pickle jars, one of which was subject to a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cointelegraph.com/news/pickle-in-a-pickle-as-attacker-swipes-20-million-in-evil-jar-exploit&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;$20 million exploit &lt;/a&gt;shortly before the merge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cream-finance-1126&#34;&gt;Cream Finance (11/26)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: CREAM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Money Market - Lending &amp;amp; Borrowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger with Cream is even more exciting as it would expand the range of strategies Yearn vaults could use. Cream is a lending platform, a fork of Compound with several changes including the collateral accepted. yUSD (Yearn yCRV vault share) has been supported as collateral for a few months already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two teams teaming up mean a more systematic approach, eventually &lt;strong&gt;paving the way for leveraged vaults&lt;/strong&gt;: the vault token share being used as collateral on Cream to borrow more stablecoin and increase exposure. Cream would eventually become the lending arm of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cream-v2-merger-e9fa6c6989b4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More info in the announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cover-protocol-1128&#34;&gt;Cover Protocol (11/28)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: COVER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Peer to peer coverage market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn has been trying to provide coverage and insurance for its products, with projects like yInsure. So working with another project on this front is highly synergistic, since it could enable &lt;strong&gt;coverage for Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; while allowing the team to focus on its core offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cover-merger-651142828c45&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the announcement here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;akropolis-1130&#34;&gt;Akropolis (11/30)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: AKRO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won&amp;rsquo;t expand too much into this one, as it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Pickle. Akropolis was providing services similar to the vaults, so &lt;strong&gt;joining forces allow increasing TVL&lt;/strong&gt; by creating another frontend for Yearn/Pickle while beefing up the security of Akropolis, as it too suffered &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://news.bitcoin.com/hackers-drain-2-million-in-dai-from-defi-protocol-akropolis/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exploit for $2M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sushiswap-1201&#34;&gt;SushiSwap (12/01)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: SUSHI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Decentralized Exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sushi is now &lt;strong&gt;the second DEX by volume&lt;/strong&gt; with roughly half ($889M) of the total value locked of Uniswap. To attract liquidity to the platform, Sushi distributes its token to the providers of liquidity on certain key pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could allow Yearn to &lt;strong&gt;incentivize liquidity providing for critical pairs of the Yearn ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, such as a CRV &amp;lt;&amp;gt; yyveCRV to drive deposit into this vault which can provide additional returns for other Yearn deposits on Curve. The team joins efforts so that Sushi/0xMaki can lead the AMM efforts amongst the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-it-mean-for-yearn&#34;&gt;What does it mean for Yearn?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this merger spree is a &lt;strong&gt;massive increase in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s firepower&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s also a &lt;strong&gt;form of recentering&lt;/strong&gt;: some key parts of the ecosystem are delegated, such as the AMM (swaps) to Sushiswap&amp;rsquo;s team, or the lending markets to Cream. It should enable the team to move faster on its core products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are now so many mergers announced that CoinGecko created a category to track them: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.coingecko.com/en?category_id=yearn-yfi-partnerships-mergers&amp;amp;view=market&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🦎YFI Partnerships &amp;amp; Mergers Coins by Market Capitalization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, composability is key and Yearn is yet another demonstration of what it can achieve. Indeed, there is one last dimension to stress with these mergers: liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/yearn-merger-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn-Merger-TVL-Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these 5 acquisitions, Yearn will roughly triple its total value of assets locked across its ecosystem. Along with the synergies, it could help Yearn develop a moat that will be hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🤖 Vaults: DeFi Investing Streamlined?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/vaults-defi-investing-streamlined/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/vaults-defi-investing-streamlined/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/vaults/harvest.gif" alt="Featured image of post 🤖 Vaults: DeFi Investing Streamlined?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the ecosystem of decentralized financial services on Ethereum grows and matures, the service offering is becoming more dense and sometimes hard to understand. While the most technically savvy users can chase the latest releases and hedge their risk appropriately, less-seasoned investors might feel left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are DeFi services made to match the diverse set of investors exploring the space. Yearn Finance was the first platform to pioneer a passive-type of investment products: vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base idea is simple as 1, 2, 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaults are &lt;strong&gt;tokenized investment strategies&lt;/strong&gt;: your deposit is represented by a token (for instance, yCRV in Yearn’s Vault -&amp;gt; yyCRV/yUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The vault frequently harvest and re-invest the profits&lt;/strong&gt; (here CRV) to purchase more of the base asset supplied, compounding the returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fees are streamlined&lt;/strong&gt;: the depositors do not pay for the gas costs of the vaults operation (such as harvesting). Fees are usually charged while exiting the vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;rsquo;d like to &lt;strong&gt;avoid the headaches&lt;/strong&gt; of chasing the latest farm, managing the claim of the profits you earn, when and how to reinvest them, without forgetting, of course, to account for the gas costs of all these operations in the calculation of your profits, vaults are a credible alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaults are made to &lt;strong&gt;abstract the complexity for the end-users&lt;/strong&gt;. You deposit some tokens and wait while they are farming a set strategy for you. So let&amp;rsquo;s see what options are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is straight to the point and highlights the different vaults available. To learn more about Yearn Finance debuts, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;read this piece&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. For more context on Yearn’s forks, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-waifus.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;check this one&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplest-basic-vaults&#34;&gt;Simplest: Basic Vaults
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaults use the token you deposit (DAI for instance) to farm a given strategy, produce a return and re-invest it automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pioneer is of course Yearn with the yCRV vault, but several options are now available or progressively rolling out. This article provides a structured overview of the main earning opportunities enabled by vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you deposit a given token to earn more of it over time, and potentially additional reward. The tokens you are supplying are not used to provide liquidity on decentralized exchanges, &lt;strong&gt;so there is no exposure to impermanent losses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;as more and more vault-types products are being released, you want to take the time to understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening with the one you choose&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below you will find tables summarizing the main vaults that I know of, with the tokens they accept, the service they farm, and how the return is denominated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mention &amp;ldquo;returns normalized to the base&amp;rdquo; means that the strategy generates a return frequently settled for the base token supplied - this operation is sometimes referred to as “harvesting”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The frequency of the harvest is important as it will influence the compounding factor of the overall position, as well as level of risk taken on the price of the farmed token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins--btc-vaults&#34;&gt;Stablecoins &amp;amp; BTC Vaults
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Vaults, the most common tokens accepted as deposits are stablecoins. Such vaults will deploy your capital on Curve Finance pool to earn CRV tokens, usually the Y pool, . More recent projects, such as Pickle Finance also enables farming from the Curve sUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/vaults/pickle-pjar0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pickle-finance-pjar0&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pickle Finance pJar 0 explainer infographics &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@picklefinance/introducing-picklejars-70a311ab65c5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, some services like Harvest or YFV have an incentive model on top of their vault: depositors earn the governance token of the platform (FARM or YFV) on top of the base return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKENS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV (Seed Pool)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Value&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV/VALUE staking reward&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;yCRV, DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;pJar 0 + psCRV pool (Curve sUSD)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve/Pickle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to sCRV + PICKLE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Curve also supports tokenized BTC pools, there are now vaults for them too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;wBTC, renBTC &amp;amp; CRVRENWBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;hBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Rewards normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Harvest.Finance, you can deposit wBTC or renBTC directly, or the CRVRENWBTC token, which represents a deposit in Curve&amp;rsquo;s Pool 5 (RenBTC &amp;amp; wBTC pool).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-based-vaults&#34;&gt;ETH-Based Vaults
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;BTC &amp;amp; Stablecoins positions are interesting, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;d like to keep an exposure to the price ETH?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can achieve such a result by yourself by leveraging your ETH. You&amp;rsquo;ll use them as collateral to mint or borrow stablecoins/wBTC that are then deployed to produce a return superior to your borrowing cost: here&amp;rsquo;s an article I wrote providing tips and tools to leverage ETH efficiently - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/leveraging-ETH.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, with such a position, you can be exposed to liquidations if the price of ETH was to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, Yearn was the pioneer here with the release of the wETH vault that automated this whole process. However, the volume of deposit was massive and the service ran into some technical issues currently being worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of waiting for the re-release of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s wETH vault, why not consider the &lt;strong&gt;existing available options&lt;/strong&gt;? They are not as intricate as Yearn&amp;rsquo;s wETH, since they do not leverage your ETH; the ETH is simply deposited somewhere to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Maker + Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Normalized to ETH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Cream Deposit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Cream returns normalized to wETH + FARM return (fwETH staking)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Soda&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Soda returns normalized to wETH + VALUE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Returns normalized to wETH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve stuck to &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; vaults where you deposit a given token, let it sit for a while, and hopefully walk out of there with more of it (+potentially some governance extra tokens). Yet, the release of Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s UNI token, another kind of riskier vault is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;riskier-uniswap-uni-farming-vaults&#34;&gt;Riskier: Uniswap UNI-farming Vaults
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;uni-farming-basics&#34;&gt;UNI farming basics
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with the release of the UNI token came a distribution program instauring UNI incentives on specific pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/USDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/wBTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you provide liquidity on any of the pools listed above, you can stake your liquidity pool token for an additional UNI income directly on Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s website. You&amp;rsquo;ll be earning UNI continuously. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to manage the position yourself, which means claiming the UNI (and pay the associated gas costs), as well as selling and reinvesting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These strategies are riskier than ETH/BTC/Stablecoins vaults. Indeed, while farming UNI tokens you are providing liquidity on Uniswap, which comes with a risk of impermanent losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why face the hassle of &amp;ldquo;manual farming&amp;rdquo; when you can &lt;strong&gt;let a vault do the hard work for you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uni-farming-using-a-vault&#34;&gt;UNI farming using a Vault
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, quickly after the launch of Uniswap, several services started offering vault-type products to streamline the farming of UNI. Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKENS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/USDC, ETH/DAI, ETH/USDT, ETH/wBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/DAI, ETH/USDC, ETH/USDT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + PICKLE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/USDC, ETH/wBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + VALUE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This list is not exhaustive. Only vaults are included - services which automatically re-invest the profits for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other opportunities exist to farm UNI, but they require more intervention from your end. For instance, with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://sakeswap.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sake Swap&lt;/a&gt; you can stake your ETH-Stable Uni-V2 LP tokens to earn both UNI &amp;amp; SAKE tokens. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to claim and manage the SAKE &amp;amp; UNI tokens earned yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about a given vault and how they operate, feel free to check their resources. Yearn and Harvest Finance have great documentation with infographics explaining their vaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://farm.chainwiki.dev/en/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farm Wiki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not investment advice, stay sharp and do your own research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harvest Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pickle.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;YFV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Farming! 🚜&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day a new Yearn fork is popping up: how to keep track with them? There is no simple answer to this dilemma, however, I believe I can &lt;strong&gt;provide you with some clues to help you spot YFI fork with high potential.&lt;/strong&gt; To do so, I’ll cover three (+1) YFI forks and try to pinpoint the changes to the secret sauce that made them stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is more than Yearn.Finance product itself: it became a template to kickstart a project, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Yearn pioneered the method which stands on three key elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining Fair Launch&lt;/strong&gt;: the initial distribution of the token of the platform (ex: YFI) happens through liquidity mining. Supporters can stake tokens like yCRV to earn the governance token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt;: the decisions regarding the development of the project are taken by the community of token holders, through informal and formal (on-chain) votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pooled Investment Strategies (Vaults)&lt;/strong&gt;: the Yearn-inspired projects usually also try to replicate this core feature of Yearn: they offer tokenised investment strategies. The vaults are essential for the long-term success of the project past the initial liquidity mining phase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Vault&amp;rdquo; is used to cover two vastly different reality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Basic Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where tokens are collected and stake to produce a yield. The yield produced is frequently settled for stablecoins (no leverage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Delegated Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where once tokens are deposited, they are used as collateral (thanks to credit delegation) to borrow stablecoins then used to produce a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegated Vaults are much more complex to develop and implement, while basic vaults can be sprung quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfi-wifey-wai-fu&#34;&gt;YFI? Wifey? Wai-fu?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Yearn, people were unclear on how to pronounce &amp;ldquo;YFI&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/make-yfi-pronounced-waifu/552&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A discussion on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; settled for &amp;ldquo;Wai-fu&amp;rdquo; (/waɪfu/). From this point onward, there was only one wai-fu but plenty of wifeys: the YFI forks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, despite being barely a few months old, &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has already been forked, a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. There is now a whole family of wifeys built upon similar premises, each project adjusting different parameters to attempt to better fit their envisioned use case. Many of these forks were unnecessary, however, &lt;strong&gt;several managed to bring something new and exciting to the table&lt;/strong&gt; —  the ones we will consider today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This content assumes an understanding of Yearn, to brush up on the topic I&amp;rsquo;d recommend &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;my previous article on Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dfimoney-yfiihttpdfimoney&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money (YFII)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest discussion in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s community was around the &lt;strong&gt;emission schedule&lt;/strong&gt;: while it was initially planned for a week, there were discussions about extending it - most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yips.yearn.finance/YIPS/yip-8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YIP 8&lt;/a&gt; which proposed a longer emission schedule halving weekly. &lt;strong&gt;Despite support from the Yearn Community, the proposal did not meet the quorum and was not implemented&lt;/strong&gt;, which lead to the YFII fork** - a fork of YFI implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;instead of having a week-only distribution, YFII opted for a longer schedule, still ongoing.&lt;/strong&gt; It started July 27 and will end on October 5. The farming pools proposed are very similar to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s: staking the yCRV token or staking the Balancer pool token (98%DAI / 2 % YFII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of this base differentiation, YFII develops an interesting angle with a &lt;strong&gt;strong presence in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: the DFI.Money website was quickly translated into Chinese and soon other languages. There is also a strong &lt;strong&gt;focus on UX&lt;/strong&gt; to make the experience as easy as possible to onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/dfi-money.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Overview of the DFI.Money Vaults&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stats.dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can view the stats here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 14, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DfiMoney/status/1305339433638531072?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money launched the v2 of their vaults&lt;/a&gt;, supporting ETH, USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD, HBTC, &amp;amp; yCRV. As this piece was written, there was a total of $70M deposited into DFI&amp;rsquo;s vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is not an exhaustive overview of YFI forks. There were other forks of Yearn with minimal changes that are not covered, such as YFFI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yflink-yflhttpyflinkio&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yflink.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink (YFL)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFL is another one of the early forks of YFI. Here, the twist is simple:** LINK was used as the base token of the system** - the one to deposit for the initial liquidity mining phase. The farming pools structure was similar to YFI/YFII, but with LINK/aLINK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial vision was to create a farming collaborative for LINK holders. YFL was developed by 5 anonymous teams working together and initially released on August 7 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/Linkswap.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFL LinkSwap&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth was quick and the plan soon refined! YFLink is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@linkswapco/yf-link-ecosystem-linkswap-development-update-44f8413721c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;now working on LINKSwap&lt;/a&gt;, a community-governed Automated Market Maker (AMM), focusing on safety and value capture for LINK holders. LINKSwap explores novel ideas to increase investors&amp;rsquo; safety - for instance, the RugLock feature, designed to avoid rug pulls - when the token’s creators drain the liquidity pools, leaving holders with a sizeable bag of worthless coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfvalue-yfvhttpyfvfinance&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFValue (YFV)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue adds several more twists, with a similar goal of providing a service facilitating yieldfarming and making it more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the farming pools were mostly 98% ERC20-token / 2% YFV Balancer pools and the emission schedule is much longer (5 to 20 weeks) - it&amp;rsquo;s still ongoing while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/yfv-bringing-true-value-to-yield-farming-bddc4edf889a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFV launched mid-August.&lt;/a&gt; There is also a &amp;ldquo;seed pool&amp;rdquo; accepting stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV was one of the first project to provide credible earning opportunities on tokens such as BAL, YFI, BAT, REN, KNC, BTC, WETH, or LINK: it really helped to attract liquidity — there are around $470 M deposited on YFV as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/yfv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFV Staking Interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV&amp;rsquo;s core product, the Governance Vault was just &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/roadmap-update-value-contract-governance-vault-e226ad2f909e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;launched on September 15&lt;/a&gt;. YFV Holders can stake their token for several benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting power in the governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A return paid in vUSD and vETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV token from the emission schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from the strategy implemented with the Governance vaults funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from buying back YFV with 6.8% of the profits made with the vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV is a highly ambitious project. The vaults (wETH, wBTC, renBTC) are expected shortly. On top of the existing farms and governance structure, the team is working on transitioning to an AMM/farming collaborative called Value Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue is in the process of transitioning to VALUE (token) and Value Liquid (name of the exchange/service). You’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/faq-yfv-and-value-migration-af3a5a5c2190&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more information on this rebranding and transition here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfinspired---harvestfinance-farmhttpsharvestfinance&#34;&gt;YFInspired - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance (FARM)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Harvest.Finance is technically not a fork of Yearn, one could say it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;fork in spirit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, Harvest ambitions to streamline yieldfarming to make it more accessible &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s quite a success: Harvest is now home to more than $200 M (+200 M) of diverse assets farming with no stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience on Harvest is quite straightforward, just like with the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault. &lt;strong&gt;Users deposit tokens into the strategy of their choice to put them to work&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, they deposit their DAI to get fDAI, DAI currently farming on Swerve.fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/harvest-finance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once they own fDAI (or other fTokens), users can stake them to earn FARM - the native token of the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; They can also provide liquidity to the fDAI/DAI pair on Uniswap which facilitates the entry and exit of smaller capitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvest.Finance launched on September 15 a new vault accepting for wETH. The community is highly active and committed, and it shows in the reactivity of the team: to better the yield, the stablecoin farms (DAI, USDC, USDT) switched from the Curve strategy to Swerve barely 16 hours after &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://swerve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Swerve&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yfi-fork-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;The YFI-Fork Secret Sauce?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope these quick introductions will help to better understand the recipe for a successful YFI fork. Considering the sample size (3+1), it’s hard to draw some conclusions but allow me to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I see a YFI-Fork scoring some resilience points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;focuses on a clearly identified community&lt;/strong&gt; (ex: LINK holders for YFLINK).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol parameters (pools, tokens, etc.) are adjusted to match the target community wants and needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A one-week emission schedule was a luxury only affordable by the first Waifu,&lt;/strong&gt; mother of all others (YFI). Successful YFI-forks tend to need a longer schedule (5-20 weeks) to gather and structure their community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A farm by itself is not enough, there is a real need for &lt;strong&gt;a convincing vision for the project in the long-run&lt;/strong&gt;, such as an AMM (YFL/YFV), or going above and beyond on the farming front (Harvest), and more than anything a driven and dedicated community to support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Thanks to Ashitaka#4868 from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RheJ78p&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance Discord&lt;/a&gt; for the amazing cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-disclaimer&#34;&gt;NECESSARY DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;NOT investment advice&lt;/strong&gt; or a recommendation to purchase any of the token mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not a financial advisor. I have no formal financial advising training, certification, nor experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a DeFi native sharing my insights, do with it as you may, but please think twice and avoid impulsive decisions at all cost: they are usually the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚜 Merry Farming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/wifeys.jpg" alt="Featured image of post YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Yearn v2 release and the launch of the YFI token (pronounced &amp;ldquo;Waifu&amp;rdquo;) shook decentralised finance. Indeed, the whole recipe was there: Yearn is like a robo advisor, it helps you save and grow a capital - obviously one of the most thought after use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the product itself, core to defining what Yearn became was its founder Andre Cronje, &lt;strong&gt;his choice of fully opening the governance&lt;/strong&gt;, and the amazing community that soon federated around the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this piece today, I want to share some pointers to understand why Yearn came to be, how it works, and why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-yearn&#34;&gt;What is Yearn?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first version of Yearn started with a simple promise: it &lt;strong&gt;helped you get the best lending rate available at any time on a given stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed as there were more and more options to lend stablecoins (Compound, Aave, dYdX, etc.), yield optimization quickly became essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn v2 already brought a new product to the market, the yVaults: they go beyond yield optimization (rebalancing stablecoins between several lending platforms) to provide more returns. Let’s see how this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-user-perspective-deposit-wait-money-go-up&#34;&gt;End-User Perspective: Deposit, Wait, Money go Up
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we go in the specifics, here it&amp;rsquo;s how it works for an end-user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You own a token supported in the yVaults, such as LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can deposit your LINK in the yVault to start earning. Entry and exit to the vaults are gas optimised (usually ~$2-3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re done, you exit the pool. 0.5% of the &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; value is taken by the system to cover all the fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given &lt;strong&gt;enough time spent in the vault to make up for the exit cost&lt;/strong&gt;, investors walk out with a profit paid in the token they entered (ex: more LINK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: yVaults are still highly experimental. Make sure you know what you are getting into. Andre has quite an interesting approach, stated in his twitter bio &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1291252150635560960?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;I test in prod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-happening-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;yVaults are amazing because &lt;strong&gt;they abstract an immense amount of complexity for the users,&lt;/strong&gt; and do it better than most of us. Going back to our yLINK vault, here&amp;rsquo;s what happens to provide the yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINK are deposited on Aave (Credit Delegation) and used as collateral to open positions. The positions are maintained within a safe range using an safety mechanism (funded on the returns).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stablecoins are borrowed and put to work to provide a return. The latest strategy farms the mUSD/USDC MTA Balancer Pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any actual returns of the farming portion of the position (stablecoins earned above the debt) are sold for LINK, increasing the effective returns of the whole position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist of yVaults is that &lt;strong&gt;they harness DeFi synergies to provide yields on autopilot.&lt;/strong&gt; They are designed to be flexible with their capital allocation - so that it can easily be re-allocated to follow a different strategy with better yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each vault has a different strategy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a neat explainer graphics made to explain the yCRV vault strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yCRV-vault.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance yCRV vault strategy explained&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining this one would be another article by itself, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let you dig the graph and join the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/HFK5uea&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Discord&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yearn-is-unlike-anything-else-before&#34;&gt;Why Yearn is unlike anything else before
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is DeFi on steroids, and made possible by developments that occurred over the last year. Yearn is harnessing synergies between several &amp;ldquo;DeFi legos&amp;rdquo;. Without going too deep in, here are the key ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aave recently launched the Credit Delegation feature&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling a contract to open a position on your behalf. This feature was necessary for the yVaults to function as they do now, as they enable the first part of most strategies - getting leverage.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEX &amp;amp; Automated Market Makers - especially &lt;strong&gt;Curve.fi&lt;/strong&gt;, an obvious dependency for the yCRV Vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall &lt;strong&gt;dynamism of the stablecoins markets&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to new entrants such as mStable or the COMP token release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is the perfect example of DeFi composability!&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-as-little-as-possible--assembling-legos&#34;&gt;Building as little as possible &amp;amp; assembling legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why am I focusing on this? Because as someone working in the DeFi space for two years, I can tell you that the biggest operational mistake I see ALL THE TIME - is simple: &lt;strong&gt;teams re-building the wheel - reinventing what already exists and working&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think DeFi projects (like most startups) would gain immensely from actively trying to reduce the scope of work they undertake - here are two amazing questions that should be asked more often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is the unique value delivered by our product?&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do we need to deliver it? Can we harness existing solutions to achieve this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s structural design demonstrates a keen eye to identify high-potential DeFi projects and harness their synergies. In short, by &lt;strong&gt;assembling several DeFi legos together in an unprecedented way&lt;/strong&gt;, Andre efficiently delivered a brand new use case if not a new subset of the whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-defi-100-community-driven-project&#34;&gt;The first DeFi 100% community-driven project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This headline is not at attention grab, I stand by it as there is meat on the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first, let us restress than &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has been a working product handling significant volumes for a while before the YFI token&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, you can add to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% of the tokens distributed to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a novel liquidity mining approach, pertinent to the product (yCRV pool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community was quick to step up and is booming with well-articulated ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andre relinquished control of the main contracts governing the service, in favour of a multisig with reputable actors of the space.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I regard and value an open governance process as a net positive, at least in the long-run, this is also a risk - and &lt;strong&gt;this is usually how people in the industry reads it&lt;/strong&gt;. An open governance can be hijacked in a direction that does not match the best interest of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;defiweb3---communities-hegemonize-brands&#34;&gt;DeFi/Web3 -&amp;gt; Communities Hegemonize Brands
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might not be on board yet, but for me, building and growing communities - that’s essentially my life. In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it, I found no secret sauce yet I &lt;strong&gt;uncovered an obvious truth: communities &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; brands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of DeFi, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the &lt;strong&gt;clash of brands&lt;/strong&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re about to witness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the one hand, VC-funded brand-companies tend to lack personality and have a harder time bolstering dynamic organic communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, a community-driven project is &lt;strong&gt;a story writing itself every day.&lt;/strong&gt; And when it comes to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s brand, we see it growing fast: the swag is already there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yearn-swag.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance Swag&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feeling-the-yearn&#34;&gt;Feeling the Yearn
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is so much more than yVaults! I focused this explainer on them for clarity, but there are several other Yearn products being developed. Without diving too much in, here some promising ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yborrow.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yBorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a generalised credit delegation interface using Aave. What makes it amazing is the synergy with the vaults, it will enable anyone to access vaults like yCRV from an ERC-20 token they like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ySwap: a novel automated market maker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mysterious leveraged stablecoin-farming solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yearn-toolbox&#34;&gt;The Yearn ToolBox
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools and resources developed by the community that proves super helpful if you are exploring or using Yearn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LearnYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A comprehensive Yearn wiki frequently updated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://feel-the-yearn.vercel.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FeelTheYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple page to get the current status of the vaults: assets locked in, assets deployed and the strategy used for each vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ycosystem.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YCosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A community aggregator to find all the useful links, from docs/YIP to where to purchase Yearn swag!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you are interested in Yearn, I URGE YOU to give the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;governance forum&lt;/a&gt; a read - you are forever invited to read and partake in the discussions shaping Yearn. This time, there is no VC, no BS - just a DAO and a one-man-army named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre Cronje&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wifeys-family&#34;&gt;The Wifeys Family
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it would be dishonest to cover Yearn/YFI &amp;amp; without mentioning that YFI sparked a whole movement - there are now dozens of forks, more or less credible. While the first few ones where just &amp;ldquo;miners fork&amp;rdquo;, adjusting a few parameters, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing more creative approaches. Indeed, Yearn is open source so easily forkable, and Andre even invited the community to get creative with it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some communities are forking YFI to create their own pooled earning system, with a longer-term vision. It&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning but I think we will see fascinating development in that space. I think we will see communities reappropriating themselves parts if not the whole YFI system - remember the Wifeys family earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already starting! I&amp;rsquo;m following closely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/yflink/the-idea-of-yflink-is-born-aa520921a4a3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink&lt;/a&gt;, a YFI fork adjusted for the needs of the LINK community. Right now, it looks like a farming cooperative, but the end game might be a community staking node - the perfect match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to the Yearn and its family grow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn vaults are novel DeFi products integrating many others meaning the failure risks are compounded. I am not a financial advisor - you make your own decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am NOT responsible for &lt;u&gt;YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, may they bring you Lambos or bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1280500969986498561?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s Stani (Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO) giving you a rundown of why this is big!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre himself is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1290845154430025731?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the first to acknowledge&lt;/a&gt; what made Yearn possible and the importance of composability.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol governance now lies in the hands of YFI holder. The access to the main contracts are held by a multi-sig, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1285427748761198594?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a key&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1289959986190147585?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;If you do clone /and you are welcome to/, please change a few things so we get new data from the experiment. Repeating the same experiment isn&amp;rsquo;t fun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post 💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeFi is like a layered yield cake. When you first walk through the door, making a deposit on Aave and seeing your balance grow puts you in awe. Shortly thereafter, through your own research or discussions with the community, you realize there is more to it &lt;strong&gt;- there could be icing on the cake too!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you could find several streams of yields on a given capital utilizing Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. &lt;strong&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll exclude out of the box any strategy involving leverage&lt;/strong&gt; - the easiest way to achieve such a feat. There are still a lot of high-quality crops to plant, even without leverage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, capital efficiency is increasing at a rapid pace in DeFi thanks to novel financial primitives like Compound, Balancer or Curve. It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to &lt;strong&gt;achieve up to 3 layers of returns&lt;/strong&gt;, and there are pools for any risk appetite, from pure stablecoins ones to 100% ERC-20 tokens exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Liquidity Wars are merely beginning.&lt;/strong&gt; Follow the governance of the protocol you&amp;rsquo;re invested in closely, it&amp;rsquo;s even more critical now. Meanwhile, since DeFi feels more and more like gaming, allow me to import a concept inherited from there: tier list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In video games, tier lists are useful to navigate the different types of characters or builds. They establish both a typology and a ranking. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll bring this concept back to DeFi to arrange the most attractive liquidity pools into coherent groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-we-start&#34;&gt;BEFORE WE START
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ℹ Please note - This content assumes a basic understanding of the world of Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. Refer to my earlier articles if that&amp;rsquo;s the first time you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This piece will not cover basic DeFi investment strategies, detailed in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 DeFinancial Services Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information regarding the tools you can use to implement and manage these strategies, please check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not investment advice and reading this document as anything more than a structured list of incentivised liquidity pools would be a misrepresentation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suggest-yours&#34;&gt;Suggest yours!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post can be a living document. Feel free to suggest incentivised pools I&amp;rsquo;ve missed. If you are familiar with Github, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/TokenBrice/blog/blob/master/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;you can do a pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If not, just reach out and share documentation about the pool and its incentive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, allow me to make the distinction between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining&lt;/strong&gt;: a base action of the platform (such as supply liquidity) is rewarded with the platform native token (ex: BAL on Balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Incentive Programs&lt;/strong&gt;: a specific liquidity pool is eligible for extra rewards, through staking of the pool token or weekly distributions (ex: Wednesday for JRT Balancer pools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is: you can stack both! Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/yield-farmer-tier-list.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TokenBrice-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List-DeFi&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-1-defi-yield-trifecta&#34;&gt;Tier 1: DeFi Yield Trifecta
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I walk you through the main earning-staking opportunities I&amp;rsquo;ve found, I will also share broader considerations about providing liquidity on AMMs, such as thoughts on the pool weighting to help you make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we chase our wildest dream, the highly-thought-after yield trifecta, let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to consider what it looks like. When it comes to yields, the cream of the crop is usually an incentivised &amp;amp; balanced Balancer pool with low fees, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s eligible for the maximum amount of BAL liquidity mining rewards, on top of the liquidity incentive program (&amp;amp; the commissions on swaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is exactly one Balancer pool matching these criteria with 2 stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; to my knowledge, so this is where we start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-50-musd--50-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;The 50% mUSD / 50% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mstable&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a meta-stablecoin. You can go on their app to lock your USDT, USDC, DAI &amp;amp; TUSD to mint mUSD. Once you own mUSD, several earning opportunities are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most direct one is the &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; feature on the mStable app. It will lock your mStable tokens and generate a return through lending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/mstable.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s a simple yield and won&amp;rsquo;t deserve a feature here by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect introduction to the Balancer mUSD/USDC pool, our first trifecta of the day. What&amp;rsquo;s a trifecta you ask? Pretty simple: 3 layers of yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commissions on swaps&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s a liquidity pool facilitating trades and earning a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAL liquidity mining&lt;/strong&gt;- this is a balanced 50/50 pool with low fee (5 bps) earning the maximum amount of BAL possible (mining factor = 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/mstable/introducing-meta-mta-mstables-protocol-token-6e1032291ccf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MTA liquidity incentives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; program on this pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% USDC&lt;br/&gt;50 %mUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;MTA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 26 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;?? BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 000 MTA/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Native rewards = earned in the same token as the exposure (usually a commission fee taken on trades facilitated)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: The respective ratios of four stablecoins backing the mUSD (half of the exposure) can vary, go to the m stable app&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to view it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/musd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable-asset-distribution&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is particularly attractive because the exposure is 100% stablecoin-based, despite a very solid yield thanks to the max BAL mining ratio + the incentive program paid in the highly anticipated MTA token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note/Warning: 💬 Discussions are ongoing in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/ARJWaeF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Balancer Discord&lt;/a&gt; governance channel to lower the BAL mining ratio on this pool. It was lowered to 0.1 for tokens tracking the same asset.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9010-incentivised-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;90/10 Incentivised Balancer Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;90-snx--10-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;90% SNX / 10% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel like you missed out on SNX rise? For medium capitals (&amp;lt; 5000 SNX) it makes little sense to stake if you account for the gas costs. This pool is a great alternative for a bullish SNX exposure with great yield potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% SNX&lt;br/&gt;10% USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5 Jun 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DONE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, since the pool is heavily skewed towards SNX, the BAL mining is not maximized. Remember the factor of 1 for the BAL mining on the mUSD pool? Here it&amp;rsquo;s 0.36: you get about a third of the amount of BAL you would mine in a 50/50 &amp;amp; low-fee pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 90/10 pools are great to heavily minimize impermanent losses risk if you believe the token has a lot of upside potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/balancer-snx-usdc-liquidity-trial/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;incentive program on this pool is now over&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s back to being a regular twofecta pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;jrt-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;JRT Balancer Pools
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jarvis Network offers an incentive program over three pools, all 90 % JRT + 10% DAI, ETH or USDC. The reward model is similar to the previous pool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% JRT&lt;br/&gt;10% ETH, DAI or USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;JRT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Jun 17 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;70 000 JRT/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/jarvis-network/liquidity-program-with-balancer-db23aa0ce10&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: JRT price&amp;rsquo;s action has been quite explosive lately. DYOR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚡ Update (&lt;em&gt;July 08&lt;/em&gt;): JRT rewards are now distributed to ANY Balancer pool (whitelisted):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ampl-geyser&#34;&gt;AMPL Geyser
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AMPL is a beast of its own, so I invite you to read more on it &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; before you dive into this one. Here, the exposure is 50 % ETH and 50 % AMPL. On top of your commissions, you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for extra AMPL &amp;amp; as well as the AMPL rebalances (on your AMPL = 50% of the exposure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 % ETH&lt;br/&gt;50 % AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;April 21st 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable - AMPL Rebalances&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;36 911 AMPL/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ampltalk.org/app/forum/ampl-geyser-19/topic/about-the-geyser-21/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 AMPL Geyser Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebalances compounded impact can be hard to calculate. This spreadsheet recently emerged to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.publish0x.com/canuhodl/ampleforth-dollar-ampl-calculator-spreadsheet-for-investors-xmdjxvy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧮 help AMPL investors calculate the impact of the rebalances.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ampleforth-geyser&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geyser code is audited&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and insured on Nexus Mutual&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The reward calculation here takes into account the time staked - so this pool is best utilised over the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-2-how-many-fecta-can-there-be&#34;&gt;Tier 2: How many fecta can there be?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synthetix-incentivised-pools&#34;&gt;Synthetix Incentivised Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Synthetix has been pioneering liquidity incentive programs with the early Uniswap sETH/ETH pool (+SNX incentives). Synthetic pools are still highly attractive, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider the two main ones of interest for yield stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note the Curve&amp;rsquo;s token (CRV), one of the liquidity mining rewards of both pools presented below, is not live yet. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/curvefi/curve-dao-contracts/blob/master/doc/readme.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CRV currently documented mechanisms&lt;/a&gt; can change before the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-og-curve-susd-pool&#34;&gt;The OG: Curve sUSD Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the mUSD/USDC pool, this pool exposure is 100% in stablecoins, yet the rewards are paid in SNX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;31.58 % USDT&lt;br/&gt;30.67% USDC&lt;br/&gt;24.62% suSD&lt;br/&gt;13.13% DAI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Aprill 22 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;CRV (not live yet)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;48 000 SNX / week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/new-curve-pool-launch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is one of the earliest liquidity mining programs there is yet still quite competitive. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous guides, you know about this already&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-btc-og-variant-curve-renbtcsbtcwbtc&#34;&gt;The BTC-OG Variant: Curve renBTC/sBTC/wBTC
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/curve-btc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-synthetix-balancer-ren-btc-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is similar to the first one, with different tokens. Here, your price exposure is 100% in BTC, while your liquidity mining rewards are made of four hot DeFi tokens: BAL, SNX, REN &amp;amp; CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;44.54% renBTC&lt;br/&gt;32.21% wBTC&lt;br/&gt;23.26% sBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX, REN, BAL &amp;amp; CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 19 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;10 000 SNX/week&lt;br/&gt;25 000 REN/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/btc-yield-farming-pool/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because these two Curve pools have full exposure in a stable (USD) or relatively stable assets (BTC), they are a great resource to &amp;ldquo;park&amp;rdquo; profits realised on more risky ERC-20 based pools. You still &lt;strong&gt;maintain a decent APR on the base asset (~3-5%) while having a nice upside potential on the liquidity mining rewards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-3-twofecta-are-nice-too&#34;&gt;Tier 3: Twofecta are nice too!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-favorite-erc-20-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;Your Favorite ERC-20 Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Balancer exchange comes with built-in BAL mining incentives. They apply to any pool involving whitelisted tokens. Therefore, any Balancer pool is already a twofecta: you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for commissions on the swaps facilitated + the BAL mining rewards. Please keep in mind that the pool weighting (ideally balanced) and fees (ideally low) affect the BAL mining ratio. The table below assume a ratio of 1, observed for instance on 50/50 pairs with 5 bps fees (0.05%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the return profile generic Balancer pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% wETH&lt;br/&gt;50% ERC20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~60% for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Balancer, Liquidity incentives programs are getting into fashion, expect more to be revealed, as well as liquidity mining programs. You can &lt;strong&gt;use a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pools.fyi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool FYI&lt;/a&gt; which now has an &amp;ldquo;Incentivised&amp;rdquo; tag to check for the best opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. For Balancer, use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/balancer/%5B%5D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; to explore the pools and check their BAL mining factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compound-deposit&#34;&gt;Compound Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of COMP, a Compound deposit could also be considered a twofecta. Indeed, on top of the base APR the deposit is earning, users are also now eligible for COMP rewards. You can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/compound/None&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;calculate them here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Depends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable in COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-risk-breakdown---read-this&#34;&gt;⚠ RISK BREAKDOWN - READ THIS
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each pool comes with its own sets of risk, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview to help you account for them. When you invest in a liquidity pool, you&amp;rsquo;re assuming the following risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ The base Ethereum network risk (51% attack, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ You&amp;rsquo;re also assuming the risk carried by the token contracts of any token involved in the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ As well as the risk involved to the exchange&amp;rsquo;s contracts, which can be hacked or faulty to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ An economic risk, the impermanent losses (loss vs raw holding) - that will be heavily affected by your token choices &amp;amp; the pool weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/WHILE ENTERING &amp;amp; EXITING/ The risks associated with any service you use, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;, for the time of the transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will walk you through the risk profile of one of the pools to help you model it: the mUSD/USDC pool. Just like the returns, the risk profile is a cake with many layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t develop on the Ethereum network risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we have two tokens in the pool: mUSD &amp;amp; USDC. To compute the risk, we need to look at what&amp;rsquo;s backing mUSD - unwrapping, we&amp;rsquo;re exposed to: USDC, USDT, TUSD. Each of these tokens carry their own risks, since for instance &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://support.usdc.circle.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001314526-Circle-USDC-Risk-Factors&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Circle can freeze USDC balances of any account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we&amp;rsquo;re using Balancer. Their contracts were audited by Trail of Bits recently&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Still, the protocol is quite recent. We&amp;rsquo;re also relying on mStable contracts for the mUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re lucky on the impermanent losses - considering the pool involves two stablecoins, the risk is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It all depends on the tools you&amp;rsquo;re using here. Bear in mind that you&amp;rsquo;re also assuming a risk associated with mUSD/Mstable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gregoireljda&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Grégoire&lt;/a&gt; for his help proofreading this article.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; for his careful review of the FR translation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mstable.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;meta stablecoin&amp;rdquo; aggregating several stablecoins together (USDC, USDT, TUSD &amp;amp; DAI) under the mUSD token, while the underlying supply is mobilised similarly to Curve (lending and liquidity providing).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the current mUSD underlying distribution on the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.mstable.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable app&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://ampleforth.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ampleforth (AMPL)&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;adaptive money built on sound economics&amp;rdquo;. It intends to provide a new type of asset which price movement is uncorrelated from any other.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ampleforth/ampleforth-audits/blob/master/token-geyser/v1.0.0/CertiK_Verification_Report.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Certik - Audit Report 28 Feb 2020&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently 51 643 NXM staked on the AMPL Geyser Contract &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;code&gt;0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser-insurance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;cover-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List&#34;
	
	
&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curve sUSD pool was already mentioned as part of a DeFi investment strategy built on an SNX stake in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/#5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFinancial Service Guide&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
