<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>📔 Guide on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/-guide/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 📔 Guide on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 13:21:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/-guide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Exploring and Industry &amp; Finding Content Ideas: a matter of tools?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/exploring-and-industry-finding-content-ideas-a-matter-of-tools/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/exploring-and-industry-finding-content-ideas-a-matter-of-tools/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring and Industry &amp; Finding Content Ideas: a matter of tools?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing the audience is the key to successful content; it’s the key to successful marketing itself. Yet, for a start-up and moreover at an early stage, &lt;strong&gt;it’s damn hard&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried a lot of different tools before finding the one I’m happy with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory is known, and well documented online: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://backlinko.com/skyscraper-technique&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Skycrapper Technique&lt;/a&gt; is now commonplace. Yet, I find that jumping from theory to field tests and implementation is probably the toughest step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/explaining-seo.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Explaining SEO - Source: webconfs.com | Check it out for more SEO-related comics&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Explaining SEO - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.webconfs.com/seo-comics.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Source: webconfs.com | Check it out for more SEO-related comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll walk your through the basics of exploring an industry using a mix of free and paid tools in order find content ideas and insights to improve your web presence&lt;/strong&gt;. To make it less abstract, I’ll use insights gathered with SEMRush on the telecommunications industry, during the March-April 2017 period to demonstrate my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploring-and-analyzing-seo-strategies&#34;&gt;Exploring and analyzing SEO strategies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The SEO Arms race&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to spot top organic performing content, you’ll need tools. Some free tools can do, but you’ll find yourself using &lt;strong&gt;dozens of them&lt;/strong&gt; in order to match the possibilities offered on a premium SEO service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was looking for my SEO all-in-one dream tool, I put MozPro and SEMRush to the test for a month since both offer a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;//www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34; &gt;free trial&lt;/a&gt;. To sum it in one sentence, the difference between the two lies in the &lt;strong&gt;accessibility versus exhaustivity dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;. While MozPro is easy to on board, SEMRush can be intimidating; yet it offers more features and add new ones at an impressive rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEMRush was particularly useful to track the results of your SEO efforts, be it search position or backlinks. Its usefulness doesn’t stop here as you can use SEMRush on any domain. &lt;strong&gt;Looking at competitors’ metrics&lt;/strong&gt; helps to discover opportunities and to &lt;strong&gt;confirm hunches you may have on potential strategies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true value of SEMRush to me lies in two things. First, it does in one single tool what would require 15+ free tools. Also, the data given by free tools won’t be as &lt;strong&gt;detailed, precise, and easy to access&lt;/strong&gt;. Second, the depth and the scope of the data provided is arguably unmatched by other paid services and nonexistent in free services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dig into the Rolls Royce, &lt;strong&gt;let’s see how far some free tools can get you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free SEO tools and services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of tools, web-services, chrome extensions and such made for SEO and Content is overwhelming. The following tools list is just &lt;strong&gt;a partial, and ultimately biased selection&lt;/strong&gt; that should help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The essentials toolbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/screaming-frog.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Checking a blog sitemap (Screaming Frog)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Checking a blog sitemap (Screaming Frog)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Screaming Frog SEO Spider&lt;/a&gt;: It’s a &lt;strong&gt;swiss-army knife tool&lt;/strong&gt;, used for anything from finding broken links to checking for duplicate content or analyzing pages titles and meta descriptions. It’s one of the few free tools I find myself using frequently, even when I have access to a premium tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/siteinfo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alexa Ranking&lt;/a&gt;: Very basic, but it still gives you an idea of the current traffic flow to a given website and its recent trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.spyfu.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Spyfu &lt;/a&gt;— This tool is very valuable to get an idea for the AdWords strategy of your competition, including CPC, keyword and creatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.dareboost.com/en/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dareboost&lt;/a&gt;: Check your websites and your competitors for web performance, security and on-page SEO optimizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Exploration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://adwords.google.com/home/tools/keyword-planner/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Keyword Planner&lt;/a&gt; — very useful tool for keyword discovery and CPC/volume estimations. You can also mix and match words to produce new keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trends.google.com/trends/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Trends&lt;/a&gt; — easily compare volumes between different keywords, see data on volume such as interest over time, where are the search made, or related topics and queries. + &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.google.com/trends/correlate&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Trends Correlate&lt;/a&gt; — Find keywords correlated to yours. Here are two Google Trends I like to use to showcase the potent of the tool: queries on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” (with the New Year’s Eve impact) and queries on “gift” and “present” (with Christmas’ impact).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends1.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A somehow famous Google Trends: volume on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” reaches its peak just after New Year’s Eve&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A somehow famous Google Trends: volume on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” reaches its peak just after New Year’s Eve&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A similar dynamics is observed for “gift” and “refund”. “Gift” peaks a week before Christmas while “Refund” peaks mid-February.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A similar dynamics is observed for “gift” and “refund”. “Gift” peaks a week before Christmas while “Refund” peaks mid-February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Trends is one of the most basic tool there is, yet it can give you invaluable insights. &lt;strong&gt;Trends are strongly correlated with the real world&lt;/strong&gt; and now used for literally anything such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://qz.com/1052656/bitcoin-price-google-trends-can-help-you-figure-where-bitcoins-price-is-headed/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;to estimate prices evolution of cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;, measure volume distribution for similar keywords, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://searchengineland.com/google-trends-election-hub-offers-deep-dive-search-trends-2016-candidates-political-issues-258784&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;gauge the efficiency of political communications.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a last one with Hillary vs Trump over the last 9 months of the campaign. Ignoring the massive spike on the Election Day, Trump was consistently generating more volume that Hillary months before the election. &lt;strong&gt;Even if the election was a surprise to most, the data doesn’t lie: it clearly hinted a Trump victory for a long-time before he was elected.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Searches about Hillary and Trump, between the 01/01/2016 and the 11/30/2016 (the election was the 8)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Searches about Hillary and Trump, between the 01/01/2016 and the 11/30/2016 (the election was the 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ubersuggest.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ubersuggest &lt;/a&gt;— Find new keywords with suggestions based on one keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://keywordin.com/keyword-generator.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Keywordin’s Keyword Generator&lt;/a&gt; — Mix and match different words or groups of words together to create more long trend variations of your keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/relatedkw.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Level 1/2/3 related keywords for “content promotion” using SEOChat&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Level 1/2/3 related keywords for “content promotion” using SEOChat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://tools.seochat.com/tools/related-keywords-tool/#sthash.PVTTGKHQ.HntdXy5H.dpbs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SEOChat Related Keyword&lt;/a&gt; — Find level 1/2/3 (long trend) related keywords based on one given keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEMRush insights’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of this article, I’ll show what kind of insights a premium tool can land. The insights presented below were gathered using SEMRush ($99/m) during the &lt;strong&gt;March-April 2017 period&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEMRush works as an “SEO search engine”. In the top bar, you can input any domains (yours or competition’s) and get precise metrics on it including backlinks, top keywords, paid vs organic distribution… Here’s how it looks like on a sample domain query (twilio.com):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/domain-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Domain overview for twilio.com (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Domain overview for twilio.com (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;domain overview&lt;/strong&gt; include metrics about backlinks, their types, anchors… Every entry is accessible in a dedicated and exportable full report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/img/2017/seo-tools/backlinks.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Backclink section of Twilio’s domain overview (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Backclink section of Twilio’s domain overview (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also search keywords. The overview tab will give you data about organic and paid volumes, search results and copies. Two other tabs are dedicated to keywords: phrase match and related keywords. &lt;strong&gt;The amount if data available on any keyword is really vast, this where SEMRush shines; as long as the search volume is sufficient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/keyword-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Keyword overview for “SMS API”: Twilio is clearly dominating for now (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Keyword overview for “SMS API”: Twilio is clearly dominating for now (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, the tools provided by SEMRush let you conduct true &lt;strong&gt;surveys of your competitors’ digital activities and estimate the success of their strategies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a quick overview of the insights gathered during the first round of competitor’s analysis for &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.callr.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CALLR,&lt;/a&gt; a voice and SMS API and SIP Trunking provider (03–28–2017) using SEMRush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A voice and SMS API essentially allows computers to interact directly with phone networks. Services such as Twilio’s, CALLR’s, or Nexmo’s are behind the text messages you get to confirm your authentication on websites (2FA), the notification texts you can get from services such as Uber or Amazon, etc. and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://customers.twilio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;many other use cases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;involving automated phone calls and text messages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over 12% of Twilio’s organic traffic comes from a single article&lt;/strong&gt;, not strongly related to their expertise. Indeed, it’s a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.twilio.com/blog/2017/02/an-easy-way-to-read-and-write-to-a-google-spreadsheet-in-python.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tutorial detailing how to handle (read and write) Google Sheets with Python&lt;/a&gt;. 12% of Twilio’s organic entries is around 15K monthly sessions according to SEMRush. It could be surprising but it makes sense: people using Voice/SMS APIs find themselves interacting with huge sheets quite often, contact lists for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 10% of Sinch’s organic traffic come from keywords related (or matching) &lt;strong&gt;flash call&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the business use case they put forward. ~38% of their organic traffic lands on their tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still on Sinch, &lt;strong&gt;41/500 of their top queries were due to an extensive tutorial&lt;/strong&gt; (with 700+ comments) on how to build a messaging app on Android. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sinch.com/tutorials/android-messaging-tutorial-using-sinch-and-parse&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Now the page returns a 404&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nexmo’s present a sensibly different organic traffic profile than the rest of the competition. While most providers get the bulk of their organic search traffic from brand or even exact query, &lt;strong&gt;Nexmo’s top entry points are their products pages&lt;/strong&gt;, especially the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nexmo.com/products/sms&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SMS page&lt;/a&gt; (25% of organic sessions) and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nexmo.com/products/chat&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chat app page&lt;/a&gt; (another 12%). At CALLR, we studied them extensively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The American competitor CallFire is deploying &lt;strong&gt;a smart strategy to increase their organic presence&lt;/strong&gt;. They have seemingly auto-generated page to match every US area code. A large part of their traffic comes from people looking for “XXX area code”. Conversion on this traffic must be low though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, SEMRush helps you find an already field-tested, working strategy used by your competitors. While your chances of achieving the same success by purely replicating them are slim, it gives you an idea of what works in the industry and what people are looking for. &lt;strong&gt;Just as a note, it’s the first time I share this unexploited list, and even though the tips are 6 months old, they might still be valid&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the list above, the first one I would address would be Sinch 404’s as it’s the most straightforward: your job would be to &lt;strong&gt;produce a tutorial on the same topic&lt;/strong&gt;, better than Sinch, and then reach out to all those who still links to Sinch’s 404 to offer your own tutorial instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the page is now a 404, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160408195857/https://www.sinch.com/tutorials/android-messaging-tutorial-using-sinch-and-parse/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;using the Internet Archive you can still access the original tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to see what you’ll have to overtake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can try both SEMRush and MozPro for free to make up your mind&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moz.com/products/pro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MozPro&lt;/a&gt; offers a free one month trial and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;you can get a free trial of SEMRush&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-content-performing-on-social-network-withbuzzsumo&#34;&gt;Finding content performing on social network with BuzzSumo
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://buzzsumo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BuzzSumo&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;social analytics and monitoring tool.&lt;/strong&gt; Before I dig in, it’s time for a disclaimer. BuzzSumo is $99/month with a 14-days free trial. Because of the price, I decided to opt out of it, but I did use it for the duration of the free trial. It helped me get a better understanding of the dynamics in my industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering my limited experience with the tool, I won’t go into too much depths. If you’re considering paying for BuzzSumo and using it extensively, I recommend you to read these comprehensive resources: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://raelyntan.com/buzzsumo-tutorial/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Raelyn Tan’s BuzzSumo tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://buzzsumo.com/knowledge/getting-started-with-buzzsumo/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BuzzSumo’s team itself densely document its product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can search for topics or keywords and see the most shared (social) content. You can go even further and see, for any given post, &lt;strong&gt;the accounts who shared it allowing you to understand how each post got&lt;/strong&gt; its reach. This is also particularly useful is you are publishing similar content: it gives you a list of people potentially interested in sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/buzzsumo.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The results of a search on BuzzSumo&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The results of a search on BuzzSumo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up the BuzzSumo trial in February, to find the top-content addressing VoIP, SIP, and telco APIs. Back then, I recently joined CALLR and was in a reading spree to get a better hang of the main themes to address. Thanks to BuzzSumo, I &lt;strong&gt;compiled a list of the top-performing content&lt;/strong&gt; of the industry. I sorted them according to varied factors: topics, quality of content, approach, tone, targeted audience… Then, looking at sharers, I tried to &lt;strong&gt;correlate these factors to the article’s performance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BuzzSumo’s main strength is that it’s a &lt;strong&gt;must-have tool if you want to use the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://backlinko.com/skyscraper-technique&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;skyscraper technique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It facilitates the process of finding people potentially interested by your content. Indeed, BuzzSumo’s main strength is that it lets you see the list of sharers of a given content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/buzzsumo-sharers.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preview of the sharer list feature&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Preview of the sharer list feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, the metrics it gives you can be hard to interpret&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, in the telco industry I found basic heavily-shared 500–1000 words articles, sometime even just basic product pages from competitors, not particularly qualitative. The gist? Most of these shares are on LinkedIn, and it turns out &lt;strong&gt;a lot of these shares comes from the company’s own employees.&lt;/strong&gt; If a 2000+ employees company manage to get them to share their own content, it can really skew the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice with BuzzSumo is to &lt;strong&gt;dig deeper.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t stop at what BuzzSumo gives you. This is also part of the reason I decided to not subscribe to it: it facilitates the research of content performing on social and influencers, but &lt;strong&gt;it’s not sufficient by itself&lt;/strong&gt; as it relies on indicators that are easily fooled (shares, likes and such are easily bought or automated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From theory to practice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the most actionable insights are sadly gated behind heavily priced tools. While BuzzSumo has its flaws due to the shaky nature of social media, it can prove itself useful from a company investing on social medias. On the other hand, a SEO/SEM tool seems to be a must have for any business in for the long-haul, looking to build a &lt;strong&gt;durable online presence&lt;/strong&gt;. Whatever tool you choose, you’re essentially looking for two major benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/ Ability to fetch SEO and SEM data on your competitors / partners / any 3rd party website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2/ Greater tracking capabilities of your own and competitors domains metrics and content performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are just looking to &lt;strong&gt;facilitate your tracking efforts,&lt;/strong&gt; there are some tools cheaper than SEMRush or MozPro. For simple keyword position tracking, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.serplab.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SERPLAB&lt;/a&gt; offering free version with the paid version starting at $5/m. For backlink tracking, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkody.com/en/plans&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Linkody&lt;/a&gt; starting at 13€/m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are serious about building a long-lasting web presence, you’ll eventually need one of the shiny big tools. Good luck finding your dream SEO toolbox, I’m still constantly tweaking mine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moz.com/checkout/freetrial&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Free trial on MozPro (1 month)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Free trial on SEMRush (7 days)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Reddit and Reddit Ads Hitchhiker’s Guide</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/reddit-and-reddit-ads-hitchhikers-guide/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 11:16:29 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/reddit-and-reddit-ads-hitchhikers-guide/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Reddit and Reddit Ads Hitchhiker’s Guide" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I realized most content and marketing materials focused on the main social networks — Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Instagram, leaving little to no room to the countless other services used around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my last gig, I explored content promotion and marketing using “alternatives sources”. Indeed, platforms such as Reddit, Quora, Medium, Hackernews or directories helped us tremendously to &lt;strong&gt;make&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.callr.com/blog/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;our blog&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;visible to new audiences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Alexa, Reddit is now the &lt;strong&gt;eighth most visited website in the world&lt;/strong&gt;, and the fourth in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/alexa-reddit.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reddit is the #8 top visited website in the world, according to Alexa&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Reddit is the #8 top visited website in the world, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/siteinfo/reddit.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;according to Alexa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s even more interesting is the progressive internationalization of Reddit: in its early days, most of the website’s visitors were Americans. Nowadays, even if the &lt;strong&gt;English-speaking world still makes for roughly 3/4 of Reddit&lt;/strong&gt;, thriving national communities developed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/alexa-reddit-2.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Reddit, a window into the English-speaking world (source: Alexa)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Reddit, a window into the English-speaking world (source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/siteinfo/reddit.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alexa&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, massive social platforms such as Reddit emerged over the last few years and while some marketers notice, &lt;strong&gt;most stayed in the old playground&lt;/strong&gt;. Worse, a fair share of those who noticed the popularity on Reddit are &lt;strong&gt;aggressively trying to game it for their own benefits&lt;/strong&gt;, with bots and other dubious methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll explore the shady side of marketing on Reddit in the last section — Corporate Shilling on Reddit. Before that, I would love to share my own experience with Reddit, to give a feedback on the network as a content promotion platform both organically and with ads as well as share the lessons I learned and the tools I used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to keep it as concise as possible, but Reddit is a whole world: expect quite a ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;organic-posting-onreddit&#34;&gt;Organic Posting on Reddit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-isreddit&#34;&gt;What is Reddit?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was an avid Redditor before starting &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.callr.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my last gig at CALLR&lt;/a&gt;, and it helped tremendously. With a healthy daily dose of Reddit comes an &lt;strong&gt;intrinsic knowledge of the rules and expectations of its users&lt;/strong&gt; that helped us understand what the community liked and disliked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are working in a startup or in tech, ask around in your company, chances are some of your developers are on Reddit and could help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most other organic channels, which offer targeting options only through their ads platform, &lt;strong&gt;Reddit “organic targeting” is precise&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, to put it simply &lt;strong&gt;Reddit is like a huge board&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/all/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/All&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;of boards&lt;/strong&gt; (subreddits). Any user can create a subreddit to discuss the topic of his choice. Some subreddits grow big and are heavily moderated (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/Technology&lt;/a&gt; for instance). Others are more niche and stay small with dynamic and qualitative discussions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;/r/All is the global frontpage of Reddit. When he user connects to the website, he/she lands in his personal frontpage: a page made of the best posts taken from all the subreddit he/she has subscribed to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;posting-onreddit&#34;&gt;Posting on Reddit
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As a brand, it’s hard to be visible on Reddit organically&lt;/strong&gt;. If you create a brand-named account, users might perceive your post as intrusive. Moreover, a lot of subreddits have restrictions on the type of links you can submit: links to brand blogs are quite often prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find sizable audience on Reddit, &lt;strong&gt;you must frame your content a certain way.&lt;/strong&gt; Redditors are very attached to the community: if you want to fit in, you need to respect this attachment and contribute. Two types of submission are possible on Reddit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link Post:&lt;/strong&gt; they include an URL and a title. On the frontpage, the title will be displayed and if the user clicks it, he’ll get to the page linked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text Post:&lt;/strong&gt; they include a title and a body text. &lt;strong&gt;The text itself can include links.&lt;/strong&gt; On the frontpage, if a user clicks a text post, he stays on Reddit and sees the body of the post as well as the comments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/fronpage.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of the frontpage of Reddit, here all posts are link posts. You can tell by the domain displayed in parenthesis after the title. The top post squared in black is an ad.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Screenshot of the frontpage of Reddit, here all posts are link posts. You can tell by the domain displayed in parenthesis after the title. The top post squared in black is an ad.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-link-vs-textstruggle&#34;&gt;The link vs text struggle
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We quickly realized one thing that helped us step up our Reddit game: link-posts are very hard to get right, while &lt;strong&gt;text posts are received with more benevolence&lt;/strong&gt;. With the body text, you can explain what your post is about and provide a summary of it. &lt;strong&gt;It can include a link to your blog post&lt;/strong&gt; so Redditors who want to know more about your topic can find the information they need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Text posts were essential to our success on Reddit.&lt;/strong&gt; We understood the value of it with our first text post that got a moderately positive reception. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/learnpython/comments/6bowht/built_my_own_apartment_search_bot_with_python/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;One of our most successful text post&lt;/a&gt; was made by one of our developers. He had just published a DIY bot tutorial on our blog and then presented it in a Reddit text-post in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/learnpython/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/LearnPython subreddit.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Link posts are not to avoid altogether though. Indeed, if you find a good subreddit/blog post fit, it’s worth trying. &lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to check the sidebar of the subreddit your posting on before publishing&lt;/strong&gt;: rules vary per subreddit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reddit’s activity is “spikey”: if you manage to create a successful post, it might stay on the top of its subreddit for a day or two. Yet, if you want to keep it qualitative, &lt;strong&gt;you’ll avoid publishing too often&lt;/strong&gt; as it may feel like spam to the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your post is tremendously successful, &lt;strong&gt;it might reach the frontpage or even /r/All where the volumes generated are an order of magnitude higher.&lt;/strong&gt; Since our topics are mostly niche, we never reached /r/All yet we consistently generated at least &lt;strong&gt;2000 sessions/month from Reddit since May&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reddit-ads&#34;&gt;Reddit Ads
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reddit Ads is the platform on which you can find &lt;strong&gt;an unbeatable CPC (Cost Per Click)&lt;/strong&gt; with very precise targeting**.** I’ve already explained the subreddits system in the organic section, so the Ads part is straightforward. &lt;strong&gt;You pay to get your message occasionally displayed at the top the subreddits of your choice&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which means displayed to users without ad blockers. Stats estimate &lt;strong&gt;AdBlocker usage around 20% for Europe/US.&lt;/strong&gt; Considering the average Redditor is much more tech-savy than the general population, I wouldn’t be surprised if the number jumps closer to &lt;strong&gt;40% on Reddit&lt;/strong&gt;. Hopefully, you only pay for displayed ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like any other ad platform, Reddit lets you set different creatives for the same campaigns. As it turns out, &lt;strong&gt;difference of CTR (Click-Through-Rate)and CPC between creatives can be huge&lt;/strong&gt;, anywhere between 2–4x. So far, we’ve lead three campaigns on Reddit. While the first, being a test run was far from optimized, the metrics from the following two are really encouraging. We’ll go back on each of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first Reddit Ads Campaign: What’s an API?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first campaign targeted &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/tech/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/tech&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/learnprogramming/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/learnprogramming&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/webdev/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/webdev&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/technology&lt;/a&gt; with our &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.callr.com/blog/what-is-an-api/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;What’s an API article&lt;/a&gt;? As you can see, targeting was not the smartest: /r/webdev is a community for developers who probably already know what an API is. Here are the results we obtained, with an average CPC at $0.60.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ads1.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Results of the ‘What’s an API?’ Reddit Ads campaign&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Results of the ‘What’s an API?’ Reddit Ads campaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite sub-par targeting, this campaign helped me familiarize myself with the platform. Once Davy’s House Hunter bot article was out, I now it was our time to shine on Reddit Ads. I also quickly realized that 4 creatives was far from enough to reach decent results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The second run: House Hunter Bot&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after this campaign, Davy published his &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.callr.com/blog/python-house-hunter-bot/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;House Hunter Bot article&lt;/a&gt; and the organic Reddit post was quite a success. Considering the &lt;strong&gt;potential of the content,&lt;/strong&gt; we decided to boost it with Reddit Ads &lt;strong&gt;targeted at Python developers and learning communities.&lt;/strong&gt; Here is the initial targeting: /r/learnprogramming, /r/Python, /r/LearnPython, /r/Programming and /r/Flask. We added /r/webdev and /r/coolgithubprojects later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the large differences we observed between all the four creatives on our first campaign, we went with &lt;strong&gt;12 different creatives this time&lt;/strong&gt;, to progressively weed out the worst performer. On the following screen, 5 creatives with the lowest CTR/highest CPC were already deleted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ads2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Results of House Hunter Bot Reddit Ads campaign&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Results of House Hunter Bot Reddit Ads campaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPC improved tremendously, sitting at a $0.14 average at the end of the campaign. &lt;strong&gt;It ran for a month and half and suffered from ad-fatigue&lt;/strong&gt;: over the first two weeks, the total average CPC was as low as $ 0.10 and CTR &amp;gt; 0.20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the traffic, the campaign landed over 10 business lead and a few newsletter signups. Compared with the cost of a lead from AdWords, &lt;strong&gt;the ROI of this campaign was promising&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The third try: Nested Symbols on Sketch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads us to our third and latest campaign. Once again, we wanted to bank on an organic success. With the reach of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.callr.com/blog/how-i-streamlined-my-design-process-with-a-few-nested-symbols-on-sketch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;our Sketch post&lt;/a&gt;, we decided to give it a try on Reddit as designer communities are dynamic. The targeting was the following: /r/SketchApp, /r/design, /r/web_design, /r/userexperience, /r/userexperiencedesign, /r/graphic_design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ad3s.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Results of Sketch Reddit Ads campaign&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Results of Sketch Reddit Ads campaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the content did not have the same conversion potential as the House Hunter Bot, it helped us raise awareness in the entrepreneurs and design communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tips-to-redditsmart&#34;&gt;Tips to Reddit smart
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-finding-subreddits-relevant-to-your-content-with-a-dynamic-community&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Finding subreddits relevant to your content with a dynamic community&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finding relevant subreddits is crucial for both your organic and promotional activity on Reddit. A minimal amount of activity is necessary for a subreddit to be able to receive advertising. Using Google Sheets IMPORTXML function, we &lt;strong&gt;produced this sheet to fetch automatically the number of subscribers of any given subreddit and determine if ads are available or not&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find it here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1I1HHpUhkaqE8hiC7Es63pBn2n2ex04rScoCrySR2X5s/edit?usp=sharing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Subreddits list and activity Google Sheets&lt;/a&gt; — everything is automated, you just need to fill the name of the subreddit in column B (exact spelling) and let the magic happens. The second tab is what I use to track the results from all organic reddit posts in the same place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheet will help you gauge the activity of any given subreddit but finding the subs itself can be tricky. Yes, Reddit has a search engine, but it’s notoriously bad. Here are the tools/services I used to find our subreddits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Search “site:reddit.com some topic”.&lt;/strong&gt; The “site:” syntax allows you to restrict a google search to a single website. It’s neat in this case, as Google is (sadly) a much more efficient way to search Reddit than Reddit’s built-in search engine. Exploring the first results pages with this method will land you the biggest subreddits related to any topics. &lt;strong&gt;To find smaller subreddits using Google, you can use the “-” exclude parameter&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, to find subreddits other than /r/Chatbots on the same topic, the query would be:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“site:reddit.com -reddit.com/r/chatbots chatbot”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/sidebar.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The sidebar of /r/Design&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The sidebar of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/Design/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branching out from known subreddits:&lt;/strong&gt; this technique is useful to find more subreddits relevant to your niche once you have already found the biggest ones. &lt;strong&gt;Most subreddit include a list of related subreddits in their sidebar, check it!&lt;/strong&gt; Keep in mind that each subreddit has its own moderator and might not list related subreddits in the sidebar. See on the left a snapshot of /r/Design Sidebar, listing design related subreddits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subbredit search websites:&lt;/strong&gt; Finding subreddit is a struggle, not only for marketers. Numerous services now exist, including: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://metareddit.com/reddits/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MetaReddit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://snoopsnoo.com/subreddits/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SnoopSnoo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.joelriley.com/subreddit-explorer/index.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SubRedditExplorer&lt;/a&gt;…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subreddits to help you find subreddits&lt;/strong&gt;: yes, you read it right. Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/findareddit/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/findareddit&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/subredditoftheday/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/Subredditoftheday&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-reddits-posts-and-comments-formatting&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Reddit’s posts and comments formatting&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/markdown.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot of Dillinger&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Screenshot of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dillinger.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dillinger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text posts and comments use a specific Markdown formatting. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/wiki/commenting&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The syntax&lt;/a&gt; is straightforward. You can also use a text editor or an online editor. I personally use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dillinger.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dillinger&lt;/a&gt; which displays the markdown and the preview side by side, with the words and characters which is basically all I need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-how-does-the-ad-looklike&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. How does the ad look like?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like organic Reddit posts, &lt;strong&gt;promotional posts can be texts or link&lt;/strong&gt;. Both looks the same on Reddit, only the action on click changes: text post takes you to the Reddit thread, with your text and the comments while link post takes you straight to the linked page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike organic Reddit posts, we’ve seen performing creatives both as link or text post. Below is the preview of how an ad looks like on Reddit. This one is &lt;strong&gt;our top performer for the campaign&lt;/strong&gt;, with a &lt;strong&gt;$0.12 CPC and 0.210% CTR.&lt;/strong&gt; The text is a slightly edited version of the one used in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/learnpython/comments/6bowht/built_my_own_apartment_search_bot_with_python/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the organic reddit post.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ads4.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preview of one the creative used for the House Hunter Reddit Ads campaign&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Preview of one the creative used for the House Hunter Reddit Ads campaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ads are displayed on top of the reddit stream, featuring a “Sponsored” mention to state their nature. Here is an example of an ad displayed on the user side:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ads-preview.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preview of how a Reddit Ad (DuckDuckGo) looks for a user&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Preview of how a Reddit Ad (DuckDuckGo) looks for a user&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-what-others-parameterstargeting-options-can-be-setup&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. What others parameters/targeting options can be set up?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see below, apart from the subreddits targeting we already presented, you need to decide on a bid (maximum price for 1000 impressions, from $0.20 to $100) and a budget for the campaign. It’s straightforward and &lt;strong&gt;people used to advertise on other platforms will quickly find their marks.&lt;/strong&gt; You can also target by interest, exclude specific subreddits, day/time or platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/ads-settings.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Budget, Schedule and Targeting options for the Reddit House Hunter bot campaign&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Budget, Schedule and Targeting options for the Reddit House Hunter bot campaign&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-organic-reddit-vs-redditads&#34;&gt;5. Organic Reddit vs Reddit Ads
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to decide what is the best fit for each post: organic Reddit or Reddit Ads? Here are a few rules I use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If I am promoting a &lt;strong&gt;content&lt;/strong&gt; (= an article that actually provides value), I will try posting it &lt;strong&gt;organically&lt;/strong&gt; on relevant subreddits. If the organic post is successful, I might consider starting an Ad campaign a few days after the post.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If what I am promoting is not a content, but for instance it’s a &lt;strong&gt;product presentation page&lt;/strong&gt; or a new product announcement, I go &lt;strong&gt;straight with Reddit Ads&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, your chances of getting traction with a promotional material are close to none organically.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An organic Reddit post can be the perfect way to test Reddit’s appetite for a topic or a type of content&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are planning to do large scale campaigns on your content (&amp;gt;$100/$150), I recommend you try an organic post first. It will help you figure out performing creatives for your Ads campaign later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-trackingresults&#34;&gt;6. Tracking results
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we conclude with a brief overview of corporate shilling on Reddit, I thought it would be useful to address the question of &lt;strong&gt;link tacking on Reddit&lt;/strong&gt;. I won’t got into the details of UTM codes, Buffer produced a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.bufferapp.com/utm-guide&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;very comprehensive guide already.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While link tracking is a reflex for most marketers, it can be dangerous on Reddit. UTM codes are immensely useful yet &lt;strong&gt;they are visible&lt;/strong&gt;: some subreddits remove any submissions with UTM. In my experience, it’s safer to &lt;strong&gt;completely avoid using link tracking for Reddit organic posts&lt;/strong&gt;. With Google Analytics, you will have enough data anyways to understand your traffic from Reddit anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Reddit Ads though, of course tracking codes are not an issue. Moreover, Reddit &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/redditads/comments/6x1wj9/announcing_the_release_of_the_reddit_conversion/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;recently announced the release of its tracking pixel&lt;/a&gt; along with a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddithelp.com/en/categories/advertising/advertising-101/installing-reddit-conversion-pixel&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;guide on how to install and use it&lt;/a&gt;. I haven’t lead a campaign since the release of the pixel, but since it facilitates the tracking of conversion made from Reddit, it seems to be worth considering for anyone advertising on the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;corporate-shilling-onreddit&#34;&gt;Corporate Shilling on Reddit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the article, I mentioned the aggressive behaviors of certain brands who try to game Reddit’s mechanics for their own profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of actual behavior on the platform, &lt;strong&gt;it translates into bots, vote manipulation and obfuscation&lt;/strong&gt;. Let’s dig into a specific event to make the big picture clearer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-macdonalds-incident&#34;&gt;The MacDonald’s Incident
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;About two months ago, a post appeared on /r/Gaming, entitled &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/HailCorporate/comments/6qmc68/made_my_delivery_drivers_night_by_showing_him_vr/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Made my delivery driver’s night by showing him VR for the first time”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It was a picture, displayed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/mc-astro.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The picture used for MacDonald’s con act on Reddit, to announce the delivery of their burgers on Uber Eats&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The picture used for MacDonald’s con act on Reddit, to announce the delivery of their burgers on Uber Eats&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of things are suspicious, and Reddit was quick to notice. Here are the main flaws:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall disposition seems unnatural, the food is placed at the forefront, with the burger in the hands of the OP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have you ever met anyone having McDonald’s + Wine night?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bottle in the middle of the table is red wine while the glasses contain white wine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A whole bottle of wine and three glasses for a lady presumably eating alone — it was a fun night!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The delivery bag left on the table as a way to broadcast the availability of McDonald’s on UberEats, the goal of this ad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The whole “white girl eating food kindly delivered by his nice black Uber driver who she introduced to a new tech” has a dangerous … lack of taste to it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the reactions were unanimous, &lt;strong&gt;the post still reached the frontpage&lt;/strong&gt; — the whole operation is probably seen as successful for MacDonald’s. Indeed, in the early hours of the post, the masquerade was still uncovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first comment chains read like an ad script. Are they from real users, bots or fake accounts? Probably an &lt;strong&gt;unhealthy mix of all three&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/mc-astro-comment.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;First reactions on MacDonald’s post/ad, screen by /u/SwellandDecay (source: /r/HailCorporate)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
First reactions on MacDonald’s post/ad, screen by /u/SwellandDecay (source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/HailCorporate/comments/6qmc68/made_my_delivery_drivers_night_by_showing_him_vr/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/HailCorporate&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, MacDonald’s strategy relied on three things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finding a way to frame their ad that would resonate with /r/Gaming — here they used VR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a fake/bought/rented account to post it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buying upvotes or using fake and bot accounts to upvote the post to the frontpage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using bots and fake/bought/rented accounts to submit and upvote comments that were in accordance with MacDonald’s message, in order to keep control over the discussion (and &lt;strong&gt;downvote contradicting comments&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combined actions allowed them to have a lot of control over the post and its most visible comments. Yet, even if they managed to reach the frontpage, &lt;strong&gt;the Reddit community was also quick to react&lt;/strong&gt;. The comment now at the top of the post is denouncing the ad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/mc-astro-comment2.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The first comment (10/07/2017) on the MacDonald’s post&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The first comment (10/07/2017) on the MacDonald’s post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reddits-corporate-shilling-watchdogs&#34;&gt;Reddit’s corporate shilling watchdogs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Corporate Shilling got so bad on Reddit, a subreddit emerged to denounce it: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/HailCorporate/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/HailCorporate/&lt;/a&gt;. Here is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/HailCorporate/comments/6qmc68/made_my_delivery_drivers_night_by_showing_him_vr/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the post on /r/HailCorporate addressing the MacDonald’s ad&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem is sadly only beginning. At the same time of the MacDonald’s shadow-ad, &lt;strong&gt;a regular Redditor proved you can buy your way to the frontpage&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/conspiracy/comments/6osp4h/guy_buys_upvotes_on_rvideos_gets_to_front_page/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;He published a video&lt;/a&gt; in which he explained how he did it: buying upvotes. In his own words, “it wasn’t event that much money”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video indeed reached the frontpage showcasing the Redditor explaining Reddit’s flaws. His cat makes an appearance. Yet, it’s hard to know if its because of the upvotes he bought or because Redditors who stumbled upon the video upvoted it as a way to denounce corporate shilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either way, the &lt;strong&gt;upvotes he bought at least helped him give hist post the initial traction&lt;/strong&gt; it needed to reach the frontpage, which is already more than enough to skew Reddit’s natural behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;where-does-reddit-go-fromhere&#34;&gt;Where does Reddit go from here?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/reddit/snoo.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Snoo, Reddit’s mascot&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Snoo, Reddit’s mascot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is far from fixed, as a dumb Google search such as “Reddit buy upvotes” gives you countless of options to chose from. I’m sure the admins are working hard to detect and prevent abuses, but considering the scope of the issue and the stakes, it’s gonna take a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the main reason that motivated me to write this post. I wanted to give to anyone, my feedback and tools to harness the power of Reddit — without falling into the dark side of it. Reddit can generates fascinating discussions and his the home of numerous and dynamic communities built around anything from video games ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://redditmetrics.com/r/gaming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/gaming&lt;/a&gt; — #9 top subreddit), cute animals ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://redditmetrics.com/r/aww&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/aww&lt;/a&gt; — #12), philosophy ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://redditmetrics.com/r/philosophy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/philosophy&lt;/a&gt; — #44) to make-up ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://redditmetrics.com/r/MakeupAddiction&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;/r/MakeupAddiction&lt;/a&gt; — #183).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It reminds me of an concept that fit sadly well to this discussion: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;the tragedy of the commons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, when a marketer find a channel that performs well for his brand, **his first reaction will be to milk it dry **— try to harness the maximum of attention he could get from this channel (hello MacDonald’s). And it’s understandable, who wouldn’t bank on a success?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, doing so quite often &lt;strong&gt;comes at the cost of the channel fundamentals&lt;/strong&gt;— the channel progressively become a flavorless advertising medium instead of what it was supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you consider both the long-term and macro perspective, there is but one option left which is more profitable in the long run, both for the marketer and for the channel: &lt;strong&gt;try to develop the channel as you grow on it&lt;/strong&gt;. It means taking your time, respecting the channel, learning about its customs and of course, when you’re ready, adding you contribution to it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
