<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Compound on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/compound/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Compound on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/compound/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding innovations in money markets to envision their future</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/money-market-innovations/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/money-market-innovations/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/cover-en.png" alt="Featured image of post Understanding innovations in money markets to envision their future" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Money markets like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/compound-v3/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/sky/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt; are the heart of the DeFi ecosystem. For the final user, these protocols have the same function than a classic bank : borrowing or putting sleepy money at work by lendind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, &lt;strong&gt;the analogy stops immediately at this functional comparison&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the underlying logic of money markets has nothing to do with the functioning of a bank. Money markets benefit from all the advantages of DeFi and, in particular, the transparency and accessibility of all operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a user borrows on Aave, &lt;strong&gt;the protocol does not need to know his age or identity&lt;/strong&gt;: validate all conditions is enough ! It means that you just have to put enough collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same way, a user who deposits stablecoins on Aave to generate a return by lending them to others does not trust anyone: he can check at any time which amounts are borrowed by each address to &lt;strong&gt;ensure the solvency of the entire system.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem basic to a DeFian, but it is a real paradigm shift. In traditional finance, we have no choice but to trust a third party (auditor, rating agency, etc.) to obtain this kind of information - with the reliability that we know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-money-markets&#34;&gt;Discovering money markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have already talked a lot about money markets on this blog, especially in the article that offers a qualitative methodology to evaluate their risks : &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or the one about the different services of abstraction and distribution of the inherent risks in money markets: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/risk-tranching.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Risk? Yes please, but exactly how I like it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, money markets are constantly evolving, both through their updates and through the contribution of third-party services built on top. In addition, new and more challenging money markets are being launched to cover needs that are still unsatisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is precisely our purpose today: &lt;strong&gt;understanding the essential innovations underway in money markets in order to better envision their future development.&lt;/strong&gt; Rather than making an exhaustive list, I propose to look at a selection of projects that I think are relevant to understanding the industry evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovations-built-on-existing-money-markets&#34;&gt;Innovations built on existing money markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Money markets may seem really complex at first glance. The curious are most often frightened by the risks of liquidating the collateral when its value is no longer sufficient to secure the borrowed amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;easy-loan-positions-management-with-defisaver&#34;&gt;Easy loan positions management with DeFiSaver
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many DeFi users have not yet fully understood the issues at stake here. Many still think that liquidation can be total and sudden. In addition to information and education, tools for managing one&amp;rsquo;s positions help users to feel more confident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, tools that facilitate and automate the management of borrowing positions on money markets have emerged very quickly, such as DeFi Saver. I already talked about it last year in this article &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/leveraging-ETH.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFiSaver works as a proxy between the user and money markets. It allows new features such as the well-loved &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo;: when the position falls below a user-defined collateralization limit, DeFiSaver automatically rebalances the position with a flash loan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In concrete terms, this function sells a part of the user&amp;rsquo;s collateral to pay off some debt and return to a collateralization ratio decided earlier. Such a tool allows the most aggressive or worried borrowers to sleep much more peacefully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reclaiming-liquidation-with-bprotocol&#34;&gt;Reclaiming liquidation with B.Protocol
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although DeFiSaver is very useful, it remains a tool that does not fundamentally change the way the underlying services work. Other projects go further, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bprotocol.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BProtocol&lt;/a&gt; which I discovered recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is very simple: instead of borrowing directly from Maker, the user goes through the BProtocol contract. Funds available to the protocol allows it to &lt;strong&gt;liquidate the user&amp;rsquo;s position (if necessary) before other liquidators do so.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/bprotocolexplainer.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bprotocol explainer&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is usually a gas war between different liquidators becomes a more predictable operation. It also allows &lt;strong&gt;redistributing part of the liquidation premium to the user himself rather than to the miners.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On money markets, users deposit collateral to borrow. If the value of the collateral is too low compared to the borrowed amount, a liquidation is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually this liquidation is at the expense of another type of user who gets paid (premium liquidation).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea, simple at a high level, is nonetheless very reassuring for users while allowing for &amp;ldquo;professionalization&amp;rdquo; of liquidations which become more predictable. There are now about $100M of assets managed by the protocol which already covers Maker and Compound (Aave is coming soon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovations-of-the-makerdao-model&#34;&gt;Innovations of the MakerDAO model
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;MakerDAO is probably the best-known money market, but it is also a special one. Indeed, MakerDAO serves a dual function: the service allows borrowing just like Aave or Compound, however &lt;strong&gt;no one lends you anything when you borrow on Maker - borrowers directly mint a currency (DAI) that corresponds to their debt.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, while allowing borrowing, MakerDAO also produces a stable asset, the DAI, which is indexed on dollar. Although DAI has its limitations, it is less centralized and requires less trust than stablecoin models like USDC. This is why Maker&amp;rsquo;s model has been taken up many times to serve new purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mimo-capital-down-with-the-dollar-up-with-the-euro&#34;&gt;Mimo Capital: down with the dollar, up with the euro!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until now, the dollar has been the reference fiat currency for DeFi. Almost all stablecoin projects aim to produce an asset that tracks the value of the dollar. In addition, it is also the dollar value of volatile assets that is considered by borrowing systems to determine the collateralization ratio, both on Maker and Compound or Aave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar being the most common and best known fiat currency, it made sense to start with but it is time to go beyond that to meet the needs of all types of users and make DeFi more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely what a project like Mimo Capital is looking for, as it proposes &lt;strong&gt;a system similar to MakerDAO but where the Euro is the base currency&lt;/strong&gt;, instead of the dollar. This means that the stablecoin produced by the borrowers - the PAR - follows the Euro, but also that the internal prices of the system are in €, as the value of the collateral used (ETH, wBTC or USDC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/mimo-capital-par.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Mimo-Capital-PAR&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mimo is not coming up in an empty market as Euro stablecoins are beginning to emerge. In addition to Mimo&amp;rsquo;s PAR, there is the EURS stablecoin which follows a centralized model: each EURS in circulation is backed by a Euro fiat owned by the issuer. Thus, &lt;strong&gt;yield opportunities are starting to emerge via Euro exposures&lt;/strong&gt;, for example the sEUR/EURS pool on Curve also accessible via vaults on StakeDAO or Harvest Finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of &lt;strong&gt;a protocol like Mimo allows European investors to consider a circuit with the Euro as the reference currency&lt;/strong&gt;. Using their ETH or wBTC as collateral, they can borrow PAR (stablecoin €) and make it productive via, for now, two liquidity pools on Balancer, but eventually, probably more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mimo is still a fairly new system with approximately €25 million of collateral deposited as collateral for approximately 12.5 million PARs issued (€). The governance token associated with the service - MIMO - is currently distributed to any active vault holder as well as to liquidity providers on the PAR/ETH and PAR/USDC pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-fiat-currencies-with-reflexer&#34;&gt;Beyond fiat currencies with Reflexer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Switching from dollar to euro is good, going completely without a fiat currency reference is even better&lt;/strong&gt; This is exactly what Reflexer, another service inspired by the Maker model, offers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no reference price here. The price of the RAI (borrower-generated asset) is governed directly by the market (average price on the RAI/ETH pair). The system also has its &amp;ldquo;internal&amp;rdquo; price, the &lt;em&gt;Redemption Price&lt;/em&gt; - the rate used when users directly mint RAI (by depositing ETH as collateral).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/raiprice.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;reflexer RAI price&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various parameters in the Reflexer system adjust to &lt;strong&gt;converge the two prices over time, or at least keep them within a narrow range&lt;/strong&gt;. While this approach is much more difficult for the user to learn, it is completely uncorrelated with the dollar (or any other fiat currency), which is valuable in itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better understand Reflexer, I recommend you to read my previous article on stable assets:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/pegged-assets.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp;amp; endgame?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;new-generation-of-money-markets&#34;&gt;New generation of money markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we have considered innovations built on the existing core money markets or directly inspired by their models. There is also a whole new wave of money markets exploring different approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I therefore propose to consider two final projects that bring real fundamental changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alchemix-productive-assets-as-collateral&#34;&gt;Alchemix: productive assets as collateral?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t start this section with another project than Alchemix! The idea of this project is as simple as powerful:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if, instead of taking non-productive collateral, we only took productive collateral &lt;strong&gt;like a stablecoin that produces a return ?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our collateral now has a return: what if the return on the collateral &lt;strong&gt;was used to pay off the loan?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And there you have it: &lt;strong&gt;A loan that pays for itself over time!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/alchemix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Alchemix overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alchemix launched by accepting yDAI (DAI deposited on Yearn Finance) as collateral. Depositors can borrow up to 50% of the value of their yDAI in AlUSD, another stablecoin dollar. T&lt;strong&gt;heir collateral is not at risk, and the loan pays for itself through the interest generated by the yDAI: it takes about 3 years at the current return rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alchemix quickly became a very popular service, especially for &lt;strong&gt;proceeding large purchases without spending crypto&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s just a matter of patience. Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Bob, a DeFi farmer who has worked hard: he now wants to enjoy the fruits of his labor. He wants to raise $50,000 to buy a car. Rather than taking $50,000 directly from his assets, Bob can achieve the same result without spending anything thanks to Alchemix :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob deposits 100,000 DAI on Alchemix, which are then deployed on Yearn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This allows him to borrow up to 50,000 AlUSD, which he can use to buy his car.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bob just has to wait while the yDAI returns pay back his loan. In ~3 years, once the debt is paid off, he can get his original 100,000 DAI back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Such flow allows to spend immediately without any other cost than the fact of locking about 2 times the amount mobilized within Alchemix.&lt;/strong&gt; The future of programmable money is live!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is so powerful and innovative that many still find it hard to believe. The feedback from Alchemix users still attracts many skeptics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquity-efficiency-at-all-costs&#34;&gt;Liquity: efficiency at all costs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; is another money market that innovates on several levels. The fundamental concept to understand here is that &lt;strong&gt;liquidations are automated and therefore much more predictable and quick.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; to offer &lt;strong&gt;lower collateralization ratios&lt;/strong&gt; than other systems, or to put it another way: Liquity users can raise more dollars per ETH deposited than on a system like Maker:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The maximum loan-to-value ratio (maximum LTV) determines the borrowing power of a collateral. A maximum loan-to-value of 50% means that up to half of the dollar value of the deposited collateral can be borrowed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maker : minimal ratio = 150% ⇒ approximately 66% max LTV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity : Collateralisation minimal ratio = 110% ⇒ approximately 90% max LTV&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquity also innovates on the fees side since &lt;strong&gt;the loans are interest free&lt;/strong&gt; unlike other systems. On Maker/ETH for example, the stability fee is 5.5%. If you borrow 10,000 DAI today, you will have to pay back 10,550 DAI in 1 year (if the fees do not change).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-innovations/liquity.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Liquity&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, there is no stability fee on Liquity. Instead, users pay &lt;strong&gt;a one-time, immediate fee when borrowing&lt;/strong&gt;. This fee depends on the &amp;ldquo;base rate&amp;rdquo; which is governed by the protocol directly. It is currently 0.5%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Liquity, those who deposit ETH to mint LUSD can then deploy them into the Stability Pool (LUSD) or the LUSD/ETH pair for remuneration in LQTY - the service&amp;rsquo;s native token.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; The LQTY can then be staked to &lt;strong&gt;get a share of the LUSD paid to the protocol when a loan is contracted&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the redemption fee (ETH ↔ LUSD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquity is a so-called &amp;ldquo;governance mimized&amp;rdquo; platform - LQTY is therefore not a governance token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Liquity also innovates in terms of decentralization since &lt;strong&gt;the interface used to access the service is not managed by the team behind the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;. Different frontends operated by third parties are offered while the team focuses on the protocol itself. This ensures that many mirrors exist so that the service is always easily accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-next-step-to-understand-money-markets&#34;&gt;The next step to understand money markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you have found this introduction to the latest innovations in the money markets informative. I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to see the offering growing and becoming denser to cover ever more varied needs. Money markets are essential elements of DeFi, and with the growth of the space, they will become more and more preponderant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, let me remind you that in addition to functionality, &lt;strong&gt;risk management is the essential element that differentiates each money market&lt;/strong&gt;. Before you start spending large sums of money on them, I invite you to familiarize yourself with the associated risks. It&amp;rsquo;s a good thing, I wrote what remains to this day &lt;strong&gt;the most exhaustive and comprehensible synthesis to understand the risks incurred in the money markets&lt;/strong&gt;, I invite you to read it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find more info &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.liquity.org/faq/lqty-distribution-and-rewards&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;regarding the LQTY token distribution&lt;/a&gt; in the official documentation.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/money-god-meme.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to cover an essential topic for Ethereum and other blockchains and often misunderstood: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; assets&lt;/strong&gt;, which track the price of a reference asset. Before looking at the different approaches to producing such an asset, we&amp;rsquo;ll first start with a higher level of analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are such assets needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are they used for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we want to standardize non-native Ethereum assets on this chain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these foundations are established, we will have all the tools to &lt;strong&gt;figure out the different methods and what is at stake&lt;/strong&gt;.. I will conclude with a more detailed analysis of a project that seems to me very relevant and innovative : the RAI of Reflexer Labs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already familiar with the different pegging mechanisms, you can jump &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34; &gt;directly to the section on Reflexer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assets-standardization-on-the-ethereums-blockchain&#34;&gt;Assets standardization on the Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s blockchain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volume of issuance and use of pegged-assets has exploded last year, but before we look at what they are actually used for, let&amp;rsquo;s understand why. The simplest use case is to produce a stable asset, most often indexed to the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, &lt;strong&gt;the method used at a high level is tokenization&lt;/strong&gt;: we represent an asset that comes from another chain / world on Ethereum, such as wBTC (corresponding to 1 BTC on the Bitcoin chain) or USDC (corresponding to 1 USD in Circle&amp;rsquo;s bank account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;addresses one of the most common concerns for the general public: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cryptos are volatile assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;the rise of stablecoins has gone hand in hand with the rise of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;, why? According to me, there are many reasons, the main ones being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrowings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable assets can be very productive in DeFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-borrowings-mostly-in-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Why are borrowings mostly in stablecoins?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The money markets allow their users to borrow assets using other assets as collateral. The most frequent use case corresponds to the following pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user deposits a volatile asset, such as ETH, wBTC or LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He uses it as collateral to &lt;strong&gt;borrow a stable asset, like USDC or DAI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so? To put it simply, few people are fond of the risks associated with price changes. &lt;strong&gt;Borrowing an asset, if you then mobilize it, is like shorting it&lt;/strong&gt;. No problem with stablecoins - in theory - but the reality is quite different with a non-stable asset: if the price goes down, good for you: the debt will only be cheaper to repay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the other way around, the scenario can be frightening since &lt;strong&gt;you can end up with a debt that increases&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you borrow 1000 UNI when one UNI is worth $20. You sell them for another token, for example stablecoins. So here you are with $20,000 DAI that you mobilize in DeFi for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You hold your debt for several months and now you want to pay it off. Except that one UNI is now worth $30 and you no longer have any: you have to buy some back on the markets to pay off the debt and close the position. &lt;strong&gt;The debt is always paid in the borrowed asset&lt;/strong&gt;: you therefore owe 1,000 UNIs at $30 per unit or 30,000 DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am ignoring the loan interest&amp;rsquo;s here for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake. In reality you should pay back slightly more UNI, according to the interest rate and the length of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yield-farming-with-stable-assets&#34;&gt;Yield-farming with stable-assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the first point understood, the second one makes perfect sense.: &lt;strong&gt;a lot of people are borrowing stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;, so that means that on the other side of the market people are lending them out, for attractive interest rates considering the demand. For example, on Aave, one of the main money markets, there has been &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity crunch in stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; almost since the launch of v2. Depositors enjoy an average annualized return of about 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is quite similar elsewhere with differences due to the specificities of each money market. Nevertheless, the liquidity crisis on stablecoins goes far beyond Aave: it potentially extends to the whole DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;there is no shortage of opportunities to produce a return with stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about loans here, but it is also possible to bring liquidity to stablecoin pairs and even combine the two approaches to increase returns with a product like Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/curve-yield-pool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-yield-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explosion-of-the-pegged-assets-use-in-2020&#34;&gt;Explosion of the pegged-assets use in 2020
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, we have seen a real explosion in the issuance and use of pegged-assets in 2020. On the one hand, more and more projects are being launched to propose &lt;strong&gt;new asset types or new approaches to represent them&lt;/strong&gt;. On the other hand, the scenarios for using these pegged-assets are multiplying thanks to the growth of Curve money markets, vaults like those offered by Yearn or Harvest, and other even more complex DeFi products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name but one, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://alchemix.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alchemix&lt;/a&gt;, a new synthetic asset service that allows &lt;strong&gt;loans secured by your future return&lt;/strong&gt;. Let me explain: with Alchemix, everything starts with a stable asset that produces a return. They chose the yDAI to start with (DAI productive thanks to the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user starts by depositing yDAI. He can then &lt;strong&gt;give up his future return&lt;/strong&gt; to borrow up to 50% of the deposited value. His loan is &lt;strong&gt;reimbursed automatically thanks to the interest generated by the yDAI&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, since he has access to 50% of the deposited value immediately (borrowed in alUSD), he can put it to work to increase the return of the entire strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of product allows for an interesting across time arbitrage and leads to an even greater demand for stablecoins: at the launch of Alchemix, deposits in the yDAI vault took off up to the maximum capacity available for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about stablecoins so far, but a similar scenario has played out on other pegged-assets like tokenized BTC on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/stablecoin-growth.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stablecoin-growth-ethereum-messari&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the impressive growth of DeFi, we can only expect the demand for this type of asset to grow ever faster. So let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the different approaches used to produce them to understand their trade-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-different-methods-to-produce-pegged-assets&#34;&gt;The different methods to produce pegged-assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, the vast majority of this demand for stable assets is being addressed with solutions based on a 1:1 match requiring trust. Thus, it is &lt;strong&gt;mostly USDT ($38.5B issued) and USDC ($9.4B) that are leading the way&lt;/strong&gt;, well ahead of DAI ($2.7B). The same goes for Bitcoin, without going into detail, all the most used solutions require trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pegged-assets&amp;quot; are assets that follow the price of another via a mechanism called &amp;ldquo;pegging&amp;rdquo;. Therefore, the &amp;ldquo;peg&amp;rdquo; is the value that the asset must maintain, for example $1 for stablecoins that follow the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growing variety of approaches are being explored to produce a pegged-asset with less compromise. They are generally grouped into large families that correspond to the main method used to maintain the peg. However, as these approaches develop, the boundaries between them become blurred as several projects explore &lt;strong&gt;hybrid approaches mixing several elements of each&lt;/strong&gt;. We will start from the simplest to understand and progressively go to the most complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-a-trusted-third-party-11-ratio&#34;&gt;Using a trusted third party (1:1 ratio)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The peg is easily maintained and rather stable. The system is solvent at all times (-&amp;gt; 1 USD in the bank for 1 USDC issued for example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; The system requires a central trusted intermediary - the issuing organization. This same organization relies on another intermediary, the bank where the USD are deposited. In addition, the presence of a trusted intermediary creates a risk: is it reliable? transparent? The risk goes beyond image, it can also be legal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has already been detailed enough, so I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to the more complex methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins-produced-by-over-collateralization-maker-dai&#34;&gt;Stablecoins produced by over-collateralization: Maker DAI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The system no longer involves a central trusted intermediary (at least initially) &amp;amp; still manages to more or less maintain the peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; It will require &lt;strong&gt;always more $ collateral than $ (DAI) produced (over-collateralization)&lt;/strong&gt;. Governance risks. Risks at the liquidation level, carried out by third parties. The system is as trustless as its most used collateral. Maker now accepts censorable collateral (wBTC, USDC, etc.) which reintroduces a trust risk into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before algorithmic stablecoins, MakerDAO is a pioneer when thinking about how to &lt;strong&gt;produce a stable asset with less trust needed in the system than 1:1 approaches&lt;/strong&gt;. Maker is a more complex service because beyond the DAI - the stablecoin issued by the system, it also allows its users to use different assets to borrow (technically mint) DAIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it recreates risks and dangers to maintain the peg of the DAI. Many improvements have been proposed and implemented since the beginning, which allows DAI to be much more stable now than in its early days. Nevertheless, the scaling of DAI has come with additional compromises in terms of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-innovative-approaches&#34;&gt;More innovative approaches
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the approaches are more diversified - I group them into two families: the algorithmic approaches already well studied on my blog and the hybrid approaches. Both are based on an essential concept to understand: the &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; of these systems is a smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-smart-contract-as-central-bank&#34;&gt;A smart contract as &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use the words &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; because it evokes the essential concept here: the body that issues money and implements the monetary policy of the system is a smart contract. This allows for great transparency and visibility on the actions related to monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the systems presented below, you really need to understand this: &lt;strong&gt;the decisions to create or destroy new stablecoins are &amp;ldquo;taken&amp;rdquo; by a smart contract&lt;/strong&gt; - it alone has this ability to issue (and destroy / burn in some systems) tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say that the smart contract takes &amp;ldquo;decisions&amp;rdquo;, I must explain myself : &lt;strong&gt;to be more precise, one could say that it reacts to the evolution of various measurable parameters&lt;/strong&gt;. The decisions of the smart contract are therefore transparent and predictable. A change in the rules governing it is possible but only via a governance vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most often, the main parameter taken into account is simply &lt;strong&gt;the price of the stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, in early algorithmic systems like Basis (BAC is the stablecoin), the rules are simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If BAC &amp;gt; $1, then the system issues and distributes new BAC to try to bring the price back towards $1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When BAC &amp;lt; $1 the system destroys BAC to create upward pressure. The destruction is not direct but voluntary: the actors in the system are encouraged to burn their BAC for a coupon (BAB) corresponding to 1 BAC + premium, which they can collect only when BAC has a sustained price above the dollar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more background on this &amp;ldquo;smart contract central bank&amp;rdquo; idea, you can read my first article on algorithmic stablecoins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;L&amp;rsquo;état et le futur des stablecoins algorithmiques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;algorithmic-approaches&#34;&gt;Algorithmic approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; This makes systems without a central trust intermediary possible and thus opens the way to truly trustless pegged-assets. Community governance possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; Sustained peg loss or difficulty maintaining peg. Possible governance attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I analyze the main approaches to produce algorithmic stablecoins in a dedicated article :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖ L&amp;rsquo;histoire de deux modèles de seigneuriage : Basis contre ESD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, projects like ESD, DSD, or Basis Cash were the pioneers of algorithmic stablecoins. However, all of these systems are now in a bit of an abyss: &lt;strong&gt;their stablecoins have been worth well under a dollar for a long time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/bac-90days.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bac-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their users are looking forward to a V2 that will bring stablecoin back to the dollar like the messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hybrid-approaches&#34;&gt;Hybrid approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The best of both worlds?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages / Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; A new potentially central and  intermediate point of trust appears in the system. You what happened next&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the current limitations of first generation algorithmic stablecoins, another approach has successfully emerged: the hybrid approach.  These are intrinsically algorithmic systems that &lt;strong&gt;include nonetheless a reserve in stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. (different from the system) used to maintain the peg: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://samkazemian.medium.com/frax-v2-algorithmic-market-operations-b84521ed7133&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pioneer in this field is Frax. With Frax, &lt;strong&gt;when FRAX trades above the dollar the system itself sells some to accumulate USDC&lt;/strong&gt;. This helps to bring the price down while building up a reserve of stablecoins not exposed to the system itself. Thus, if FRAX is trading &lt;strong&gt;below the dollar, the system can buy FRAX directly&lt;/strong&gt; on the market (using its stock of USDC) to bring the price back down to $1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/frax-price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;frax-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this approach has the &lt;strong&gt;merit of efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; (FRAX has maintained its peg very well since launch), it reintroduces a trusted intermediary into the mechanism. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not a bank like with Tether, but it&amp;rsquo;s still necessary trust in the system. What happens if the USDC balance of Frax is seized or frozen: could the system survive it? For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, yes it is technically (and legally) possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remain very high-level on FRAX and describe the system mostly as it was in the beginning. Many integrations have been implemented or are being considered, such as the ability to mint FRAX directly into the FRAX-Tornado anonymity set (directly into TornadoCash) to offer a potentially more confidential stablecoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34;&gt;Focus on Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s RAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To finish this article, which I hope will be instructive, I suggest to analyze an innovative system: Reflexer RAI. It is a similar approach to MakerDAO, in the sense that the stable asset is produced by over-collateralization. Nevertheless, it brings many improvements over the Maker model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trustless collateral&lt;/strong&gt;: Until now, RAI only accepts ETH as collateral. This means that 100% of the collaterals in the system are not censurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond the dollar&lt;/strong&gt;: the asset produced by the system does not follow the dollar (which is not really stable itself). The price of the RAI is determined by a consensus established by the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Money God&lt;/strong&gt; : just like algorithmic stablecoins, the system reacts to different observed parameters. However, just like MakerDAO, here it is the users themselves who directly hit the RAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance&lt;/strong&gt; : the token of the Reflexer system (FLX), which will be distributed to the users, is intended to be used to progressively decentralize the governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t panic if you don&amp;rsquo;t immediately understand why this system is innovative and significant, we will explore each of these points in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;censorship-resistant-collateral&#34;&gt;Censorship-resistant collateral
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initially, MakerDAO only accepted Ether as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;. With the first significant update of the system - the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/whitepaper/White%20Paper%20-The%20Maker%20Protocol_%20MakerDAO%E2%80%99s%20Multi-Collateral%20Dai%20%28MCD%29%20System-FINAL-%20021720.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Multi Collateral DAI&lt;/a&gt; - more tokens became usable as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community was perplexed by this decision, especially because of the choice of accepted tokens. Thus, BAT was one of the first new collateral while LINK, a token with volume and liquidity already far superior to BAT at the time, only arrived much later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond this &lt;strong&gt;difficult to understand valuation&lt;/strong&gt;, the crux of the problem is that &lt;strong&gt;many collaterals now accepted are censorable&lt;/strong&gt;: wBTC, RenBTC, USDC, TUSD, etc. This reduces the trustlessness of MakerDAO since at different times up to 50% of all DAIs were minted from censorable collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure is now reduced, but the concern remains. Furthermore, the addition of a special USDC vault was criticized during Black Thursday for helping DAI regain its peg - but it also made MakerDAO even more dependent on such collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Reflexer also fits in as &lt;strong&gt;a reaction to this &amp;ldquo;drift&amp;rdquo; of MakerDAO&lt;/strong&gt;: for now, only ETH is accepted to open a vault. I will be surprised if the team or the DAO vote to accept censorable collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-the-us-dollar&#34;&gt;Beyond the US Dollar
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Reflexer goes much further than DAI in its quest for stability. Indeed, the dollar itself does not have a stable value, because of the continuous production of new units which leads to inflation: thus $10,000 in 1950 is equivalent in purchasing power to almost $110,000 in 2021 (3.42% inflation per year on average over the period).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An asset that is intended to be stable must therefore go beyond the limitations of the dollar and this is precisely what RAI does&lt;/strong&gt;: it does not follow the price of the dollar. The price of RAI is determined by pure social consensus: the system takes into account the observed price of the ETH/RAI pair (market price) as well as an internal price target (redemption rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are often gaps between the two, which creates an incentive to beat the RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/reflexer-spread.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;reflexer-spread&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore, RAI is obviously not a stablecoin, It is not a pegged-asset either&lt;/strong&gt;. There are not enough words to describe RAI accurately, but let me try. RAI is an abstraction on the ETH which is intended to be more stable than the ETH, while maintaining its trustlessness (with time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-hail-the-money-god&#34;&gt;All Hail the Money God
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Money God&amp;rdquo; is the term used to refer to the set of rules that govern the Reflexer system. The memetic potential is also enormous. To remain quite synthetic, the Money God is lenient towards those who follow a perennial and long-term logic on the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the distribution mechanism of the Reflexer token, FLX, was recently modified to better align incentives (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;). The essence of the change is to better compensate those who perpetuate the system, i.e.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit ETH to mint RAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the RAI minted + the equivalent in ETH in the liquidity pool on Uniswap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of March 8, 100% of FLX is being distributed to those who follow this scenario. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/stefanionescu/e66204be990f4bc113a022341cb39186&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The history of FLX retroactive distribution strategies is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-de-governance-plan&#34;&gt;The De-Governance Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the important technical innovation on Reflexer, barely explored here, I particularly appreciate &lt;strong&gt;their approach to governance and decentralization of the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, as described by Stefan one of its architects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The principle of “ungovernance” comes from our desire to progressively remove human control from the RAI system, thus making it socially scalable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has established &lt;strong&gt;a plan with concrete and dated goals&lt;/strong&gt; to achieve this end. The first step is to make the system&amp;rsquo;s liquidation and taxation mechanisms &amp;ldquo;governance minimized&amp;rdquo; - only a few parameters will remain changeable via governance (voting of FLX holders) from this point on. The target date is April 17, 2022, a little over a year after the initial launch of RAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each step, the scenario is similar: a critical mechanism of the system is &amp;ldquo;governance-minimized&amp;rdquo; before it is put back under the full control of FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the details of this plan here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following and waiting for Reflexer for over a year, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally tell you about it, and please forgive me for the delay: I wanted to put it in context to make sure everyone grasps the innovation brought by this protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article &lt;strong&gt;does not constitute investment advice&lt;/strong&gt;. I have no credentials in this area: they do not yet exist for DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am discussing the mechanics of several protocols and what they allow for or envision in the future. Even if I mention tokens, ditto: I discuss their utility or tokenomics but &lt;strong&gt;never their relevance as an investment&lt;/strong&gt;. On this topic, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helps you better understand the rise of pegged-assets on Ethereum - it is essential. It&amp;rsquo;s also critical to understand the different trade-off sets associated with each approach: they are all potentially more or less relevant, depending on your situation and needs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whether you are convinced by Reflexer or not, I strongly encourage you to dig into this system, just as I regularly invite you to explore the workings of Aave, Curve or Unslashed. All four are very relevant and innovative systems: understanding them in depth will allow you to internalize many essential things  to understand decentralized finance in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/money-markets-risk/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/money-markets-risk/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/cover.gif" alt="Featured image of post Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Money markets are at the heart of DeFi. From a high-level perspective, yes, they simply enable the borrowing and lending of various assets. Yet &lt;strong&gt;those functions are like the two primitive verbs of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; at the base of pretty much all use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three major money markets right now in DeFi: Aave, Compound &amp;amp; Cream. Yet all the following services use them, one way or another: Yearn Finance, Curve Finance, Alpha Finance, Harvest Finance, DeFiSaver, Saffron, 88MPH, Idle Finance, etc. To put it simply - &lt;strong&gt;money markets are one of the root-level of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money markets are amazing - simple yet very intricate. In this article, I try to provide a framework and some clues to assess the risk at different levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To dive more into the service layer currently being built on top of money markets, feel free to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-risk-scoring-is-broken&#34;&gt;I/ Risk Scoring is Broken
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the risk analysis framework, let&amp;rsquo;s quickly discuss the current leading solution used to evaluate risk in DeFi: Consensys CodeFi DeFiScore.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DeFiScore is undisputedly compromised since it&amp;rsquo;s still giving DAI a higher rate on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/compound-v3/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt; than &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; even with the oracle failure on the Compound side and the arrival of the Safety Module on Aave&amp;rsquo;s side:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consensys CodeFi team was notified a few days ago&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, acknowledged the issue&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; but yet &lt;strong&gt;refused any immediate to update the website even with just notice or disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;. Instead, one of their members proposed a 500 USDC bounty open for anyone willing to update the formula&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. It has yet to be claimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that quantitative approaches so far have failed. They must achieve both sustainability (if the formula stays consistent it allows historical comparisons) and adaptability (yet the risk parameters are always evolving): it&amp;rsquo;s not an easy feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will not delve into the depths of risk scoring, as there is a dedicated article exploring what a decent DeFi-native risk scoring system looks like coming out shortly on this blog (hint: it does not exist yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-appreciating-the-safety-of-a-money-market&#34;&gt;II/ Appreciating the Safety of a Money Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s painful to hear, but since quantitative analysis is unhelpful, you have to resort to a qualitative approaches for each project. The good news is there aren&amp;rsquo;t many money markets in DeFi worth looking at:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cream / Iron Bank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each of these, you have to look at them holistically. I propose an approach that is &lt;strong&gt;purely mine&lt;/strong&gt;, using &lt;strong&gt;8 different dimensions all critical to the safety of assets&lt;/strong&gt; committed to the money market analyzed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protocol access &amp;amp; permissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oracles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidation mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collateral listing &amp;amp; risk analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safety module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expanded insurance ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native token risk management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community &amp;amp; Ecosystem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what we have today is essentially a comprehensive framework you can use to assess the safety of a given money market. Feel free to challenge me on any item. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Necessary Disclaimer: This is not investment advice.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost no one is qualified to assess risks in DeFi: even &amp;ldquo;institutions&amp;rdquo; doing it like the DeFiscore are way off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This content is intended to help you better understand and appreciate the risk &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;by yourself&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, the most reliable way to do so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iia-protocol-access--permissions&#34;&gt;II.A/ Protocol Access &amp;amp; Permissions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the very base level, you want to know who can update the protocol core parameters (-&amp;gt; the contracts), and the different limits associated with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, there&amp;rsquo;s usually a &lt;strong&gt;timelock&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that any significant change only applies after a set duration. For the administrative functions of the protocol, you need to make sure that they are &lt;strong&gt;community-owned&lt;/strong&gt;, which usually means &lt;strong&gt;governed by a multisig&lt;/strong&gt; of designed community members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This section also includes everything related to &lt;strong&gt;the &amp;ldquo;opsec&amp;rdquo; of the wallets/people&lt;/strong&gt; governing the multisig. &amp;ldquo;Opsec&amp;rdquo; is short for &amp;ldquo;operations security&amp;rdquo; - it&amp;rsquo;s about the safety of everything digital interfaces related to the holders of these keys. Can they be hacked? Impersonated? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a matter is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;CRITICAL&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, as we saw recently with the CEO of Nexus Mutual: his laptop was compromised, allowing the hacker to submit a fraudulent transaction on top of a real transaction he signed.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have yet to see significant attacks based on social engineering in DeFi but expect them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transparency on the decisions of the protocol is key too: we address it below in the community &amp;amp; DAO section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article focuses on mature money markets like Aave or Compound. Newer projects might be less decentralized, and that can be a good thing - you might want some control and rollback options for a newer project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-protocol-accesses--decentralization&#34;&gt;Assessing the protocol accesses &amp;amp; decentralization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Assess on a protocol/team-basis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Potentially all funds deposited on the market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Not yet 🤞&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to evalutating opsec and decentralization plan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChrisBlec&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chris Blec&lt;/a&gt; is your guy. He&amp;rsquo;s uncompromising on opsec, and produced many helpful contributions on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/13S7NRk1girTdQMajnVdU5JRlVO5BG_uJKhTO2Ef10b0/edit?usp=sharing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;summarized overview of the situation for the main DeFi projects here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to wrap this up, here are some good questions to ask to assess the safety of a money market at the protocol &amp;amp; permission level:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who can update the contracts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do they have a credible opsec?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any drain function in the contracts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do the administrative functions do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How decentralized is the process to create a new lending market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iib-oracles&#34;&gt;II.B/ Oracles
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, the oracles are the source for &amp;ldquo;outside truths&amp;rdquo;. &lt;strong&gt;Blockchains are only aware of themselves&lt;/strong&gt;, so for Ethereum, the price of ETH in dollars (or any other token) is technically an &amp;ldquo;outside truth&amp;rdquo; you need to bring on-chain in a &lt;strong&gt;safe and verifiable manner&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s precisely what oracles do!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s essential, as the &lt;strong&gt;perceived price&lt;/strong&gt; delivered by the oracle is the &lt;strong&gt;source of truth for the protocol&amp;rsquo;s liquidation decisions&lt;/strong&gt;. If the oracle says DAI is worth 1.30, then you are liquidated even if your DAI-borrowing position was safe on a $1 DAI and DAI is still actually worth $1 on the markets: the oracle is the source of truth. It happened already with Compound, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a theoretical concern.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news here is that the answer is quite simple: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/chainlink-oracles/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ChainLink&lt;/a&gt; is widely recognized as the most credible decentralized oracle solution, so any money market not using at least partly their price feeds is gambling with its users&amp;rsquo; money, as Compound did with significant lossses. It seems like the situation has not improved - despite the failure Compound still uses the same centralized oracle (Coinbase) and a proposal suggesting a switch to ChainLink was refused. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-oracles&#34;&gt;Assessing oracles
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Significant (most impacting sub-theme to date).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: market-based, potentially whole markets can be drained/affected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, on Compound.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can assess the oracles for a money market with the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the source of truth for prices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How reliable is that source?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any history of abusive liquidation (stemming from oracle issues)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iic-liquidation-mechanisms&#34;&gt;II.C/ Liquidation Mechanisms
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The liquidation mechanisms are critical too, but they only happen once a liquidation can be triggered - which depends on the price the oracle returns. So the &lt;strong&gt;liquidation mechanism cannot make up for a faulty oracle&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to first understand that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, different money markets handle liquidations differently. They have different delays, fees, and restrictions with their liquidations. For instance, the Maker oracle/liquidation (internal system) has a one-hour delay to prevent flash liquidations during unsustained flash crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, liquidation is not sudden neither an all-or-nothing event. There are several buffers to your positions, for instance on Aave, every token has a &lt;strong&gt;maximum loan to value&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;liquidation threshold&lt;/strong&gt;at least slightly higher.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with USDC as collateral, for instance, there is a 5% spread between the two - the max LTV is 80% (&lt;em&gt;max $8000 worth borrowed from a 10 000 USDC collateral&lt;/em&gt;), while the liquidation threshold is 85% (&lt;em&gt;= liquidation if collateral value &amp;lt; $8500&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/aave-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave USDC collateral parameters&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It gives borrowers using USDC as collateral another 5% margin so that even if the oracle reports $0.97 no abusive liquidations would occur. The situation is similar in other money markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-liquidation-mechanisms&#34;&gt;Assessing liquidation mechanisms
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Mostly depends on the collateral price action - a flash crash could trigger a chain of liquidations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Significant (the money market can be potentially undercollateralized)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, on Maker where there were issues and delays with liquidations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some questions to ask yourself to assess the liquidation mechanisms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When liquidations are triggered; what is the flow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any additional delay?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the liquidation fees?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s another massive subtopic here: the &lt;strong&gt;liquidations do not happen magically&lt;/strong&gt; - they are triggered by other users. So the incentives need to be on point there too so that liquidations do happen when needed and promptly. This topic is even more complex now in an age of high gas costs (liquidation profits vs gas costs of the tx). Skipping it for digestibility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iid-collateral-listing--risk-analysis&#34;&gt;II.D/ Collateral Listing &amp;amp; Risk Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alright, now that we have a money market getting reliable prices and liquidating when needed, we can start looking at the tokens accepted as collateral and what is the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assessing a token&amp;rsquo;s health and overall safety is &lt;strong&gt;one of the most complex tasks nowadays in DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; because figuring out the whole ecosystem around a token can be tricky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take the SNX token, for instance, a major ERC-20 token. It&amp;rsquo;s usable as collateral on Aave, but with quite a low maximum loan to value ratio (to be raised soon?) at 15%. Other ERC-20 tokens like LINK are in the 60-75% range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without diving too much into the details, this has to do with what you can do with each token and &lt;strong&gt;SNX usage as collateral on the Synthetix platform&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s risk parameters are conservative enough to essentially &amp;ldquo;front-run&amp;rdquo; Synthetix itself in the chain of liquidations if a black swan event was to happen &lt;/span&gt;on Synthetix. It seems wise: a money market should not want to take higher exposition on a given token than the native platform itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to look at it is the other way around: assess the overall &amp;ldquo;health&amp;rdquo; of the latest tokens added as collateral on the platform: are they liquid? Credibly decentralized? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also look at the overall collateral usage for any suspicious mismatch, like on Cream where almost a third of the deposits are FTT tokens (FTX exchange).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/cream.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cream&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-collateral-listing-strategy&#34;&gt;Assessing the collateral listing strategy
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Depends on the collateral listing strategy risk appetite&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: If a dangerous token is accepted as collateral, the money market can potentially ends-up undercollateralized or even drained. For instance, Cream accepts COVER as collateral. The token suffered three infinite mint attacks already, exposing Cream to further risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; some tokens got minted to infinity, like COVER&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. But they were used as collateral on a money market yet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t expand more on this topic since Aave&amp;rsquo;s risk documentation is very well done - check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.aave.com/risk/asset-risk/risk-parameters&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the risk parameters section&lt;/a&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are the collateral listing decisions made?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What risk framework is used for collateral?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How is the money market adapting to the changing circumstances of the tokens it lists?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iie-safety-module&#34;&gt;II.E/ Safety Module
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if the risk is known at every level, &lt;strong&gt;insurance is never an option and never supernumerary&lt;/strong&gt;. The first layer of defense is of course the platform-level if there is any compensation module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that there is! Aave pioneered the field &amp;amp; even Compound has a reserve now. The second good news is that assessing the usefulness of this module is dead simple: it&amp;rsquo;s a simple ratio between the total $ value of the borrows made on the money market and the total $ that can be mobilized by the safety module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aave has roughly 2B in the Safety Module, of which up to 30% can be seized if needed = 600M. It covers both the V1 &amp;amp; V2 of the protocol. If the 30% on the slashing of the Safety Module is not sufficient, the safety module can mint additional AAVE tokens. Such a scenario is accounted for by neither Compound nor Cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/aave-safety-module.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave&amp;rsquo;s Safety Module&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of insurance, money markets can also have reserves. Compound is the pioneer here, with about $10M in reseve&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Aave also has a reserve system that was recently launched, but I excluded it from the analysis considering the limited balance.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So looking at the available numbers, here are our quick maths:
&lt;code&gt;Safety Ratio = USD value of insurance / Total borrow on the money market&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🛡 Aave =  53%&lt;/strong&gt; | $1.765 B (600M can be mobilized) in the Safety Module for $1.1B borrowed accross V1+V2 ($572M V1, $437M V2)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🕯 Compound = 0.24%&lt;/strong&gt; | $4.3B borrowed on a $10M safety capital.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💀 Cream = 0%&lt;/strong&gt; | As far as I know, Cream has no or highly limited (low amounts) native insurance module.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ℹ Note: While Compound currently has no safety module, the team/DAO is currently sitting on a large COMP reserve that could be used to that end&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The maths were done on Feb 17 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;evaluating-the-native-insurance-module&#34;&gt;Evaluating the native insurance module
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-null, but not as relevant here. The SM is here to provide compensations in case of failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Depositors know they can get slashed if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Aave&amp;rsquo;s pioneering the field. The slashing launched weeks ago. So far no events required Aave to harness the safety module, but it&amp;rsquo;s great to know it&amp;rsquo;s here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get a sense of how protecting the native safety and insurance modules are, here are some decent questions to ask:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is there any native insurance module covering the platform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it work?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the withdrawal delays &amp;amp; safeguards?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the coverage ratio (USD TVL exposed / USD TVL of Safety Module)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iif-expanded-insurance-ecosystem&#34;&gt;II.F/ Expanded Insurance Ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of the native insurance system of the money market, depositors and borrowers can &lt;strong&gt;cover their positions through a third party insurance service&lt;/strong&gt; like Nexus Mutual or Unslashed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span style=&#34;text-decoration:underline;&#34;&gt;most widely covered risk is the one of a technical failure of smart contracts&lt;/span&gt;. You will find covers for pretty much any widely used contract there is. Yet, &lt;strong&gt;smart contract failures are not the only event that can lead to a loss of funds on a money market&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of this, Robert Leshner the CEO of Compound can factually state the following&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; while the protocol recently suffered 90M of abusive liquidations because of faulty oracles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compound has been operating for close to 2 years with ZERO smart contract bugs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It creates a false sense of security many are falling for, just like the period of operation of the protocol. Notice how I left it out of these 8 criteria? It&amp;rsquo;s because it has close to zero relevance despite services like DeFiScore giving it an absurdly important weight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m careful when I talk about &amp;ldquo;90M of abusive liquidations because of faulty oracles&amp;rdquo; but to be explicit - it affected negatively potentially any DAI borrower back then that might have gotten liquidated wrongly - losing a part of their deposit with &lt;strong&gt;no recourse and no compensation&lt;/strong&gt; since Compound operated as intended (smart-contract wise).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of risks of smart contract failures, please consider the following list of non-exhaustive other risks that can result in a loss of fund:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Failure or manipulation of an oracle,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An issue with the smart contract of a token used collateral (such as infinite mint),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A stablecoin used as collateral or borrowing asset on the market lose its peg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The device or wallet of the admin of a not-so-decentralized service is compromised&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Issues or delays with liquidations, meaning the money market can potentially no longer meet its collateralization requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most insurance services are unhelpful with all these risks but for the risks of smart contract failures. The market for other types of risk is barely getting started thanks to Unslashed Finance now providing &lt;strong&gt;coverage for the risk of stablecoins losing their peg&lt;/strong&gt; or custodian risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/defiprime-insurance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Defiprime insurance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the different approaches for DeFi insurance, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiprime.com/comparing-insurance-like-solutions-in-defi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this piece from DeFi Rate&lt;/a&gt;. However please keep in mind the &lt;strong&gt;massive bias here&lt;/strong&gt;: it was written more than two years ago by Hugh Karp, founder of Nexus Mutual. However, it&amp;rsquo;s still factual enough and insightful to understand the different models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;understanding-insurances-and-the-risk-they-truly-cover&#34;&gt;Understanding insurances and the risk they truly cover
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🎯Object&lt;/strong&gt;: Smart Contract Failure + stablecoin loss of peg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💰Utility&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides compensation if a failure is observed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt;: Nexus Mutual, one of the oldest insurance options already paid out on several situations.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for the topic of extended insurances, you will want to look at services such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.unslashed.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Unslashed Finance&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nexusmutual.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nexus Mutual&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.coverprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cover Protocol&lt;/a&gt; and the plans they offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the options available through the ecosystem to cover a position on the money market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their pricing and reliability (paid out already?)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iig-native-token-risk-management&#34;&gt;II.G/ Native Token Risk Management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We discussed quite a bit about the various tokens used as collateral, but there is one you need to watch extra carefully: the &lt;strong&gt;native token of the money market&lt;/strong&gt;. So that&amp;rsquo;s the COMP token on Compound, AAVE on Aave, and CREAM on Cream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The maximum Loan to Value (max LTV) dictates the borrowing power of collaterals. A 50% max LTV means one can borrow up to half to the dollar value of the collateral deposited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The very first layer is of course to make sure that there is no fool play: &lt;strong&gt;the money market must be neutral and not favor its own token&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems obvious, but it&amp;rsquo;s not a given. Cream allows an excessive 75% max LTV on CREAM, one of the highest of the whole protocol - as high as some stablecoins. Compound itself gives COMP a permissive 60% max LTV while Aave is more conservative at 50%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the money market is healthy and the token well designed - people should be bullish on it, meaning some of them use it as collateral to long it - aka depositing AAVE on Aave to long AAVE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsurprisingly, despite the permissive LTV, COMP&amp;rsquo;s and CREAM&amp;rsquo;s longs are rarer than AAVE&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-how-a-money-market-manage-its-native-token-risks&#34;&gt;Assessing how a money market manage its native token risks
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s an all or nothing event: the money market can play with fire on its native token for months with no consequences before the situation eventually blow up and the token + the money market crumble together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: The loss can potentially be system-wide (whole money market affected).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;❌Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Not yet. But Cream is already way beyond any reasonable max LTV figure on the CREAM token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And here are some considerations worth exploring:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the health of the native token of the platform: token contract, liquidity, integrations, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at the native token usage on the protocol &amp;amp; assess the health of its market&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ownership, distribution, and Gini coefficient of the governance token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve focused on the money market themselves. Yet, they are community-driven &amp;amp; governed projects, so their community &amp;amp; integration within the ecosystem are an essential part of the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iih-community--ecosystem&#34;&gt;II.H/ Community &amp;amp; Ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, communities are essential. It&amp;rsquo;s not a &amp;ldquo;nice-to-have&amp;rdquo; to make the protocol more attractive, it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;core feature&lt;/strong&gt; and I assess it as such.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On such a topic, again, no metrics will help you just by themselves. The gist is to get a sense of how dynamic the community is. It usually translates into its core components: the DAO, the Discord, and the overall presence in the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another consequence of a healthy community is &lt;strong&gt;widespread support and usage across the ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, with many services and products built &amp;ldquo;on top of&amp;rdquo; the protocol examined. Here despite Compound&amp;rsquo;s lead being the first mover, Aave is also now a prime choice for any new protocol building a new financial primitive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, teams can purposely foster such an environment simply by having members accessible and involved in the space. Besides, Aave has an &lt;strong&gt;ecosystem grants&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:15&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;15&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; initiative helping to fund projects built on top of Aave such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/firp-apwine.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine offering fixed yields&lt;/a&gt;. Other community-related initiatives are a healthy tell, such as hackathons, AMAs, livestreams, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again here - make sure to &lt;strong&gt;assess the quality, not the quantity&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to rush out all the initiatives listed above. But doing it right, in a way that makes sense for the community and pushes it forward is much harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to make this a case against Compound, but here again, it&amp;rsquo;s so obvious. While Compound community fundings are quite limited the grants program just launched&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:16&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;16&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, its founder Robert Leshner is an active venture capital investor, with the Robot Ventures funds&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:17&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/money-market-risks/robovc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Robovc&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;assessing-the-community--dao-of-a-money-market&#34;&gt;Assessing the community &amp;amp; DAO of a money market
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮Likelihood of failure&lt;/strong&gt;: The community is the most important feature of all for the long-term success of the money market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔥Loss of funds risk if failure&lt;/strong&gt;: Long-term risk. If a money market loses the community favors, it&amp;rsquo;s not gonna be a dramatic event but more of slow and painful threading into irrelevance for the given market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;✅Already happened?&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, with Compound - they lost their top of mind position and preference for several reasons, such as their lack of support for the ecosystem, the DAI Market Oracle issue &amp;amp; the team reaction to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are some questions and clues to help you assess this last yet essential part:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the DAO-level:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does it work to submit a proposal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How are they reviewed and improved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the delay between the vote and the execution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any proposal that was ignored or not implemented for a long time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core team members:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they legit? Involved in the space? Giving back? Advising?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background-check: any involvement with a scam? What were they doing before?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present-check: on top of their involvement with the money market, what are they doing? Any potential conflict of interest?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documentation &amp;amp; support: how hard is it to build on top of this money market?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the services built on top of the money market? Are they widely used?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they communicating clearly on risk parameters? Do they have non-technical/non-dev risk-focused documentation?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-a-note-on-defi-tribalism&#34;&gt;III/ A note on DeFi Tribalism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exploring such a topic was insanely insightful for me, at so many levels. I remain quite surprised by the tribalism of the space: apart from Aave, gathering the information presented in this article was not a trivial task.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the question I asked and the observations I shared, I&amp;rsquo;ve been the target of personal attacks from founders of some of the teams mentioned in this article. Others were quite misleading and selective in their answers. I received no answers from both Cream &amp;amp; Compound official accounts or teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such attitudes gave me even more will to push this article forward. &lt;strong&gt;Beyond the technicalities of each protocol, I think the attitude of the founding team is essential too&lt;/strong&gt;. On this front, there is a protocol that stands an order of magnitude above any other: surprise surprise, it also happens to be the most technically sound, secure, integrated, and exciting, and interesting. 👻&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iiia-limitations-of-this-risk-assessment-approach&#34;&gt;III.A/ Limitations of this risk assessment approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I anticipate strong reactions already, so let me add a few more topics not addressed here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While we went quite deep, we did not discuss the tokenization process: the process used by the protocol to represent the assets deposited. On this front, &lt;strong&gt;both Compound and Cream are using an archaic approach&lt;/strong&gt; that was topped on all fronts by Aave with the first release of the aTokens in early 2020.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:18&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;18&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Aave V2 further improved the tokenization process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cream by itself is a small market, but &lt;strong&gt;through the Iron Bank other protocols can borrow from Cream&lt;/strong&gt;. Assessing the risk on such a market is even harder - and it was excluded from this analysis. To learn more about the real risk already posed and manifested by such an approach, you can check the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rekt.news/alpha-finance-rekt/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;latest Rekt on Alpha Homora&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While MakerDAO provides a service functionally equivalent to lending, the process is significantly different since each borrower is minting DAI. So for the sake of simplicity, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly excluded MakerDAO from this analysis, but for a few meaningful examples.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have no affiliation whatsoever with the Aave, Compound, Cream, or any other money market. However, I do own AAVE tokens (that I purchased myself on the markets) and stake them in the Safety Module. All the content hosted on my blog is made accessible for free - I am the sole editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you get a better grasp of the scope of risks in money markets. I want to stress again that it&amp;rsquo;s non-exhaustive, nor absolute truth but I do firmly believe provides clear and useful contributions to make sure risks in DeFi are broadly understood, better than what currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do not agree with this statement, feel free to challenge me. &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m eager for facts disproving my observations: it would mean DeFi is safer than I thought.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reminder: this blog is &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/hello-world.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;one of the few websites of the space not pillaging your data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; through the usage of Google Analytics and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-notes--references&#34;&gt;IV. Notes &amp;amp; References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can find additional information on each fact, event or figure mentioned in the article through the footnotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the get go, the formula used was abitrary, suffered dozens of obvious flaws and was rigged in favor of Compound through the ridiculous importance given to the time of operations. In my humble opinion, the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiScore&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s main goal was Consensys&amp;rsquo; promotion. If at least, they had done the work&amp;hellip;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I pinged them on Twitter and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1360296967939772423?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;suggested many obvious improvements&lt;/a&gt; anyone with some DeFi experience could have provided.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack, one of their engineer recognized that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jack_clancy93/status/1360304560846364672?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the case of Compound DAI score &amp;gt; Aave is not defensible.&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to him if you want to claim the 500 USDC bounty! &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jack_clancy93/status/1360305374033682436?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here is the tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this attack or any other in the DeFi space, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.rekt.news/nxm-hugh-speaks-out/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check the Rekt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/49657/oracle-exploit-sees-100-million-liquidated-on-compound&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info about the 89M DAI oracle abitrage on Compound here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the attack occuring several weeks ago because of their reliance on Coinbase centralized oracles, it seems like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChainLinkGod/status/1362132404484198401?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the situation has not been fixed yet&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MakerDAO team published a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.makerdao.com/the-market-collapse-of-march-12-2020-how-it-impacted-makerdao/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;write-up&lt;/a&gt; after the events explaining what happened.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cover is an insurance protocol unable to secure their own token contract and liquidity mining program. They got attaked three times already. Here are &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coingape.com/cover-becomes-latest-defi-protocol-to-get-exploited-price-crashes-by-77-within-an-hour/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;some info on the last one&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each cToken stores reserves (insurance), there&amp;rsquo;s $9.4m (and growing by over $100k/day) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358566161361821696&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are around $450K worth of tokens collected in the reserve as of now: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.aave.com/risk/asset-risk/risk-parameters#reserve-factor&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s reserve factor documentation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compound is also sitting on a 4 million COMP (roughly $1.8b) chest that could be allocated for insurance &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358569634618867714?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes he&amp;rsquo;s factual since the contract never failed so far. However for less technically-savy people, it can read like Compound never suffered any loss, which is not the case. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rleshner/status/1358566161361821696?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Robert Leshner Tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.nexusmutual.io/claim-assessment&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;claims and payouts on Nexus Mutual here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:15&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first round of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/aave/aave-ecosystem-grants-88260ede1485&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave Ecosystem grants started about a year ago&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:15&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:16&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal for Compound Ecopsystem Grants was &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/governance/proposals/30&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;executed two months ago&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:16&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:17&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://robvc.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RoboVC&lt;/a&gt;: It funded several services harnessing Compound (like InstaDapp or Multis) &amp;amp; Compound itself.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:17&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:18&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case for aTokens&amp;rsquo; technical superiority could be the topic on an article by itself but here is the gist of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simpler&lt;/strong&gt;: aTokens maintain a 1:1 ratio against the base asset while cTokens have an increasing exchange rate against their base assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier accounting &amp;amp; integrations&lt;/strong&gt;: aTokens 1:1 correspondence makes them much easier to interact with - there is no need to fetch any additional data. With Compound, any service interacting with cTokens needs to fetch the corresponding the cToken/BaseToken exchange rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic and understandable interest&lt;/strong&gt;: both a &amp;amp; c tokens accrue interest dynamically. However, here again, because of aTokens&amp;rsquo; more elegant and straightforward design, the experience is more fluid with aTokens (deposit, reassured by 1:1 correspondence, number go up)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;More potent integrations&lt;/strong&gt;: aToken allows for novel use cases, especially if you take into account the other features of Aave. For instance, there is a Yearn vault harnessing aLINK to borrow USDC from users&amp;rsquo; deposits to farm with them and settle the income for more aLINK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:18&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🍷 Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/fixed-interest-rate-protocol-firp-apwine/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/fixed-interest-rate-protocol-firp-apwine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/pac-man.png" alt="Featured image of post 🍷 Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yields are like fine wines, the secret lies in the brewing process. As DeFi is developing faster than ever, with now more than $ 50 billion of total value locked across all protocols, &lt;strong&gt;the yield offering is diversifying&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our topic today strikes at the heart of this trend, with a solution offering a potentially instant payout for deposits on DeFi protocols like Yearn or Aave: APWine. Before we get to this point however, we need to place back some context on money markets and FIRPs in general since they are still novel types of products for most DeFi users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;money-market--pacman&#34;&gt;Money Market = PacMan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/pac-man.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;the interest bearing stablecoin pacman-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tranching, insurance, and FIRPs are essentially like &lt;strong&gt;abstraction-layers built on top of a money market&lt;/strong&gt; to provide additional features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔪 Tranching&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ better separation of the different type of risks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🛡 Insurance&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ coverage against technical failures (&amp;amp; more!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🔮 FIRPs&lt;/strong&gt; ➡ &amp;ldquo;coverage&amp;rdquo; against variations of APY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While they are interesting as a features by themselves, what fascinates me is what happens &lt;strong&gt;when/if they are integrated at the base level&lt;/strong&gt;. It would enable other protocols to harness these features. For instance, Harvest could offer a &amp;ldquo;de-risked&amp;rdquo; USDC vault &amp;amp; essentially bringing the whole DeFi to another level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, DeFi&amp;rsquo;s different value set is not only a benefit for transparency and audibility: it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;also at least &lt;ins&gt;an order of magnitude&lt;/ins&gt; more efficient&lt;/strong&gt; than the dying patchwork of finance it&amp;rsquo;s bound to replace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-interest-rate-protocols-firps&#34;&gt;Fixed Interest Rate Protocols (FIRPs)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s define what Fixed Interest Rate Protocols are and what are their role within the broader ecosystem of decentralized finance on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With DeFi, the goal for most is &lt;strong&gt;to produce yields from a given asset.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually one of the easiest ways to achieve this will be to lend it for instance, for a return. Doing so means assuming several layers of risk you can insure yourself against (-&amp;gt; Unslashed) or simply avoid taking with tranching (-&amp;gt; Saffron).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you&amp;rsquo;re super responsible and try to insure &amp;amp; further protect your deposits, you are left with one sizable issue: &lt;strong&gt;the base return produced by the asset is usually volatile&lt;/strong&gt;, making the pricing of the whole package (lended deposit + insurance + tranching) hard to navigate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/coingecko-report.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coingecko-crypto-2020-report&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://assets.coingecko.com/reports/2020-Year-End-Report/CoinGecko-2020-Report.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;full report here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is precisely where FIRPs get a chance to shine: &lt;strong&gt;since they make the interest predictable, FIRPs help promote a more responsible attitude&lt;/strong&gt; for the whole space - by making it easier to use all the meta-structure now available to protect deposits on money markets or DeFi asset managers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article addresses fixed interest rate protocols only. For a broader perspective on risk management for DeFi deposits, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/risk-tranching.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read my introduction piece touching on insurance, tranching and FIRPs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. In there, we addressed how insurance, tranching, and fixed interest might eventually be integrated natively into money-markets, enabling to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/risk-tranching.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;envision &amp;ldquo;risk-free&amp;rdquo; interest bearing stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From now on, this article assume a minimal understanding of the topic. If something is still unclear, please refer to the previous article ☝&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;apwine-fixed-yield-sauternes-&#34;&gt;APWine: Fixed-yield Sauternes 🍷
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So with the hell of an intro and without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into today&amp;rsquo;s matter: &lt;strong&gt;understanding what FIRPs are and what they bring to the table through the lense of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🍷 Even better, it&amp;rsquo;s wine-themed and Frenchies are involved - what&amp;rsquo;s not to love already?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-difference-between-apwine-and-88mph&#34;&gt;The difference between APWine and 88MPH
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a high-level perspective, both projects could be described as FIRPs, yet they achieve this result through different means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With 88MPH, the yield of your deposits are fixed thanks to a secondary prediction market built for it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With APWine, you can lock your assets for a month for instance to instantly earn the yield.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to be more explicit, both are not interchangeable nor operating on the same time frame: with 88MPH, the income becomes &lt;strong&gt;predictable but it&amp;rsquo;s still an iterative process&lt;/strong&gt;. With APWine, the income becomes &lt;strong&gt;predictable &amp;amp; instantly delivered&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also means different tradeoffs on the risk management side. With 88MPH, the yield is calculated algorithmically - there&amp;rsquo;s always a buyer, which is neat for convenience, but also means the protocol can accrue debt if there is a mismatch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposite is true for APWine: since it&amp;rsquo;s market-based, no mismatch can occur (-&amp;gt; no protocol debt), but it means there can be demand/offer issues (such as heavy discount on FYTs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/firp-apwine/apwine.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;apwine-deposit-process&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apwine-instant-payday&#34;&gt;APWine: Instant Payday?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With APWine, the logic is quite straightforward. It all starts by depositing a token earning some yield, such as a stablecoin deposited on Aave or a Yearn vault token onto the platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of each period, users receive FYT (Future Yield Tokens) representing their yields for the period. &lt;strong&gt;The FYT are standard ERC-20 tokens&lt;/strong&gt; that will be tradable shortly after launch on APWine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deposit is locked for the period, however users can withdraw early with a fee, by burning their FYT tokens. The slashing is deactivated for the beta period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the yield is instantly available and usable, APWine should provide ample opportunities for both hedging and arbitraging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After several weeks of testnet, APWine is coming to mainet! The beta will start in a couple of weeks with a first period starting on March 1st for 30 days. The APW token and liquidity mining should could shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.medium.com/our-beta-is-live-on-the-ethereum-mainnet-3860491a365c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More information on APWine beta &amp;amp; launch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next-for-apwine&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next for APWine?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the short term, I&amp;rsquo;ll be following closely the upcoming launch of the platform next week. Several upcoming releases have already been announced such as the arrival of more services and pools on the platform and the release of the APW token and its associated liquidity mining plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like always though, what gets me really excited is the endgame!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-endgame-a-yield-hedging-protocol&#34;&gt;The Endgame: a yield hedging protocol
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we envision the end-game here, first we need to see if the idea works and &lt;strong&gt;if there is a real fit.&lt;/strong&gt; In the APWine case, &lt;strong&gt;success will be measured by looking at the health of the markets for FYT tokens&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect them to settle at parity with expected yields, but if users can really get an &lt;strong&gt;instant payday even with a 20% fee&lt;/strong&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Achieving this means having really liquid FYT markets, which is perfectly doable especially if there is a liquidity mining plan in APW token to bootstrap them. Regarding the APW token itself, diving in the FAQ will give you a bit more insight into what the team envisions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each future expiration, 10% of the generated yield is shared between all APW token holders (percentage subject to change in the future based on the market demand). The token will also enable them to participate in the governance mechanisms of APWine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/faq&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ApWine FAQ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on top of the usual governance right of the protocol, it seems like there is already a revenue stream considered for the APW token, on top of any potential liquidity mining plan involving an APW-based pair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French being the language of DeFi, it was about time we got some fine wine-makers involved in the yield brewing process! If you are interested in the protocol, you can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.medium.com/our-beta-is-live-on-the-ethereum-mainnet-3860491a365c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read more about the beta here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be following closely as I&amp;rsquo;m having &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zo0B64swtPI&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a chat with Antoine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the persons involved with APWine next week (in French).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🗡 Risk? Yes please, but exactly how I like it</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/risk-tranching-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/risk-tranching-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/cover.gif" alt="Featured image of post 🗡 Risk? Yes please, but exactly how I like it" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeFi has grown tremendously over the past year, partly thanks to the appearance of more streamlined investment products such as Yearn&amp;rsquo;s or Harvest&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/vaults.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;vaults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to their architecture, they facilitate the mutualization of capital which enables smaller yet profitable investments on money markets and other DeFi services like Curve or SushiSwap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a necessary and much-welcomed layer, and several improvements are still to be made to streamline things even further and increase gas efficiency. However, I believe the bulk of the innovation this year will come from another front: risk management on the vault-type products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, several definancial primitives have been developed to provide more options to segregate and hedge risks. There are now credible insurance options available for DeFi, as well as a new approach (in DeFi) to better distribute the risk between consenting and informed actors: tranching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll dive right in, but just before that, I think it&amp;rsquo;s apt to examine the terminology too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-lending-protocols-to-money-markets&#34;&gt;From Lending Protocols to Money Markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been reading me for a while, you might have seen the term &amp;ldquo;lending protocol&amp;rdquo; being used. While it was suited to describe their first purpose, I believe the concept has now outgrown the word, so I&amp;rsquo;ll refer to them as money market from now on. Indeed, &amp;ldquo;lending protocol&amp;rdquo; fails to capture all the subtleties now offered by services like Aave — I&amp;rsquo;m actually a bit late to the party of this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, the change of nomenclature reflects the different stages of evolution of these money markets. In their first months of existence, there was &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity imperative&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a fight to grow to a sizeable size, big enough to justify interest from other projects to integrate with the money market fuelling a positive growth loop as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen on Aave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/aave-debank.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave TVL Growth - Debank&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the critical mass is reached, &lt;strong&gt;the focus can and must evolve&lt;/strong&gt;. To further expand, the money market must extend its range of features - again, like we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Aave do with flashloans and fixed rate loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems clear now that &lt;strong&gt;the second phase of growth of the money markets will be feature-driven&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the base features available on the money market are essential, as these markets are more integrated into other DeFi protocols. The money markets with the most flexibility at the base layer will be able to handle more intricate use cases, such as credit delegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, I want to focus this piece on a risk management concept that hasn&amp;rsquo;t found its way to a mainstream money market yet: &lt;strong&gt;tranching&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what it can enable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tranching-would-you-like-another-slice-of-risk&#34;&gt;Tranching: would you like another slice of risk?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s start with &lt;strong&gt;the most straightforward &amp;ldquo;risk alteration&amp;rdquo; there is - tranching&lt;/strong&gt;. The idea here is quite straightforward: the different risk layers taken by the depositor of a given money market are tranched - meaning segregated one from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each depositor can choose his preferred exposure. It enables, for instance, a confident degen to &lt;strong&gt;bear all available layers of risk to maximize his APY&lt;/strong&gt; while a more conservative whale could &lt;strong&gt;downsize its risk perimeter&lt;/strong&gt; by exposing oneself to the technical risk only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the core idea, but let&amp;rsquo;s not forget we&amp;rsquo;re talking about decentralized finance here, so &lt;strong&gt;composability is key&lt;/strong&gt;. What makes tranching so exciting is its future as a &lt;strong&gt;financial primitive&lt;/strong&gt; - a building block that other apps and projects can use to deliver new services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore more in-depth what tranching as financial primitive entails right after we consider how it currently works in practice, and examine the broader context of risk hedging and APY fixation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to DeFi or even finance in general, you might wonder why we care so much about these different flavors of risks?
You can picture these mechanisms enabling diverse types of risk exposure as building blocks making it possible to &lt;strong&gt;build end-user products fitting all ranges of risk appetite&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explain why tranching matters more explicitly in the last part of this article where we consider some end-game scenarios for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-tranching-in-practice&#34;&gt;Risk tranching in practice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This whole article was actually inspired by a tweet I published where I shared what a tranched aDAI could look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, there is mostly one product delivering tranching on mainnet I&amp;rsquo;m looking at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://saffron.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Saffron Finance&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a tranching abstraction layer built on top of the Compound DAI market. The risk segregation is straightforward with two main tranches + one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;AA tranche&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;covered in case of platform failure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;A tranche&lt;/strong&gt;, supplying the cover for the AA tranche (= slashing if a failure occurs) but earns a much &lt;strong&gt;more favorable APY&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a third tranche - the &lt;strong&gt;S tranche&lt;/strong&gt;. However, it is simply rebalancing between the two others as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/saffron.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The different tranches available on Saffron Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tranching occurs on an epoch-basis, currently set at two weeks. So if you supply the A tranche, for instance, you are bearing the risk of platform failure for the AA tranche for a 2 week period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the excitement that followed the launch, Saffron grew to close to $60M assets deposited. Since then, the dust settled around a low bar of roughly $15M of assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/saffron-debank.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Saffron Finance TVL - Debank&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the charts, we can see some sharp withdrawals: it&amp;rsquo;s due to the epoch-based logic of Saffron. At the end of every epochs, depositors are not earning rewards anymore until they pull out and deposit in the next epoch tranches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saffron is looking to expand to other money markets, most obviously Aave and expand their token coverage (currently only DAI). Other projects are exploring the idea of tranching, most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://barnbridge.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BarnBridge&lt;/a&gt;, but their current achievements are less enticing in my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last minute edit: BarnBridge &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CoinbaseCustody/status/1348739247277268997&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BOND token is now listed on Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a more practical understanding of tranching and how it can work, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back to understand what it provides in the broader context of risk management in decentralized finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-broader-context-of-risk-management-in-defi&#34;&gt;Understanding the broader context of risk management in DeFi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve focused on the sole risk related to the definancial product itself: mainly smart contract risks, oracle, and economic attacks. We&amp;rsquo;ve left at least two layers of risk untouched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APY Variation&lt;/strong&gt;: The APY of the service used is usually variable, so there is an additional layer of exposure there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token Price Fluctuation&lt;/strong&gt;: Sometimes, the returns are paid in token different from the ones deposited. If the payout token is not a stablecoin, its price can vary - meaning there is yet an additional layer of exposure to consider here if we want to be exhaustive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, to fully understand the broader context, let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that there are several distinct &amp;ldquo;temporal approaches&amp;rdquo; to risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an approach such as tranching, you can be &lt;strong&gt;proactive&lt;/strong&gt;, splitting the risk &lt;strong&gt;beforehand&lt;/strong&gt; between participants that understand their exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can also go hand in hand with more &lt;strong&gt;reactive approaches&lt;/strong&gt;, such as insurance - a system providing payout &lt;strong&gt;afterward&lt;/strong&gt; in the event of a failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurance markets are another fascinating topic by themselves, so we&amp;rsquo;ll stick to this simple mention for now and go back to our yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re talking about insurance, a fascinating project just launched - Unslashed Finance. It&amp;rsquo;s made in France by a builder I admire, so I&amp;rsquo;m a little biased, but feel free &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/unslashed/manifesto-for-a-decentralised-crypto-insurance-unslashed-finance-873078fd0ddd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;to read their manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more about their vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-take-on-risk-management-for-yields-apy-fixation&#34;&gt;Another take on risk management for yields: APY-fixation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we were saying, the APY of the different yield products available in decentralized finance are constantly fluctuating. It makes for a less predictable income and prevents the entry of investors who are not willing to stomach several layers of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, another layer of meta-financial services is emerging - the base value proposition as an investor is quite simple: they offer a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY on depositors&amp;rsquo; investments&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially another flavor of &amp;ldquo;insurance&amp;rdquo;: you&amp;rsquo;ll get overall a bit of a lower yield, but it&amp;rsquo;s predictable. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to a stable-interest loan on Aave (vs variable rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buyer side of such services is super interesting: picture it &lt;strong&gt;like a prediction market, for the yield of a given vault or investment product.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers deposit some assets and place a bet on the expected average yield: the closer their prediction is, the better is the return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see the buyer side becoming mainstream anytime soon, but it provides the backbone to yet another useful financial primitive useful to provide services more suited to more risk-averse investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apy-fixation-in-practice&#34;&gt;APY-Fixation in practice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, there are two projects working on delivering fixed-APY yield on popular decentralized investment products such as the Yearn vaults: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://88mph.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;88mph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Saffron, 88mph is another abstraction layer built on top of Compound, Aave, and Harvest deposits. It provides a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY for depositors&lt;/strong&gt;, while on the other side of the market buyers of floating-rate bonds are bearing the risk of the fluctuations of the APY of the underlying investment product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/88mph.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;88mph main interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-the-endgame-look-like&#34;&gt;What does the endgame look like?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s wrap this up with a little thought experiment. We&amp;rsquo;re now leaving the present and what is currently live on the Ethereum mainnet to extrapolate a bit and consider what tranching &amp;amp; other risk management approaches can enable in DeFi a few months or years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An investment product built, for instance, on the Aave money market:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a Saffron-like product integrated into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also with an 88mph-like service integrated into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, an insurance such as Unslashed also natively integrated for the DAI peg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could envision &lt;strong&gt;the first &amp;ldquo;risk-free&amp;rdquo; DeFi investment&lt;/strong&gt;, which would be a wrapped deposit of say DAI on Aave, coming along with tranching to only bear the price risk hedged by a coverage against DAI losing its peg on Unslashed earning a fixed APY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s insane to consider the different steps of the evolution of let&amp;rsquo;s say DAI we witnessed or are about to witness in barely two years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest-bearing&lt;/strong&gt; DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a fixed APY &lt;strong&gt;not bearing the technical risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a fixed APY not bearing the technical risks &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;covered against DAI losing its peg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aFIXEDAPYDAI_PEGINSURED: our new monetary overlord? The actual name will be way more catchy, rest assured!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to witness &lt;strong&gt;the future of money unfolding methodically before your very eyes as your assets receive software updates&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one cannot wait: I&amp;rsquo;ve been prepping for the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Waël for making the cover image featured at the top of this article (as well as the TokenBrice emblem).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/wifeys.jpg" alt="Featured image of post YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Yearn v2 release and the launch of the YFI token (pronounced &amp;ldquo;Waifu&amp;rdquo;) shook decentralised finance. Indeed, the whole recipe was there: Yearn is like a robo advisor, it helps you save and grow a capital - obviously one of the most thought after use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the product itself, core to defining what Yearn became was its founder Andre Cronje, &lt;strong&gt;his choice of fully opening the governance&lt;/strong&gt;, and the amazing community that soon federated around the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this piece today, I want to share some pointers to understand why Yearn came to be, how it works, and why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-yearn&#34;&gt;What is Yearn?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first version of Yearn started with a simple promise: it &lt;strong&gt;helped you get the best lending rate available at any time on a given stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed as there were more and more options to lend stablecoins (Compound, Aave, dYdX, etc.), yield optimization quickly became essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn v2 already brought a new product to the market, the yVaults: they go beyond yield optimization (rebalancing stablecoins between several lending platforms) to provide more returns. Let’s see how this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-user-perspective-deposit-wait-money-go-up&#34;&gt;End-User Perspective: Deposit, Wait, Money go Up
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we go in the specifics, here it&amp;rsquo;s how it works for an end-user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You own a token supported in the yVaults, such as LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can deposit your LINK in the yVault to start earning. Entry and exit to the vaults are gas optimised (usually ~$2-3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re done, you exit the pool. 0.5% of the &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; value is taken by the system to cover all the fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given &lt;strong&gt;enough time spent in the vault to make up for the exit cost&lt;/strong&gt;, investors walk out with a profit paid in the token they entered (ex: more LINK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: yVaults are still highly experimental. Make sure you know what you are getting into. Andre has quite an interesting approach, stated in his twitter bio &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1291252150635560960?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;I test in prod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-happening-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;yVaults are amazing because &lt;strong&gt;they abstract an immense amount of complexity for the users,&lt;/strong&gt; and do it better than most of us. Going back to our yLINK vault, here&amp;rsquo;s what happens to provide the yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINK are deposited on Aave (Credit Delegation) and used as collateral to open positions. The positions are maintained within a safe range using an safety mechanism (funded on the returns).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stablecoins are borrowed and put to work to provide a return. The latest strategy farms the mUSD/USDC MTA Balancer Pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any actual returns of the farming portion of the position (stablecoins earned above the debt) are sold for LINK, increasing the effective returns of the whole position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist of yVaults is that &lt;strong&gt;they harness DeFi synergies to provide yields on autopilot.&lt;/strong&gt; They are designed to be flexible with their capital allocation - so that it can easily be re-allocated to follow a different strategy with better yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each vault has a different strategy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a neat explainer graphics made to explain the yCRV vault strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yCRV-vault.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance yCRV vault strategy explained&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining this one would be another article by itself, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let you dig the graph and join the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/HFK5uea&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Discord&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yearn-is-unlike-anything-else-before&#34;&gt;Why Yearn is unlike anything else before
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is DeFi on steroids, and made possible by developments that occurred over the last year. Yearn is harnessing synergies between several &amp;ldquo;DeFi legos&amp;rdquo;. Without going too deep in, here are the key ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aave recently launched the Credit Delegation feature&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling a contract to open a position on your behalf. This feature was necessary for the yVaults to function as they do now, as they enable the first part of most strategies - getting leverage.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEX &amp;amp; Automated Market Makers - especially &lt;strong&gt;Curve.fi&lt;/strong&gt;, an obvious dependency for the yCRV Vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall &lt;strong&gt;dynamism of the stablecoins markets&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to new entrants such as mStable or the COMP token release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is the perfect example of DeFi composability!&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-as-little-as-possible--assembling-legos&#34;&gt;Building as little as possible &amp;amp; assembling legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why am I focusing on this? Because as someone working in the DeFi space for two years, I can tell you that the biggest operational mistake I see ALL THE TIME - is simple: &lt;strong&gt;teams re-building the wheel - reinventing what already exists and working&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think DeFi projects (like most startups) would gain immensely from actively trying to reduce the scope of work they undertake - here are two amazing questions that should be asked more often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is the unique value delivered by our product?&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do we need to deliver it? Can we harness existing solutions to achieve this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s structural design demonstrates a keen eye to identify high-potential DeFi projects and harness their synergies. In short, by &lt;strong&gt;assembling several DeFi legos together in an unprecedented way&lt;/strong&gt;, Andre efficiently delivered a brand new use case if not a new subset of the whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-defi-100-community-driven-project&#34;&gt;The first DeFi 100% community-driven project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This headline is not at attention grab, I stand by it as there is meat on the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first, let us restress than &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has been a working product handling significant volumes for a while before the YFI token&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, you can add to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% of the tokens distributed to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a novel liquidity mining approach, pertinent to the product (yCRV pool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community was quick to step up and is booming with well-articulated ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andre relinquished control of the main contracts governing the service, in favour of a multisig with reputable actors of the space.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I regard and value an open governance process as a net positive, at least in the long-run, this is also a risk - and &lt;strong&gt;this is usually how people in the industry reads it&lt;/strong&gt;. An open governance can be hijacked in a direction that does not match the best interest of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;defiweb3---communities-hegemonize-brands&#34;&gt;DeFi/Web3 -&amp;gt; Communities Hegemonize Brands
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might not be on board yet, but for me, building and growing communities - that’s essentially my life. In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it, I found no secret sauce yet I &lt;strong&gt;uncovered an obvious truth: communities &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; brands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of DeFi, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the &lt;strong&gt;clash of brands&lt;/strong&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re about to witness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the one hand, VC-funded brand-companies tend to lack personality and have a harder time bolstering dynamic organic communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, a community-driven project is &lt;strong&gt;a story writing itself every day.&lt;/strong&gt; And when it comes to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s brand, we see it growing fast: the swag is already there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yearn-swag.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance Swag&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feeling-the-yearn&#34;&gt;Feeling the Yearn
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is so much more than yVaults! I focused this explainer on them for clarity, but there are several other Yearn products being developed. Without diving too much in, here some promising ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yborrow.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yBorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a generalised credit delegation interface using Aave. What makes it amazing is the synergy with the vaults, it will enable anyone to access vaults like yCRV from an ERC-20 token they like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ySwap: a novel automated market maker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mysterious leveraged stablecoin-farming solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yearn-toolbox&#34;&gt;The Yearn ToolBox
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools and resources developed by the community that proves super helpful if you are exploring or using Yearn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LearnYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A comprehensive Yearn wiki frequently updated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://feel-the-yearn.vercel.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FeelTheYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple page to get the current status of the vaults: assets locked in, assets deployed and the strategy used for each vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ycosystem.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YCosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A community aggregator to find all the useful links, from docs/YIP to where to purchase Yearn swag!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you are interested in Yearn, I URGE YOU to give the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;governance forum&lt;/a&gt; a read - you are forever invited to read and partake in the discussions shaping Yearn. This time, there is no VC, no BS - just a DAO and a one-man-army named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre Cronje&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wifeys-family&#34;&gt;The Wifeys Family
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it would be dishonest to cover Yearn/YFI &amp;amp; without mentioning that YFI sparked a whole movement - there are now dozens of forks, more or less credible. While the first few ones where just &amp;ldquo;miners fork&amp;rdquo;, adjusting a few parameters, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing more creative approaches. Indeed, Yearn is open source so easily forkable, and Andre even invited the community to get creative with it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some communities are forking YFI to create their own pooled earning system, with a longer-term vision. It&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning but I think we will see fascinating development in that space. I think we will see communities reappropriating themselves parts if not the whole YFI system - remember the Wifeys family earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already starting! I&amp;rsquo;m following closely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/yflink/the-idea-of-yflink-is-born-aa520921a4a3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink&lt;/a&gt;, a YFI fork adjusted for the needs of the LINK community. Right now, it looks like a farming cooperative, but the end game might be a community staking node - the perfect match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to the Yearn and its family grow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn vaults are novel DeFi products integrating many others meaning the failure risks are compounded. I am not a financial advisor - you make your own decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am NOT responsible for &lt;u&gt;YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, may they bring you Lambos or bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1280500969986498561?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s Stani (Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO) giving you a rundown of why this is big!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre himself is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1290845154430025731?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the first to acknowledge&lt;/a&gt; what made Yearn possible and the importance of composability.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol governance now lies in the hands of YFI holder. The access to the main contracts are held by a multi-sig, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1285427748761198594?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a key&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1289959986190147585?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;If you do clone /and you are welcome to/, please change a few things so we get new data from the experiment. Repeating the same experiment isn&amp;rsquo;t fun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How DeFi can pay for your lunches</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;This tactic was first published in the Bankless newsletter and written with advice and support from Ryan.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Link to the original publication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Crypto Natives,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember that guy &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.forbes.com/sites/laurashin/2016/01/07/this-man-has-been-living-on-bitcoin-for-3-years/#3c9a747a2697&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;who tried to live on Bitcoin&lt;/a&gt; in 2013?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Living bankless was harder back then. No one accepted it. Lots of friction. But people kept saying that one day every Starbucks would accept Bitcoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it didn’t stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s funny because the guy in that story is now &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fortune.com/2019/12/11/crypto-crown-prince-olaf-carlson-wee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a mega-millionaire&lt;/a&gt; much the result of…not spending his Bitcoin!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does that teach us? It teaches to not to spend our BTC &amp;amp; ETH! Who wants to end up like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/news/bitcoin-pizza-day-celebrating-20-million-pizza-order/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bitcoin pizza guy&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it’s time to check in again. New tools like stablecoins and DeFi protocols are now make going bankless easier…and even…better than a bank?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I asked &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice&lt;/a&gt; to share his story. He’s uses an Ethereum address, a few protocols, and a wallet + visa card combo to get passive DeFi income to pay for his lunches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/paying.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;paying-lunch-with-DAI-from-DeFi&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Above—&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1225773317598187527?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;watch Brice pay for French cheese&lt;/a&gt; the bankless way)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And he plans to do a whole lot more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re closer than ever to the dream of a crypto money system yet hardy anyone’s talking about it. They will. The next 10 yrs is where crypto becomes useful in daily life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the decade we go bankless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-RSA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;🙏Sponsor:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;—earn &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;high yields&lt;/a&gt; on deposits &amp;amp; borrow at the best possible rate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tactics-tuesday&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TACTICS TUESDAY:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tactic-26-how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tactic #26:&lt;/strong&gt; How DeFi can pay for your lunches
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brice tells us his system for earning daily DAI to pay for expenses like lunch. He uses an Ethereum address as his bank, DAI as his stablecoin &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-a-dai-saving-account&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;and savings account&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tokenized real-estate&lt;/a&gt; to generate passive income, and a smart-contract wallet plus &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visa card&lt;/a&gt; for spending. Learn about his 5 DAI per day portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Goal: &lt;em&gt;Generate a stable return in DAI to cover for living expenses.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skill: &lt;em&gt;Intermediate&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Effort: &lt;em&gt;An hour or two a week, sometimes less&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROI: &lt;em&gt;9-12% annual if fully passive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;⚠️&lt;strong&gt;RSA’s note on risk&lt;/strong&gt;: In this bankless frontier Brice is taking on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-assess-the-risk-of-lending&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;many risks&lt;/a&gt;—to name a few: failure of DAI, failure of protocols like aDAI, failure of smart-contract wallet, variable interest rates, failure of the entire Ethereum protocol. He could lose all or a portion of his funds in a worse case. The passive income opportunities he mentions should be adjusted for these risks.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest post:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice Berdah&lt;/a&gt;, Community at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; DeFiFrance Co-Organizer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My relationship with money has always been ambiguous. As a teen, I was your usual &amp;ldquo;get money it’s spent that day&amp;rdquo; kind of guy—I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really thinking or strategic about it, just looking forward to enjoying what money enables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-masterplan&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The masterplan&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I grew up and started earning money on my own, I began thinking more and more about money and personal finance. Shortly after my first proper job, I was already doing math on my expenses, my income, and how long I would need to work and save in order to not have to work anymore. The dream of freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quickly, this turned into a basic plan with two arbitrary choices:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I would aim to acquire $1.5M. I assumed this capital would earn 5% / year landing me around $75K/year of interest before taxes—enough to sustain my lifestyle if not too excessive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And I’d get there by the time I&amp;rsquo;m 35 (giving 20-30 good years to do my things)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It was obviously and predictably a failure&lt;/strong&gt;. Between the start of my plan at 21 years old and now (I’m 28), I was barely able to save a fraction of the required amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;why-did-my-plan-fail&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why did my plan fail?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I was learning about decentralised finance, I took some time to reflect on the back-then current failure of my masterplan. Here are the main reasons I identified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I did not define steps to reach the end goal&lt;/strong&gt;: I wanted to jump straight from no passive income to full passive income, without planing any intermediary step to make it more realistic and achievable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I had little to no discipline&lt;/strong&gt; when it came to taming my expenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I overlooked the &amp;ldquo;details&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. I had little to no idea of how I was actually going to produce a stable and consistent 5% return on such capital. I just assumed it would be attainable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-decentralised-finance&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enter decentralised finance&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s jump to the current situation! I followed the development of the DeFi ecosystem very closely, thanks to my job at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DeFi-France/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;different meetups&lt;/a&gt; I co-organise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I used DeFi out of curiosity: the amount I engaged was marginal—most of my net worth was still in ETH/ERC-20 tokens. Like most, I was both curious and perplexed—is this magic internet money experiment really working?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-aha-moment&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My &amp;ldquo;Aha!&amp;rdquo; moment&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started seriously using more DeFi services, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/markets&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; bZx and then later the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://oasis.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dai Saving Rate&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;. It was awesome and magical, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t what lit the spark for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The magic spark came from a piece a tokenised real estate I bought on Ethereum using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;. You may already know RealT—it’s a platform for tokenized real-estate. You own property tokens and receive &lt;strong&gt;daily rental payments in DAI.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why this? It got my mind racing. This was how it went:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1st day of rent:&lt;/strong&gt; oh okay, this thing is real. &lt;em&gt;By this point, I started discussing RealT with other people in the scene.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of first week:&lt;/strong&gt; now I was checking my wallet balance every morning—seeing the list of rent paid was exhilarating but left me craving more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End of first month:&lt;/strong&gt; at first I spent the DAI almost immediately using my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith Visa card&lt;/a&gt;. It was so tempting—the DAI sitting there in my wallet, accumulating every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After first month:&lt;/strong&gt; as the idea of daily DAI became a reality to me, I started rethinking about my masterplan: how much DAI do I need per day to live solely on that? How much capital would it represent? (&lt;em&gt;Hint: way less than $1.5M)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Above: a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1223641685898465282?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi Milkshake&lt;/a&gt; I bought with my daily DAI passive income using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visa card&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dai-per-day-as-a-framework&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAI per day as a framework&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What happened there? Why would RealT have this impact on me while Compound did not? (Huge respect for all the projects mentioned in this post, please keep going!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the answer is more straightforward than what people expect:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We used to download movies or buy them to watch them. At some point, Netflix offered us streaming and 99% of us never looked back—&lt;strong&gt;I expect the same thing to happen with money.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;money-that-empowers-people&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money that empowers people&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, daily DAI streaming is a paradigm shift that enables most of us to instantly become much smarter and efficient in the way we relate and manage our assets. It’s empowering to the individual.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why? The concept of DAI per day reinforces two powerful ideas: first, streaming money and second, using DAI as the base monetary reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is streaming money a paradigm shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It makes it easy to break down significant objectives in small chunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is no wait time between the first initial investment and the first payout. Payouts are available instantly—and spendable anywhere that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;accepts Visa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is DAI a paradigm shift?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI is a stablecoin—you don’t have to hoard it or worry about daily value lose&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI is at a bridge: easy to spend in the real world but also a hop away from all other Ethereum-based assets (including passive income assets like RealT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As DeFi grows sources of DAI/day are becoming more numerous and attractive&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the tokens used for payouts are more diverse (consider liquidity pools). Bringing everything back in DAI/day gives you exhaustive visibility over all your crypto-passive income sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;that-daily-dai-lifestyle&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That Daily Dai Lifestyle&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough context, let&amp;rsquo;s get practical: what can we do today with these shiny new financial levers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went back to my masterplan to give it a second try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, instead of going straight for full financial independence, I decided to aim for something more practical. For me, it was straightforward: I have three lunches in London every week, costing me around $30 per week on average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means I need roughly &lt;strong&gt;4.3 DAI per day&lt;/strong&gt; to pay for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I could also skip lunch, but I decided to have it for free thanks to DeFi!&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m not there yet but getting close: according to my revised plan, I&amp;rsquo;ll be getting free lunches by the end of March.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;starting-with-a-5-dai-per-day-portfolio&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starting with a 5 DAI per day portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am currently exploring different possibilities in my portfolio, so let&amp;rsquo;s consider a simple one: one that nets you 5 DAI per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what you can expect if you want a simple passive DAI strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8-9% APR with DAI: for instance, locking your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-a-dai-saving-account&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DAI in the DSR&lt;/a&gt; is at 8%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9-12.5% APR with income assets: but with a higher risk, using RealT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s if you want to set it and forget about it. There are other opportunities with additional earning opportunities. For instance, if you own a RealT asset, you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to sell at a premium on Uniswap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Benefits from their liquidity incentive program&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let’s keep this simple and passive:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll stick with the Dai Saving Rate—the safest way to produce DAI interests right now—and RealT—a more risky bet that can offer higher returns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much in assets values is required for 5 Daily DAI at the below rates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
![earning-table](/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/earning-table.png)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;going-farther&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going farther&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this is a simple framework to get started it suffers from some limits. For instance, if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to generate 100 DAI/day from this approach, RealT will not cut it. You&amp;rsquo;ll run into issues of liquidity (not enough estate available) or systemic risk (you&amp;rsquo;d be owning a sizeable share of ALL RealT estates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my current understanding, I intend to maintain a similar strategy up to roughly 10 DAI/day. My current portfolio also includes aDAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I blast through the 10 DAI/day, this year, that is if the plan stands, I will be diversifying more and more. I think liquidity pools &amp;amp; staking (SNX, for instance) can be a way to go. However, I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar enough with these topics &amp;amp; haven&amp;rsquo;t started committing serious amounts of money to it—so I&amp;rsquo;m not the best one to talk about it right now: maybe in a few months?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wonder how this looks in practice? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/tokenbrice.eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;See for yourself at tokenbrice.eth.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
![zerion-preview](/img/2020/bankless-defi-lunches/wallet.png)
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Above: see Brice’s DAI earnings &amp;amp; spending in real-time—&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.zerion.io/0x030de46c333dfd602442a103919412a7987d0ac7/lend?utm_campaign=aw&amp;amp;utm_medium=header_button&amp;amp;utm_source=landing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;plug tokenbrice.eth into Zerion&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-on-projections&#34;&gt;** On projections…**
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Allow me to loop back to my masterplan. While the DAI per day approach is fantastic it has one main downside: it makes yearly projections harder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a minute now and try to guess how much daily DAI you need to produce 50k DAI per year? Did you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How close were you to 137, the actual answer? Most people tend to overestimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while DAI/day is my base, I also look at two other levels to not lose track of the big picture: the DAI per month and the DAI per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;going-bankless-in-the-real-world&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Going bankless in the real world&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you found value in this tactic—my goal is practical DeFi: demonstrating what you can do harnessing DeFi today. This post was written down &amp;amp; translated adaptation of my &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/DeFi-France/events/268374027/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;last talk at DeFi France.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late last year &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://slideslive.com/38920018/living-on-defi-how-i-survive-argentinas-50-inflation&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mariano Conti’s talk&lt;/a&gt; sent an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/straddling-two-worlds-crypto-and&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;electro-shock to the crypto world&lt;/a&gt;: he reminded us that DeFi is already used for very real situations, such as avoiding losing 50% of your net worth to inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the perfect demonstration of someone living in the real world using the opportunities offered by DeFi. My goal was to provide the European version of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mariano survived inflation using DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, on the opposite, want to live my best life, thanks to DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the magic: &lt;strong&gt;both of us are acting in our own best interest and in doing so, we are supporting the development of a fairer &amp;amp; more accessible financial system for all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a clear illustration of how fast the industry is evolving: hop on &amp;amp; enjoy the ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;author-blub&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Author Blub&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brice Berdah&lt;/a&gt; is the community manager at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; and co-organizer of DeFi France. He’s an active crypto user and leader in the grassroots movement for decentralized finance in the EU.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;action-steps&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action steps&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the passive income opportunities in DeFi and what are the risks?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get a Visa card for daily DAI spending (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt; if in EU or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-to-get-your-first-crypto-visa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;other options&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless&lt;/a&gt;. $12 / mo. Includes &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/archive?utm_source=menu-dropdown&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;archive access&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/welcome-to-the-inner-circle-wave&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Inner Circle&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/the-deal-sheet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Deals&lt;/a&gt;—[(pay w/ crypto)](&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Free coffees ☕, thanks to DeFi</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/free-coffees-thanks-to-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/free-coffees-thanks-to-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Free coffees ☕, thanks to DeFi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overview of the passive income-earning opportunities enabled by decentralised finance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, it feels like the world of money is upside down: while the returns offered by banks keep getting lower (if not negative!), innovative techs enabled the emergence of an alternative financial system that is already delivering incredible value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it short: Ethereum created money on steroids while regular finance simply fails at delivering anything else than surface-level innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the money you have sitting at the bank has barely seen a one-digit interest rate for years, the yearly return enabled by decentralised finance frequently prints 2 digits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can this situation even be real? It seems like decentralised finance (DeFi) is still a little too intimidating for outsiders. Or more like used to! After reading this, you’ll have no excuse!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t want you scratching your head at the fifth line, so let’s clear the air on DeFi before we go on. Decentralised Finance is a term used to refer to the nascent &amp;amp; novel new financial ecosystem, built on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this parallel finance ecosystem, thousands of users from around the globe borrow, lend and exchange tokens with one another. They do so using uncensorable and unstoppable services, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.exchange/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;free-coffees-thanks-to-strangers-from-theinternet&#34;&gt;Free coffees, thanks to strangers from the Internet
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fully harnessing the capabilities of Ethereum, those new financial services are able to (potentially) operate in a decentralised, trustless and transparent manner — making the system &lt;strong&gt;more accessible and inclusive&lt;/strong&gt; overall (no credit check!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key aspect of DeFi is its composability, often referred as “money lego”: projects built using Ethereum’s DeFi follow standards (such as ERC-20 for basic token definitions) enabling “permission-less interoperability” — it’s possible to integrate any project one with the other, without even requiring the help of its creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are curious about the topic, you’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.notion.so/defifrance/DeFi-Onboarding-Guide-a0713cfe5d844ff28bc829006625b118&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exhaustive DeFi onboarding guide&lt;/a&gt; here that introduces many articles, podcasts and videos to learn more about DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I know DeFi can be a lot, so I develop a very practical approach to it: &lt;strong&gt;we’ll talk only about LIVE, working services&lt;/strong&gt; that have been paying interests to their users for several months at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;earning-returns-on-a-stablecoin&#34;&gt;Earning returns on a stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ A stablecoin (such as DAI) is a token with stable value. It&amp;rsquo;s usually achieved by tracking the value of a stable asset, like the dollar: 1 DAI = $1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decentralised finance ecosystem is structuring itself as a more credible alternative every day. Strong &amp;amp; resilient services emerged as basic tools used by most:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt;: Borrow against ETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/da/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DAI&lt;/a&gt;: Avoid price volatility &amp;amp; earn interest (Dai Saving Rate)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.exchange/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt;: tokens exchange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound Finance&lt;/a&gt;: borrow or lend &amp;amp; earn interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other services exist to produce a passive income thanks to Ethereum, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://realt.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://fulcrum.trade/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;bZx&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the help of these new services, you can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have your assets in $ — &lt;strong&gt;DAI is a cryptocurrency tracking the price of $1&lt;/strong&gt; — so that you’re &lt;strong&gt;not exposed to the markets’ volatility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earn a &lt;strong&gt;5–8% yearly return&lt;/strong&gt;, on that $: your DAI will either be lent or locked directly in the Maker system (Dai Saving Rate) to help stabilize the price of DAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-a-wallet-earning-5-daiday-looklike&#34;&gt;How does a wallet earning 5 DAI/day look like?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To keep it simple here, we’re considering only 3 investments strategy matching different risk profiles, using only two different services:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/5DAI.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Dai Saving Rate is arguably the safest way to earn a return on your DAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The risk is minimal because you’re not lending your money to anyone. To keep it short, you lock your DAI in the Maker system, and the system pays you a premium because you’re helping DAI to maintain its peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;🖊 Edit: Please note that the earning rates presented for specific protocols are no longer accurate. However, similar results can still be achieved with alternative methods.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/defiscore.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;👆 DeFiscore is a community project offering a comprehensive rating of the risks associated with different lending protocols. What you see above is an overview of their ranking of DAI lending opportunities.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;👆&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;DeFiscore&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is a community project offering a comprehensive rating of the risks associated with different lending protocols. What you see above is an overview of their ranking of DAI lending opportunities.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the other solution used, RealT, is a &lt;strong&gt;little more novel and risky&lt;/strong&gt;. RealT tokenises real estate on Ethereum &amp;amp; allow anyone to become an owner. If you own a share of RealT estate, you’ll receive &lt;strong&gt;your share of the rent, paid in DAI, daily&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ Since RealT tokens are securities, you will have to through a KYC to purchase them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the level of risk is higher with RealT than Maker, RealT does have one advantage — so far, the returns are stable. On the other hand, Maker’s DSR rate is still changing quite often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(&lt;em&gt;Nov 18 2019)&lt;/em&gt; DSR  Launched at 2%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(3 Jan)&lt;/em&gt; 4 %&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(8 Jan)&lt;/em&gt; 6 %&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(26 Jan 2020)&lt;/em&gt; 7.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(4 Feb)&lt;/em&gt; 8.75%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;➡ &lt;em&gt;(9 Feb)&lt;/em&gt; 7.5%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-dai-tocoffees&#34;&gt;From DAI to coffees
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a clearer picture as to how we can generate a passive income using cryptocurrencies, you might wonder: what about the coffees?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, thanks to Monolith (disclaimer: I work there) it’s easy as ABC. We provide you with a non-custodial Ethereum wallet, paired with a Visa Debit Card. You can go from DAI in your wallet to a €/£ balance ready to be spent on your card in 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was step 1. We’ve shared recently about a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/monolith_web3/status/1223597132952887302?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;significant upcoming update&lt;/a&gt;, that will let you exchange tokens and access decentralised lending services straight from your Monolith app:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;before-you-jumpin&#34;&gt;Before you jump in
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are seriously considering investing amounts close to those presented in the table above, &lt;strong&gt;please ensure that you know the basics&lt;/strong&gt;: such as using &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/monolith/5-rules-you-need-to-know-to-stay-safe-on-ethereum-2447244cdcb3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;securing&lt;/a&gt; an Ethereum wallet, understanding threats and choosing an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/monolith/the-usability-of-security-the-choice-of-a-contract-wallet-1e32f92ea9a1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;appropriate security model&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You do not need an account on any exchange to use DeFi.&lt;/strong&gt; It is much safer to access DeFi services directly from your wallet. Using a centralised service generates additional risks for your assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to make the jump? Deploy your first contract wallet today and order your Visa debit card &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.app.link/ETH-IS-MONEY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;with the Monolith app&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/freecoffees/card.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.app.link/ETH-IS-MONEY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🆓 &lt;strong&gt;Get your Monolith card for free&lt;/strong&gt; | 🇪🇺 Shipping to 31 countries in Europe | 💸 Spend DAI in a flash with minimal fees | 🔐 Advanced security model | 💱 Built-in DEX Aggregator (soon)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article represents my personal view only — and is written free of any professional affiliation. Facts &amp;amp; data are sourced as much as possible, but my views are my own.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It does not constitute an offer to sell, a solicitation of an offer to buy, or a recommendation of any cryptocurrency, digital token, investment, security or any other product or service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Furthermore, nothing in this article is intended to provide legal or investment advice and nothing in this article should be construed as a recommendation to buy, sell, or hold any cryptocurrency, digital token, investment or security, or to engage in any investment strategy or financial transaction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
