<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>DIGG on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/digg/</link>
        <description>Recent content in DIGG on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/digg/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>BadgerDAO&#39;s story: an intro through DIGG</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/badger-digg/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/badger-digg/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/cover.png/" alt="Featured image of post BadgerDAO&#39;s story: an intro through DIGG" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite launching barely a few weeks ago, BadgerDAO quickly grew into a DeFi powerhouse now &lt;strong&gt;hosting &amp;gt; $1.2B of assets farming&lt;/strong&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;ve quickly touched on Badger in previous articles or shows, I think it&amp;rsquo;s about time for a dedicated piece focusing on DIGG but not forgetting about its context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-quick-intro-to-badger-dao&#34;&gt;A quick intro to Badger DAO
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;BadgetDAO is a community-driven project with a clear value proposition: to help &lt;strong&gt;build the infrastructure needed to relay BTC into DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;. This core vision manifests through all their products, all centered around representations of Bitcoin on Ethereum like wBTC or sBTC and the native tokens - BADGER and now DIGG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clear-value-proposition-btc-on-ethereum-optimizer&#34;&gt;Clear value proposition: BTC on Ethereum optimizer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first layer of this onion is pretty straightforward: Badger offers a Yearn-like service for BTCs on Ethereum: users can deposit tokens representing a position in a Curve BTC pool to earn BADGER &amp;amp; DIGG on top of the native APY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-stats.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-sett-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also vaults (called &amp;ldquo;setts&amp;rdquo;) available for BADGER and DIGG themselves, as well as their respective LP tokens on both Uniswap and SushiSwap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setts function like the Yearn vaults, inspired by the aTokens design on Aave: initially when the vault is launched, the correspondence between the base asset and the vault token is 1:1. As the vault accrues additional tokens through its harvests, the vault token increasingly represents more and more of the underlying asset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This value proposition by itself is nothing new and could have been delivered by Yearn directly. What makes Badger special is &lt;strong&gt;how the team approaches building the product and the whole underlying vision behind it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-focus&#34;&gt;Community-focus
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the start, the community has been put at the center with Badger. It&amp;rsquo;s clearly visible simply by looking at the token distributions&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-breakdown.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-distribution-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/digg-breakdown.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;digg-distribution-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the two largest shares of the supply of both tokens were allocated to the liquidity mining program - rewarding active users of the protocol as well as the DAO&amp;rsquo;s treasury tasked with structuring the long-term operations of the protocol and its growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airdrops, along with the vaults created a very attractive loop for the receivers: unlike the UNI airdrop where most people choice was to sell or hold, with BADGER &amp;amp; DIGG, people &lt;strong&gt;optimistic about the protocol from the get-go had the chance to compound their airdrop with the vaults&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial BADGER airdrop recognized key actions tied to Bitcoin on Ethereum, as well as gitcoin donors. The second airdrop (DIGG) rewarded interactions with the Badger ecosystem itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the momentum created by the launch and initial distribution, the community was able to sustain it thanks to a blossoming spirit of meming: a distribution of NFT was organized on Meme&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, available to the depositors in the bBADGER sett or wBTC/BADGER Uniswap sett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of 6 different NFTs were available and the fist one to collect them was able to claim a neat BADGER bounty. Being a holder or farmer of these NFTs was acknowledged in the initial DIGG distribution &amp;amp; their inclusion to Badger as yield multiplier is being discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-nft-satoshi.gif/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-meme-satoshi-nft&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are very bullish on a token price short-term wise, it&amp;rsquo;s usually a bad idea to enter a 50/50 liquidity providing position on it. You&amp;rsquo;ll be much better off simply holding your stack and selling it. If you are worried about this scenario unfolding with Badger or DIGG, you can deposit to the BADGER or DIGG only vaults (no risk of impermanent loss).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-digging-it-yet&#34;&gt;Are you DIGGing it yet?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG is the second major step of Badger&amp;rsquo;s DAO project: a new type of representation of BTC living on the Ethereum blockchain. Unlike wBTC or renBTC, DIGG is not backed by a fixed supply of BTCs. Instead, it uses the rebase mechanism initiated by Ampleforth to attempt to eventually deliver an asset keeping track of BTC&amp;rsquo;s price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into how DIGG works, let&amp;rsquo;s quickly discuss the pre and post-launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wen-digg&#34;&gt;Wen DIGG?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG&amp;rsquo;s launch was a highly anticipated event. While from the outside it looks like it took longer than what was expected, what happened internally was fascinating: the &lt;strong&gt;initial community gathered around Badger was actively involved in the key decisions surrounding DIGG.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussion within the community, it was decided to go with a relatively low starting supply (4000) allowing for a &lt;strong&gt;stress test from the start of the rebase mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;. The rebases also started from the very beginning - 24h after the launch of the token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/wen-digg.jpeg/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;wen-digg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Badger being Badger, the hype machine was of course on point with a &amp;ldquo;Wen DIGG?&amp;rdquo; meme contest to make sure everyone was aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the meat of it: the rebases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rebases&#34;&gt;Rebases
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG is what is called an &amp;ldquo;elastic currency&amp;rdquo;, as initiated by Ampleforth. What it means is that the total supply of DIGG is not set, but fluctuates daily based on the time-weighted average price of DIGG against its peg - BTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more DIGG is &amp;ldquo;off from his peg&amp;rdquo;, meaning its price is superior to the price of BTC, the more the DIGG supply is diluted, with the additional DIGG produced distributed proportionately to all the holders. The mechanism works exactly the same the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like with AMPL, with DIGG all holders (liquidity pool tokens included) are impacted by the rebase, be it positive or negative. However with DIGG, just like with the seigniorage tokens, there is a mechanism to abstract it to allow for a better composability within DeFi: that&amp;rsquo;s bDIGG, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss it right after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebases happen at a set time, for DIGG it&amp;rsquo;s 3pm EST, that&amp;rsquo;s 9 pm for my dear French readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase tokens harness mechanisms similar to the ones involved in algorithmic stablecoins / seigniorage tokens, so feel free to read my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;previous post on the topic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, after the first day, the genesis rebase was positive and triggered a production and redistribution of about 12% of the initial supply. Several positive rebases followed and DIGG is still trading above peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the rebase mechanism is quite straightforward but it might be better aligned with the setts incentives in the future to help DIGG maintain its peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-step-for-the-setts&#34;&gt;Next step for the setts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With DIGG launched, the next big step for Badger as the protocol is to start increasing its capital efficiency: to put it in simple words - to allow its users to borrow from their setts positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it clearer (while extrapolating quite a bit): picture the current Badger, with an additional function allowing you to mint DAI from your setts like you do with your vaults on Maker. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, setts would make for quite desirable collateral, considering they accrue in value against the base asset. So BTC setts for instance could be potentially as safe as their underlying assets, accounting for the additional layers of risks involved by the fact that the underlying asset is a Curve LP token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, before we see a native lending market on Badger, I expect to see different &lt;strong&gt;Badger-related tokens and setts accepted as collateral&lt;/strong&gt; on other lending platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this front, I&amp;rsquo;d like to draw your attention to bDIGG in particular. While it represents a position made a 100% of DIGG which rebases, &lt;strong&gt;bDIGG itself does not rebase&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s like a layer of abstraction built on top of DIGG, a rebase-buffer amongst other things. It makes it easier to integrate it into other protocols, and I expect to eventually see a wide range of support for bDIGG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-endgame-for-badgerdao--defi-in-general&#34;&gt;The endgame for BadgerDAO &amp;amp; DeFi in general
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The endgame for Badger would be like what I described before along with a full ecosystem around the CLAW or whatever his name is.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It would increasingly turn Badger into a more of a Synthetix-like service where holders are given different options of more or less active involvement in the ecosystem, with the appropriate rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As services like Badger integrate money-market components such as borrowing, they &lt;strong&gt;increase the capital efficiency for their users&lt;/strong&gt;. What used to be a representation of BTC producing 20% APY is now the same + you can borrow a share of its value in stablecoin to further increase the yield, if that suits your risk appetite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This logic is bigger than Badger, as it&amp;rsquo;s observed elsewhere too, we could call it the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;platformization of Defi&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Yearn is implementing a similar approach with the Iron Bank where some services will be able to borrow under-collateralized, generating a capital-efficiency moat for the eligible lucky ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to go back to Badger, moving towards a model like this could mean native &amp;amp; sustained revenue feeds to potentially tie back to Badger. Considering that most of the yields currently come from liquidity mining incentives, that would be quite synergistic to grow out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/dex-value-capture.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;success of the Curve &amp;amp; CRV model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, it makes sense to see more and more protocol adopting elements of it: the gist being giving your holders the options to commit their tokens to participate in governance, tap into the platform revenue streams &amp;amp; boost their own returns obtained by the usage of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphs are coming from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://badgerdao.medium.com/badger-dao-liquidity-mining-launch-b2415301bd31#:~:text=Tokens%20distributed%3A%20%24BADGER%20and%20%24,2nd%20product%20of%20the%20DAO.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Badger&amp;rsquo;s DAO liquidity mining launch announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dontbuymeme.com/collections/badger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Meme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a distribution mechanism for NFT where users stake a given token (bBADGER in our case) to earn points - pineapples. They can them redeem the pineapples for the NFT of their choice.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not purerly speculative as BadgerDAO is already exploring how it could &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/spadaboom1/status/1354826775801561091?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;harness synergies with UMA and SushiSwap&lt;/a&gt; to achieve a similar end.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
