<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>NFT on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/nft/</link>
        <description>Recent content in NFT on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/nft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Chicken Bonds: an NFT-powered hatching factory to beat DeFi’s liquidity chicken and egg problem</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/lusd-chicken-bonds/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/lusd-chicken-bonds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-chicken-bonds-cover-tokenbrice.png" alt="Featured image of post Chicken Bonds: an NFT-powered hatching factory to beat DeFi’s liquidity chicken and egg problem" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquity recently released the LUSD Chicken Bonds, a &lt;strong&gt;game-theory experiment merging DeFi and NFT elements to grow LUSD’s liquidity and reduce its price premium&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Chicken Bonds are building on top of existing protocols, such as Yearn, b.protocol, or Curve, it also instigates novel mechanisms, the two leading ones being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No maturity principal-protected bonding&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicken Bonds use a new type of bonding offering strong guarantees to the depositor, including the possibility to recoup the entire initially supplied capital at no cost (Chicken Out).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate to Earn dynamic NFT&lt;/strong&gt;: While interacting with the LUSD Chicken Bonds protocol, users obtain a &lt;strong&gt;dynamic NFT&lt;/strong&gt; that evolves depending on their choices and previous onchain interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds tackle one of the core challenges of DeFi, the sustainable growth of liquidity pools, first for the LUSD token only. Still, eventually, the model will be made available in a generalizable permissionless version for any protocol in need of liquidity to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post explores how &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chickenbonds.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LUSD Chicken Bonds&lt;/a&gt; work and what they achieve. However, before answering these questions, additional context is needed on LUSD: let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context-lusd-price-premium&#34;&gt;The context: LUSD price premium
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most misunderstood dimensions of Liquity’s model is &lt;strong&gt;LUSD pegging mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, while LUSD has strong guarantees (hard peg) than LUSD&amp;gt;$1.00 (redemption) and &amp;lt;$1.10 (110% minimal collateralization ratio), in between the equilibrium is more based on a &lt;strong&gt;game of incentives (soft peg)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.chainalysis.com/reports/tornado-cash-sanctions-challenges/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OFAC’s crackdown on Tornado Cash&lt;/a&gt; back in August, there has been an &lt;strong&gt;increased demand&lt;/strong&gt; for censorship-resistant stablecoins. Yet, the &lt;strong&gt;appetite for leverage is low&lt;/strong&gt; because of the deteriorated market conditions. Thus, will the demand for LUSD is high, a significant share of its adopters purchase it at a premium on the markets instead of minting it by leveraging their ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both factors have converged over the last few months, leading to a &lt;strong&gt;sustained price premium&lt;/strong&gt; for LUSD, often trading in the $1.02 to $1.04 range. I won’t expand too deeply into this topic here, as it has already been covered on Liquity’s blog: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/the-premium-of-resiliency&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Premium of Resiliency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. However, let’s discuss &lt;strong&gt;the impact of the premium on Liquity users&lt;/strong&gt; since it has real consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-peg-incentives.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-peg-incentives&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-of-the-lusd-premium&#34;&gt;Impact of the LUSD premium
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impact of a price premium on borrowers &lt;strong&gt;can be positive or negative&lt;/strong&gt;, depending on their timing and actions. Borrowers worried about LUSD price volatility can use Chicken Bonds, or b.protocol to preserve a pure LUSD exposure while earning yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that borrowers who preserve a 100% LUSD exposure do not suffer any consequence from its price fluctuations since they do not need to buy it back when repaying their debt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, having LUSD fluctuates can also benefit informed users that can arbitrage the discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profit margin&lt;/strong&gt; | The more LUSD goes over $1, the more profitable it is to take an arbitrage trade on its peg: at $1.01, shorting the peg returns $0.01 per LUSD if successful. At $1.09, the profits jump to $0.09 per LUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Likelihood of profits being realized&lt;/strong&gt; | The farther away LUSD strands from $1.00, and the closer it gets to $1.10, the more likely it is for peg arbitrageurs to outweigh LUSD buyers and thus push the price downward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus arbitraging LUSD is a game of balance between maximizing profits (1) and their odds of realizing (2). To put it simply: past a certain price point, the arbitrage trade becomes &lt;strong&gt;too profitable and too likely to realize for arbitrageurs to ignore&lt;/strong&gt;. It has helped to ensure that LUSD stayed in the lower bond of its soft peg, the $1.00-$1.05 range, even during phases of peak demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For users who do not monitor the situation continuously, though, it can translate into a loss of capital — for instance, if one borrows LUSD while the price is at $1.02, invest it into something else, and then weeks later try to buy back LUSD to repay its debt, only to find the price at $1.04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, LUSD’s fluctuations in the $1.00-1.10 range add &lt;strong&gt;an additional layer of uncertainty for borrowers&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing the liquidity of LUSD and stabilizing its peg will help restore the borrowers’ confidence and streamline interactions with the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-lusd-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;Enter LUSD Chicken Bonds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/chicken-bonds.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-chicken-bonds&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve LUSD’s liquidity challenge, the Liquity team worked on a &lt;strong&gt;brand new protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, first tried out with LUSD: Chicken Bonds. If successful, the model will be generalized with an LQTY instance. As a final step, the generalized model could be made ready to be harnessed by any DAO with the Chicken Bond Factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/chicken-bonds-is-live&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the LUSD Chicken Bonds were released&lt;/a&gt;, offering &lt;strong&gt;a novel proposition merging DeFi and NFTs&amp;rsquo; elements providing optimized yield-producing opportunities to LUSD holders&lt;/strong&gt;. It will also fuel the growth of LUSD’s liquidity on the LUSD/3CRV Curve pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two protagonists interacting with Chicken Bonds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The depositors (users)&lt;/strong&gt; enjoy a gamified experience delivering &lt;strong&gt;amplified and auto-compounded yields on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The deployer (protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; sets up an &lt;strong&gt;engine enabling the sustained growth and capture of liquidity on its token&lt;/strong&gt; while actively engaging its holders.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-exactly-are-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;So, what exactly are Chicken Bonds?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, Chicken Bonds fulfill the function of different types of products depending on the perspective. &lt;strong&gt;For users, Chicken Bonds act like an NFT-enhanced yield optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;. Bonding enables them to maximize their returns on LUSD by optimizing the compounding frequency and amplifying the existing yields. From their perspective, they could compare the utility of Chicken Bonds to the one already delivered by a protocol like Yearn, lacking the NFT element. It maximizes and streamlines yield-producing activities on LUSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the deployer (protocol) perspective, Chicken Bonds are a &lt;strong&gt;cost-effective solution to develop the available liquidity on their token&lt;/strong&gt;. Alternative solutions to achieve a similar goal would include liquidity mining, POL-capture solution like Olympus Pro, acquiring liquidity-driver tokens (CRV, BAL, VELO, etc.)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or bribing liquidity-driver token owner votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/chicken-egg.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;chicken-egg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While each existing solution has its own tradeoffs, they all share a similar profile: they &lt;strong&gt;require recurring expenses to grow and sustain liquidity&lt;/strong&gt;. Only the acquisition of liquidity-driver tokens can provide continuous incentives to support liquidity, but it’s also the most costly approach as it requires significant investments from projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Chicken Bonds have no cost as they harness existing yield sources: &lt;strong&gt;all it needs to capture and grow liquidity is time&lt;/strong&gt;. They harness a novel form of &lt;strong&gt;no-maturity principal-protected bonding&lt;/strong&gt;, offering amplified yields and strong protections for the depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain the model of LUSD Chicken Bonds, let’s jump to the depositor perspective by looking at the lifecycle of a bond and its impact on the associated NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-story-of-a-bond-through-its-nft&#34;&gt;The story of a bond through its NFT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3chickens-static.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3chickens&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create a bond, a user deposits LUSD. In exchange, he receives an 🥚 Egg NFT representing his deposit&lt;/strong&gt;. The NFT contains the claim on the underlying bonded LUSD and can be sold or transferred. From thereon, the user has two mutually exclusive options that will transform his NFT too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐔 Chicken In&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or 🐣 Chicken Out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Egg NFTs have four attributes: a card, egg, and background colors rolled randomly, and an egg-size scaling with the deposited LUSD amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an egg is created, it starts progressively accruing bLUSD. As the bond matures, it becomes profitable for the users to claim it, forgoing their LUSD to obtain the bLUSD accumulated — It’s the “&lt;strong&gt;Chicken In&lt;/strong&gt;” option and makes the visual of the NFT evolve accordingly: the Egg turns into a 🐔 &lt;strong&gt;Proud Chicken&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user can recover the full invested amount at any time during the process. Still, he will renounce the bLUSD accumulated so far — it’s the “&lt;strong&gt;Chicken Out&lt;/strong&gt;” option and also leads to an evolution of the NFT from the Egg to a 🐣 &lt;strong&gt;Scared Chick&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3chickens.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3chickens&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;going-deeper-into-the-chicken-bonds-nft&#34;&gt;Going deeper into the Chicken Bonds NFT
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Chickening In, the NFT gains additional attributes rolled at random (comb, tail, beak, and wings) and special attributes depending on the wallet onchain activities. Wallets engaged in the following activities are eligible for special attributes or boosted chances at rolling rarer ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning a Liquity Trove with ongoing debt,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning LQTY, or staking it either directly or with Pickle,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting for the LUSD/3CRV gauge (veCRV holders).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NFT collection also harnesses interesting mechanisms, such as the &lt;strong&gt;affinity&lt;/strong&gt; to generate the coolest chickens possible; read the dedicated article on Liquity’s blog for more information on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/egg-variants-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;egg-variants-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All NFTs are part of the same collection and can be traded on the usual venues, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://looksrare.org/collections/0xa8384862219188a8f03c144953Cf21fc124029Ee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LooksRare&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://x2y2.io/collection/lusd-chicken-bonds-nfts/items&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;X2Y2&lt;/a&gt;. Chicken Bonds is a generative NFT collection as much as a DeFi protocol: both are intrinsically tied together. The art and initial generation script were made by the NFT artist &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://luchadores.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Luchador&lt;/a&gt;, creator of the eponym game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an explainer of all the attributes and modifiers taken into account, read the article dedicated to the NFTs on the Chicken Bonds blog:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/nft-x-defi-deep-dive-into-lusd-chicken-bonds-dynamic-nft&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFT x DeFi: Deep dive into LUSD Chicken Bonds&amp;rsquo; Dynamic NFT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;boostedlusd-blusd-a-yield-enhanced-auto-compounded-lusd&#34;&gt;boostedLUSD (bLUSD): a yield-enhanced auto-compounded LUSD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By bonding and eventually Chickening In, depositors can accumulate bLUSD, but you might wonder at this point why this token can be desirable: let’s dive into the beefy DeFi side of Chicken Bonds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/blusd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;blusd&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short story is that &lt;strong&gt;owning bLUSD provides access to auto-compounded and amplified yields on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. bLUSD is a standard ERC-20 token backed by LUSD thanks to the redemption mechanism, with a rising price floor thanks to the yield amplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/user-flow-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;user-flow-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;base-yield-source&#34;&gt;Base yield source
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a protocol, Chicken Bonds collect LUSD and deploy them into two potential yield sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquity Stability Pool&lt;/strong&gt;, where LUSD can be deposited to earn LQTY as well as variable ETH liquidation premiums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Curve LUSD/3CRV&lt;/strong&gt;, where LUSD can be supplied against USDC/USDT/DAI to earn trading fees as well as CRV tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with how Liquity works yet, you can get up to date with this dedicated article: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖️ Liquity: an unstoppable, efficient and innovative borrowing service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;auto-compounded&#34;&gt;Auto compounded
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of plugging into the yield sources directly, middleware solutions are used to provide various benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposits into the Liquity Stability Pool are managed using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bprotocol.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;B.Protocol vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which handles the frequent harvesting and compounding of ETH and LQTY obtained into LUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Curve Pool, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yearn.finance/#/vault/0x5fA5B62c8AF877CB37031e0a3B2f34A78e3C56A6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is used to optimize the yields obtained by harnessing Convex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, so good: streamlined solutions to simple problems. Yet, the yield amplification, one of the biggest feats of the Chicken Bonds, is a bit trickier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;yield-amplification&#34;&gt;Yield Amplification
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand how it can achieve this, we must start peeling the onion that is the internal accounting tool of the protocol: the Buckets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three buckets enabling the Chicken bonds to guarantee the three core features of the protocol: the option to Chicken Out (Pending), the yield amplification (Reserve), and the growth of liquidity (Permanent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3buckets.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3buckets&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Pending Bucket&lt;/strong&gt; has a simple job: it must be able to repay investors fully if they were to Chicken Out. To ensure it’s always possible, the Pending Bucket harnesses a yield source free of impermanent loss: the Stability Pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users Chicken In a bond, the corresponding LUSD balances are split between the Reserve and Permanent Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reserve Bucket backs bLUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. With redemptions, bLUSD holders can burn their tokens to obtain a pro-rata share of the LUSD contained in the Reserve Bucket —  securing a price floor for bLUSD. Funds in reserve are also producing a yield harnessing the Stability Pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, the Permanent Bucket grows the liquidity of LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to its shifting function, triggerable by anyone when LUSD is overpeg, the Permanent Bucket can pull its liquidity out of the b.protocol vault to single supply the Curve LUSD/3CRV pool instead. It helps reduce the LUSD price and secures a favorable entry point in the pool since the deposit rebalances it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yield produced by the Pending and Permanent buckets is redirected to the Reserve Bucket&lt;/strong&gt;, which creates the yield amplification and rising price floor of bLUSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-cb-user-timeline.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-cb-user-timeline&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bootstrap-period--next-steps&#34;&gt;Bootstrap period &amp;amp; next steps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LUSD Chicken Bonds have been live since Tuesday, October 4, 2022. During the first two weeks of the system, until Oct 19, it’s still in the &lt;strong&gt;bootstrap period&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicken Ins are not possible, which means the supply of bLUSD is still 0. It means that all the LUSD are in the Pending Bucket, except the yield already produced that is being redirected to the Reserve Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the bootstrap period is over, the Chicken In option will be available, enabling depositors to start accessing bLUSD. To facilitate getting in and out of bLUSD, a &lt;strong&gt;bLUSD liquidity pool will be incentivized on Curve Finance, using a 3% fee paid while Chickening In&lt;/strong&gt;. It will enable the liquidity to develop progressively as the first batch of bonds reaches their break-even point (~Oct 19) and optimal rebond time (~Nov 4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section will discuss the chosen liquidity structure and its impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chicken-bonds-impact-on-lusds-price-and-liquidity&#34;&gt;Chicken Bonds’ impact on LUSD’s price and liquidity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you read me up to this point, you are now in the know regarding LUSD’s price premium and the model introduced by the Chicken Bonds. Let’s connect the dots then and consider how the LUSD Chicken Bonds will &lt;strong&gt;contribute to LUSD’s overall liquidity and help to contain its premium&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds have two impacts on LUSD liquidity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the growth of the Permanent Bucket, the liquidity supplied to the LUSD/3CRV will grow as long as the LUSD price still has a premium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The liquidity pool structure was chosen for bLUSD to help further grow liquidity on the LUSD/3CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a short time frame, the release of LUSD Chicken Bonds lead to more demand for LUSD and an increase in its price. However, LUSD deposited into the Chicken Bonds proves beneficial to LUSD’s liquidity in the long run, as we highlight in this section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-engine-to-capture-liquity-over-time&#34;&gt;An engine to capture liquity over time
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As deposits into the LUSD Chicken Bonds accrue, the potential impact on the LUSD peg grows. Indeed, when a user Chickens In, the underlying LUSD are distributed between the Reserve and the Permanent Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, all three buckets produce yield by deploying the LUSD into the b.protocol vault. However, the Permanent Bucket also features a &lt;strong&gt;shifting function&lt;/strong&gt; triggerable by anyone as long as LUSD trades at a premium. It shifts the LUSD of the Permanent Bucket to &lt;strong&gt;provide liquidity on Curve&lt;/strong&gt; (single asset supply), helping to progressively rebalance the pool while also growing its liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The share of the total amount of LUSD deposited into Chicken Bonds allocated to the Permanent Bucket is hard to predict, as it depends on users&amp;rsquo; behaviors. Here are some napkin maths using a conservative estimate of 10% of the total assets in the Permanent Bucket, with the 5M LUSD currently available in the LUSD/3CRV to estimate the Chicken Bonds impact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Chicken Bonds TVL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Directly Added Liquity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Added Liquity (%)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;7M (Current)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;700K LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;14.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;10M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;20.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;20M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;40.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;50M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;5M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;100.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The added liquidity percentage could be a good proxy indicator of how much of the price premium can be reduced. Keep in mind that it remains approximative, as it only considers the LUSD/3CRV main pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, with $10M TVL into the Chicken Bonds by the end of the first cycle, the impact could already be palpable with an increase of ~20% of the LUSD amount available in the Curve pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shifting function is disabled for the first 45 days of the system, i.e. until November 19. After this date, anyone will be able to move the Permanent Bucket liquidity from Curve &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; B.Protocol if &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://liquity.gitbook.io/chicken-bonds/faq/lusd-peg-stability#_vowf7444yzdt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;conditions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are met.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;growing-blusd-liquidity-hands-in-hand-with-lusd&#34;&gt;Growing bLUSD liquidity hands in hand with LUSD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is another indirect beneficial effect of the Chicken Bonds, stemming from the chosen structure for bLUSD liquidity, incentivized by the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, a &lt;strong&gt;3% Chicken In fee is collected and redirected to incentivize liquidity providers of the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool&lt;/strong&gt;. This pool is a meta pool made of bLUSD paired with the LP token of the existing LUSD/3CRV. At perfect equilibrium, the asset exposure would be: 50% bLUSD / 25% LUSD + 25% 3pool (8.33% USDC / 8.33% USDT / 8.33% DAI).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This liquidity structure ensures that &lt;strong&gt;50% of the deposits made into the bLUSD LP pool directly contribute to growing the liquidity of the main LUSD/3CRV&lt;/strong&gt;. Moreover, because this pool has its own incentive budget (Chicken In fee), it will provide an attractive LUSD yield to stakers on top of the base yield generated by swaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Chicken Bonds mature, the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool could get its own gauge, securing additional CRV (and potentially CVX) rewards on top of the existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model was chosen over a bLUSD/LUSD pool which would have required a sizeable amount of LUSD without contributing to LUSD’s liquidity against other stablecoins. The main downside of the chosen model is that it makes the deposit and withdrawal interactions more complex for liquidity providers. However, this concern will be lifted with &lt;strong&gt;zaps enabling the supply and withdrawal from LUSD and bLUSD directly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool equilibrium, supplying it single-sided with either LUSD or bLUSD can result in a premium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is too much LUSD-3CRV in the pool, providing bLUSD rebalances the pool and results in a premium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is too much bLUSD in the pool, then supplying it with LUSD will result in a &lt;strong&gt;double premium&lt;/strong&gt; as both the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV and LUSD/3CRV pools are rebalanced in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV in the dedicated article on the Chicken Bonds blog &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/game-of-chickens-the-end-of-the-bootstrap-period-and-what-it-means-for-blusd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Chickens!&lt;/strong&gt; The end of the bootstrap period and what it means for bLUSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-solutions-to-grow-lusds-liquidity&#34;&gt;Additional solutions to grow LUSD’s liquidity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds are the main ongoing initiatives attempting to grow LUSD’s liquidity, yet, other projects and solutions are being explored too. Here’s an overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vecrv-position-and-bribes&#34;&gt;veCRV position and bribes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liquity treasury entered the Curve Wars months ago, acquiring and locking CRV tokens to support the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV gauge. To maximize the impact of the LUSD Chicken Bonds, &lt;strong&gt;a bribing campaign&lt;/strong&gt; is also synchronized with the release to increase the CRV APY of LUSD/3CRV pool depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Warden Quest, LQTY tokens are awarded to veCRV and vlCVX voters on the LUSD/3CRV CRV gauge. The bribing campaign secured &lt;strong&gt;5M veCRV votes (~1% of total votes)&lt;/strong&gt;, which led to a sharp increase in the APY, bringing it to parity with a basic Stability Pool deposit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you out of the loop with the Curve Wars? Start here: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV wars: the race to accumulate the ability to influence the Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;powerpools-lucy-interest-bearing-lusd-lp-position&#34;&gt;PowerPool’s LUCY: interest-bearing LUSD LP position
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PowerPool team has been working on an interesting &lt;strong&gt;novel type of Balancer pool&lt;/strong&gt; suited for LUSD, and it’s now close to being released: the LUSD-a-bb-USD pool, also known under the sweet name of &lt;strong&gt;LUCY&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Chicken Bonds, this pool &lt;strong&gt;harnesses b.protocol to provide an auto-compounded earning opportunity on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the main innovation of this pool is to involve interest-bearing assets and constantly &lt;strong&gt;rebalances between yield-bearing and liquidity-providing activities&lt;/strong&gt;. The pool is made of two wrapper tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-balancer-boosted-aave-usd&#34;&gt;1/ Balancer Boosted Aave USD
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pool is essentially the &lt;strong&gt;Balancer’s equivalent of Curve’s 3 pool&lt;/strong&gt;, the main stablecoin pool of the decentralized exchange. The key difference here is that the pool involves &lt;strong&gt;interest-bearing wrappers&lt;/strong&gt; of each stablecoin. Depending on the pool’s liquidity needs, each stablecoin rebalances between liquidity-providing or yield-bearing through Aave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/bbaUSD-pool-composition.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bbaUSD-pool-composition&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-lusd--bprotocol&#34;&gt;2/ LUSD + b.protocol
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bb-a-USD tokens are paired against LUSD, which also &lt;strong&gt;rebalances yield-bearing (Stability Pool with b.protocol) and liquidity-providing&lt;/strong&gt; depending on the needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the LUCY pool should be interesting to grow LUSD’s available liquidity, as it could provide an interest yield-stacking option for liquity providers, earning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;swap fees APR&lt;/strong&gt;, collected on exchanges involving the pool’s tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;base yield&lt;/strong&gt; on each pool token (Aave’s yield for USDC/USDT/DAI, Stability Pool’s yields for LUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[If a BAL gauge is obtained] the &lt;strong&gt;LP token BAL staking APY&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be further increased with gauge votes and bribing campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel pool will mark the arrival of LUSD on Balancer, diversifying its liquidity source further, as the main venues to trade LUSD are currently Curve, Uniswap, and Velodrome on Optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lusd-integrations-into-other-lending-protocols&#34;&gt;LUSD integrations into other lending protocols
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, LUSD has been increasingly integrated across various DeFi protocols, providing &lt;strong&gt;additional options to LUSD holders and arbitrageurs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.aave.com/reserve-overview/?underlyingAsset=0x5f98805a4e8be255a32880fdec7f6728c6568ba0&amp;amp;marketName=proto_mainnet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;addition of LUSD as a borrowable asset on Aave&lt;/a&gt; marked the first time the stablecoin could be borrowed using collateral other than ETH to secure the position. As the liquidity available on the market grows, it opens LUSD arbitrage to non-ETH holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-aave-market.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-aave-market&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;strong&gt;LUSD was also added as collateral on two €-based lending protocols&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://angle.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Angle Money&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mimo.capital/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mimo&lt;/a&gt;. Both enable LUSD holders to enter a short position on €, using their LUSD as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gearbox.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GearBox&lt;/a&gt; is gearing up to release its V2 shortly, enabling users to get leverage according to a pre-determined and smart-contract-enforced set of rules. Amongst the options available at release, &lt;strong&gt;liquidity providers of the LUSD/3CRV will be able to leverage their position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing the lending market of LUSD beyond Liquity grows the stablecoin utility while enabling more various types of users to arbitrage its price fluctuations. Paired with the ongoing efforts to grow LUSD’s liquidity on DEX, it will help stabilize its price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lusd-on-optimism-velodrome-and-stargate&#34;&gt;LUSD on Optimism: Velodrome and Stargate
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LUSD also &lt;strong&gt;has a strong presence on Optimism&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to Liquity being one of the protocols involved in the Velodrome races. With a respectable veVELO position, Liquity has been able to grow several LUSD-related pools to sizeable TVL. Moreover, pools on Velodrome tend to be more balanced than the mainnet pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-velodrome.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-velodrome&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, bridging LUSD to Optimism is currently a bit of a one-way trip. Bridging LUSD to Optimism is easy and only takes 5-10 min using the official bridge. However bridging back to the mainnet takes 7 days with the official bridge, and no alternative options with decent liquidity are available yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is about to change, enabling LUSD’s strong liquidity on Optimism to positively impact the mainnet situation: Stargate, the omnichain liquidity transport protocol, recently voted to &lt;strong&gt;add support for LUSD&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://snapshot.org/#/stgdao.eth/proposal/0xe6fef4aa9c8e9d162f694ab764b11c06918b9f199aafe43e0d85b12d8271011c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SIP#16&lt;/a&gt;), which will enable its fast bridging from and to Optimism once implemented. If Stargate can provide a reliable solution to fast bridge LUSD from Optimism to mainnet, it could positively impact mainnet’s LUSD liquidity pools balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-more-about-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;Learn more about Chicken Bonds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article piqued your curiosity about Chicken Bonds and LUSD. If that’s the case, many resources are available for you to explore the model further; here are some recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chicken Bonds website&lt;/a&gt; is a great starting point — you’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/lusd-bonds#front-ends&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the list of the front ends&lt;/a&gt; you can use to interact with LUSD Chicken Bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To go deeper, feel free to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check the blog&lt;/a&gt; available on the website: it features several articles deep diving into critical dimensions of the Chicken Bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the most comprehensive resource about Chicken Bonds is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://liquity.gitbook.io/chicken-bonds/faq/table-of-content&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the user documentation&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to check it if some of your questions are left unanswered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep track of what is happening with the Chicken Bonds, you&amp;rsquo;ll find stats in the UI of the front-end you use. Else, a community member has made a neat &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.com/nemoventures/chicken-bonds&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chicken Bonds Dune Analytics&lt;/a&gt; that will be helpful. For further discussion, you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/WQMEcgHBpc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;join the Liquity Discord&lt;/a&gt;, where a brand new section is dedicated to Chicken Bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, Liquity is the only &amp;ldquo;deployer.&amp;rdquo; This concept will gain relevance with the Generalized version of the Chicken Bonds, where other protocols can harness the model to benefit their tokens.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquidity driver tokens enable direct incentives to selected liquidity or lending pairs, usually through a locking system. They allow projects which lock them to direct emissions to pools of their choosing to attract liquidity.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, this is the first time this kind of bribery has been attempted on Curve voters (or any other DeFi token holders): NFT-attribute-based bribes; here we come!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pool is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/factory-crypto/134&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;already live&lt;/a&gt; but cannot be supplied before the end of the bootstrap period.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>NFTfi: NFT meets DeFi, liquidity and leverage ensue</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/nftfi-defi-nft/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/nftfi-defi-nft/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/nft-defi-infrastructure-tokenbrice.png" alt="Featured image of post NFTfi: NFT meets DeFi, liquidity and leverage ensue" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decentralized finance has opened up a world of possibilities: a myriad of previously necessary intermediaries are now supernumerary. Nevertheless, it is intimidating because of its potential complexity and interdisciplinary. In addition to the obvious technical dimension, DeFi also invokes concepts from various disciplines: economics, social sciences, &amp;ldquo;memetics&amp;rdquo;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, for years now, NFTs have served as a gateway to the decentralized world, demonstrating the benefits of tokenization and disintermediation to a population still not very fond of DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today I propose to converge the two main themes of this blog into one captivating topic: the emergence of DeFi infrastructure for NFTs, or the arrival of NFTs/gamification in DeFi - it&amp;rsquo;s all about perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;defi--nft--nftfi--a-world-of-possibilities-for-your-jpegs&#34;&gt;DeFi + NFT =&amp;gt; NFTfi : a world of possibilities for your JPEGs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The use cases at the crossroads of DeFi and NFTs are numerous and in full development. Rather than an exhaustive list, I propose to analyze a few emblematic projects to understand how they assemble elements from both universes to offer a relevant service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This infography is a good starting point to deepen your analysis of the NFTfi landscape if this article arouses your curiosity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/nftfi-landscape.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;nftfi-landscape&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the most intuitive one for those who are already a bit up to date with DeFi: the arrival of a financial infrastructure to exchange, but also to lend, to make productive or to split NFTs. To tackle this vast subject, let&amp;rsquo;s start from the first layer: the infrastructure used to buy and sell NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nft-buying-and-selling-services&#34;&gt;NFT buying and selling services
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Until recently, NFTs were in a strange in-between situation. In essence, NFTs allow disintermediation and more direct interaction between creators and their audience. With this disintermediation comes a massive reduction in the costs incurred to bring a work to market and new possibilities, such as their interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only thing is, NFTs are still exchanged mainly on a service that is not up to their standards, I named OpenSea - which still remains dominant although the situation is changing rapidly since the arrival of LooksRare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail, OpenSea has many limitations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A near-weary fee for each exchange - 2.5% - and that is reserved exclusively for the team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A basic lack of respect for the NFT community: violation of their privacy, manipulation, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A certain disregard for the most community-based NFT projects: the verification mechanisms on OpenSea are not very transparent and do not really depend on the volume. Pitiful projects, but carried by celebrities, have been verified quickly while Luchadores, for example, are still waiting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A lack of investment in its own development: the platform is slow to evolve and does not listen to its users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A 100% business approach: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.crunchbase.com/organization/opensea/company_financials&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenSea has done 9 fundraisings&lt;/a&gt; so far, and this despite the gargantuan profits they generate via the excessive fees charged: $100M in volume &lt;strong&gt;on 1 day ⇒ $2.5M in the team&amp;rsquo;s pockets&lt;/strong&gt; (- operational fees, but still&amp;hellip;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So we get a situation close to the US ISPs: OpenSea is used by everyone in the NFT world, but also &lt;strong&gt;virtually hated by a significant part of its users&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s start by looking at the data which speaks for itself:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/looksrare-vs-opensea.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;looksrare-vs-opensea&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re just looking at volume here. In terms of number of users and transactions OpenSea still dominates. You can find all the data on the super dashboard &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hildobby_&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;from Hildoby&lt;/a&gt; : &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.xyz/hildobby/LooksRare-VS-OpenSea&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LooksRare VS Opensea (Dune Analytics)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of us were waiting for a credible alternative, and fortunately it has arrived: LooksRare. The case is worth digging into, but in short LooksRare is the exact opposite of OpenSea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transaction fees are reduced to 2% and &lt;strong&gt;redistributed entirely&lt;/strong&gt; to LOOKS token stakers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The LooksRare team is very attentive to the community and in two months of existence, they have already implemented many features requested by their users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The LOOKS token has been airdropped to OpenSea users. It can now be obtained by buying or selling NFT on Looksrare: &lt;strong&gt;a direct distribution&lt;/strong&gt; to the users of the service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A POL (Protocol Owned Liquidity) strategy is implemented by the protocol: a significant part of the liquidity on LOOKS is owned directly by the protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol already has nearly $13M in ETH+LOOK deployed on UniswapV3 to support liquidity - here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://debank.com/profile/0xc8c57e4c73c71f72ca0a7e043e5d2d144f98ef13&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LooksRare&amp;rsquo;s wallet&lt;/a&gt; to see for yourself. The fees collected on the LP are used to&amp;hellip; bring more and more liquidity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/looksrare-pol.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;looksrare-pol&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new set of rules allows LooksRare to be extremely competitive compared to Opensea, since the fee is 20% lower, and each purchase/sale is also paid in LOOKS. The result is clear: both buyers and sellers benefit from preferring LooksRare to Opensea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/looksrare-vs-opensea-cost.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;looksrare-vs-opensea-cost&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenization-explained-with-nfts-partialization&#34;&gt;Tokenization explained with NFTs partialization
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exchanging NFTs is great: you still need to understand what&amp;rsquo;s in the box! We will therefore detail the stakes of tokenization with several examples. Indeed, the possibilities offered by the latter are immense, so let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take the time to explain the concept. Tokenization is the action of creating a token (a token that &lt;strong&gt;represents&lt;/strong&gt; something). At first sight like that, the interest can be hard to conceive. However, tokenizing also allows for a form of &amp;ldquo;alchemy&amp;rdquo;: a transmutation - a change in the type of token from fungible to non-fungible, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example that illustrates the benefits of tokenization - the case of &lt;strong&gt;fractionalizing an NFT&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We start with a specific non-fungible token, CryptoPunk #666 for example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We lock it in a contract that issues 10 000 PUNK tokens, ERC-20 tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We now have a token that represents 1/10,000 of the original CryptoPunk #666. This token is a classic ERC-20 and therefore easily exchangeable via Uniswap or other (⚠️ Liquidity)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⇒ Tokenization here allows &lt;strong&gt;collective ownership of a unique asset&lt;/strong&gt; (the NFT CryptoPunk #666).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept, while illustrating the benefits of tokenization also corresponds to a real use case. The reality is of course more complex, since we have only described here the collectivization mechanism (1 NFT ⇒ 10 000 ERC20). The reverse path is also possible to recover access to the locked NFT: 10 000 PUNK ⇒ NFT CryptoPunk #666: this is privatization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model is the one of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://spectre.xyz/litepaper&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Spectrum.xyz&lt;/a&gt;, a service that allows to manage the collectivization and privatization of NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/spectre.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;spectre-xyz&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the collective possession, such a solution also has an interest in terms of liquidity: the obtained token (PUNK) is a classic ERC20, it is thus much easier to develop solutions allowing its immediate purchase and sale than with an NFT, which requires the meeting of a simultaneous demand and offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenization-to-develop-liquidity-vaults&#34;&gt;Tokenization to develop liquidity: vaults
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once tokenization is well understood, the next chapter - NFT vaults - is almost a given. One of the challenges of NFTs is the liquidity of the markets. Non-fungibility is great for making collections of 10,000 coins, all of which are unique but similar - but what about the valuation and exchange of these?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides LooksRare and Opensea mentioned above, there are other marketplaces for NFTs that rely on a different logic: this is &lt;strong&gt;the NFT vault model&lt;/strong&gt; - which has many interests, but also limitations - the main one being that this approach is only possible with large collections (several hundred units) and/or quite popular (high demand).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[MINT] A &amp;ldquo;vault&amp;rdquo; (smart contract) specific to a collection is created; users can deposit their NFTs in it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a user deposits an NFT in the vault, its contribution is recognized by the emission of an ERC20 token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[REDEEM] At any time, the ERC20 token can be exchanged for any NFT in the vault. The ERC20 token is then destroyed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;⚠️ As you can see, the vault assumes that all NFTs are equivalent: so it is better to enter a vault with an NFT among the least rare of the given collection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The leader in this field is probably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nftx.io/vault/0x87931e7ad81914e7898d07c68f145fc0a553d8fb/info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFTX&lt;/a&gt;, but there is also &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nft20.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFT20&lt;/a&gt;. This method allows you to get an ERC20 token - for example the WIZARD - that corresponds to a claim on any NFT in the vault, in this case any of the 215 Forgotten Wizard Cult (NFTs) contained in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nftx.io/vault/0x87931e7ad81914e7898d07c68f145fc0a553d8fb/info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the vault.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/nftx-wizard-list.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;nftx-wizard-list&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The liquidity on the WIZARD token can be developed against ETH for example, allowing the immediate purchase of any wizard contained in the vault. The reverse is also possible: any owner of a Forgotten Wizard Cult can deposit it in the vault in order to obtain 1 WIZARD which he can then sell for ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally NFTX goes even further since the platform&amp;rsquo;s native token as well as the collected fees are used to offer incentives to deṕoser in the vault and develop liquidity. &lt;strong&gt;Users who&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;deposit NFTs into the vault are thus eligible for a staking fee&lt;/strong&gt; - and higher returns are possible for those who deposit + LP: the financialization of NFTs is launched!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/nftx-wizard.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;nftx-wizard&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The focus here is on liquidity, but keep in mind that switching from an NFT to an ERC-20 comes with many other benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the liquidity on the pair is sufficient - then it also becomes &lt;strong&gt;a price source&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Price source (oracle) + liquidity means&amp;hellip; collateral of course! With these two elements, there is nothing to prevent the WIZARD from being considered as &lt;strong&gt;collateral for borrowing&lt;/strong&gt; other tokens like stablecoins. This is feasible but much more complex starting directly from the NFT.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, keep in mind that there is no limit to tokenization, as long as there is an interest. We stayed here on single tokenization cases, but &lt;strong&gt;tangled tokenization&lt;/strong&gt; scenarios are also possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ERC-20 token that represents a claim on a given Wizard is great. Now imagine that you have the same thing for CryptoPunks, BAYC and so on - this is the case on NFTX. There is nothing to prevent us from considering an additional tokenization step to create an &lt;strong&gt;NFT index&lt;/strong&gt; represented by an ERC20 token but which would itself &lt;strong&gt;be exchangeable against the tokens representing the underlying assets:&lt;/strong&gt; :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One could thus imagine the NFT-Bluechip-Index, an ERC-20 token created by locking 1 WIZARD + 1 PUNK + 1 BAYC. This token would be easily liquid, and thus allow for easy exposure to all three collections in a single transaction. In addition, the token would remain fully collateralized at all times by 1 NFT from each collection. An owner of the NFT-Bluechip-Index could do the opposite at any time, i.e.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[With the NFT-Bluechip contract] : burn 1 NFT-Bluechip-Index to get 1 WIZARD + 1 PUNK + 1 BAYC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Using NFTX contracts/vaults] burn of 1 WIZARD + 1 PUNK + 1 BAYC to retrieve one NFT (of your choice from those in the vault) from each underlying collection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;idol--ntfs-to-tokenize-a-defi-yield&#34;&gt;Idol : NTFs to tokenize a DeFi yield
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To continue and finish on tokenization, know that it also allows to link the two worlds - NFTs and DeFi: the perfect example here is the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.theidols.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IdolsNFT&lt;/a&gt; project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IdolsNFT were initially sold via a bonding curve for a price between 0.25 and 0.5 ETH. All ETH collected during the sale are staked via Lido (StETH). Owning an Idol makes you eligible for the corresponding share of the returns. Here, it is the yield generated by the StETH that is tokenized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/idol-nfts.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;idols-nft&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the project goes even further! Indeed, there is also an ERC-20 in the story, the VIRTUE, initially distributed to the first buyers. From now on, to obtain VIRTUE, it is necessary to bond stETH (-&amp;gt; which increases the productive capital of the project).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The VIRTUE corresponds to a proxy exposure on NFT Idols: for each sale of an NFT Idol, a fee of 7.5% is taken and given to the VIRTUE stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/idol-cycle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;idolnfts-virtue-cycle&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the Idols, &amp;ldquo;Guardians of Ethereum&amp;rdquo; use NFTs to make ETH staking more fun and interactive. In addition, the capture of fees on the VIRTUE token allows to avoid an &amp;ldquo;external capture&amp;rdquo; of fees generated by IdolsNFT exchanges as it is the case for NFTs exchanged on NFTX for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the large owners of the collection have a clear path to compound their return if their conviction is strong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possession of several IdolsNFT ⇒ Yield in stETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Composition of farmed stETH via bonding ⇒ VIRTUE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stake of VIRTUE ⇒ Yield in ETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Staking ETH with Lido ⇒ StETH ⇒ Bonding for VIRTUE then stake&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever happens with this collection, I think it has laid the foundation for what NFTs collections augmented by and synergistic with DeFi can be. I expect to see many more relevant variations on this model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggregation-of-various-liquidity-sources&#34;&gt;Aggregation of various liquidity sources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we have already mentioned three different platforms to buy or sell NFTs: OpenSea, LooksRare and NFTX. The reality is even denser, there is an armada of marketplaces for NFTs, more or less successful and more or less specialized, here are some others: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://superrare.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Superrare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://foundation.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nft20.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFT20&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with this myriad of options, buyers do not necessarily have the time, inclination, energy or knowledge to explore all their options before concluding a transaction. The situation is very similar to buying/selling an ERC20 token in DeFi: liquidity is very fragmented. Logically, the solution is therefore similar to the one deployed in DeFi: aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/gem-xyz.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;gem.xyz&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, there are several services capable of directing &amp;ldquo;orders&amp;rdquo; to different marketplaces, or even ŕealising a &amp;ldquo;swipe&amp;rdquo; across multiple platforms with a single transaction: these are &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://genie.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Genie&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gem.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here again, it is the responsiveness of the team and the composability of the service that will make the difference in the long run: Gem seems to be ahead of the game thanks to its advanced integration of LooksRare (claim LOOKS possible for buyers via Gem).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nft--defi--games-with-real-stakes&#34;&gt;NFT + DeFi =&amp;gt; Games with real stakes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If DeFi has discovered the huge market that is NFTs recently, the reverse march is also observed: &lt;strong&gt;the arrival of DeFi components in NFTs projects&lt;/strong&gt; - we often talk about GameFi to describe this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been several years since the first iterations of GameFi appeared, with games that can become a credible source of income for their players: the most famous is of course &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://axieinfinity.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Axie Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, but there are many others: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.aavegotchi.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AaveGotchi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cryptoraiders.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CryptoRaiders&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I&amp;rsquo;m not very active on these projects myself, so I propose to detail one that is more familiar to me: Luchadores. Here again, we find DeFi components that are grafted on the NFT project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning a Luchador (NFT) gives the right to a return in LUCHA (ERC20 token).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol owns about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://debank.com/profile/0x0cb11b92fa5c30eafe4ae84b7bb4df3034c38b9d&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;60% of the liquidity on the two LUCHA pairs&lt;/a&gt;, thanks to the funds raised during the sale of the first pinatas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 🪅 are ERC-1155 tokens that contain 1 accessory for Luchadores, whose rarity is determined by verifiable randomness (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.chain.link/vrf-v2-mainnet-launch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chainlink VRF&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol also has about 30 Luchadores (⇒Yield in LUCHA) purchased with part of the profits from the first pinata: the purchase was made using an aggregator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A marketplace is available for accessories, with payment in LUCHA: a redistribution of the collected fees is also possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/luchadores.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game is not yet available (Alpha by the end of March!), but interactions of this type will only become more dense as it develops. With the arrival of the game, new features will come: staking your LUCHA tokens will allow you to get MASK, a non-transferable token but necessary to buy different items to increase the power of your Luchadores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the launch of the game, players will earn LUCHA for each victory. Depending on their ranking, the amount of LUCHA obtained increases: the best players will be able to get interesting returns, for a very moderate initial cost (1 Luchador, potentially minted for ~0.03 ETH). Be prepared!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you discover Luchadores with this article, feel free to read this introduction: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/luchadores-nft.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🤼 Long live free (and verifiable onchain) wrestling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-next&#34;&gt;What next?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, we have stayed on the visible part of the iceberg. At the crossroads of DeFi and NFTs, there are still many new possible use cases. I propose to make a list with the main services that explore these fields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;floordao--nft-x-defi-x-dao&#34;&gt;FloorDAO : NFT x DeFi x DAO
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://floor.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FloorDAO&lt;/a&gt; is sort of an extra layer built on top of NFTX. FloorDAO uses the OlympusDAO model but adapted for NFTs. The objective is to ensure a return and support liquidity on the collections concerned (Punk and Wizard for the moment). How does it work? Simple: for the concerned collections, the owners of the corresponding NFTX token (ex WIZARD for Forgotten Wizards) as well as the LP (WIZARD/ETH) can bond it to obtain FLOOR tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/nft-defi-infrastructure/floordao-bond.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;floordao-bond&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The collected tokens and LPs are used by FloorDAO to generate a return (NFTX staking). The community (gFLOOR holders) votes to decide which assets to acquire next. Olympus uses the inflation of its governance token to acquire strategic assets such as DAI, LUSD, or CRV; FloorDAO does the same thing but targets NFTX tokens and therefore backs them with an NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here again, the protocol owns a share of its own liquidity on FLOOR/ETH (on Uniswap) and the fees generated by the position contribute to the returns of the FloorDAO treasury.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nfts-to-collateralize-loans-without-going-through-an-erc20vault&#34;&gt;NFTs to collateralize loans (without going through an ERC20/vault)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main limitation to overcome here is of course the fact that the sale of NFT is done in a bid/ask logic and is therefore not immediate. Several projects are nevertheless tackling the problem:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://drops.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DropsDAO&lt;/a&gt; : which imports the logic of lending pools, for NFT collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.arcade.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Arcade.xyz&lt;/a&gt; : OGs remember ETHLend, the ancestor of Aave. Arcade is the same logic but for NFTs : a borrowing service without pool, which works by offer/demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/JPEGd_69&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;JPEGd&#39;69&lt;/a&gt; - which should launch soon and allow CryptoPunks to be used as collateral.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nftfi.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFTfi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pricing-of-nfts--oracle&#34;&gt;Pricing of NFTs / oracle
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For borrowing, a price source is needed to determine if the position is solvent. Here again, several projects are working on this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://abacus.wtf/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abacus&lt;/a&gt; - a decentralized service to price an NFT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pilgrim.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pilgrim&lt;/a&gt; - an AMM / valuation method for NFTs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;renting-of-nfts&#34;&gt;Renting of NFTs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Renting allows for example to borrow an NFT to play a game without having to own it. It also creates opportunities for large NFT owners in a GameFi collection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beta.rentable.world/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rentable&lt;/a&gt;, a generalist protocol for NFT rentals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ship lending + revenue sharing generated with on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cometh.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cometh&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gfinityesports.com/cryptocurrency/axie-infinity-scholarship-what-is-it-how-to-apply-axs/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Axie Infinity scholarship model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you found this peek into the NTFfi landscape insightful, you are now sitting at the crossroads:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/categories/nft/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read my other articles on NFTs here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/categories/defi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;explore the depths of DeFi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Long live to free and on-chain auditable wrestling</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/luchadores-nft/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/luchadores-nft/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/luchadores-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Long live to free and on-chain auditable wrestling" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is going to be more personal than usual, but given the subject I can&amp;rsquo;t do otherwise. We&amp;rsquo;re going to focus on an NFT project in which I&amp;rsquo;m strongly involved: the Luchadores. They are fully onchain wrestlers, soon to be characters in an upcoming game, also onchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the project itself, I will explain the thesis I am developing about it. I think this approach may interest you and help you develop personal beliefs about other collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, I don&amp;rsquo;t detail the mechanics of the Luchadores or the upcoming game. Feel free to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://whitepaper.luchadores.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper now available&lt;/a&gt; for more info on this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-my-thesis-on-the-luchadores&#34;&gt;📑 My thesis on the Luchadores
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are not yet well informed about NFTs and my activities in this area, feel free to read the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/nft/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;introduction page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are four main reasons for my interest in the Luchadores and my enthusiasm for this collection, so let&amp;rsquo;s get right to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-innovative-and-inclusive-generation-process&#34;&gt;🔮 An innovative and inclusive generation process
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The generation of the Luchadores was a fully onchain process thanks to the use of Chainlink&amp;rsquo;s VRF. It allows to &lt;strong&gt;generate random numbers in a verifiable way&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to this feature, the minting of a Luchadores was done with the guarantee that there were no possible manipulations, and the proof of the calculation remains available for verification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was this innovative technical dimension that helped me spot the project initially. Limited to &lt;strong&gt;10,000 Luchadores in total&lt;/strong&gt;, the mint remained available for about &lt;strong&gt;3 months&lt;/strong&gt; (March-&amp;gt;June 2021), with some excitement in the last days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The long minting period allowed everyone who wanted to be involved to do so, with plenty of time to achieve more timely transaction costs if desired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The generation was done at the price of 2 LINK (fee needed for the VRF mechanism), paid in ETH + gas costs. Depending on the LINK price and the transaction costs on the network, miners paid between 0.015 and 0.025 ETH per Luchadores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The verifiable random generation has given rise to some rather amusing &amp;ldquo;trivia&amp;rdquo; facts about the Luchadores:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/luchadores-distribution.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-distribution&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of rarity is a normal curve: there are more than 8000 Luchadores (81.3%) in the group of 3, 2 or 4 attributes, the most common. The closer we get to the extremes, the rarer the Luchadores become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Common (3*, 2*, 4*)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Rare (1*, 5*)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Epic (6*, 0*)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Legendary (7*)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generated numbers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;8130&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1654&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;205&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;81.30%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;16.54%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2.05%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;0.11%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There could have been a Luchador with 8 attributes, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. There would most likely have been only one: no Lucha god.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes the attribute &amp;ldquo;mustache&amp;rdquo; falls on a Luchador whose skin color is very close to the one used for the mustache, creating a &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://luchadores.io/luchador/8085&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;hidden mustache&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. These Luchadores are given special attention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/hidden_mustache_difference.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-hidden_mustache_difference&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-the-onchain-approach&#34;&gt;⛓ The onchain approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the generation done entirely onchain, the visual of the Luchadores is in an optimized format (svg) that allows &lt;strong&gt;storage directly on the Ethereum chain&lt;/strong&gt;, thus bringing a consequent resilience to the media associated to each NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop there since the upcoming game, which we discuss next, will also rely on &lt;strong&gt;verifiable random generation mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;. So in the arena, critical hits or dodges will be the result of verifiable randomness and very hard to manipulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/AFA-score.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-art-for-all&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one to notice this very resilient approach, which also appealed to the Link marines. Luchadores is also the only 100/100 project with Avastars on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://artforall.io/score?search=&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ArtForAll, a service that evaluates the resilience of NFTs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, one could describe the project as &amp;ldquo;on chain maximalist&amp;rdquo; but it is not the case: compromises, unfortunately necessary, are envisaged at the level where it is possible to afford it: the random draws related to the game, will be realized on a sidechain (Polygon) or a rollup. This will allow &lt;strong&gt;to keep the game accessible and inexpensive&lt;/strong&gt;, while taking advantage of maximum guarantees for the NFT, which is always warm on the Ethereum chain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-luchadores--the-game&#34;&gt;🎮 Luchadores : The Game
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game itself probably resonates with my nostalgic side. Indeed, the fight will be &lt;strong&gt;turn by turn&lt;/strong&gt;, with a system of attributes (stats), passive skills and triggered skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/luchadores-stats.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll let you read up on the impact of attributes and skills, but as a fan of turn-based games, strategies and RPGs, I can tell you that I&amp;rsquo;m ready for theorycraft 🧙&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/final-lucha-arena.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-arena&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An associated token&lt;/strong&gt; (LUCHA) will be available to be won. It will also be distributed in the first year to NFT Luchadores owners. The token will have several forms of use related to the game (respect, prodigy system, rename?) and can also be &lt;strong&gt;staked to earn MASK&lt;/strong&gt;, a non-transferable token (only in-game) useful to equip your Luchadores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-the-community-and-its-history&#34;&gt;📜 The community and its history
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The game is developed by a single person, Luchador, who was gradually joined by several profiles needed for the development:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From the beginning, community members emerged like Teh_Griz and LuchaBroy: they became the first moderators of the Discord.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got progressively involved, to help make the project known, to develop the French-speaking community and to bring my help where it is relevant, more info later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A game designer and two pixel artists (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/AbueloRetroWave/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AbueloRetroWave&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artstation.com/m3r0j&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;m3r0j&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are talking here only about &amp;ldquo;formal&amp;rdquo; implications. Of course, we must not forget all the community initiatives. It is impossible to list them all here, but I will mention them anyway:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicosz who created a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/sznicolas/luchadata&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tool in Python to analyze data related to Luchadores&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.xyz/lokhidor/Luchadores&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;dashboard to track key metrics on Luchadores&lt;/a&gt;, offered by cnhkp.eth, using Dune Analytics and thanks to Nicosz&amp;rsquo; help.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or OxMule which has &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://whitepaper.luchadores.io/v/francais/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;translated the whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; in a few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Without forgetting the many collectors and &amp;ldquo;snipers&amp;rdquo; of the Discord who animate it every day, like Chainlinkers, one of the first members of the community who won two giveaways in a row on his birthday and became a legend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-my-involvement&#34;&gt;🐒 My involvement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I discovered the Luchadores in May, I minted about 80 of them and I followed the project quite passively at the beginning. In June, when the craze started to be more palpable, I got more actively involved, first as a moderator for the French community and then as an administrator of the Discord server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see my involvement in the project as an opportunity to educate about the technical dimensions of NFTs. I didn&amp;rsquo;t choose this project at random: I think that the SVG onchain approach used by the Luchadores is among the most credible, despite the graphical compromise (-&amp;gt; pixel style).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concretely, I animate the community with different giveaways and I help to make the Luchadores known.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-my-luchadores&#34;&gt;🃏 My Luchadores
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty unlucky at minting my Luchadores, so I&amp;rsquo;ve made up for my luck with my acquisitions. Although most of them are a mechanical cleaning of the floor price, mostly between 0.025 and 0.035 ETH, I also acquired some rarer Luchadores including three 7 attributes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My best catch is the &amp;ldquo;Batman&amp;rdquo;, a &amp;ldquo;7 attributes&amp;rdquo; that will be one of my main fighters in the arena:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;-lucha-7-attributes-8956&#34;&gt;⭐ Lucha 7 attributes #8956
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/luchadores-nft/luchadores-8956.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;luchadores-8956&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now in possession of 3 Luchadores 7 attributes, &lt;strong&gt;I wish to put one back into play&lt;/strong&gt;. This one will not go to the highest bidder&amp;hellip; no way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://luchadores.io/luchador/8956&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Luchador #8956&lt;/a&gt; will be won in the arena&lt;/strong&gt;, so it will go to the most skilled player. Looking forward to sharing more details about the allocation mechanism when the game is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;-giveaways&#34;&gt;🎁 Giveaways
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;So I have minted about 80 Luchadores, and bought over 150 on OpenSea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to use a good part of it as a &amp;ldquo;promotional budget&amp;rdquo; for the Luchadores - and it is already done. Several distributions have taken place and a good 50 have already been given away, including 25 to the top wheat farmer DeFi France.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the rest, as I&amp;rsquo;m a fan of the skin-in-the-game concept (direct involvement with consequences), and given my involvement in the project I couldn&amp;rsquo;t see it any other way. I don&amp;rsquo;t have any Luchadores in my possession on other wallets, I centralize everything on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://opensea.io/tokenbrice?search[sortBy]=LISTING_DATE&amp;amp;search[query]=luchadores&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my ENS by transparency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-the-value-of-a-wrestler&#34;&gt;📈 The value of a wrestler
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;⚠ This article does not constitute investment advice. Choosing when and which jpeg/svg to acquire is a personal choice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luchadores first traded near the cost of minting, before establishing a second floor around 0.03 ETH. Since the end of September, with the arrival of the whitepaper, the craze is palpable and is reflected on the floor (price) now around 0.07 ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a wrestler&amp;hellip; great, but at what price? Don&amp;rsquo;t expect a direct answer from me on that. At this point in time and at this stage of development, it is still a gamble. Nevertheless, the approach is relevant and I think that Luchadores has the potential to enter the NFTs canon, pushing the frontier of interactivity made possible with these digital objects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acquiring a Luchadores today means paying about three times minimum the price seen a few weeks ago - and yet it would be a good deal if the current trend continues 🔮 welcome to the world of NFTs, where pricing is a social and highly reflective mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now place your bets, &amp;ldquo;rien ne va plus&amp;rdquo; 🎲.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m only talking about it now on the blog because I wanted to take the time to articulate my thoughts. Those who follow me live or on Twitter heard about the project in May and could read about it directly, if they wanted to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this article has helped you understand what it is about a collection of wrestlers that fascinates me, and more generally how I analyze a collection, and that it will also help you evaluate others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Non-fungible tokens (NFTs): the weight and contribution of ascertainable history </title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/nft-usecases/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/nft-usecases/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/88DeLo.png" alt="Featured image of post Non-fungible tokens (NFTs): the weight and contribution of ascertainable history " /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-fungible tokens are attracting a lot of attention lately. On the one hand, the general public is scratching its head about the ever-rising records observed on flagship sales, now covered in the mainstream press&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. On the other hand, artists still not initiated to blockchains realize the potential offered by &lt;strong&gt;disintermediation&lt;/strong&gt; as well as the possibilities offered by &lt;strong&gt;the programmable nature of this new art form&lt;/strong&gt;. In between, a diverse audience ranging from the casual collector to the seasoned speculator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing is certain: NFTs leave no one indifferent. Indeed, by &lt;strong&gt;combining the logic of provable digital scarcity with art&lt;/strong&gt;, NFTs allow to explore new forms of expression. Moreover, the programmable dimension of NFTs opens the way to a barely begun exploration of new forms of interactivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I would like to leave theory aside as much as possible and focus on &lt;strong&gt;the practical uses observed with these NFTs.&lt;/strong&gt; We will therefore analyze two fundamental characteristics of NFTs - &lt;strong&gt;their community dimension&lt;/strong&gt; and their &lt;strong&gt;ability to become social markers&lt;/strong&gt;. Once these two dimensions are established, we can consider different use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;![88DeLorean]( &amp;ldquo;The DeLorean 88MPH, an NFT at the center of a small experiment that you will read about below&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-fungible tokens are like a new type of lego used to represent families of assets that share common attributes. They are extremely relevant for community-based uses or in video games but &lt;strong&gt;NFTs offer much more&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example in DeFi, an inter-asset exchange on Curve involves a &amp;ldquo;receipt&amp;rdquo; NFT and more recently Uniswap is considering NFT tokens to represent liquidity provider positions (and their many parameters) for V3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these different uses of &amp;ldquo;NFT technology&amp;rdquo; are relevant. However, we are going to focus on the artistic and community uses of NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-community-dimension-of-nfts&#34;&gt;The community dimension of NFTs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand collectibles and NFTs, I think it is essential to understand their community and social dimension. From a community point of view, the simple possession of an NFT can be enough to show a belonging to a given group, like the CryptoPunks for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that at a primordial level NFTs are a direct response to a very human tendency: &lt;strong&gt;we are all collectors&lt;/strong&gt;, in one way or another. Items usually collected require &lt;strong&gt;trust in the issuer to be certain of rarity&lt;/strong&gt; (e.g. Pokemon card). NFTs allow assets with provable numerical rarity, which completely changes the parameters of the equation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henceforth, &lt;strong&gt;each work of art can become famous and its entire history is accessible to all and tamper-proof&lt;/strong&gt;. Where in classical art, only the history of the most famous pieces is told (by secondary sources), with NFTs each piece get the same treatment: its creation as well as each purchase or transfer are recorded on a public blockchain. They can be consulted (and verified) by everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-weight-of-ascertainable-history&#34;&gt;The weight of ascertainable history
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story behind a work of art has always been an integral part of it. But with its incorporation directly into the object, without intermediation and therefore without the need to have a third person to tell it, we go to a much more interesting level. My views are still young on the subject, but I am convinced that &lt;strong&gt;with this new tamper-proof interface to access the history of the object, comes a revaluation of it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m testing this hypothesis with a artwork of which I write part of the history, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:111850&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the famous DeLorean 88MPH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. By acquiring a quarter of the circulating total, that is progressively distributed to DeFi France / TokenBrice contributors, I simultaneously articulate these two overarching theses about NFTs: this iconic car becomes both a community tool and a social marker. It shows the belonging to a group, while allowing to prove one&amp;rsquo;s involvement in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is too early to draw conclusions from this experiment but nevertheless the first results are encouraging: out of the 22 DeLos, 8 have been distributed. The best buyback offer is currently at 0.15 ETH, which is about 3x the initial purchase price (88 DAI) but none of the 8 people who received this NFT gave in. The Delo is still being traded though: one of them was just sold for 0.5 ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/delo-sale.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;rarible-88-DeLorean&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For them, some of them at least, this NFT also has &lt;strong&gt;a very personal story&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, it was the first digital object of its kind owned by several of the winners and the context of its acquisition quickly makes it a symbol: it was earned trough their hard work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I do not give resale instructions for NFT donations. I encourage the winners to keep the NFT if they like it, but &lt;strong&gt;also point out sale opportunities that exist at the time of donation if they wish.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nfts-as-a-social-marker--crytopunks-analyses-&#34;&gt;NFTs as a social marker : CrytoPunks analyses !
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to the NFTs&amp;rsquo;s social aspect, together with their ability to incorporate and verify their own storyline, another feature emerged : they can be used as a social distinction. Using CryptoPunks to make this point is quite suitable in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/punk-variety-2x.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cryptopunk-list&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were among the first NFTs collection projects. The originality lies in their unique charateristics : No two Punks are alike as they have been generated algorithmically with some traits rarer than others. In this way some Punks have become almost legendary as well as their prices !&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time goes by, CryptoPunks have established themselves as the symbol of something way greater than just NFTs. It is now the most traded NFTs collection on the market with a floor price that lies around 17 ETH :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/punk-stats.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cryptopunk-stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-recognize-the-scarcity-&#34;&gt;How to recognize the scarcity ?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing and being able to recognize the Punks attributes is a high-valuated skill to be part of the community. There is a total of 10,000 Punks. Indeed, each Punks have their own profile page showing their type (human, Zombie, Ape or Alien) and their different traits, from absolutely none to a maximum of 7 for the most unique of them : only one Punk gathers as much !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This does not mean that more is best : the demand for Punks without any attribute is really strong due to the very low supply : only 8 in total !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, there are only 333 Punks (/10 000) with 1 trait, which also makes them quite rare and wanted. Similarly, Punks with 5 (166 units) or 6 attributes (11 units) are also uncommon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest part of the collection is made up with &amp;ldquo;common&amp;rdquo; Punks, with 2 ( 3560 units ), 3 ( 4501 units ) or 4 attributes ( 1420 units ) : these Punks represent almost 95% of the total supply.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/punk-attributes-count.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cryptopunk-stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punks are now at the center of a whole ecosystem : from technical integrations (with the ERC-721 wrapper for example or into NFTs indexes&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) to the artistic field such as the PicassoPunk :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as exhibiting well-chosen modern art in a living room gives a special aura, &lt;strong&gt;displaying your Punk becomes a symbol that goes far beyond the token itself.&lt;/strong&gt; It may now be in good taste to use a Punk from your collection as a profile picture on Twitter. Of course, the more unique and rare it is, the more intrigued the savvy audience will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The analysis of CryptoPunks allows us to understand many fundamental things to assimilate the use of NFTs. Nevertheless, the use cases for NFTs are much more diversified. So I suggest you explore a few more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-main-use-cases-of-nfts&#34;&gt;The main use cases of NFTs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;creation-and-sales-services&#34;&gt;Creation and sales services
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to acquire your first NFTs is still to buy them. This is &lt;strong&gt;far from being the only method,&lt;/strong&gt; as we will see below, but before that, let&amp;rsquo;s have a quick look at &lt;strong&gt;the main platforms and their modalities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most commonly used site is probably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://opensea.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenSea&lt;/a&gt;, which allows direct sales or auctions. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt; is another easily accessible and potentially more optimized option for creators to emerge. It is sometimes described as &lt;strong&gt;the &amp;ldquo;Etsy&amp;rdquo; of NFTs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other services exist, with more curatorial approaches, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://foundation.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Foundation&lt;/a&gt; which is &lt;strong&gt;selective about its artists and where each work is a unique copy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each service comes with different modalities and sometimes different NFT types as well: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/nft.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ERC-721 or 1155 explained here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. The rules that govern their auctions and revenue sharing also affect the overall direction of the platform. To start collecting with taste, it&amp;rsquo;s good to know at least what you&amp;rsquo;re buying!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nfts--video-games-in-all-forms&#34;&gt;NFTs + Video games, in all forms
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most obvious use cases for NFTs is of course video games. Almost everyone understands this immediately once the issue of provable digital scarcity is well understood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-new-level-of-persistence&#34;&gt;A new level of persistence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without NFT, a player can find himself fighting for days in an online game to get an item&amp;hellip; that is not actualy his. It is sometimes so repetitive that the term &amp;ldquo;farming&amp;rdquo; is also used by players to describe their practice (a slightly different meaning from the DeFians&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;farming&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/nft-usecases/meuporg.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;meuporg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game services may stop for example (if it is an online game) and often the player cannot exchange his item freely. Incorporating NFTs in video games allows &lt;strong&gt;the existence of a persistence that is not dependent of the game editor&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Persistence, as every gamer and every DeFian understands, is in a way the soul of an online game. However, this is only the most fundamental level of the potential contribution of NFTs to video games. They also allow a whole set of additional logic thanks to their &lt;strong&gt;programmable dimension,&lt;/strong&gt; among others:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stories that are truly co-written by players and can be remembered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items that can exist in multiple games, even potentially with a story that feeds from the different universes where the item is involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Famous players who leave a real mark in the game, far beyond a boss or place named after them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some NFT standards, such as 1155, go further and allow the existence of attributes that evolve on different tokens. They allow to consider a new form of persistence where &lt;strong&gt;the player&amp;rsquo;s actions would potentially translate into concrete actions (on-chain) taken for the organization (the DAO) master of the game(s) involved.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-contribution-of-a-marketplace-in-digital-worlds&#34;&gt;The contribution of a marketplace in digital worlds
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proven digital scarcity has been a key issue since the beginning of the first persistent online worlds. All games that have a large audience also have a developed and successful &amp;ldquo;black market&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;strong&gt;each digital world its bazaar paid in real money&lt;/strong&gt;: for example in World of Warcraft, a simple google search allows you to buy gold or various other services to accelerate the progression of your character thanks to a secondary market of service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Having an object, potentially created by the game publisher but not dependent on it for its concrete existence, is absolutely new&lt;/strong&gt;. This does not mean, of course, that every object in every game will have a second and third existence, but it is now a possibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine if you could deploy your own Charizard - the one that&amp;rsquo;s been sleeping in your GameBoy for over 15 years - in a Pokemon arena in virtual reality. It would become a digital object, represented by an NFT and incorporating all your history with it, making it also, in effect, unique. Each battle or tournament could leave traces on the NFT-object, such as a temporary weakening or learning new abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a primitive vision of the &amp;ldquo;endgame&amp;rdquo; that I foresee, at the crossroads of video games, NFTs and virtual reality. &lt;strong&gt;There is already a concept to describe this new reality that is taking shape : the Metaverse&lt;/strong&gt;. These are persistent virtual worlds composed among others of NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;farming-nfts--nft--defi&#34;&gt;Farming NFTs ? NFT + DeFi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If NFTs are coming to games, the reverse is also true: games and NFTs are also coming into DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all started very simply, with an approach that every DeFian knows well: &lt;strong&gt;This is the concept of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dontbuymeme.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Meme&lt;/a&gt;, where the user stakes MEME tokens to obtain points (pineapples) used to obtain the desired NFTs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no other fees than gas costs of the various operations and potentially a minting fee paid in ETH for some coins. Even so, many coins are highly desirable and wanted on the secondary market.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meme is now several months old and has become a service that has managed to surpass its own token. Collaborations with different artists are frequent to propose new collections, but &lt;strong&gt;also directly with projects&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Meme was used to support a game with BadgerDAO. By depositing bBADGER or UNIv2 BADGER/wBTC tokens, users could farm 6 different NFTs related to the project universe. The first player to assemble all 6 different NFTs was able to open a smart contract and receive a nice amount of BADGER tokens as a bonus. &lt;strong&gt;In addition, the possession of these NFTs served as a bonus factor on the distribution (airdrop) of the DIGG token.&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://badgerdao.medium.com/badger-x-meme-nft-honeypot-part-ii-diamond-hands-7111d38b5df4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;second part of the Badger NFT game&lt;/a&gt; has just begun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other services use Meme with a similar approach : the YOP platform proposes to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dontbuymeme.com/collections/yop&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;farm &amp;ldquo;tickets&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; of different rarities. They will potentially allow &lt;strong&gt;access before the general public, once the service is available.&lt;/strong&gt; Here we find the community dimension of NFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;88MPH is doing something similar &lt;strong&gt;by offering NFTs to the biggest users of its new products a few weeks after their launch&lt;/strong&gt;. Holding such an NFT would also be an excellent criterion to target the most relevant users to test the new versions and participate more actively in the development of the project (purely an illustration on my part, there has been no official announcement in this sense to my knowledge).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;to-infinity-and-beyond-&#34;&gt;To infinity, and beyond !
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article we have mainly developed few analyses that demonstrate possibilities offered by NFTs. Finally, I will give you a brief overview of what&amp;rsquo;s left to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In France, I had the opportunity to talk with an artist who explores a universe that could be described as &amp;ldquo;role playing with NFTs&amp;rdquo;.  Arke, for example, offers &lt;strong&gt;an innovative collection that is animated with Legends of Cryptonia.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside for the usual characters, some have been poisoned, others have specific status and the story of Cryptonia is still being written every day.  The first &amp;ldquo;creature&amp;rdquo; is now available for sale and unlocks access to multiple poisoned characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The possibilities offered by NFTs, thanks to their programmable structure, are actually infinite. Before concluding, let&amp;rsquo;s consider few other use cases not yet covered in this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NFTs are also used as commemorative badges to remember and show presence at a particular event. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.poap.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;POAP project&lt;/a&gt; allows for example to create &amp;ldquo;proofs of attendance&amp;rdquo; for an event with ease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community membership could also be directly represented by a scalable NFT&lt;/strong&gt;. This would allow, among other things, to record the common history by saving each of the on-chain actions of all its members. This use case is obviously unrealistic today with the gas costs of the mainnet, but possible on L2 or sidechain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget also that I have focused this article on the community and artistic uses of NFTs. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t mention what NFTs can allow in terms of intellectual property or even physical goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, NFTs have the potential to become &lt;strong&gt;a new type of &amp;ldquo;universal dictionary &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt; allowing to represent and define any object but especially family or category of objects &lt;strong&gt;in a reliable and on-chain way&lt;/strong&gt;. This allows the &amp;ldquo;tokenization&amp;rdquo; of what was not tokenizable in the past (non-fungible goods). With tokenization comes a whole set of options - as seasoned DeFians know well and others will soon discover.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, &lt;strong&gt;the use cases of NFTs are still very primitive&lt;/strong&gt;, due to their main limitation: &lt;strong&gt;very expensive gas costs to create, manipulate and interact with&lt;/strong&gt;. I think that the essential dimension of NFTs in the organization of tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s digital world will become even more obvious with the democratization of NFTs that the development of various sidechains and Layer 2 will allow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;censorship-of-media-associated-with-nfts&#34;&gt;Censorship of media associated with NFTs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this article, I did not address a key point about NFTs: &lt;strong&gt;the persistence of their associated media&lt;/strong&gt;. To be truly persistent and censorship resistant, the NFT must incorporate a direct reference to the associated media file, which is itself hosted using a resilient medium like IPFS. For more details on the issue, I refer you to this clear and detailed discussion on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discovering-nfts&#34;&gt;Discovering NFTs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you enjoyed this introduction and learned something new. NFTs have been a topic of interest for me for a long time that I renewed recently. Besides my research on DeFi, I also intend to share my experience with NFTs on this blog. My last article on the subject was written more than three years ago, so it&amp;rsquo;s about time I took up the pen again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;notes-and-references&#34;&gt;Notes and references
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The footnotes help you to deepen different topics mentioned in the article:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artiste Beeple sold his artwork &amp;ldquo;Everydays : The First 5 000&amp;rdquo; for approximately $69M. Mainstream medias like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/11/22325054/beeple-christies-nft-sale-cost-everydays-69-million&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TheVerge&lt;/a&gt;, le &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/11/arts/design/nft-auction-christies-beeple.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-03-11/beeple-everydays-nft-sells-at-art-auction-for-60-million-paid-in-ether&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bloomberg&lt;/a&gt; covered the event.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.artnome.com/news/2019/4/08/autoglyphs-generative-art-born-on-the-blockchain&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; will help you learn more about CryptoPunks and the approach of the team behind (LarvaLabs).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the CryptoPunks types and all their attributes &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.larvalabs.com/cryptopunks/attributes&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.nftx.org/cryptopunks-single-index-funds-now-also-on-sushiswap/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFTX&lt;/a&gt; is one of pioneers in this field.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like in classic DeFi, several tools exist to follow your farming and the situation on the pools. The farm overview is very useful on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://niftyrank.com/meme-farms&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NiftyRank&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>DeFi is a toolbox reaching beyond finance</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/defi-is-a-toolbox-reaching-beyond-finance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/defi-is-a-toolbox-reaching-beyond-finance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post DeFi is a toolbox reaching beyond finance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance is ready to grow beyond its sandbox: with a dense network of financial primitives, it&amp;rsquo;s now easier than ever to harness DeFi for other ends, such as to replace a predatory relic of our past like the lottery, still insanely popular and detrimental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this story, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a step back and adopt a macro perspective on Ethereum. So far, my interest mostly revolved around decentralized finance, as it drove the innovation over the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I believe we&amp;rsquo;re reaching the next step of the growth of the incredible human coordination experiment that is the Ethereum network: the lego blocks provided by DeFi are now mature enough to be harnessed for other ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing how these &lt;strong&gt;streamlined value capture and exchange devices&lt;/strong&gt; can be harnessed to facilitate the creation of engaged communities or sustain the commons. So this time, instead of what or how, let&amp;rsquo;s ask why? After a quick reminder on the key benefits delivered by DeFi legos, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few projects harnessing them to flip the table in their respective domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defis-legos-the-core-building-blocks&#34;&gt;DeFi&amp;rsquo;s Legos: The core building blocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The myriad of decentralized financial services available on Ethereum demonstrated the benefits of what I like to call &amp;ldquo;pragmatic values&amp;rdquo;: transparency, accessibility, accountability, and interoperability. Why pragmatic? Because withholding them is not a matter of goodwill of the system&amp;rsquo;s participants, they are &lt;strong&gt;enforced by default and continuously as long as the network is operating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask your bank how your money is invested, you get an answer you can trust or not. Verifying it involves inquiries from your end. On the other hand, you don&amp;rsquo;t ask Yearn where your money is: you see what it&amp;rsquo;s doing at all times, and this information is reliable and unfalsifiable. It&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental change in the relationship - the user of a DeFi service is not a mere &amp;ldquo;customer&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;☝ This is what the term &amp;ldquo;trustless&amp;rdquo; usually refers to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to unpack these core pragmatic values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;: By default, transactions on the Ethereum network are public. For DeFi, this translates into very concrete benefits - for instance, volumes &lt;strong&gt;observed (on the chain)&lt;/strong&gt; on decentralized exchanges tend to be much more realistic than volumes &lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt; by centralized exchanges (tracked in their internal database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;: To use a DeFi service, such as an exchange or an asset management system, all you need is an Ethereum wallet and a device with an internet connection. On unstoppable services like the DEX Uniswap, there is no way to blacklist an address from using it. This has obvious benefits for populations usually discriminated against by financial services operators, such as gamblers, sex workers, or foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/strong&gt; DeFi services are like lego blocks, they are open source so that they can be improved and built on top of. It enables rapid innovations as new projects can quickly deliver value by assembling several existing services in new ways. Everyone can check their code and easily contribute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalism&lt;/strong&gt;: Ethereum is a network designed for resiliency and it comes with interesting consequences. With a highly redundant infrastructure where bandwidth and storage capacity are limited, successful projects tend to be those able to reduce or avoid unnecessary complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/defi-legos.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DeFi-legos&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeFi ecosystem delivered a range of services thanks to which anyone can buy, sell, secure, exchange tokens in a decentralized fashion. They also &lt;strong&gt;normalized behaviors that were uncommon before&lt;/strong&gt;, such as staking tokens, borrowing, using leverage, minting synthetic assets, and many other options made possible once assets are tokenized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as I was saying in the introduction, so far these new legos have been used mostly in a reflexive manner. Now, they are increasingly used to deliver innovative services offering even more possibilities. It&amp;rsquo;s essential as each new DeFi layer enables many more use cases outside of finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fixing-a-detrimental-societal-institution-using-defis-legos&#34;&gt;Fixing a detrimental societal institution using DeFi&amp;rsquo;s legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the obvious and trickle down from here: fixing the lottery. As you probably already know, lotteries are poverty traps sometimes described as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://erlc.com/resource-library/articles/state-lotteries-are-an-exploitative-tax-on-the-poor/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exploitative tax on the poor&lt;/a&gt;. Their public is predominantly poor, and overall the lottery is not helping with their budget. Even with a lucky outcome, other issues arise sometimes leading right back to the starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with the lottery has many roots, including the fact that they are usually owned or operated by national governments. The good news is that DeFi can deliver the core element of the lottery - the prize - in a much more sustainable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, to deliver a jackpot, you need some form of prize. Current lottery models pool together contributions from everyone to return it to one player, minus the cost of the operations and a fee: money is &amp;ldquo;burned&amp;rdquo; within the base loop because of the infrastructure required to run the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi can do much better on both fronts. First, for the prize: instead of a net-loss system, PoolTogether provides a &lt;strong&gt;no-loss lottery&lt;/strong&gt; to its players. The gist is simple: they are not buying a ticket but instead depositing stablecoins into a pool. Assets from all players are used to produce a return using the decentralized lending markets. The &lt;strong&gt;winner earns the interest generated by the whole capital over the period, and everyone gets back their initial investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also comes with many improvements over legacy lotteries infrastructure: using Ethereum tokens to represent lottery tickets comes with additional benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; - drawing the winner and paying the prize is much faster, public, and verifiable by anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceability&lt;/strong&gt; - every operation is public and auditable, making it easier to prevent frauds and abuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt; - all you need is a wallet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lottery example is essential to better understand &amp;ldquo;DeFi+&amp;rdquo; use cases. DeFi by itself is amazing. But &lt;strong&gt;using DeFi to replace predatory societal infrastructure? Sounds like even closer to its reason to be!&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll explore this theme further by looking at the funding of public goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enabling-sustainable-commons-gitcoin&#34;&gt;Enabling sustainable commons: Gitcoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For decentralized DeFi projects, the community is key as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;we’ve seen with Yearn Finance&lt;/a&gt;. On top of their role of driving the project development and growth, communities also frequently deliver key resources, such as dashboards, calculators &amp;amp; diverse tools to facilitate the tracking and management of positions, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zerion.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zerion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the macro level, the main tools used to track the overall growth of the industry also stem from the community, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defillama.com/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFillama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarming.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YieldFarmingInfo&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarmingtools.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YieldFarmingTools&lt;/a&gt;. The development of such services is usually fueled thanks to community donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To facilitate the discovery and funding of such projects, there is a platform harnessing the possibilities offered by Ethereum to improve public good funding: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://gitcoin.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gitcoin&lt;/a&gt;. Gitcoin streamlines the creation of “Grants” to collect donations for given projects and communities. It makes the most of Ethereum core attributes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/gitcoin-grants.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gitcoin-grants-round7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All donations are public and transparent&lt;/strong&gt;, making it easy to measure and track contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects can be funded with common Ethereum-based tokens, usually stablecoins such as DAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the community is the main driver of contributions, Gitcoin uses a system called quadratic funding to balance contributions. Each round, &lt;strong&gt;it matches contributors&amp;rsquo; donations&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to an additional budget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The budget is provided by donors from the ecosystem. While it used to be mostly large Ethereum-based companies, a new type of sponsor is emerging: treasury funds of DeFi projects. Indeed, some key DeFi players like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/yip-direct-of-rewards-towards-ethereum-public-goods-funding/3699/22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance voted to allocate a portion (1%)&lt;/a&gt; of their protocol income to fund Gitcoin grants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is still room for improvement - and Gitcoin keeps getting better with every new matching round - it’s already a critical part of the infrastructure used to fund the commons on Ethereum. It really streamlines the process of collecting donations for community-driven projects. We use it for the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR newsletter&lt;/a&gt; along with other sources, and it’s part of what is enabling us to deliver a high-quality yet free newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest Gitcoin grants round just started. You can give to support your favorite projects with an additional matching until December 17. Allow me to suggest a selection of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/collections?featured=true&amp;amp;collection_id=24&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;people documenting DeFi in non-English languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - just like I try to do with French.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to support French DeFi particularly, feel free to check the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr-the-daily-gwei-fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR &amp;amp; DailyGweiFR grants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a pair of newsletter offering two different takes to learn about DeFi, in French.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-ethereum-help-art-markets-be-more-transparent-and-fair&#34;&gt;Can Ethereum help art markets be more transparent and fair?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another subset of the Ethereum ecosystem has been delivering incredible value for community building lately: non-fungible tokens (NFT). While the term is a mouthful, the base idea is actually quite simple: NFTs deliver another level of digital scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find a detailed explainer on NFT two years ago, still relevant and accessible for newcomers: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/nft.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paired with DeFi, NFTs are now enabling new forms of community interactions and fundings. Using &lt;strong&gt;self-serve platforms&lt;/strong&gt;, artists and communities can autonomously create and sell NFTs with services streamlining the process like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to their programmable nature, NFTs enable &lt;strong&gt;new re-distribution models&lt;/strong&gt; such as a contribution on secondary market purchases. Finally, since they live on the Ethereum blockchain, NFTs also provide a transparent history of ownership and previous prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet again, thanks to Jon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;@OtherBright&lt;/a&gt;), BanklessFR has been exploring this new frontier too. Thanks to a collaboration with the artist Arke, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:43413:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;we’ve released a NFT&lt;/a&gt; tied to the newsletter&amp;rsquo;s content. I&amp;rsquo;ve asked Jon to share some pointers on the experiment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://banklessfr.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygweifr.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Daily Gwei FR&lt;/a&gt; we are trying different experiments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/banklessfr-nft.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;BanklessFR-NFT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Arke56374430&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Arke&lt;/a&gt;, we started with the sale of a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:43413:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR NFT&lt;/a&gt;, representing the newsletter BanklessFR. This collectible card, available in 40 copies, was successfully sold at 0.15 ETH each. We shared the profits with the artist. We included an article that can be unlocked at the time of purchase, 24 hours ahead of readers who do not have the card. This distribution model is clearly innovative, but in my opinion requires to be developed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:64356:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;second sale&lt;/a&gt;, different from the first, still for BanklessFR, illustrated an article, and offered 10 copies of the card, at 0.3 ETH per unit. It also contained an article that could be unlocked 24 hours in advance. The latter worked much less, certainly because of a relatively high price, despite a rarity 4 times greater.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/the-daily-gwei-fr.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TheDailyGwei-FR-NFT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:81692:0x83ac01254b0b8e9745492c5e73f5f32a05570a76?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;last sale&lt;/a&gt; concerns the launch of The Daily Gwei FR. We published 50 copies of a card representing the newsletter. We haven&amp;rsquo;t sold one yet, 0.05 ETH per card, 50 cards available. We will modify this sale to continue the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have other ideas in mind, here the experiments are relatively simple, but much more complex systems should be implemented. I think we should insist on funding from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;gitcoin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://clr.fund/#/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;clr.fund&lt;/a&gt;, before accelerating on the NFTs side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these services provide innovative tools to build and grow communities. Thanks to the disintermediation, NFTs put artists back at the center of the stage. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing more and more instances of collaboration between an artist and a community, like we did for BanklessFR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;rsquo;re entering an age of renewed excitement, especially for people outside the space, make sure to direct newcomers to reliable resources: how about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/-guide-1-starting-with-bankless&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless&amp;rsquo;s getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-markets-blackhole&#34;&gt;The markets blackhole
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, the trajectory of the last couple of years of development makes even more sense. The financial functions were the necessary first steps, as they now operate as primitive enabling more intricate interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At their very base, &lt;strong&gt;markets simply are distribution/allocation mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;. So far, in the world of old finance, we&amp;rsquo;ve let technocrats design them, to the benefits of the most connected and rich participants. With DeFi, we&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with our own ways of creating markets. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen migrations of billions over a few days to chase a given incentive such as Uniswap UNI mining or the one-week YFI mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly put, our finance is already strongly superior to any meatspace counterpart. We can create immense and healthy markets in days. Have derivatives and other options for the next one. Leverage soon after. &amp;amp; all/most of this delivered in an unstoppable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a trader, this might sound like tooling overkill. It&amp;rsquo;s really not. Picture finance like a base layer underlying all the others. Whatever your goal is, your system will probably have to manage some finite resources, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that our markets - our base layers - are more efficient than any other so we can reasonably expect a compounding impact of this increased efficiency as we move down the stack. Simply put, finance is the first battlefield we&amp;rsquo;ve won: the decentralized approach succeeded and delivered a superior infrastructure without equivalent. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the next!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/non-fungible-tokens-explained-with-blastoise-and-charizard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/non-fungible-tokens-explained-with-blastoise-and-charizard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Non-fungibles” — don’t let yourself be fooled by the mushroom-evoking name, fungibility is an old concept that is finding a second wind nowadays. It’s mostly about collectibles and video games for now, but it will soon outgrow these industries. Indeed, the potential of non-fungibles tokens is much more significant than this: from official documents to titles of ownership, their use cases are diverse and numerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by establishing the basics about non-fungible tokens (NFTs from now on) thanks to Pokémon cards before we dive into their potential use cases and the future developments of the underlying technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tokens-smart-contracts&#34;&gt;Tokens? Smart Contracts?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we explore NFTs and talk about Pokémons, let’s restate two definitions necessary to understand the rest of the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;: A smart contract is a computer protocol intended to digitally facilitate, verify, or enforce the negotiation or performance of a contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token&lt;/strong&gt;: a token represents a particular tradable asset or a utility that is often found on a blockchain. Each token has specific properties that are defined to match its usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-does-fungibility-evenmean&#34;&gt;SO, what does fungibility even mean?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A fungible good is a good defined by its belonging to a type: different units of fungible goods are interchangeable. “Fungibility,” as a concept, is used in several different academic disciplines; we’re addressing the economic definition only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump to the examples which make the concept much easier to understand. Our modern currencies, such as the dollar, are fungible: one $5 bill can be exchanged with another. Gold is also a fungible good: 1 ounce of (pure) gold is worth another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A fungible good is standardized: each unit of this good has no uniqueness, which is why we can exchange them with one another.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-about-non-fungible-goods-then-can-we-still-eatthem&#34;&gt;What about non-fungible goods then? Can we still eat them?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some goods are non-fungibles. They are goods which &lt;strong&gt;share common attributes but have their uniqueness&lt;/strong&gt;: each good has a unique set of values for each trait which is shared with the whole type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example of non-fungible goods are… Pokemon cards of course! While we’re at it, let’s pick the one that used to be enough to crown you king of the playground: Charizard himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/charizard.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Pokémon card is made of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A name (and a level): Charizard, level 76,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Points (HP): 150,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A type: fire,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ability: Energy Burn,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An attack and its cost: Fire Spin (4 fire energies),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness and Resistance: water and fighting,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A retreat cost: 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Pokémon card is unique, but all follow this typology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider Blastoise for instance: he too has the 7 attributes we have already described, but he has different values for each which make him different from Charizard and unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/blastoise.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the combination of the value for all the attributes that make the cards’ uniqueness. Hence, a card describing a fire type Pokémon with 150HP is not a Charizard — it is merely a card with 2 attributes equal to those of Charizard, out of 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pokémon cards are useful because they make most of the concept of non-fungibility easy to grasp. &lt;strong&gt;NFTs are a category of tokens that share common attributes&lt;/strong&gt;. But each token has a set of unique values for these attributes which make the token itself unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were too young for Pokémon cards, or too old, it’s precisely the same principle for other card games: Magic, Yu-Gi-Oh !, World of Warcraft (the card game) and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fungibility-applied-to-cryptocurrencies&#34;&gt;Fungibility applied to cryptocurrencies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the cryptocurrencies you already know such as Bitcoin or Ethereum can be considered fungible (see below ⬇️). One BTC is worth another and two BTC can be exchanged with one another. It’s the same for all cryptocurrencies you could find on Coinmarketcap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since the history of transactions of most cryptocurrencies can be checked on block explorers, some tokens involved in illicit activity are flagged and blocked on exchanges. Therefore, cryptocurrencies with public transaction histories are not truly fungible. Full fungibility is currently achieved by privacy-focused coins such as Monero, because the transaction history is not publicly disclosed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won’t address these today, as we focus on non-fungible tokens. There were several attempts, as early as 2013 to create NFTs, but they were mostly unsuccessful. What made a difference was a new Ethereum standard, the ERC-721 which greatly facilitated the creation of “cryptocollectibles.” They are unique goods which share common attributes — the blockchain equivalent of Pokémon cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-humble-beginnings-powered-by-theerc-721&#34;&gt;The humble beginnings powered by the ERC-721
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cryptokitties.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cryptokitties&lt;/a&gt; is what made NFTs known to the general audience — they are virtual kittens which were the precursors of the ERC-721.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/cryptokitties.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project went live in October and took a couple month to reach its peak of virality last December. Cryptokitties were such as success than the whole Ethereum network was clogged for several days by the flood of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/ck-price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific kittens, the most desirable of the bunch, reached prices in the 5 digits ($) and changed hands several times in a few days early December. Considering the success of the CryptoKitties, the ERC-721 went through the due diligence to get approved and finalized last June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-fungible-tokens-in-the-everydaylife&#34;&gt;Non-fungible tokens in the everyday life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to pushing and improving new technologies, you’ll often find porn and video games sharing the front line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, collectible and video games are at the forefront of the innovation. Indeed, when it comes to pushing and improving new technologies, you’ll often find porn and video games sharing the front line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the real-world applications of NFTs are very diverse, numerous, and much closer than we think. Thanks to their characteristics, NFTs can be an excellent support for the tokenization of real-life goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokenize means creating a token representing a good. The token by itself has no value; it draws its value from the good it represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenize-everything&#34;&gt;Tokenize everything!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tokenization allows to handle goods like tokens which open a wide range of possibilities: exchange, P2P transferring, fractional ownership (0.x), etc. Besides, other features can be added depending on the tokenized goods: list of the previous owners, history of the value of the good, exhaustive list of the goods’ characteristics, limitations of ownership…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the benefits of tokenization are understood, we realize that tokenizing real goods will let us &lt;strong&gt;spare ourselves the need for greedy intermediaries while getting many exciting new features&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of real estate =&amp;gt; who need notaries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of pieces of art =&amp;gt; auctioneers and several other jobs would see their utility and even their existence challenged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of official documents (IDs for instance) =&amp;gt; a substantial cleanup in the actors and institutions currently involved in their emission, as well as those in charge of detecting and preventing frauds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the three scenarios detailed above, checking the authenticity of these goods as well as making sure their owner is indeed the real owner of the good would be much easier than now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-disintermediation-thanks-to-tokenization&#34;&gt;The benefits of disintermediation thanks to tokenization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tokenization is much bigger than creating a token to represent a real-world good. Let’s come back to the definition of NFTs we proposed: “unique goods which share common attributes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tokenization would work as well for certificates. IDs, passports, report cards or even software license could be tokenized. Not only would it greatly facilitate the process of emitting and sharing them; it would also provide traceability, unlike anything we’ve ever known so far. Which in turns would make a 99.9% fraud detection and prevention goal a realistic one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we keep pushing the logic further, we could go back to the digital world and envision NFTs to store our digital identity. Our social network profiles could be open-source and easily exportable from one network to the others. Besides, it would give full control and ownership over our own data and prevent malicious third parties from stealing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get there, we need to &lt;strong&gt;overcome the current limitations of both the Ethereum network and non-fungible tokens&lt;/strong&gt;: as stated before, the CryptoKitties were enough to clog the whole Ethereum network for several days. The current state of the tech (or December’s state at least) is apparently insufficient for a large scale usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ercsthe-new-standards-of-the-ethereumnetwork&#34;&gt;ERCs — The new standards of the Ethereum network
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Ethereum network, several teams are already working on the technical optimization of the network. Among them, we could mention Omisego/Plasma or the upcoming Ethereum update (Casper). Check the sources at the end of the article for resources on these matters; today we’re talking about NFTs so let’s get back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-721 was a good start yet it faces many problems while going at scale. Before we get here, let’s zoom in on ERCs. An ERC (Ethereum Request for Comment) is a proposal submitted by an Ethereum developer. It introduces methods, behaviors, innovations or research that could be used to used to improve the network functionality. Once accepted, an ERC can become a standard — it’s quite a long process. Once again an example makes the concept much clearer: the most famous standard for Ethereum is the ERC-20. It described a fungible and straightforward token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The primary interest of ERCs is that they allow integrating the tokens within the ecosystem smoothly&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need to know the specifics of each token since they follow a set of methods shared with others (defined by the ERC). This is why a wallet which supports ERC-20 tokens support all of them without requiring particular development for each new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;erc-1155-the-future-of-non-fungible-tokens&#34;&gt;ERC-1155, the future of non-fungible tokens?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 is a new standard for NFTs proposed by Witek Radomski, the founder of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://enjincoin.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EnjinCoin&lt;/a&gt;, a platform made to facilitate the development of games with tokenized goods on the Ethereum network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 fixes many issues raised when trying to use NFTs based on the ERC-721 at scale, and also brings many new features. Regarding the technical optimization, the ERC-1155 allows sharing a given piece of code between several different tokens or collections of non-fungible tokens. It will enable to support a much higher volume of transactions for the same load on the Ethereum network (compared to the ERC-721).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/erc1155.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A transaction involving several fungible and non-fungible goods thanks to ERC-1155&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A transaction involving several fungible and non-fungible goods thanks to ERC-1155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using ERC-1155, it’s also possible to exchange several items in one single transaction. With ERC-721, if Bob wants to exchange its cryptokitties #1, #2, #3 and #4 for Alice’s Cryptokitty #5, it would require 5 different transactions while one would be enough using ERC-1155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 also supports fungibles goods which are plenty in online games: think about all the coins, potions, arrows and other consumables. Using only one standard, the ERC-1155, versus a mix of them (ERC-721 for non-fungible goods and ERC-20 for fungible goods) makes it much easier for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, ERC-1155 could treat NFTs in a group, allowing them to retain some fungibility. It would allow players to differentiation the different iteration of a same common object, and the first owner of it could prove he was indeed the first to own it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-fungible goods are taking off, and Ethereum is a the forefront of the innovation. To better understand the ramifications of this concept, it’s best to go check its current usages. Let’s have a look at some games being developed/already available in pre-release versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/godsunchained.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gods Unchained&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Gods Unchained&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://godsunchained.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gods Unchained&lt;/a&gt;: We used card games to introduce the concept, it’s only logical to find one here. Gods Unchained is among the most well-known one and uses the ERC-721 standard. The benefits compared to regular card games (such as Hearthstone) are numerous: immutability of the cards after the release (no more surprise nerfs), full transparency of the rarity of each type of cards, traceability of the previous owners of a given card… The team is focusing on eSports, and the first world championship will take place early 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decentraland.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Decentraland&lt;/a&gt;: Take Minecraft, in virtual reality with blockchain-based mechanisms to handle ownerships: Welcome in today’s Tomorrowland! Once they own a piece of virtual land, users can create/develop the experience of their choosing (thanks to the SDK); they will then be able to control the access to their land and make other users pay for it if they want. Decentraland is a human and social experiment at world scale. It will be seriously insightful!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/augmentors.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A creature of Augmentors&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A creature of Augmentors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.augmentorsgame.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Augmentors&lt;/a&gt;: Since we were talking Pokémon earlier, what about Pokémon GO? Augmentors combined Augmented Reality with blockchain to offer a game where NFTs allow each user to truly own their augmented reality creatures and trade them as they want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dismissing NFTs could be tempting as for now it could appear like something for kids and nerds. Yet, it’s precisely the opposite: as the CryptoKitties have demonstrated it, NFTs are one of the best Trojan horses to drive the mainstream adoption of cryptocurrencies and decentralization-based mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With new technologies, the technical development is only the warming up phase. &lt;strong&gt;The real challenge lies with the social and legal acceptance of the tech: on that front, CryptoKitties and other collectibles are precursors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr/vulgarisation/tokens-non-fongibles-expliques-par-tortank-et-dracaufeu/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an original (French) EcoCrypto.fr story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources--deepdive&#34;&gt;Sources / Deep Dive
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/point-nine-news/mapping-the-emerging-non-fungible-token-landscape-ee56f0d1079f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Mapping the Emerging Non-Fungible Token Landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Pawel Chudzinski on Medium, 06/15/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/0xcert/erc-721-ethereum-standard-confirmed-and-finalized-73b78f7ea315&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;ERC-721 Ethereum standard confirmed and finalized!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — 0xcert on Medium, 06/24/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/porn-drives-technological-innovation-again-this_us_59f8085de4b094db8e76f834&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;_Porn Drives Tech Innovation Again, This Time In VR _&lt;/a&gt;— Jarone Ashkenazi on the HuffPost, 10/31/2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@argongroup/ethereum-plasma-explained-608720d3c60e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Explained: Ethereum Plasma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;— Lukas Schor on Medium/ArgonGroup, 05/28/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jonchoi/ethereum-casper-101-7a851a4f1eb0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethereum Casper 101&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Jon Choi on Medium, le 10/22/2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/a-proposal-to-shake-up-ethereum-a-new-standard-on-the-horizon-d2dfa88507a6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;A Proposal To Shake Up Ethereum — A New Standard On The Horizon? Mapping the Emerging Non-Fungible Token Landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Ermos Kyriakides on HackerNoon, 06/27/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
