<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stablecoin on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stablecoin/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stablecoin on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/stablecoin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/defi-vs-inflation-tokenbrice-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation is more than ever at the center of discussions and concerns: no one understands much about it, no economist has really anticipated it, but we all have an opinion about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we leave economics and politics aside to focus on what matters for your wallet: in decentralized finance, all kinds of protocols are developed, and a good part of them &lt;strong&gt;provide credible and innovative tools to preserve and develop the purchasing power of a portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;, even when the macroeconomic context is most uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to evaluate strategies involving different assets and protocols, all with the same goal: to preserve and develop the effective purchasing power of a given portfolio. Nevertheless, we have to start with the basics, level 0: what is inflation and why should we, DeFians, care about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover image was made by a generous anonymous contributor and features the majestic &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/valkyre/created&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Valkyr-E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;α-tutorial-understanding-the-impact-of-inflation-on-a-crypto-portfolio&#34;&gt;α/ Tutorial: Understanding the impact of inflation on a crypto portfolio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t venture into the details of inflation for fiat currencies here, but the basic concept is known to anyone familiar with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the term: here is how the INSEE (Institut National de la Statistique et des Études Économiques) defines inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation is the loss of purchasing power of money that results in a general and lasting increase in prices. It must be distinguished from the increase in the cost of living. The loss of value of money is a phenomenon that hits the national economy as a whole (households, businesses, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just remember that, &lt;strong&gt;just like in DeFi where each token is associated with a protocol and potentially even an ecosystem, each fiat currency is also based on an economy as well as a set of rules&lt;/strong&gt; (legal system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-macro-point-of-view-scale--country&#34;&gt;Inflation, macro point of view (scale = country)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation corresponds to the production of new money, the important thing is not so much the quantity of money created, but more &lt;strong&gt;what is done with&lt;/strong&gt;. We all understand this rather well with two caricatural examples at each extreme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country A issues a large amount of money in order to invest massively in its transport infrastructure and its energy supply (= long-term investments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here, inflation can be controlled because the new money issued is used to finance investments that develop the country&amp;rsquo;s economic potential in the long run (-&amp;gt; compensation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country B issues a large amount of money to finance an emergency plan to compensate for the foreseeable consequences of previous pseudo-sanitary measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second scenario, the new money is used to cover a &amp;ldquo;current expense&amp;rdquo; of the government. The personal equivalent would be to go into debt every day to pay for lunch. This is obviously unsustainable in the long run. In this scenario, inflation can only be massive as a large amount of new money is issued, while the economic potential of the country in question stagnates or deteriorates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluating-future-inflation&#34;&gt;Evaluating future inflation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough about the macro, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our scale, with things we know well. Here is the evolution of the M1 money supply on the dollar, this allows us to visualize its &amp;ldquo;marketcap&amp;rdquo; in a way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/USD-m1-supply.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;USD M1 Supply&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we only look at M1 for simplicity but the trend is similar on M2 and M3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested here in the dollar which, although challenged, remains the fiduciary currency that sets the tone. As you can see, the curve has been going vertical since the beginning of the Covid crisis. The curve is now much scarier than the worst shitcoins I have ever seen. Doubt it? Consider the same information, presented in this light:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dollar has been around since 1914. 20% of all dollars in circulation were created in 2020. At the current rate, the total amount of dollars in circulation doubles about every 4-5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare with crypto, many are concerned about inflation / new token issuance on Curve Finance (CRV). The 4 year issuance curve looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/crv-release-schedule.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-release-schedule&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no economist, but I know my shitcoins. The official US inflation figure we are given is 7.5% per year. Like unemployment figures, it&amp;rsquo;s a highly political metric that&amp;rsquo;s hard to really appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7.5% figure may seem high, but it is still low when compared to the unprecedented money creation to deal with Covid. So I expect to see this inflation rise further, or else to be sustained over an extended period of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So inflation is here, at 7.5% minimum for several years at least. Enough with boomers&amp;rsquo; macro, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the range of tools that the DeFi offers us to face it and overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-beating-inflation-with-classic-stablecoin-returns&#34;&gt;I/ Beating inflation with &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; stablecoin returns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first approach is as always the simplest, &lt;strong&gt;the brute force method&lt;/strong&gt;: an inflation of 7.5% means that USD left as is will lose 7.5% of their value over the year. The point here is to find a source of return higher than inflation: the difference between the two is the effective return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inflation at 7.5% on the USD, I think it is prudent to make sure to &lt;strong&gt;reach at least 1.5x this figure in yield&lt;/strong&gt; to really consider yourself inflation-proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the game is simple and the rules fairly easy to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with a position in a given stablecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to make it productive, without assuming IL risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a return that exceeds the inflation figure, once the gas costs have been amortized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-stablecoin-deposit&#34;&gt;Simple stablecoin deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we would aim for &lt;strong&gt;a 10.875% annual return on stablecoin $ at the very least&lt;/strong&gt;. With recent declines and yield compression this is increasingly difficult, but still findable even with a single stablecoin deposit without IL risk. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coindix.com/?kind=stable&amp;amp;sort=-apy&amp;amp;chain=ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Coindix&lt;/a&gt; can help you find the vault of your dreams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/coindix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coindix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, &lt;strong&gt;not all vaults are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;! For example, we see nice returns on Bancor on the screenshot: don&amp;rsquo;t forget to consider the volatility of these returns as well as the fees in gas to deploy the position (a Bancor LP is notoriously more expensive than a Yearn deposit for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention it here only to forget it just as quickly afterwards: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.anchorprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Anchor protocol&lt;/a&gt; also offers you a &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; return close to 20% on UST stablecoin. Such a guaranteed rate does not come, of course, without serious compromises that raise real questions about the sustainability of this whole ecosystem (Terra/Luna).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;provision-of-liquidity--time-commitment&#34;&gt;Provision of liquidity + time commitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still in dollars, but a bit riskier, we can consider different types of commitments, with very controlled / no IL risks. For example, a liquidity provision between FRAX and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/DAI LP opportunities on Frax&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax Finance&lt;/a&gt;, the prime rate (x1) is just our minimum target, but it is possible to reach up to x5 with two types of commitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X3 by locking LP tokens for 3 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X2 by using your veFXS (much harder to reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective return on a position locked in for three years corresponds to about 3 times our minimum target, thus offering a credible protection against the loss of value due to the consequences of inflation, but you still have to be able to assume the three-year commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is taken here on DAI, but the situation is similar on the other major stablecoins; for example, here are the FRAX/USDC pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/USDC LP opportunities&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex for Frax is coming (optimizing Frax LP farming via Convex), if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own veFXS, it&amp;rsquo;s probably pertinent to wait until the service is released to make a decision with all the cards in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenizing-and-speculating-on-future-yields&#34;&gt;Tokenizing and speculating on future yields
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To beat that famous 10% return on the dollar, there are still many other options. I present you one last one here to help you consider the other possible strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, we rely on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol that allows the tokenization of future yields on productive assets. The principle is both simple and complex: depositing an asset on APWine allows to separate its future yield (FYT: Future Yield Token) from the underlying principal (PT: Principal Token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, different strategies are possible, such as immediately selling the future yield (FYT) in order to increase the quantity of the productive principal. Such a tool enables better risk management considering the volatily of yields observed in DeFi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and still well above the 10% requirement: let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on the aUSDT vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apwine-USDT-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine aUSDT vault&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automatically exclude the PT/FYT pool which is more complex to understand and has much higher risks than the PT/Underlying offering a 44% return in APW anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the strategy is simple, but you have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the important gas costs linked to the use of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;. To implement the strategy using USDT in the wallet, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit a part of them on Aave (I&amp;rsquo;d recommend 55% of the total maximum for this specific strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit the aUSDT obtained in 1 on APWine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow (x2) + Deposit the PT and Underlying (USDT) tokens as liquidity providing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Stake of the LPs PT/Underlying tokens to obtain the return in APW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget also the gas fees related to the APW claims + unwinding of the position at the end of the period (or before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore better to wait for a day when the transactions clear under 30 gwei so as not to suffer too much from the gas costs on such a strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage here, compared to Frax for example, is that &lt;strong&gt;the position is much more liquid&lt;/strong&gt;. APWine works with an epoch logic that lasts 90 days. Thus, to more easily amortize the costs in gas it is preferable to deploy the strategy at the beginning of the epoch: this is also when the returns are generally the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third winelisting (where the next tokens supported on APWine are decided) has just ended, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apw-winelisting3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine - Winelisting 3&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APWine is still a young protocol, but the governance is dynamic. The next step is approaching: as on Curve, it will soon be the veAPW holders (locked APW) that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.apwine.fi/t/apgp-2-enable-gauges-for-apw-rewards/171&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;will decide on emissions&lt;/a&gt; for each given vault. A redistribution of the cards is to be expected, plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-hedged-productive-positions-with-various-alternative-stablecoins&#34;&gt;II/ Hedged productive positions with various &amp;ldquo;alternative&amp;rdquo; stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have stayed for now on the dollar, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to begin with. Although dollar stablecoins are still largely dominant, there are now &lt;strong&gt;many stablecoins based on other fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt; such as EUR, JPY (Japanese Yen), CHF (Swiss Franc), KRW (Korean Won) or even CAD (Canadian Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the few centralized stablecoins (EURS or EURT), this market is mostly covered by protocols that offer to create synthetic stablecoins backed by other stablecoins. This is the case for example with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jarvis Network&lt;/a&gt;, which uses USDC to collateralize different types of stablecoins: jEUR, jCHF, jKRW, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-deposit&#34;&gt;Single deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yield opportunities with no/low IL for such stablecoins are still quite rare, and usually found on Curve: providing liquidity against other stablecoins based on the same fiat currency, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/curve-chf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CHF pool on Curve Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few stablecoins have lucrative single deposit options jEUR, jCHF, jJPY. They are based on the corresponding Curve pools, with additional incentives offered by Jarvis and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via Jarvis (also available farmed by Harvest), it is also possible to generate a return without IL on jCAD and jJPY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiatafiatb-liquidity-providing&#34;&gt;FiatA/FiatB Liquidity Providing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a slightly different approach, more risky, but also potentially more protective against inflation: providing liquidity on two stablecoins representing two different fiat currencies, for example EURT/3pool (USD) still on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, especially for smaller portfolios, many alternative stablecoins are available on Polygon or Avalanche, with a fairly dense ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarvis offers jCHF-USDC, jEUR-USDC or jCAD-USDC pools with returns above 20%. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beefy.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Beefy.Finance&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to automatically compose the returns obtained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/harvest-jarvis-2-stables.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Network Jarvis jFIAT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: depending on your base asset (e.g. USDC), exposure to EUR (or other currencies) can be lucrative or costly - depending on the evolution of the USDC/EUR exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the more adventurous among you, you should know that APWine is also available on Polygon and already supports several Jarvis tokens, such as the MooJarvis_4eur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity contribution on Curve (4eur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed by Beefy Finance (moo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which compounds return that Jarvis offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the addition of tokens voted during winelisting 3 will open new doors with the upcoming arrival on APWine/Polygon of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooKyber_USDC-jEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooMai_USDC-MAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forex-borrowing&#34;&gt;Forex Borrowing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if liquidations don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, know that a Fuse pool on Polygon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://polygon.market.xyz/pool/7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool7 - Jarvis Forex Market&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to use different jFiat as collateral as well as to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/fuse-pool7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Fuse pool 7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a service, almost anything is possible, here are some examples to inspire you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long USD + short EUR = MAI in collateral, borrow jEUR then sell jEUR and potentially loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short GBP via CHF = jCHF in collateral, borrow jGBP then sell and potential loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also note that the productive stablecoins m2CAD and m2JPY are available as collateral while keeping their yield: they can be interesting for more traditional leverage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding your balance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than just one magic position, what I like about Jarvis stablecoins is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;diversify easily into different types of fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to the low transaction fees on Polygon, it is quite possible to mix several different currencies and positions to make a coherent whole and well protected against its local inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a European (= spending €):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in stable productive € without IL, for example MooJarvis_4eur (+APWine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in jEUR/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% in stable productive dollar (e.g. aUSDT APWine strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Diversification: 15% jCHF/USDC + 15% jGBP/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject of &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; stablecoins, you should know that there are also a few that track gold or silver - they can be relevant from this perspective too. For example XAUT (with Pool Curve XAUT/3crv). Gold and silver remain &lt;del&gt;barbaric&lt;/del&gt; boomers&amp;rsquo; relics, personally I see very little interest in them for a competent DeFian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-inflation-resistant-stablecoins&#34;&gt;III/ Inflation resistant stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beating inflation is nice. Hedging it? Even better. But &lt;strong&gt;why not just abstract it&lt;/strong&gt;, using products that are naturally resistant to it? There are still very few stablecoins that are not tracking fiat currencies, but the supply is growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-the-first-dollar-free-stablecoin&#34;&gt;RAI, the first dollar-free stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast, the very first &amp;ldquo;unpegged stablecoin.&amp;rdquo; Launched at a value of Pi in USD (3.14) in 2021, it has been moving between 3.02 and 3.06 almost since its launch. Given its recent arrival (just over a year), it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how RAI will perform in a period of prolonged inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, diversifying a portion of your stablecoins into RAI may be an attractive option. In addition, there are different return options available on RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple deposit without IL risk: Idle Finance deposits your RAI in Fuse/Aave to optimize the native return + incentives in FLX from Reflexer + incentives in IDLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle-0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Additional FLX incentives for RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By assuming IL risk via liquidity provision on Curve vs. 3pool, a better return is possible. The crvRAI can then be staked directly on Curve or via Convex or Yearn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is based on a mechanism inspired by Maker MCD but with many modifications to make it possible. To understand how it works, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Signals that the mentioned protocol is still under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-inflation-resistant-stablecoin-the-frax-fpi&#34;&gt;🚧 An inflation-resistant stablecoin? The FRAX FPI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Frax Price Index is a new protocol that should arrive soon within the Frax ecosystem. The goal is to offer a new stablecoin, which would follow the CPI (Consumer Price Index) to protect against inflation. Just like Frax, &lt;strong&gt;the system is based on two tokens&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stable - Frax Price Index (FPI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the governance token - Frax Price Index Share (FPIS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/frax-price-index/inflation-hedge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax documentation&lt;/a&gt; offers some information about the upcoming token. &lt;strong&gt;An airdrop of FPIS is planned&lt;/strong&gt; for veFXS or cvxFXS holders. Thus, the protocol will be independent of FRAX/FXS, although a value capture mechanism to FXS is planned beyond the initial airdrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to project solely on a mere design, but it is clear that a stablecoin that would maintain its value despite inflation is a very desirable product. &lt;strong&gt;There are several questions as to whether the peg on FPI can be maintained&lt;/strong&gt;: to keep its equilibrium, people will have to take the opposite trade to FPI, i.e. &amp;ldquo;short inflation&amp;rdquo;. However, in the current context of galloping inflation, it is hard to imagine who could assume such a position and massive incentives might be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the arrival of the FPI is imminent. Traces of the token &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/token/0xdb68c6264e9d0f8a6df1fa5a89f205da38698d15&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FPIS on EtherScan&lt;/a&gt; can be found as early as early March. I look forward to seeing the Frax team&amp;rsquo;s proposed design to address these consequential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-inflation-resistance--degen--volt&#34;&gt;🚧 Inflation resistance + degen = VOLT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI, there is another project I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely, waiting for a long time and holding high hopes for. The high-level concept is very simple: an Abracadabra-like product that would not be a walking security loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Abracadabra allows borrowing from various productive collaterals, which makes the service desirable. Nevertheless, the infrastructure is close to a hack and the actions of the team members make Abracadabra a second or third grade money market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here, with Volt, is to cover the same vertical using a proven infrastructure: the base offered by Reflexer (RAI). Three main changes are expected on this model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Reflexer, which only accepts ETH as collateral, Volt will diversify the available options, notably with productive collateral such as wstETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of VOLT, the system&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, will be indexed to Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI. The Reflexer infrastructure will be reused (PID controller adapted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Volt team is also working in collaboration with Fuse and Olympus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow Volt, as always, the alpha lives on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dGhvDmCNGr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I describe here the initial design of Volt Protocol, which has since evolved. The vision of creating a borrowing service with an inflation-proof stablecoin remains, but the technical choices have evolved. Read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/volt-protocol/whitepaper/blob/main/volt.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper available here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-beating-inflation-with-returns-on-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;IV/ Beating inflation with returns on volatile assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a world where nothing holds and value leaks, what&amp;rsquo;s left? How about good, proven DeFi assets backed by protocols with massive, recurring revenues shared directly with their holders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few of them, very few. We will detail them one by one, as well as the different options available on them to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-the-origin-and-the-end&#34;&gt;ETH: the origin and the end
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is of course ETH, which has many different sources of return - just like stablecoins, there is nothing to stop you from diversifying your ETH exposure with several sources of return, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH staked with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lido.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lido Finance &lt;/a&gt;(low yield, but a priori the safest) [~5%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rocketpool.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rETH&lt;/a&gt; on Curve (more innovative, more lucrative, more risky) [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vault covered call options on ETH via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stakedao&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ribbon.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ribbon Finance&lt;/a&gt; [~25%, risks!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-chain liquidity on a Bridge, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cbridge.celer.network/#/liquidity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celer&lt;/a&gt; [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A position balanced in this way tracks/exceeds inflation slightly with the returns obtained on ETH. The profitability of the position over the long term depends of course mainly on the average entry price on ETH and its evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crv-cvx-and-fxs-the-three-fates-of-the-defi&#34;&gt;CRV, CVX, and FXS: The three Fates of the DeFi?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Romans, the Fates are three goddesses who govern the lives of humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clotho weaves the thread of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lachesis unwinds it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atropos cuts it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi also knows these Fates: three protocols that play a critical role in the survival and growth of potentially any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in addition to ETH, there are several DeFi projects that have already proven themselves, control substantial revenue streams, and offer a truly relevant service in a macro context of prolonged inflation; I see three essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve Finance - CRV&lt;/strong&gt;: the mother of all yields in DeFi + peg machine and liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convex Finance - CVX&lt;/strong&gt;: an option on CRV, which controls almost 50% of all locked CRVs and adds real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frax Finance - FXS&lt;/strong&gt;: innovative stable project, native DeFi, very productive via AMOs + arrival of FPI + Frax has a big position on CVX &amp;amp; some other protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being tokens backed by key protocols in DeFi, there is no shortage of return options on these three tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV -&amp;gt; Deposit on Convex in CvxCRV then stake or LP cvxCRV/CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVX -&amp;gt; Locked vote on Convex in vlCVX -&amp;gt; Return in cvxCRV + bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FXS -&amp;gt; Direct deposit on Frax (veFXS) or management via Convex (cvxFXS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-promising-tokens&#34;&gt;Other promising tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still other projects that have not yet reached the profitability of Curve or Convex but represent credible bets. In a world where inflation is here to stay, the tools that will allow us to protect ourselves from it can become very popular: I propose you some other theses related to what has been already mentioned in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apwinefi-apw-betting-on-the-advanced-defi-infrastructure&#34;&gt;APWine.fi (APW): betting on the advanced DeFi infrastructure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When inflation goes up, everyone is looking for yield. Let them run behind the %, and instead target the pick sellers in this gold rush. This is the main thesis behind a bet on APW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the article already, APWine offers interesting products to bet on the evolution of yields or even realize a future yield immediately. As DeFi develops, the demand for a product like APWine will keep growing. Will it be APWine, or another one? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the APWine Wars coming up, it&amp;rsquo;s not a stretch to envision bribes similar to what we see on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflexer-flx-a-bet-on-degovernance&#34;&gt;Reflexer (FLX): a bet on degovernance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the very interesting technical approach, Reflexer also innovates on another level. Indeed, since the launch of the protocol, the team has presented a &amp;ldquo;De-governance Plan&amp;rdquo; aiming at progressively minimizing the team&amp;rsquo;s control over the protocol through two main means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of everything that can be automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management by FLX holders for situations still requiring manual analysis/decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;Reflexer now exceeds RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The Money God League is a set of projects building using the Reflexer infrastructure, with the support of the team. So it seems quite natural to consider an airdrop of the governance token of these new projects, including VOLT, to FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last tip: the stakers of the FLX/ETH LP in the Reflexer Safety Module are the last resort to guarantee the solvency of the protocol. If I were to consider an airdrop to thank the Reflexer community, I would probably target them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looksrare-looks-bet-on-nfts&#34;&gt;LooksRare (LOOKS): bet on NFTs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of LOOKS as an option on the NFT market. In fact, LooksRare is the first NFT marketplace that shares revenue. This translates into &lt;strong&gt;an ETH yield for stakers on LOOKS that reached 3 digits sustained during the first few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/looks-eth-farm.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ETH yields on LOOKS staking&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, trading volume has dropped and the ETH yield with it, but &lt;strong&gt;the staking LOOKS is still one of the biggest ETH yields out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with these three suggestions, but of course there are other options - you be the judge. For example, the QI Wars have started and the protocol has good traction. Be careful, however, not to fall into the trap of thinking that all protocols that adopt the ve + bribes model will be as successful as Curve and Convex. ve tokenomics will multiply: it&amp;rsquo;s about making the right choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-and-happy-harvesting-&#34;&gt;Good luck and happy harvesting 🚜
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be tempted to apologize for the length of this article, but I remain confident that it&amp;rsquo;s worth a read and will be informative even for the most knowledgeable DeFians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have considered other useful strategies or protocols for protecting against inflation, please feel free to suggest them to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further reading, here are some recommended related articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-wars/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Curve Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Reflexer RAI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, for the practice, which remains ESSENTIAL, your best bet to warm up is to try with small amounts on inexpensive sidechains/L2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The APWine protocol on Polygon to familiarize yourself with these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting jFIAT / Liquidity contribution on Curve + farming to discover Jarvis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long/short on Forex with jFiats + Fuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: I have invested in APWine pre-sale and I am a big user of the protocol. I am a user and frequent holder of almost all the protocols mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice, I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing my research to help you do yours!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt; for their careful proofreading and their suggestions to help improve this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/ethereum-stable-assets/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/money-god-meme.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp; endgame" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to cover an essential topic for Ethereum and other blockchains and often misunderstood: &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;stable&amp;rdquo; assets&lt;/strong&gt;, which track the price of a reference asset. Before looking at the different approaches to producing such an asset, we&amp;rsquo;ll first start with a higher level of analysis:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are such assets needed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are they used for?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do we want to standardize non-native Ethereum assets on this chain?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once these foundations are established, we will have all the tools to &lt;strong&gt;figure out the different methods and what is at stake&lt;/strong&gt;.. I will conclude with a more detailed analysis of a project that seems to me very relevant and innovative : the RAI of Reflexer Labs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already familiar with the different pegging mechanisms, you can jump &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;#focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34; &gt;directly to the section on Reflexer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;assets-standardization-on-the-ethereums-blockchain&#34;&gt;Assets standardization on the Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s blockchain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volume of issuance and use of pegged-assets has exploded last year, but before we look at what they are actually used for, let&amp;rsquo;s understand why. The simplest use case is to produce a stable asset, most often indexed to the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, &lt;strong&gt;the method used at a high level is tokenization&lt;/strong&gt;: we represent an asset that comes from another chain / world on Ethereum, such as wBTC (corresponding to 1 BTC on the Bitcoin chain) or USDC (corresponding to 1 USD in Circle&amp;rsquo;s bank account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;addresses one of the most common concerns for the general public: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;cryptos are volatile assets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;strong&gt;the rise of stablecoins has gone hand in hand with the rise of DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;, why? According to me, there are many reasons, the main ones being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Borrowings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stable assets can be very productive in DeFi&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-borrowings-mostly-in-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Why are borrowings mostly in stablecoins?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The money markets allow their users to borrow assets using other assets as collateral. The most frequent use case corresponds to the following pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user deposits a volatile asset, such as ETH, wBTC or LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He uses it as collateral to &lt;strong&gt;borrow a stable asset, like USDC or DAI&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is this so? To put it simply, few people are fond of the risks associated with price changes. &lt;strong&gt;Borrowing an asset, if you then mobilize it, is like shorting it&lt;/strong&gt;. No problem with stablecoins - in theory - but the reality is quite different with a non-stable asset: if the price goes down, good for you: the debt will only be cheaper to repay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the other way around, the scenario can be frightening since &lt;strong&gt;you can end up with a debt that increases&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s say you borrow 1000 UNI when one UNI is worth $20. You sell them for another token, for example stablecoins. So here you are with $20,000 DAI that you mobilize in DeFi for example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You hold your debt for several months and now you want to pay it off. Except that one UNI is now worth $30 and you no longer have any: you have to buy some back on the markets to pay off the debt and close the position. &lt;strong&gt;The debt is always paid in the borrowed asset&lt;/strong&gt;: you therefore owe 1,000 UNIs at $30 per unit or 30,000 DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am ignoring the loan interest&amp;rsquo;s here for simplicity&amp;rsquo;s sake. In reality you should pay back slightly more UNI, according to the interest rate and the length of exposure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yield-farming-with-stable-assets&#34;&gt;Yield-farming with stable-assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the first point understood, the second one makes perfect sense.: &lt;strong&gt;a lot of people are borrowing stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;, so that means that on the other side of the market people are lending them out, for attractive interest rates considering the demand. For example, on Aave, one of the main money markets, there has been &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity crunch in stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; almost since the launch of v2. Depositors enjoy an average annualized return of about 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is quite similar elsewhere with differences due to the specificities of each money market. Nevertheless, the liquidity crisis on stablecoins goes far beyond Aave: it potentially extends to the whole DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;there is no shortage of opportunities to produce a return with stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m talking about loans here, but it is also possible to bring liquidity to stablecoin pairs and even combine the two approaches to increase returns with a product like Curve:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/curve-yield-pool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-yield-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;explosion-of-the-pegged-assets-use-in-2020&#34;&gt;Explosion of the pegged-assets use in 2020
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thus, we have seen a real explosion in the issuance and use of pegged-assets in 2020. On the one hand, more and more projects are being launched to propose &lt;strong&gt;new asset types or new approaches to represent them&lt;/strong&gt;. On the other hand, the scenarios for using these pegged-assets are multiplying thanks to the growth of Curve money markets, vaults like those offered by Yearn or Harvest, and other even more complex DeFi products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To name but one, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://alchemix.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alchemix&lt;/a&gt;, a new synthetic asset service that allows &lt;strong&gt;loans secured by your future return&lt;/strong&gt;. Let me explain: with Alchemix, everything starts with a stable asset that produces a return. They chose the yDAI to start with (DAI productive thanks to the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user starts by depositing yDAI. He can then &lt;strong&gt;give up his future return&lt;/strong&gt; to borrow up to 50% of the deposited value. His loan is &lt;strong&gt;reimbursed automatically thanks to the interest generated by the yDAI&lt;/strong&gt;. In addition, since he has access to 50% of the deposited value immediately (borrowed in alUSD), he can put it to work to increase the return of the entire strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This type of product allows for an interesting across time arbitrage and leads to an even greater demand for stablecoins: at the launch of Alchemix, deposits in the yDAI vault took off up to the maximum capacity available for a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve talked about stablecoins so far, but a similar scenario has played out on other pegged-assets like tokenized BTC on Ethereum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/stablecoin-growth.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stablecoin-growth-ethereum-messari&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the impressive growth of DeFi, we can only expect the demand for this type of asset to grow ever faster. So let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at the different approaches used to produce them to understand their trade-off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-different-methods-to-produce-pegged-assets&#34;&gt;The different methods to produce pegged-assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, the vast majority of this demand for stable assets is being addressed with solutions based on a 1:1 match requiring trust. Thus, it is &lt;strong&gt;mostly USDT ($38.5B issued) and USDC ($9.4B) that are leading the way&lt;/strong&gt;, well ahead of DAI ($2.7B). The same goes for Bitcoin, without going into detail, all the most used solutions require trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pegged-assets&amp;quot; are assets that follow the price of another via a mechanism called &amp;ldquo;pegging&amp;rdquo;. Therefore, the &amp;ldquo;peg&amp;rdquo; is the value that the asset must maintain, for example $1 for stablecoins that follow the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A growing variety of approaches are being explored to produce a pegged-asset with less compromise. They are generally grouped into large families that correspond to the main method used to maintain the peg. However, as these approaches develop, the boundaries between them become blurred as several projects explore &lt;strong&gt;hybrid approaches mixing several elements of each&lt;/strong&gt;. We will start from the simplest to understand and progressively go to the most complex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-a-trusted-third-party-11-ratio&#34;&gt;Using a trusted third party (1:1 ratio)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The peg is easily maintained and rather stable. The system is solvent at all times (-&amp;gt; 1 USD in the bank for 1 USDC issued for example)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; The system requires a central trusted intermediary - the issuing organization. This same organization relies on another intermediary, the bank where the USD are deposited. In addition, the presence of a trusted intermediary creates a risk: is it reliable? transparent? The risk goes beyond image, it can also be legal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has already been detailed enough, so I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to the more complex methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins-produced-by-over-collateralization-maker-dai&#34;&gt;Stablecoins produced by over-collateralization: Maker DAI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The system no longer involves a central trusted intermediary (at least initially) &amp;amp; still manages to more or less maintain the peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; It will require &lt;strong&gt;always more $ collateral than $ (DAI) produced (over-collateralization)&lt;/strong&gt;. Governance risks. Risks at the liquidation level, carried out by third parties. The system is as trustless as its most used collateral. Maker now accepts censorable collateral (wBTC, USDC, etc.) which reintroduces a trust risk into the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long before algorithmic stablecoins, MakerDAO is a pioneer when thinking about how to &lt;strong&gt;produce a stable asset with less trust needed in the system than 1:1 approaches&lt;/strong&gt;. Maker is a more complex service because beyond the DAI - the stablecoin issued by the system, it also allows its users to use different assets to borrow (technically mint) DAIs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, it recreates risks and dangers to maintain the peg of the DAI. Many improvements have been proposed and implemented since the beginning, which allows DAI to be much more stable now than in its early days. Nevertheless, the scaling of DAI has come with additional compromises in terms of trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;more-innovative-approaches&#34;&gt;More innovative approaches
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, the approaches are more diversified - I group them into two families: the algorithmic approaches already well studied on my blog and the hybrid approaches. Both are based on an essential concept to understand: the &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; of these systems is a smart contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-smart-contract-as-central-bank&#34;&gt;A smart contract as &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use the words &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; because it evokes the essential concept here: the body that issues money and implements the monetary policy of the system is a smart contract. This allows for great transparency and visibility on the actions related to monetary policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand the systems presented below, you really need to understand this: &lt;strong&gt;the decisions to create or destroy new stablecoins are &amp;ldquo;taken&amp;rdquo; by a smart contract&lt;/strong&gt; - it alone has this ability to issue (and destroy / burn in some systems) tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I say that the smart contract takes &amp;ldquo;decisions&amp;rdquo;, I must explain myself : &lt;strong&gt;to be more precise, one could say that it reacts to the evolution of various measurable parameters&lt;/strong&gt;. The decisions of the smart contract are therefore transparent and predictable. A change in the rules governing it is possible but only via a governance vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most often, the main parameter taken into account is simply &lt;strong&gt;the price of the stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, in early algorithmic systems like Basis (BAC is the stablecoin), the rules are simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If BAC &amp;gt; $1, then the system issues and distributes new BAC to try to bring the price back towards $1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When BAC &amp;lt; $1 the system destroys BAC to create upward pressure. The destruction is not direct but voluntary: the actors in the system are encouraged to burn their BAC for a coupon (BAB) corresponding to 1 BAC + premium, which they can collect only when BAC has a sustained price above the dollar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more background on this &amp;ldquo;smart contract central bank&amp;rdquo; idea, you can read my first article on algorithmic stablecoins:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;L&amp;rsquo;état et le futur des stablecoins algorithmiques&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;algorithmic-approaches&#34;&gt;Algorithmic approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; This makes systems without a central trust intermediary possible and thus opens the way to truly trustless pegged-assets. Community governance possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages/Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; Sustained peg loss or difficulty maintaining peg. Possible governance attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I analyze the main approaches to produce algorithmic stablecoins in a dedicated article :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖ L&amp;rsquo;histoire de deux modèles de seigneuriage : Basis contre ESD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, projects like ESD, DSD, or Basis Cash were the pioneers of algorithmic stablecoins. However, all of these systems are now in a bit of an abyss: &lt;strong&gt;their stablecoins have been worth well under a dollar for a long time&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/bac-90days.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bac-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their users are looking forward to a V2 that will bring stablecoin back to the dollar like the messiah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hybrid-approaches&#34;&gt;Hybrid approaches
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👍 Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; The best of both worlds?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👎 Disadvantages / Risks:&lt;/strong&gt; A new potentially central and  intermediate point of trust appears in the system. You what happened next&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the current limitations of first generation algorithmic stablecoins, another approach has successfully emerged: the hybrid approach.  These are intrinsically algorithmic systems that &lt;strong&gt;include nonetheless a reserve in stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. (different from the system) used to maintain the peg: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://samkazemian.medium.com/frax-v2-algorithmic-market-operations-b84521ed7133&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pioneer in this field is Frax. With Frax, &lt;strong&gt;when FRAX trades above the dollar the system itself sells some to accumulate USDC&lt;/strong&gt;. This helps to bring the price down while building up a reserve of stablecoins not exposed to the system itself. Thus, if FRAX is trading &lt;strong&gt;below the dollar, the system can buy FRAX directly&lt;/strong&gt; on the market (using its stock of USDC) to bring the price back down to $1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/frax-price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;frax-price-90d&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this approach has the &lt;strong&gt;merit of efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; (FRAX has maintained its peg very well since launch), it reintroduces a trusted intermediary into the mechanism. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s not a bank like with Tether, but it&amp;rsquo;s still necessary trust in the system. What happens if the USDC balance of Frax is seized or frozen: could the system survive it? For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, yes it is technically (and legally) possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I remain very high-level on FRAX and describe the system mostly as it was in the beginning. Many integrations have been implemented or are being considered, such as the ability to mint FRAX directly into the FRAX-Tornado anonymity set (directly into TornadoCash) to offer a potentially more confidential stablecoin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;focus-on-reflexers-rai&#34;&gt;Focus on Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s RAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To finish this article, which I hope will be instructive, I suggest to analyze an innovative system: Reflexer RAI. It is a similar approach to MakerDAO, in the sense that the stable asset is produced by over-collateralization. Nevertheless, it brings many improvements over the Maker model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trustless collateral&lt;/strong&gt;: Until now, RAI only accepts ETH as collateral. This means that 100% of the collaterals in the system are not censurable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beyond the dollar&lt;/strong&gt;: the asset produced by the system does not follow the dollar (which is not really stable itself). The price of the RAI is determined by a consensus established by the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Money God&lt;/strong&gt; : just like algorithmic stablecoins, the system reacts to different observed parameters. However, just like MakerDAO, here it is the users themselves who directly hit the RAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Governance&lt;/strong&gt; : the token of the Reflexer system (FLX), which will be distributed to the users, is intended to be used to progressively decentralize the governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t panic if you don&amp;rsquo;t immediately understand why this system is innovative and significant, we will explore each of these points in more detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;censorship-resistant-collateral&#34;&gt;Censorship-resistant collateral
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initially, MakerDAO only accepted Ether as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;. With the first significant update of the system - the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/whitepaper/White%20Paper%20-The%20Maker%20Protocol_%20MakerDAO%E2%80%99s%20Multi-Collateral%20Dai%20%28MCD%29%20System-FINAL-%20021720.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Multi Collateral DAI&lt;/a&gt; - more tokens became usable as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community was perplexed by this decision, especially because of the choice of accepted tokens. Thus, BAT was one of the first new collateral while LINK, a token with volume and liquidity already far superior to BAT at the time, only arrived much later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond this &lt;strong&gt;difficult to understand valuation&lt;/strong&gt;, the crux of the problem is that &lt;strong&gt;many collaterals now accepted are censorable&lt;/strong&gt;: wBTC, RenBTC, USDC, TUSD, etc. This reduces the trustlessness of MakerDAO since at different times up to 50% of all DAIs were minted from censorable collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure is now reduced, but the concern remains. Furthermore, the addition of a special USDC vault was criticized during Black Thursday for helping DAI regain its peg - but it also made MakerDAO even more dependent on such collaterals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So Reflexer also fits in as &lt;strong&gt;a reaction to this &amp;ldquo;drift&amp;rdquo; of MakerDAO&lt;/strong&gt;: for now, only ETH is accepted to open a vault. I will be surprised if the team or the DAO vote to accept censorable collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;beyond-the-us-dollar&#34;&gt;Beyond the US Dollar
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moreover, Reflexer goes much further than DAI in its quest for stability. Indeed, the dollar itself does not have a stable value, because of the continuous production of new units which leads to inflation: thus $10,000 in 1950 is equivalent in purchasing power to almost $110,000 in 2021 (3.42% inflation per year on average over the period).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;An asset that is intended to be stable must therefore go beyond the limitations of the dollar and this is precisely what RAI does&lt;/strong&gt;: it does not follow the price of the dollar. The price of RAI is determined by pure social consensus: the system takes into account the observed price of the ETH/RAI pair (market price) as well as an internal price target (redemption rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are often gaps between the two, which creates an incentive to beat the RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/pegged-assets/reflexer-spread.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;reflexer-spread&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore, RAI is obviously not a stablecoin, It is not a pegged-asset either&lt;/strong&gt;. There are not enough words to describe RAI accurately, but let me try. RAI is an abstraction on the ETH which is intended to be more stable than the ETH, while maintaining its trustlessness (with time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;all-hail-the-money-god&#34;&gt;All Hail the Money God
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Money God&amp;rdquo; is the term used to refer to the set of rules that govern the Reflexer system. The memetic potential is also enormous. To remain quite synthetic, the Money God is lenient towards those who follow a perennial and long-term logic on the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the distribution mechanism of the Reflexer token, FLX, was recently modified to better align incentives (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more info here&lt;/a&gt;). The essence of the change is to better compensate those who perpetuate the system, i.e.:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit ETH to mint RAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; the RAI minted + the equivalent in ETH in the liquidity pool on Uniswap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of March 8, 100% of FLX is being distributed to those who follow this scenario. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gist.github.com/stefanionescu/e66204be990f4bc113a022341cb39186&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The history of FLX retroactive distribution strategies is here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-de-governance-plan&#34;&gt;The De-Governance Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides the important technical innovation on Reflexer, barely explored here, I particularly appreciate &lt;strong&gt;their approach to governance and decentralization of the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, as described by Stefan one of its architects:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The principle of “ungovernance” comes from our desire to progressively remove human control from the RAI system, thus making it socially scalable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has established &lt;strong&gt;a plan with concrete and dated goals&lt;/strong&gt; to achieve this end. The first step is to make the system&amp;rsquo;s liquidation and taxation mechanisms &amp;ldquo;governance minimized&amp;rdquo; - only a few parameters will remain changeable via governance (voting of FLX holders) from this point on. The target date is April 17, 2022, a little over a year after the initial launch of RAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At each step, the scenario is similar: a critical mechanism of the system is &amp;ldquo;governance-minimized&amp;rdquo; before it is put back under the full control of FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the details of this plan here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been following and waiting for Reflexer for over a year, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to finally tell you about it, and please forgive me for the delay: I wanted to put it in context to make sure everyone grasps the innovation brought by this protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article &lt;strong&gt;does not constitute investment advice&lt;/strong&gt;. I have no credentials in this area: they do not yet exist for DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am discussing the mechanics of several protocols and what they allow for or envision in the future. Even if I mention tokens, ditto: I discuss their utility or tokenomics but &lt;strong&gt;never their relevance as an investment&lt;/strong&gt;. On this topic, it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helps you better understand the rise of pegged-assets on Ethereum - it is essential. It&amp;rsquo;s also critical to understand the different trade-off sets associated with each approach: they are all potentially more or less relevant, depending on your situation and needs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, whether you are convinced by Reflexer or not, I strongly encourage you to dig into this system, just as I regularly invite you to explore the workings of Aave, Curve or Unslashed. All four are very relevant and innovative systems: understanding them in depth will allow you to internalize many essential things  to understand decentralized finance in general.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
