<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>YFL on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/yfl/</link>
        <description>Recent content in YFL on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/yfl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day a new Yearn fork is popping up: how to keep track with them? There is no simple answer to this dilemma, however, I believe I can &lt;strong&gt;provide you with some clues to help you spot YFI fork with high potential.&lt;/strong&gt; To do so, I’ll cover three (+1) YFI forks and try to pinpoint the changes to the secret sauce that made them stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is more than Yearn.Finance product itself: it became a template to kickstart a project, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Yearn pioneered the method which stands on three key elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining Fair Launch&lt;/strong&gt;: the initial distribution of the token of the platform (ex: YFI) happens through liquidity mining. Supporters can stake tokens like yCRV to earn the governance token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt;: the decisions regarding the development of the project are taken by the community of token holders, through informal and formal (on-chain) votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pooled Investment Strategies (Vaults)&lt;/strong&gt;: the Yearn-inspired projects usually also try to replicate this core feature of Yearn: they offer tokenised investment strategies. The vaults are essential for the long-term success of the project past the initial liquidity mining phase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Vault&amp;rdquo; is used to cover two vastly different reality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Basic Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where tokens are collected and stake to produce a yield. The yield produced is frequently settled for stablecoins (no leverage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Delegated Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where once tokens are deposited, they are used as collateral (thanks to credit delegation) to borrow stablecoins then used to produce a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegated Vaults are much more complex to develop and implement, while basic vaults can be sprung quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfi-wifey-wai-fu&#34;&gt;YFI? Wifey? Wai-fu?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Yearn, people were unclear on how to pronounce &amp;ldquo;YFI&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/make-yfi-pronounced-waifu/552&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A discussion on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; settled for &amp;ldquo;Wai-fu&amp;rdquo; (/waɪfu/). From this point onward, there was only one wai-fu but plenty of wifeys: the YFI forks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, despite being barely a few months old, &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has already been forked, a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. There is now a whole family of wifeys built upon similar premises, each project adjusting different parameters to attempt to better fit their envisioned use case. Many of these forks were unnecessary, however, &lt;strong&gt;several managed to bring something new and exciting to the table&lt;/strong&gt; —  the ones we will consider today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This content assumes an understanding of Yearn, to brush up on the topic I&amp;rsquo;d recommend &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;my previous article on Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dfimoney-yfiihttpdfimoney&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money (YFII)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest discussion in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s community was around the &lt;strong&gt;emission schedule&lt;/strong&gt;: while it was initially planned for a week, there were discussions about extending it - most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yips.yearn.finance/YIPS/yip-8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YIP 8&lt;/a&gt; which proposed a longer emission schedule halving weekly. &lt;strong&gt;Despite support from the Yearn Community, the proposal did not meet the quorum and was not implemented&lt;/strong&gt;, which lead to the YFII fork** - a fork of YFI implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;instead of having a week-only distribution, YFII opted for a longer schedule, still ongoing.&lt;/strong&gt; It started July 27 and will end on October 5. The farming pools proposed are very similar to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s: staking the yCRV token or staking the Balancer pool token (98%DAI / 2 % YFII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of this base differentiation, YFII develops an interesting angle with a &lt;strong&gt;strong presence in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: the DFI.Money website was quickly translated into Chinese and soon other languages. There is also a strong &lt;strong&gt;focus on UX&lt;/strong&gt; to make the experience as easy as possible to onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/dfi-money.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Overview of the DFI.Money Vaults&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stats.dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can view the stats here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 14, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DfiMoney/status/1305339433638531072?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money launched the v2 of their vaults&lt;/a&gt;, supporting ETH, USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD, HBTC, &amp;amp; yCRV. As this piece was written, there was a total of $70M deposited into DFI&amp;rsquo;s vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is not an exhaustive overview of YFI forks. There were other forks of Yearn with minimal changes that are not covered, such as YFFI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yflink-yflhttpyflinkio&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yflink.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink (YFL)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFL is another one of the early forks of YFI. Here, the twist is simple:** LINK was used as the base token of the system** - the one to deposit for the initial liquidity mining phase. The farming pools structure was similar to YFI/YFII, but with LINK/aLINK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial vision was to create a farming collaborative for LINK holders. YFL was developed by 5 anonymous teams working together and initially released on August 7 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/Linkswap.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFL LinkSwap&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth was quick and the plan soon refined! YFLink is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@linkswapco/yf-link-ecosystem-linkswap-development-update-44f8413721c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;now working on LINKSwap&lt;/a&gt;, a community-governed Automated Market Maker (AMM), focusing on safety and value capture for LINK holders. LINKSwap explores novel ideas to increase investors&amp;rsquo; safety - for instance, the RugLock feature, designed to avoid rug pulls - when the token’s creators drain the liquidity pools, leaving holders with a sizeable bag of worthless coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfvalue-yfvhttpyfvfinance&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFValue (YFV)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue adds several more twists, with a similar goal of providing a service facilitating yieldfarming and making it more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the farming pools were mostly 98% ERC20-token / 2% YFV Balancer pools and the emission schedule is much longer (5 to 20 weeks) - it&amp;rsquo;s still ongoing while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/yfv-bringing-true-value-to-yield-farming-bddc4edf889a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFV launched mid-August.&lt;/a&gt; There is also a &amp;ldquo;seed pool&amp;rdquo; accepting stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV was one of the first project to provide credible earning opportunities on tokens such as BAL, YFI, BAT, REN, KNC, BTC, WETH, or LINK: it really helped to attract liquidity — there are around $470 M deposited on YFV as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/yfv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFV Staking Interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV&amp;rsquo;s core product, the Governance Vault was just &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/roadmap-update-value-contract-governance-vault-e226ad2f909e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;launched on September 15&lt;/a&gt;. YFV Holders can stake their token for several benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting power in the governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A return paid in vUSD and vETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV token from the emission schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from the strategy implemented with the Governance vaults funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from buying back YFV with 6.8% of the profits made with the vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV is a highly ambitious project. The vaults (wETH, wBTC, renBTC) are expected shortly. On top of the existing farms and governance structure, the team is working on transitioning to an AMM/farming collaborative called Value Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue is in the process of transitioning to VALUE (token) and Value Liquid (name of the exchange/service). You’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/faq-yfv-and-value-migration-af3a5a5c2190&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more information on this rebranding and transition here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfinspired---harvestfinance-farmhttpsharvestfinance&#34;&gt;YFInspired - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance (FARM)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Harvest.Finance is technically not a fork of Yearn, one could say it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;fork in spirit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, Harvest ambitions to streamline yieldfarming to make it more accessible &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s quite a success: Harvest is now home to more than $200 M (+200 M) of diverse assets farming with no stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience on Harvest is quite straightforward, just like with the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault. &lt;strong&gt;Users deposit tokens into the strategy of their choice to put them to work&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, they deposit their DAI to get fDAI, DAI currently farming on Swerve.fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/harvest-finance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once they own fDAI (or other fTokens), users can stake them to earn FARM - the native token of the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; They can also provide liquidity to the fDAI/DAI pair on Uniswap which facilitates the entry and exit of smaller capitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvest.Finance launched on September 15 a new vault accepting for wETH. The community is highly active and committed, and it shows in the reactivity of the team: to better the yield, the stablecoin farms (DAI, USDC, USDT) switched from the Curve strategy to Swerve barely 16 hours after &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://swerve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Swerve&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yfi-fork-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;The YFI-Fork Secret Sauce?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope these quick introductions will help to better understand the recipe for a successful YFI fork. Considering the sample size (3+1), it’s hard to draw some conclusions but allow me to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I see a YFI-Fork scoring some resilience points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;focuses on a clearly identified community&lt;/strong&gt; (ex: LINK holders for YFLINK).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol parameters (pools, tokens, etc.) are adjusted to match the target community wants and needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A one-week emission schedule was a luxury only affordable by the first Waifu,&lt;/strong&gt; mother of all others (YFI). Successful YFI-forks tend to need a longer schedule (5-20 weeks) to gather and structure their community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A farm by itself is not enough, there is a real need for &lt;strong&gt;a convincing vision for the project in the long-run&lt;/strong&gt;, such as an AMM (YFL/YFV), or going above and beyond on the farming front (Harvest), and more than anything a driven and dedicated community to support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Thanks to Ashitaka#4868 from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RheJ78p&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance Discord&lt;/a&gt; for the amazing cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-disclaimer&#34;&gt;NECESSARY DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;NOT investment advice&lt;/strong&gt; or a recommendation to purchase any of the token mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not a financial advisor. I have no formal financial advising training, certification, nor experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a DeFi native sharing my insights, do with it as you may, but please think twice and avoid impulsive decisions at all cost: they are usually the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚜 Merry Farming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
