<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>BanklessFR on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/banklessfr/</link>
        <description>Recent content in BanklessFR on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/banklessfr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>DeFi is a toolbox reaching beyond finance</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/defi-is-a-toolbox-reaching-beyond-finance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/defi-is-a-toolbox-reaching-beyond-finance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post DeFi is a toolbox reaching beyond finance" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance is ready to grow beyond its sandbox: with a dense network of financial primitives, it&amp;rsquo;s now easier than ever to harness DeFi for other ends, such as to replace a predatory relic of our past like the lottery, still insanely popular and detrimental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this story, I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a step back and adopt a macro perspective on Ethereum. So far, my interest mostly revolved around decentralized finance, as it drove the innovation over the last couple of years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I believe we&amp;rsquo;re reaching the next step of the growth of the incredible human coordination experiment that is the Ethereum network: the lego blocks provided by DeFi are now mature enough to be harnessed for other ends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing how these &lt;strong&gt;streamlined value capture and exchange devices&lt;/strong&gt; can be harnessed to facilitate the creation of engaged communities or sustain the commons. So this time, instead of what or how, let&amp;rsquo;s ask why? After a quick reminder on the key benefits delivered by DeFi legos, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few projects harnessing them to flip the table in their respective domains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defis-legos-the-core-building-blocks&#34;&gt;DeFi&amp;rsquo;s Legos: The core building blocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The myriad of decentralized financial services available on Ethereum demonstrated the benefits of what I like to call &amp;ldquo;pragmatic values&amp;rdquo;: transparency, accessibility, accountability, and interoperability. Why pragmatic? Because withholding them is not a matter of goodwill of the system&amp;rsquo;s participants, they are &lt;strong&gt;enforced by default and continuously as long as the network is operating.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ask your bank how your money is invested, you get an answer you can trust or not. Verifying it involves inquiries from your end. On the other hand, you don&amp;rsquo;t ask Yearn where your money is: you see what it&amp;rsquo;s doing at all times, and this information is reliable and unfalsifiable. It&amp;rsquo;s a fundamental change in the relationship - the user of a DeFi service is not a mere &amp;ldquo;customer&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;☝ This is what the term &amp;ldquo;trustless&amp;rdquo; usually refers to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to unpack these core pragmatic values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency&lt;/strong&gt;: By default, transactions on the Ethereum network are public. For DeFi, this translates into very concrete benefits - for instance, volumes &lt;strong&gt;observed (on the chain)&lt;/strong&gt; on decentralized exchanges tend to be much more realistic than volumes &lt;strong&gt;reported&lt;/strong&gt; by centralized exchanges (tracked in their internal database).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt;: To use a DeFi service, such as an exchange or an asset management system, all you need is an Ethereum wallet and a device with an internet connection. On unstoppable services like the DEX Uniswap, there is no way to blacklist an address from using it. This has obvious benefits for populations usually discriminated against by financial services operators, such as gamblers, sex workers, or foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interoperability:&lt;/strong&gt; DeFi services are like lego blocks, they are open source so that they can be improved and built on top of. It enables rapid innovations as new projects can quickly deliver value by assembling several existing services in new ways. Everyone can check their code and easily contribute&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimalism&lt;/strong&gt;: Ethereum is a network designed for resiliency and it comes with interesting consequences. With a highly redundant infrastructure where bandwidth and storage capacity are limited, successful projects tend to be those able to reduce or avoid unnecessary complexity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/defi-legos.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DeFi-legos&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DeFi ecosystem delivered a range of services thanks to which anyone can buy, sell, secure, exchange tokens in a decentralized fashion. They also &lt;strong&gt;normalized behaviors that were uncommon before&lt;/strong&gt;, such as staking tokens, borrowing, using leverage, minting synthetic assets, and many other options made possible once assets are tokenized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, as I was saying in the introduction, so far these new legos have been used mostly in a reflexive manner. Now, they are increasingly used to deliver innovative services offering even more possibilities. It&amp;rsquo;s essential as each new DeFi layer enables many more use cases outside of finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fixing-a-detrimental-societal-institution-using-defis-legos&#34;&gt;Fixing a detrimental societal institution using DeFi&amp;rsquo;s legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with the obvious and trickle down from here: fixing the lottery. As you probably already know, lotteries are poverty traps sometimes described as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://erlc.com/resource-library/articles/state-lotteries-are-an-exploitative-tax-on-the-poor/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exploitative tax on the poor&lt;/a&gt;. Their public is predominantly poor, and overall the lottery is not helping with their budget. Even with a lucky outcome, other issues arise sometimes leading right back to the starting point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issue with the lottery has many roots, including the fact that they are usually owned or operated by national governments. The good news is that DeFi can deliver the core element of the lottery - the prize - in a much more sustainable manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, to deliver a jackpot, you need some form of prize. Current lottery models pool together contributions from everyone to return it to one player, minus the cost of the operations and a fee: money is &amp;ldquo;burned&amp;rdquo; within the base loop because of the infrastructure required to run the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi can do much better on both fronts. First, for the prize: instead of a net-loss system, PoolTogether provides a &lt;strong&gt;no-loss lottery&lt;/strong&gt; to its players. The gist is simple: they are not buying a ticket but instead depositing stablecoins into a pool. Assets from all players are used to produce a return using the decentralized lending markets. The &lt;strong&gt;winner earns the interest generated by the whole capital over the period, and everyone gets back their initial investment.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also comes with many improvements over legacy lotteries infrastructure: using Ethereum tokens to represent lottery tickets comes with additional benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency&lt;/strong&gt; - drawing the winner and paying the prize is much faster, public, and verifiable by anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceability&lt;/strong&gt; - every operation is public and auditable, making it easier to prevent frauds and abuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt; - all you need is a wallet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lottery example is essential to better understand &amp;ldquo;DeFi+&amp;rdquo; use cases. DeFi by itself is amazing. But &lt;strong&gt;using DeFi to replace predatory societal infrastructure? Sounds like even closer to its reason to be!&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;ll explore this theme further by looking at the funding of public goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;enabling-sustainable-commons-gitcoin&#34;&gt;Enabling sustainable commons: Gitcoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For decentralized DeFi projects, the community is key as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;we’ve seen with Yearn Finance&lt;/a&gt;. On top of their role of driving the project development and growth, communities also frequently deliver key resources, such as dashboards, calculators &amp;amp; diverse tools to facilitate the tracking and management of positions, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zerion.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zerion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the macro level, the main tools used to track the overall growth of the industry also stem from the community, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defillama.com/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFillama&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarming.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YieldFarmingInfo&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarmingtools.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YieldFarmingTools&lt;/a&gt;. The development of such services is usually fueled thanks to community donations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To facilitate the discovery and funding of such projects, there is a platform harnessing the possibilities offered by Ethereum to improve public good funding: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://gitcoin.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gitcoin&lt;/a&gt;. Gitcoin streamlines the creation of “Grants” to collect donations for given projects and communities. It makes the most of Ethereum core attributes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/gitcoin-grants.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gitcoin-grants-round7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All donations are public and transparent&lt;/strong&gt;, making it easy to measure and track contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Projects can be funded with common Ethereum-based tokens, usually stablecoins such as DAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the community is the main driver of contributions, Gitcoin uses a system called quadratic funding to balance contributions. Each round, &lt;strong&gt;it matches contributors&amp;rsquo; donations&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to an additional budget.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The budget is provided by donors from the ecosystem. While it used to be mostly large Ethereum-based companies, a new type of sponsor is emerging: treasury funds of DeFi projects. Indeed, some key DeFi players like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/yip-direct-of-rewards-towards-ethereum-public-goods-funding/3699/22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance voted to allocate a portion (1%)&lt;/a&gt; of their protocol income to fund Gitcoin grants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there is still room for improvement - and Gitcoin keeps getting better with every new matching round - it’s already a critical part of the infrastructure used to fund the commons on Ethereum. It really streamlines the process of collecting donations for community-driven projects. We use it for the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR newsletter&lt;/a&gt; along with other sources, and it’s part of what is enabling us to deliver a high-quality yet free newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest Gitcoin grants round just started. You can give to support your favorite projects with an additional matching until December 17. Allow me to suggest a selection of &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/collections?featured=true&amp;amp;collection_id=24&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;people documenting DeFi in non-English languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - just like I try to do with French.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;d like to support French DeFi particularly, feel free to check the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr-the-daily-gwei-fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR &amp;amp; DailyGweiFR grants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a pair of newsletter offering two different takes to learn about DeFi, in French.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-ethereum-help-art-markets-be-more-transparent-and-fair&#34;&gt;Can Ethereum help art markets be more transparent and fair?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another subset of the Ethereum ecosystem has been delivering incredible value for community building lately: non-fungible tokens (NFT). While the term is a mouthful, the base idea is actually quite simple: NFTs deliver another level of digital scarcity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find a detailed explainer on NFT two years ago, still relevant and accessible for newcomers: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2018/nft.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paired with DeFi, NFTs are now enabling new forms of community interactions and fundings. Using &lt;strong&gt;self-serve platforms&lt;/strong&gt;, artists and communities can autonomously create and sell NFTs with services streamlining the process like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Rarible&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks to their programmable nature, NFTs enable &lt;strong&gt;new re-distribution models&lt;/strong&gt; such as a contribution on secondary market purchases. Finally, since they live on the Ethereum blockchain, NFTs also provide a transparent history of ownership and previous prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet again, thanks to Jon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;@OtherBright&lt;/a&gt;), BanklessFR has been exploring this new frontier too. Thanks to a collaboration with the artist Arke, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:43413:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;we’ve released a NFT&lt;/a&gt; tied to the newsletter&amp;rsquo;s content. I&amp;rsquo;ve asked Jon to share some pointers on the experiment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://banklessfr.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygweifr.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Daily Gwei FR&lt;/a&gt; we are trying different experiments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/banklessfr-nft.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;BanklessFR-NFT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Arke56374430&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Arke&lt;/a&gt;, we started with the sale of a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:43413:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BanklessFR NFT&lt;/a&gt;, representing the newsletter BanklessFR. This collectible card, available in 40 copies, was successfully sold at 0.15 ETH each. We shared the profits with the artist. We included an article that can be unlocked at the time of purchase, 24 hours ahead of readers who do not have the card. This distribution model is clearly innovative, but in my opinion requires to be developed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Our &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:64356:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;second sale&lt;/a&gt;, different from the first, still for BanklessFR, illustrated an article, and offered 10 copies of the card, at 0.3 ETH per unit. It also contained an article that could be unlocked 24 hours in advance. The latter worked much less, certainly because of a relatively high price, despite a rarity 4 times greater.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-beyond-finance/the-daily-gwei-fr.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TheDailyGwei-FR-NFT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:81692:0x83ac01254b0b8e9745492c5e73f5f32a05570a76?tab=overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;last sale&lt;/a&gt; concerns the launch of The Daily Gwei FR. We published 50 copies of a card representing the newsletter. We haven&amp;rsquo;t sold one yet, 0.05 ETH per card, 50 cards available. We will modify this sale to continue the experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have other ideas in mind, here the experiments are relatively simple, but much more complex systems should be implemented. I think we should insist on funding from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/1274/banklessfr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;gitcoin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://clr.fund/#/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;clr.fund&lt;/a&gt;, before accelerating on the NFTs side.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, these services provide innovative tools to build and grow communities. Thanks to the disintermediation, NFTs put artists back at the center of the stage. We&amp;rsquo;re seeing more and more instances of collaboration between an artist and a community, like we did for BanklessFR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we&amp;rsquo;re entering an age of renewed excitement, especially for people outside the space, make sure to direct newcomers to reliable resources: how about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/-guide-1-starting-with-bankless&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless&amp;rsquo;s getting started guide&lt;/a&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-markets-blackhole&#34;&gt;The markets blackhole
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking a step back, the trajectory of the last couple of years of development makes even more sense. The financial functions were the necessary first steps, as they now operate as primitive enabling more intricate interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At their very base, &lt;strong&gt;markets simply are distribution/allocation mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;. So far, in the world of old finance, we&amp;rsquo;ve let technocrats design them, to the benefits of the most connected and rich participants. With DeFi, we&amp;rsquo;ve experimented with our own ways of creating markets. We&amp;rsquo;ve already seen migrations of billions over a few days to chase a given incentive such as Uniswap UNI mining or the one-week YFI mining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly put, our finance is already strongly superior to any meatspace counterpart. We can create immense and healthy markets in days. Have derivatives and other options for the next one. Leverage soon after. &amp;amp; all/most of this delivered in an unstoppable fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not a trader, this might sound like tooling overkill. It&amp;rsquo;s really not. Picture finance like a base layer underlying all the others. Whatever your goal is, your system will probably have to manage some finite resources, so you&amp;rsquo;ll need markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is that our markets - our base layers - are more efficient than any other so we can reasonably expect a compounding impact of this increased efficiency as we move down the stack. Simply put, finance is the first battlefield we&amp;rsquo;ve won: the decentralized approach succeeded and delivered a superior infrastructure without equivalent. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the next!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>One step closer towards working for and answering to the Ethereum &amp; DeFi community</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/one-step-closer-towards-working-for-and-answering-to-the-ethereum-defi-community/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/one-step-closer-towards-working-for-and-answering-to-the-ethereum-defi-community/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/next-steps/df1.png" alt="Featured image of post One step closer towards working for and answering to the Ethereum &amp; DeFi community" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I move on with the next chapter of my involvement in the DeFi space, I wanted to take the time to write a rare personal statement to share my story and what&amp;rsquo;s coming next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;discovering-the-ether&#34;&gt;Discovering the Ether
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;About 36 months ago, I finally read the Ethereum whitepaper after hovering around the crypto space for a while and was instantly hooked. Back then, my concerns were far remote from decentralized finance: I saw in Ethereum the first credible solution to coordinate a scale aka the first sword finally able to slay the beast Moloch&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was still working in a non-crypto related tech startup back then but quickly I found myself spending 6 to 10 hours a day reading on the space, meeting and chatting with many people that shared my interest. Shortly after, I started contributing to various projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in July 2018, &lt;strong&gt;I realized it was time to grab the bull by the horns and break my way into the space&lt;/strong&gt; - I was not going to work for yet another tech startup. I started what I wished could be a collaborative media back then: EcoCrypto. It was a bit of the precursor to this blog, and you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/tags/ecocrypto/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;find the articles re-published here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ecocrypto-the-precursor&#34;&gt;EcoCrypto: The Precursor?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The approach on EcoCrypto was quite particular: every article was reviewed by people completely outside the space, such as my parents. They were rewritten until the result was self-sufficient and understandable. After that, I also translated them into French. This writing process was intense and time consuming. Back then, naively, I thought that trying to go above and beyond in terms of research and quality would be enough to attract the crowds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the moderate audience, EcoCrypto taught me a lot about the space. To beef up and learn at an accelerated pace, I&amp;rsquo;ve also spent a few months writing &amp;ldquo;content bounty&amp;rdquo; and secured my first batch of ICO-shitcoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;going-pro&#34;&gt;Going Pro
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feeling more confident about my understanding of the space and my capabilities to handle marketing-related tasks for a crypto project, I started applying to selected companies, and went through the interview processes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I exchanged with a few prominent actors of the space, but I was &lt;strong&gt;quickly turned off by their internal culture &amp;amp; inertia&lt;/strong&gt;: all my life, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked in startups so I&amp;rsquo;ve got little patience for corporate-induced BS. Around the same time, I found Monolith (TokenCard back then) and started discussing with the team about the community manager role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited by the product and its ambitions, especially its user-focused aspect. Until then, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with products quite remote from everyday people. On the other hand with Monolith &lt;strong&gt;I could see a long-term vision where even my parents were using the product I was contributing to&lt;/strong&gt; (and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TokenBrice/status/1290979491561472000&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;it happened&lt;/a&gt;)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite my slim professional experience in the crypto space (it wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly commonplace in 2018), Monolith took a bet on me and I started in April 2018 as Community Manager.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;communities--brands&#34;&gt;Communities &amp;raquo; Brands
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned so much in that role! What I loved the most about it is that I was a frontliner always in contact with exciting people. Back then, there was no covid either so I also had the chance to actually meet these people, in Paris, in London, and even attend the DevCon V in Osaka!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s silly, but Osaka blew my mind. Before it, I felt the energy and ambition of the space. Going there, I &lt;strong&gt;saw&lt;/strong&gt; it personally, and it was something else. It bolstered my confidence in the impact Ethereum could have on the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also around this time that I&amp;rsquo;ve met &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mounibec&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mounir&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/arthurmicoulet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Arthur&lt;/a&gt;, and together we created &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/learndefi/_index.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi France&lt;/a&gt;: the attendance at our first event blew our mind, with 90 people in the room for an event organised in a few days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/next-steps/df1.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DeFi France DF1&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s precisely then that I&amp;rsquo;ve been stuck by a critical thought I needed months to digest, it goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent my whole professional life building artificial communities to support the growth of brands. How about I finally use this hard-earned expertise for a better end? How about we drop the brand &amp;amp; build a community… for the community?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-involvement-in-defi&#34;&gt;Community Involvement in DeFi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took me a while, but now is the time to finally follow through with the thought. As I transition out of my role with Monolith, &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to use this extra time to do more community-driven work&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me, time was all I needed and there is plenty of work to do! Indeed, within a year, DeFi France grew tremendously to become the most active DeFi grassroots group in Europe with now close to 2 000 FR-speaking members on Telegram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here&amp;rsquo;s what I will be focusing on now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tokenbricexyz&#34;&gt;TokenBrice.xyz
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I write a lot of content about DeFi for different companies but sometimes I want to express myself in a lighter tone, with less constraints. I started this blog to have a space that fit my ideals to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ideals? Quite simple: I think that &lt;strong&gt;delivering an honest media is extremely difficult if profits must be made, so how about we get them out of the equation?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So on this blog, I refuse all sponsored posts or promotional activities. All articles are written because I want to do so. I&amp;rsquo;ve also taken extra care to make this blog as privacy-preserving as possible: the cool news with a free blog without ads is that I would have no use of your data anyway, so let&amp;rsquo;s not collect any (but your anonymised IP for article stats).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I use an infrastructure where the content lives in a public GitHub repository: for the non-geek &lt;strong&gt;it means that every single change made on tokenbrice.xyz is documented publicly.&lt;/strong&gt; There is no flip-flopping here. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/TokenBrice/blog/commits/master&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t trust, verify.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are still costs incurred with the blog, mostly the time spent writing and researching as well the occasional illustrations when I feel like my PPT cover graphics are not enough to do the article justice. Yet, I&amp;rsquo;m not counting the hours with this blog, I enjoy updating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you appreciate my work, you can contribute to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/811/tokenbrice-shining-light-on-ethereums-defi-en-fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gitcoin grant&lt;/a&gt; to support it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the approach with this blog in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/hello-world.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this article detailling the infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;defi-france&#34;&gt;DeFi France
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quickly after the creation of DeFi France, we realized something powerful was happening. With minimal effort, the group was growing fast and the energy in there was amazing (and still is!). Finally, I think we&amp;rsquo;ve got a sense of what the growth of an &amp;ldquo;organic community&amp;rdquo; felt like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several things helped this work, one of the main one being the language: DeFi is so confusing already, so why not discuss it in our native language to make it easier? In the early discussion we could tell &lt;strong&gt;the excitement of chatting about the topic in French&lt;/strong&gt;! As it turned out, there were plenty of Frenchmen in the DeFi space already, all we needed was one place to gather and meet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the language component, the other key to the success of DeFi France lies in its community. The Telegram group and the monthly meetups are incredibly successful at one critical thing: to &lt;strong&gt;ensure that the amazing French builders of the DeFi space were accessible to anyone&lt;/strong&gt;, even to someone with no presence in the space. Every month, there is a hangout where you can come, learn from people committed in the space, and meet people (now remote: fucking covid).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute here to thanks some of the people who make this community amazing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙏 Pascal Tallarida, Marc Zeller, Alexandre Lourimi, Mosche Malawach, Mat C., Zhytop, McNulty, Jonathan, Dydymoon, Antoine, Fabrice, Florian, Romain &amp;amp; so many others!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;defi-france-youtube&#34;&gt;DeFi France (YouTube)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next to the existing Telegram group and monthly meetup, we&amp;rsquo;re now growing a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://youtube.com/c/defifrance&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; to offer high-quality content video content about DeFi, still in French. Although I&amp;rsquo;m heavily involved in the shows presenting most of them for now, the vision is to grow the channel and make it accessible to any relevant and passionate producer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed &lt;strong&gt;in France, the leading crypto media and YouTubers are running ruthless businesses&lt;/strong&gt;. They do not care about what they are pushing as long as it&amp;rsquo;s profitable. Worse, a fair share don&amp;rsquo;t even care about the factual inaccuracies of their content as long as they produce views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I figured: can&amp;rsquo;t we establish a community alternative that one day, maybe, will find it way to the crowds too? So here&amp;rsquo;s the hack: we grow a channel, and we make it accessible to other content producers based on expertise, goodwill and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project started a few months ago and is going well on its way! We crossed the 500 subscribers mark and now have 2 recurring emission formats on top of the rediffusion of the DeFi france meetups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;banklessfr&#34;&gt;BanklessFR
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I put BanklessFR right before the last, because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to steal the show here. Credits where they are due: &lt;strong&gt;BanklessFR only exists because of the sustained hard work of Jon who is the editorial director and the main translator&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back to BanklessFR&amp;rsquo;s story: I&amp;rsquo;ve reached out to Ryan one day to tell him about my bankless-first life (I&amp;rsquo;ve barely touched a non-DeFi financial product in my whole life) and surprise! he was keen - it translated into an article: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/how-defi-can-pay-for-your-lunches&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How DeFi Can Pay For Your Lunches?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around the same time (lucky timing is everything), &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; was emerging in the DeFi France community as one of the most motivated new joins. He started translating several pieces of content into French on his own initiative, including one of mine which led us to talk more about translations. We discussed potential next steps for these efforts, and BanklessFR quickly seemed like an evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve reached back to Ryan and was delighted to find out that it was actually already part of his plans for Bankless to go global! So with the support of Ryan and an initial funding collected thanks to contribution to the Bankless International grant, BanklessFR started on May 27 with the publication of the translation of the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://banklessfr.substack.com/p/le-skill-cube-de-bankless&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Skill Cube.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BanklessFR has now been growing since: we&amp;rsquo;re expanding the content offering &amp;amp; exploring different ways to turn this into a sustainable project. After the first Gitcoin grant in September, we just released the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:43413:0x6b40aca108fdb67a781ed4c6810f47f7f3764d00&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;first BanklessFR NFT series&lt;/a&gt; to illustrate an article it&amp;rsquo;s tied to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/next-steps/imageNFTbanklessfr.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;BanklessFR First NFT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-about-your-job-brice&#34;&gt;What about your job, Brice?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m recentering on my community-engagement, I&amp;rsquo;m also incredibly excited to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ll be taking on a new role. I have a hard time calling it a job considering I&amp;rsquo;d be working with a friend on the amazing product he created: ParaSwap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be helping with the topics pertaining to my expertise such as navigating the density of DeFi space, producing content and documentation, and interacting with the DeFi community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m immensely excited about this new opportunity - as &lt;strong&gt;token swaps are one of those topics that keep getting deeper the more you learn about it&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, ParaSwap is a product working magic behind the scenes, sometimes interacting with several smart contracts and routing trades through several tokens to optimize them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond the product itself, &lt;strong&gt;the story of ParaSwap is also worth telling&lt;/strong&gt;. After carrying out his project as a one-man-army for months, Mounir assembled an amazing team to take it to the next step. I&amp;rsquo;ve been following attentively since the first day so I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to get the chance to join and contribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my focus will be to &lt;strong&gt;shine a light on the complexity ParaSwap abstracts for dApp developers and end-users&lt;/strong&gt;. There are so many products and services in the space that it can get very hard to navigate. So I&amp;rsquo;ll be harnessing my expertise and network to identify win-win situations: projects which can harness ParaSwap&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure to improve the quality and operability of their service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you go for some tidbits of my crypto story! Since you&amp;rsquo;ve made it this far, allow to share one last thing - a simple illustration demonstrating some features that make ParaSwap more than a mere aggregator - it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; DeFi middleware:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/next-steps/paraswap-edge.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;What makes ParaSwap better than other aggregators like 1InchExchange?&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intrigued? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://learn2swap.com/l2s/understanding-paraswap/edge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Check this resource&lt;/a&gt; to better understand ParaSwap&amp;rsquo;s unique edge and how you can harness it to make DeFi work for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading it and I&amp;rsquo;ll see you in the Ether!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moloch is the Canaanite god of human coordination failure: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/p/ethereum-slayer-of-moloch-&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ethereum, Slayer of Moloch - Bankless&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
