<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Lending on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/lending/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Lending on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/lending/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Leverage Like a Sir: Polynomial Gains, No Liquidation Pains</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/leverage-sir/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/leverage-sir/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2025/leverage-sir/leverage-sir-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Leverage Like a Sir: Polynomial Gains, No Liquidation Pains" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Sir Trading, a fascinating novel DeFi primitive was shipped, and I quickly fell in love with it. I’ve also decided to get involved, so welcome to this article introducing Sir Trading, explaining what I found interesting in the model, and announcing my involvement as an advisor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sirtrading-explained-like-a-business&#34;&gt;Sir.Trading explained like a business
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand Sir Trading (and it works well with most protocols), we can use a business metaphor: Who are the customers, intermediaries, and stakeholders?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2025/leverage-sir/sir-diagram.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sir-diagram&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let’s start from the bottom up: our “customers” are the APEs who open leverage positions and pay fees. Everything else is a &amp;ldquo;means&amp;rdquo; to that end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second population is the “intermediaries”, the liquidity providers on the Sir Protocol, called TEA holders, also called “gentlemen”. They are necessary because the more TEA liquidity exists, the greater APE’s capacity to lever up, and thus, the more likely users are to ape at scale. Maximizing this population is essential, as it helps to address one of the main weaknesses of the Sir model: the &lt;strong&gt;absence of leverage decay can only be guaranteed if the liquidity provided is sufficient compared to the leveraged position opened.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, it makes sense to incentivize liquidity providers with SIR emissions to attract liquidity proportional to APE demand. Additionally, continuous SIR rewards provide LPers with stable income, complementing the volatile minting/closing fees they also earn—a critical advantage, as LPers usually prioritize predictability (cf. Aerodrome vs. Uniswap).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the SIR holders act as stakeholders. They can stake their tokens to receive ETH dividends from fees collected on positions opening and closing and, in the future, could be involved in a mini-governance centered around decisions about resource allocation (⇒ which vaults to incentivize with SIR emissions?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our three core populations defined, we can essentially assemble them into the “business model” of Sir:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2025/leverage-sir/sir-business-model.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sir-business-model&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SIR Protocol aims to maximize its customer base (APE holders), which drives revenue shared with stakeholders (SIR holders). Stakeholders approve SIR emissions to fund intermediaries (TEA LPers) that provide the liquidity necessary to the purpose and allocate it to the vaults most relevant to drive usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zooming-in-on-the-apes-side&#34;&gt;Zooming in on the APE’s side
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, the protocol&amp;rsquo;s core is the APE—the ability to leverage any asset traded on UniswapV3. But what makes this leverage so interesting, especially compared to the myriad of other options now available?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The table below should answer the most important questions for anyone already familiar with other protocols offering leverage, such as f(x) or Squeeth:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Type of Returns
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;polynomial (=/ multiplicative)
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Max leverage
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Up to ^5 with no leverage decay given sufficient liquidity, realistically ~ ^2
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Liquidation
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;None
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Rebalancing
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;None
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Fees
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;No funding fees, only set fees paid when opening or closing position
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Assets Supported
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Potentially any traded on UNIv3 + permissionless vault deployment
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Security Considerations
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Protocol to be eventually fully immutable once out of Beta Mode, oracle used is trustless (UNIv3)
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see above, I think the offer is quite compelling even when compared to existing options, although it is a bit “weird” if you are used to other more classical leverage products as you have to wrap your head around a few new concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;polynomial-returns&#34;&gt;Polynomial returns?!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, let’s tackle &lt;strong&gt;the question of linear (most common) vs polynomial leverage (Sir’s case)&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are not a math buff, I think the first thing to understand about polynomials is that their impact is increasingly more palpable as the price moves farther from the starting price. It is better to be careful, as it works both ways. Let’s illustrate with a hypothetical simplified position started when ETH = $2000 (fees are ignored for simplicity; we’ll come back to them later):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;$2500 (+25%)
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;$3000 (+50%)
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4000 (+100%)
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;10000 (+400%)
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Linear - ETH x2
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;3 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;6 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;18 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Polynomial - ETH ^2
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;3 125
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4 500
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;8 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;50 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Linear - ETH x5
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;4 500
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;7 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;12 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;42 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Polynomial - ETH ^5
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;6 103.52
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;15 187.5
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;64 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;6 250 000
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see that last row/column scenario, with our ETH^5 ape reaching a &amp;gt;$6M Valhalla on a mere 1 ETH base position (with a +400% price appreciation)? That’s the power of polynomial returns. What we looked at above is enticing, although it abstracts many factors, including the fees, and assumes no leverage decay for both positions. Picture it as an example of understanding the power of polynomial vs linear in a financial context more than anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Polynomial returns (convex payouts) have historically been overpromised and underdelivered. Delivering them consistently is usually challenging, but they are generally implemented with &lt;strong&gt;corrective factors&lt;/strong&gt; of different natures and names: time decay, volatility decay, leverage decay, etc. The usual model for such a product revolves around &lt;strong&gt;managing loans between traders and lenders&lt;/strong&gt; to keep the leverage as constant as possible. This leads to models where leveragers constantly stream varying fees to lenders and still see their positions often rebalanced. With Sir, this correcting factor is clear and explicit upfront – that is that steep fee, so let’s dive right into it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fee-structure&#34;&gt;Fee Structure
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next is the fee model, which is also quite different from the usual. Sir fees are fixed, dependant on your leverage, and charged ½ at position opening (APE minting) and ½ at position closing (APE redemption). At first glance, they might seem quite steep:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Leverage
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;Total Fees
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;^1.5
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;17.35% of principal
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;^5
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;69.13% of principal
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s zoom in on an ETH/USDC^1.5 position to understand better the impact of the polynomial leverage and the Sir’s fees, with a hypothetical position opened at ETH = $2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2025/leverage-sir/sir-calculator.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sir-calculator&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ETH = $4000 (+100%), such position is up ~17% in ETH terms or ~134% in USD terms. Of course, by this point, you are a polynomial leverage expert, and thus you understand that &lt;strong&gt;the gap between the ETH/USDC^1.5 and raw ETH holding increases the further the price appreciates&lt;/strong&gt;. At ETH = $6000 (+200%), the position is now up ~43% vs ETH or ~330% vs USD. At ETH = $8000, we are now at ~65% gains vs ETH and ~562% vs USD. Again, this works the same way in reverse; please remember.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this explicits well the “goal of the game” with Sir:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally, you want to seize a nice dip + reversal to open your position on a favorable price and quickly earn enough returns to cover the fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your goal is then to seize the maximal spread between your opening and closing price, knowing that each % you can grab provides exponentially more returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The product&amp;rsquo;s design is well-suited for such plays since you do not have to worry about funding fees or time decay. You’re essentially looking to buy low and sell high; welcome to crypto: except this time, you have a tool amplifying your returns the more you manage to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of its fee structure, &lt;strong&gt;Sir is geared toward leveragers with a long-term perspective&lt;/strong&gt;, which matches its other key features (no liquidation, no leverage decay). Overall, the fees paid are similar to those that would be incurred maintaining a margin position for a year, striking a balance between potential returns, protocol stability, and upfront costs. When opening a leveraged position, one of the main concerns is getting the timing wrong and chopped by range-bound price action, where the fees accumulate and take away any potential profits; this concern is non-existent in Sir’s model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I’d like to remind you one more time of the main limitation of Sir: the absence of liquidity decay can only be ensured if there is sufficient liquidity to stomach your trade. While it’s pretty &lt;strong&gt;reasonable to assume so for incentivized ^1.25, ^1.5, or even ^2 vaults&lt;/strong&gt;, it becomes much less certain for ^5 vaults, even with strong incentives, because of the maths I shared above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’d like more data to understand the impact of polynomial leverage in the context of Sir (=fees included), check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.sir.trading/leverage-calculator&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the new calculator on the Sir website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: APE tokens are ERC-20; thus, further composability could be envisioned. It could get interesting as the protocol grows!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-about-the-tea-drinkers&#34;&gt;What about the TEA drinkers?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a decent understanding of the demand side, the APE/leveragers, let’s jump to the other side, the liquidity providers/TEA holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the basics: TEA drinkers are essentially ~counter-trading APEs, as they provide the liquidity APE redeem against if they manage to earn and secure (redeem) sizable gains. When I say “counter-trading” here, I mean it similarly as a UNIv2_ETH/USDC LP is counter-trading the market: when the market is mostly buying ETH (⇒ price goes up), the liquidity providing positions are rebalancing to USDC, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, even more simply, &lt;strong&gt;TEA holders are shorter against the underlying asset than if they were just holding it&lt;/strong&gt;. Understanding this is all you need to be able to project the impact of price variants on your principal. You also have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the liquidity utilization,&lt;/strong&gt; as if you are supplying to a vault where there is little/no aping, you are counter-trading little to no one, and your principal exposure becomes similar to a naked raw holding of the underlying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While TEA holders are “shorter” compared to a naked raw holding of the underlying asset, they remain exposed to its price appreciation.  You can &lt;strong&gt;think of TEA holders as ETH/USD^0-1&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, with the principal cleared out, let’s address the earnings as a TEA holder. It’s pretty straightforward: by default, &lt;strong&gt;TEA holders of a given vault collectively earn all the fees incurred by the APE minters&lt;/strong&gt;. Fees are earned in such (same token as the supplied token) and autocompounded. TEA holders can redeem them when burning their position to recover their principal + all the fees accrued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the fees earned based on aping activity, &lt;strong&gt;some vaults are also incentivized with&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;streams of SIR emissions.&lt;/strong&gt; These currently include the most utilized: ETH/USDC1.5, wBTC/USDT1.5, SIR/ETH1.5, and SIR/ETH5. When vaults are incentivized with SIR emissions, ~10% of the fees incurred by the APE are redirected to SIR stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: TEA tokens are ERC-1155, limiting further composability, which is a good thing here, as you want to avoid restaking-type situations on those tokens, which are critical to the protocol&amp;rsquo;s proper functioning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;noteworthy-features&#34;&gt;Noteworthy features
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the above, you should already have a decent understanding of the protocol, so rather than boring you with expansive explanations of each subtleties, I’ll instead zoom in on a few features of Sir I found worthy of commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trustlessness-maximization&#34;&gt;Trustlessness maximization
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;My blog readers will not be surprised to find a section addressing this, as maximal decentralization and trustlessness are my mantras. In that regard, Sir Trading fares quite well, and the design demonstrates the priority given to those two topics by its founders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the most important – the potential immutability of the protocol. Considering its novel approach and the risks associated with it, making the protocol immediately fully immutable could be inconsequential. Instead, the approach developed here is a progressive path to eventual immutability with four modes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2025/leverage-sir/sir-beta-mode.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;sir-beta-mode&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sir is currently in Training Wheels mode, in which some parameters, such as the fees can still be adjusted. From the Training Wheels mode, it can switch to Emergency in response to a bug or exploit and from here to a Shutdown (⇒ Redeploy) if needed. On the other hand, if all goes well, the training wheels can be removed, and the protocol can be switched to Unstoppable mode, where it becomes immutable. I find this approach balanced and interesting, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.sir.trading/protocol-overview/beta-period&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;definitely worthy of studying&lt;/a&gt; for other builders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s look at the oracle solution chosen, a critical element for any lending or leverage-based protocol. Here, &lt;strong&gt;the solution is simple and fully trustless: Uniswap v3.&lt;/strong&gt; It, of course, has limits, most notably the liquidity available on Uniswap to ensure the price is not easily manipulated. However, considering the top vaults are majors like ETH or wBTC, it’s not a big concern. It could be more of an issue for SIR-related vaults, but here again, the liquidity is reasonably sufficient compared to the token market cap (TVL in pools &amp;gt; 35% FDV). Further mitigation is implemented on the UNIv3 oracle (30 min TWAP) to resist price manipulation better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting feature in terms of trustlessness and resilience is the &lt;strong&gt;harnessing of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.sir.trading/protocol-overview/token-auctions&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;token auctions&lt;/a&gt; to streamline fee distribution to stakers&lt;/strong&gt;. Sir is far from the only one doing this, as, for instance, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.euler.finance/developers/periphery/fee-flow/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Euler Finance harnesses a similar logic&lt;/a&gt;. Such auctions enable the conversion of many assets into one (in this case, wETH) without adding unnecessary compromises to the protocol. I expect to see even more of these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Xatarrer (founder) has self-submitted a DeFiScan review for Sir Trading, which is currently under review. Please check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiscan.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiScan&lt;/a&gt; once the review is published for more details regarding Sir&amp;rsquo;s decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;protocol-owned-liquidity&#34;&gt;Protocol Owned Liquidity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquidity is Sir&amp;rsquo;s lifeblood, and the protocol design acknowledges this with &lt;strong&gt;a keen focus on growing permanent liquidity (TEA) reserves&lt;/strong&gt;. Every liquidity provider deposit includes a fee (~8.99% of their principal) retained as permanent protocol-owned liquidity. Thus, incentivizing LPers with SIR isn’t just &amp;ldquo;renting&amp;rdquo; liquidity—it’s also an immediate partial &amp;ldquo;buyout&amp;rdquo; of their deposit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this, as the protocol grows and can attract more liquidity providers, it builds permanent liquidity reserves, enabling an ever-increasing “minimal guaranteed liquidity for APEs”. It’s essentially a virtuous loop progressively solving one of the main drawbacks of the model: elegant!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;continuous-token-emission-model&#34;&gt;Continuous Token Emission Model
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;SIR works under a &lt;strong&gt;constant emission model at the rate of 2015M SIR per year&lt;/strong&gt;, with the lion’s share always going to incentivize liquidity providers. There is, however, a switch in the distribution logic, made to give the protocol the means for its early growth in the first three years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the first 3 years, 68.13 % directed to liquidity providers, 13.65 % to pre-mainnet contributors, 10 % reserved in a treasury, and 8.22 % to investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After that: 100% to liquidity providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model is efficient, as no vesting is needed for the team/investors/treasury, since the logic is wholly shifted here: you have to think in terms of streams of tokens (X SIR/day) instead of total balance and associated vesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;putting-your-understanding-in-practice&#34;&gt;Putting your understanding in practice
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To wrap things up, we can now articulate our shared understanding of the protocol by studying three different market hypotheses articulated into strategies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-bullish-eth-or-btc-over-a-midlong-time-frame&#34;&gt;“I am bullish ETH or BTC over a mid/long time frame”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This one is the most straightforward; it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as minting the ETH/USDC^1.5 APE token. The absence of liquidation and funding fees will allow you to set this position and forget about it. &lt;strong&gt;Your primary metric to watch for here is the opening+closing fee at 17.35%: you need to seize a ~26% price appreciation on ETH to enter profit territory&lt;/strong&gt;, with your gains increasing in a polynomial fashion from thereon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Variants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am bullish BTC: all the same, except using the wBTC/USDT^1.5 APE (main vault: good amount of liquidity available).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am bullish ETH against BTC and looking for adrenaline: all the same, except using the wETH/wBTC^5 vault (careful, low liquidity right now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am bullish SIR against ETH: you have several tiers of leverage available to express that conviction onchain (SIR/ETH^1.5 and SIR/ETH^5 being the most liquid).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-bearing-eth-over-a-midlong-time-frame&#34;&gt;“I am bearing ETH over a mid/long time frame”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Really?! No judgment; there is also a vault for that, in the name of USDC/wETH^1.5! Because this vault is USDC based, against ETH, opening an APE position there means going short ETH with polynomial leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inversely, supplying that vault as a liquidity provider (TEA) means counter-trading the (potential) shorters ⇒ being long ETH (if there is utilization), but from a USDC base this time. However, this vault is not incentivized with SIR emissions currently, so your earnings will stem only from APEs opening positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-am-bullish-sir-but-not-really-a-leverage-hungry-ape&#34;&gt;“I am bullish SIR, but not really a leverage-hungry APE”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s understandable; not everyone is a thrill-maxxer. Here, you could consider &lt;strong&gt;harnessing the constant emissions to liquidity providers to build your SIR stash over time and only at capital opportunity cost&lt;/strong&gt;. Considering the LP supply fee, you are “forced” to sustain the position for a few weeks/months to reduce the fee&amp;rsquo;s impact. If you are worried about principal depreciation in the case of a significant market reversal upward, you could consider splitting your deposits over several incentivized vaults to hedge for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming you initially farm with an ETH or wBTC deposit, you have a compounding option with your freshly farmed SIR: supplying the SIR vaults. Also, consider staking your SIR to maximize a mid/long-term SIR position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;discussing-my-involvement&#34;&gt;Discussing My Involvement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before you, I’d like to give you more context on my involvement with Sir: I am advising the Sir team to help them with my core topics: growth, tokenomics optimization, and BD. I am compensated for this endeavour, and I am also an APE and TEA holder and, therefore, a SIR farmer – &lt;strong&gt;I am long SIR in all possible ways&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I discovered Sir somewhat recently (the protocol is still just a few weeks old), but the timing was excellent. As those following me on Twitter probably already know, I have been profoundly disappointed with f(x), where I suffered from an abusive liquidation stemming from infrastructure shortcomings on their end (RPCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was, since then, on the hunt for an alternative solution to f(x) and stumbled upon Sir, which delivers some similar features (“real” no liquidation, no funding fees) but also brings welcome additions to the mix, such as the polynomial leverage vs linear: both the protocol and the timing were perfect, so going the extra mile to help it succeed happened very spontaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do not approach advisory as a collectible to add to my wallet, show in 2 monthly calls, collect the payout, and call it a day. I am on the opposite side, equally maximally committed, involved, and selective with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Sir, considering the recency of the protocol, my current contributions revolve around raising awareness for the protocol, helping it get well integrated into the ecosystem, and expliciting its benefits to as many people as possible, as done with this article. I harness my extensive DeFi experience, network, and presence to support the team in all relevant ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-valhalla-or-hell-nothing-in-between-position&#34;&gt;My “Valhalla or hell, nothing in-between” position
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/tx/0x5f9038d9004b53501bdf05b3f30d8fc8fd2d8da6a89299a624276c7605bf4ea7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;I opened a ^5 SIR position on my public wallet tokenbrice.eth&lt;/a&gt; – feel free to track it: 500K SIR levered ^5 ⇒ redeemable for ~155K SIR at inception (~69% fees), opened on Mar-04-2025 08:34:47 PM UTC. If all goes well, I hope to eventually redeem this for ~8M SIR (⇒ SIR at 2x my starting price, assuming sufficient liquidity) and do something fun with it. &lt;strong&gt;I want to remind you that such leverage is the closest you can get to onchain insanity; this position is now known in the community as “Valhalla or hell, no in-between”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: As a protocol built for resilience, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://x.com/DeFiCollective_/status/1897575989032497390&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sir is also supported by the DeFi Collective&lt;/a&gt;, which received a SIR donation, matched it with ETH, initiated and supplied the UNIv2 LP, and locked the LP token for one year to secure a liquidity baseline on the token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: This article and the above strategy are not investment advice but practical illustrations of what the protocol can do. You make your own decisions, and you are responsible for them. In case that wasn’t clear enough with the previous warnings: I am exposed to SIR as a token and protocol and stand to benefit from its growth; in other words, I am maximally aligned.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/jr-strategist/jr-strategist-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a Junior DeFi Strategist to join me on my daily DeFi adventures, learn and grow. The fundamental missions are governance proposals, liquidity management, business development, and partnerships, but the scope is quite flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique opportunity for a passionate DeFi curious to jumpstart his/her career in crypto. Be the first hire for a community-led effort to cater governance-minimized and immutable protocols to achieve the mission of DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be working closely with me and learn my tactics to successfully grow liquidity and utility for immutable DeFi projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-activities&#34;&gt;Your activities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek and find new partnership opportunities for DeFi projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with other DeFi protocols and DAOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write governance proposals, and support proposals submitted by third parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage strategies enforced on the various liquidity-driver tokens owned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize Protocol Owned Liquidity strategies across main net and L2s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and tweet about partnerships and liquidity opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-experience-and-skills&#34;&gt;Your experience and skills
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive DeFi on chain track record - who cares about diplomas? Show me a wallet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively involved in DeFi, owning some key governance tokens, knowledgeable about the main models (Liquity, Curve, Aave, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of DEXs like Curve, Uniswap, Balancer and voting protocols I.e.  Convex, Aura as well as ve(3,3) models like e.g. Velodrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well versed in the differences of cvxCRV, yCRV, sdCRV, uCRV, and aCRV
Solid understanding of the top DeFi protocols and good overview of the promising newcomers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re already active on various governance forums or DeFi-related Discords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written and spoken English proficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work independently as well as team up with your peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-can-offer&#34;&gt;What I can offer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exciting part time position (~50%) with a monthly retainer in FIAT (for the beginning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive a community-led initiative (more to be announced soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be part of a top notch and proven DeFi team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work remotely (ideally in Europe or US timezone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forms.gle/6qaXgkczuhiaqNTV6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Please apply via this form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back in touch shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Announcement: Joining Liquity to bolster the growth of unstoppable DeFi</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/joining-liquity/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/joining-liquity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/tokenbrice-liquity/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Announcement: Joining Liquity to bolster the growth of unstoppable DeFi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little less involved in the DeFi discussion lately  and you might righfully wonder why. First, I needed to slow down and take some time for myself, and the timing could not be better. While I was off, I had the time to reflect on what drew me to DeFi in the first place and how the space has evolved since I started getting involved about four years ago. Watching protocols with massive design flaws blowing up is reassuring, especially to those who anticipated it, but not exactly what I dreamed of when I discovered DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;has-defi-lost-its-way&#34;&gt;Has DeFi lost its way?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems like we&amp;rsquo;ve lost our ways. TradFi turned into the non-sensical monster we know not on purpose nor by design: it was simply the result of every person and entity trying to pull the blanket to themselves: &lt;strong&gt;an accumulation of individual&amp;rsquo;s greed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developments during this last year in DeFi felt very similar to TradFi&amp;rsquo;s avarice: in terms of building a resilient and self-sovereign financial system for all, close to nothing was achieved. Instead, most of the releases were focused on delivering yet another flavor of ponzinomics to sustain the greed of apes for a few weeks until they move to the next shiny farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remain convinced that what &lt;strong&gt;we need in the end-game are systems able to resist the (potentially coordinated) attacks of states, organized crime, and whales&lt;/strong&gt;. Most of the current protocols available in DeFi would not stand a day against structured attacks of significant magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large share of &amp;ldquo;DeFi&amp;rdquo; protocols are vulnerable to the good old wrench attack because of their reliance on multisigs: identifying, locating and threatening a dozen individuals is not an arduous task, especially when billions are at stake. Economic attacks can also seriously affect another significant share of DeFi protocols, especially if perpetrated by an actor willing to burn money in the process. Finally, governance attacks are so commonplace it&amp;rsquo;s not even exciting to cover them anymore. It is not the DeFi I signed up for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built a platform and shed light on the projects that brought something new and relevant to the table during the last few years. Complimentary to my analysis and commentaries, I&amp;rsquo;ve supported several projects, shared my insights with creative and sensible teams, and sometimes been involved in the governance processes. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt ready to assume a more active role within the ecosystem: today is the day! I&amp;rsquo;m confident my honest, sometimes brutal, yet always informed approach was and still is something lacking in the industry where shills are king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;announcing-tokenbrice-x-liquity&#34;&gt;Announcing: TokenBrice x Liquity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; as Head of Marketing to support the growth of protocol, mainly focusing on a yet-to-be-announced project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Liquity protocol is just over a year old, the team has already been active and building for much longer. What has been achieved is truly unique, remarkable, and needed. Liquity is the &lt;strong&gt;first and still only lending service available in DeFi that is  unstoppable&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; likewise, LUSD is the only stablecoin capable of resisting all kinds of censorships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What always amazed me is that this feat is delivered without compromising on the protocol&amp;rsquo;s efficiency: Liquity is extremely cost-efficient, and the protocol&amp;rsquo;s design is one of rare elegance. Liquity is &lt;strong&gt;built like mission-critical software&lt;/strong&gt;: failure is not an option. I&amp;rsquo;m glad such a protocol, truthful to the root spirit of DeFi, exists, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to get the chance to help it grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar yet with what Liquity does and why it matters, feel free this intro:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖️ Liquity: an unstoppable, efficient and innovative borrowing service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-will-i-do&#34;&gt;What will I do?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Liquity, I&amp;rsquo;ll spearhead the growth efforts through all relevant channels: documentation, content strategy, media, events, and more, without forgetting, of course, to fuel the memetic. While I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly focus on an upcoming and yet to be announced product, I&amp;rsquo;ll also support the existing one in all relevant ways. With my efforts to craft and grow Liquity&amp;rsquo;s narrative, the community&amp;rsquo;s support, I&amp;rsquo;m confident Liquity&amp;rsquo;s prime time is yet to come!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still entirely convinced that great things are built from the bottom-up: I&amp;rsquo;ll be in close touch with the Liquity&amp;rsquo;s community to incorporate its insights and feedback at every possible level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m excited by the mission, my latest time-off taught me a lot about work/life balance: therefore, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep my involvement with Liquity part-time. It lets me make sure I still have the time for a healthy personal life and hobbies, including DeFi, such as conducting my research and sharing them with you on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my live shows on Twitch, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to the weekly rhythm I used to have, but I&amp;rsquo;m not excluding some occasional shows to discuss relevant protocols and topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled for this next step of my journey and eager to share more with you regarding what is coming next for unstoppable DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤗 Thanks to all my readers and listeners for your support so far. I have several upcoming blog posts with unique insights to share with you in the coming months, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/y-among-us.gif" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn Finance has been making headlines lately with the announcement of &lt;strong&gt;several acquisitions&lt;/strong&gt; like Pickle Finance or SushiSwap. The Yearn team has joined its development forces with five other DeFi projects already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To grasp what&amp;rsquo;s happening, we&amp;rsquo;ll look back at the main events since September and how each of the different sub-projects is now working to achieve a shared goal. While Yearn is still relatively new, there are already many chapters to its story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to better understand the latest events - the merger spree, let&amp;rsquo;s first quickly consider the three phases of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development and how they led to today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beginnings of Yearn with the fair launch of the YFI token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How YFI&amp;rsquo;s launch became a template with the waifus (forks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of the Yearn Ecosystem: Yearn beyond the vaults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-backstory-launch-waifus--the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Backstory: Launch, waifus &amp;amp; the ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last June, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s token launch was a unique moment, initiating what is now called a &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Essentially, the &lt;strong&gt;YFI token was distributed over a week to users&lt;/strong&gt; depositing to several pools related to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s products. Feel free to check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my first story on Yearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more about this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It translated into a growing awareness for the project, a rapid price appreciation of the token, and attracted involved DeFi users to contribute to Yearn through the DAO&amp;rsquo;s discussions. The launch was so successful that it actually became a template replicated more or less successfully by many other projects: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-waifus.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s waifus (forks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, Yearn was focusing on its own products, the main ones being the vaults enabling streamlined implementations of farming strategies. The vaults too grew beyond Yearn to become a product offered by many DeFi services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direction was not exactly clear back then. Indeed, there were many products being worked on, such as yBorrow, ySwap, yinsure, or the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/43292/eminence-finance-exploit-leads-to-degen-soul-searching&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Eminence exploit&lt;/a&gt;. However, the core product, the vaults saw little improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last few months, the vision for Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development evolved. Instead of an inward-facing plan focused on the ecosystem, the Yearn team started to look outward. At the same moment, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s DAO was structuring its processes and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/yip-54-formalize-operations-funding/7956&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;formalized operations fundings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads to the current merger phase - joining development efforts with other DeFi projects on relevant areas of expertise. Token-wise, nothing is changed, each project keeps its own token and sovereignty over it. So let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-mergers&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Mergers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the context set, let&amp;rsquo;s now look at the different projects joining forces with Yearn and how they contribute to add value to the offering. We&amp;rsquo;ll consider them as they happened, in their chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Some of these mergers are still pending a token holder vote to be validated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A NFT was made to immortalize this moment of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s history: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:90731:0xac6d5c44c7a089101c53735211b12f5f722c7688&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yAmong us, by Cryptouf - available on Rarible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pickle-finance-1124&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance (11/24)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: PICKLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;symbiotic relationship&amp;rdquo; with Pickle Finance was the first to be introduced on November 24. The idea is to merge the efforts of the two projects currently offering similar products. Pickle will now deliver an &lt;strong&gt;incentive mechanism on top of the Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; through gauges, similar to Curve&amp;rsquo;s current model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By joining forces, it creates additional options for Yearn vaults depositors while securing the assets deposited in the Pickle jars, one of which was subject to a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cointelegraph.com/news/pickle-in-a-pickle-as-attacker-swipes-20-million-in-evil-jar-exploit&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;$20 million exploit &lt;/a&gt;shortly before the merge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cream-finance-1126&#34;&gt;Cream Finance (11/26)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: CREAM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Money Market - Lending &amp;amp; Borrowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger with Cream is even more exciting as it would expand the range of strategies Yearn vaults could use. Cream is a lending platform, a fork of Compound with several changes including the collateral accepted. yUSD (Yearn yCRV vault share) has been supported as collateral for a few months already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two teams teaming up mean a more systematic approach, eventually &lt;strong&gt;paving the way for leveraged vaults&lt;/strong&gt;: the vault token share being used as collateral on Cream to borrow more stablecoin and increase exposure. Cream would eventually become the lending arm of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cream-v2-merger-e9fa6c6989b4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More info in the announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cover-protocol-1128&#34;&gt;Cover Protocol (11/28)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: COVER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Peer to peer coverage market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn has been trying to provide coverage and insurance for its products, with projects like yInsure. So working with another project on this front is highly synergistic, since it could enable &lt;strong&gt;coverage for Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; while allowing the team to focus on its core offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cover-merger-651142828c45&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the announcement here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;akropolis-1130&#34;&gt;Akropolis (11/30)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: AKRO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won&amp;rsquo;t expand too much into this one, as it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Pickle. Akropolis was providing services similar to the vaults, so &lt;strong&gt;joining forces allow increasing TVL&lt;/strong&gt; by creating another frontend for Yearn/Pickle while beefing up the security of Akropolis, as it too suffered &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://news.bitcoin.com/hackers-drain-2-million-in-dai-from-defi-protocol-akropolis/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exploit for $2M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sushiswap-1201&#34;&gt;SushiSwap (12/01)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: SUSHI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Decentralized Exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sushi is now &lt;strong&gt;the second DEX by volume&lt;/strong&gt; with roughly half ($889M) of the total value locked of Uniswap. To attract liquidity to the platform, Sushi distributes its token to the providers of liquidity on certain key pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could allow Yearn to &lt;strong&gt;incentivize liquidity providing for critical pairs of the Yearn ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, such as a CRV &amp;lt;&amp;gt; yyveCRV to drive deposit into this vault which can provide additional returns for other Yearn deposits on Curve. The team joins efforts so that Sushi/0xMaki can lead the AMM efforts amongst the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-it-mean-for-yearn&#34;&gt;What does it mean for Yearn?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this merger spree is a &lt;strong&gt;massive increase in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s firepower&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s also a &lt;strong&gt;form of recentering&lt;/strong&gt;: some key parts of the ecosystem are delegated, such as the AMM (swaps) to Sushiswap&amp;rsquo;s team, or the lending markets to Cream. It should enable the team to move faster on its core products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are now so many mergers announced that CoinGecko created a category to track them: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.coingecko.com/en?category_id=yearn-yfi-partnerships-mergers&amp;amp;view=market&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🦎YFI Partnerships &amp;amp; Mergers Coins by Market Capitalization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, composability is key and Yearn is yet another demonstration of what it can achieve. Indeed, there is one last dimension to stress with these mergers: liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/yearn-merger-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn-Merger-TVL-Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these 5 acquisitions, Yearn will roughly triple its total value of assets locked across its ecosystem. Along with the synergies, it could help Yearn develop a moat that will be hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day a new Yearn fork is popping up: how to keep track with them? There is no simple answer to this dilemma, however, I believe I can &lt;strong&gt;provide you with some clues to help you spot YFI fork with high potential.&lt;/strong&gt; To do so, I’ll cover three (+1) YFI forks and try to pinpoint the changes to the secret sauce that made them stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is more than Yearn.Finance product itself: it became a template to kickstart a project, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Yearn pioneered the method which stands on three key elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining Fair Launch&lt;/strong&gt;: the initial distribution of the token of the platform (ex: YFI) happens through liquidity mining. Supporters can stake tokens like yCRV to earn the governance token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt;: the decisions regarding the development of the project are taken by the community of token holders, through informal and formal (on-chain) votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pooled Investment Strategies (Vaults)&lt;/strong&gt;: the Yearn-inspired projects usually also try to replicate this core feature of Yearn: they offer tokenised investment strategies. The vaults are essential for the long-term success of the project past the initial liquidity mining phase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Vault&amp;rdquo; is used to cover two vastly different reality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Basic Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where tokens are collected and stake to produce a yield. The yield produced is frequently settled for stablecoins (no leverage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Delegated Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where once tokens are deposited, they are used as collateral (thanks to credit delegation) to borrow stablecoins then used to produce a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegated Vaults are much more complex to develop and implement, while basic vaults can be sprung quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfi-wifey-wai-fu&#34;&gt;YFI? Wifey? Wai-fu?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Yearn, people were unclear on how to pronounce &amp;ldquo;YFI&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/make-yfi-pronounced-waifu/552&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A discussion on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; settled for &amp;ldquo;Wai-fu&amp;rdquo; (/waɪfu/). From this point onward, there was only one wai-fu but plenty of wifeys: the YFI forks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, despite being barely a few months old, &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has already been forked, a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. There is now a whole family of wifeys built upon similar premises, each project adjusting different parameters to attempt to better fit their envisioned use case. Many of these forks were unnecessary, however, &lt;strong&gt;several managed to bring something new and exciting to the table&lt;/strong&gt; —  the ones we will consider today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This content assumes an understanding of Yearn, to brush up on the topic I&amp;rsquo;d recommend &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;my previous article on Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dfimoney-yfiihttpdfimoney&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money (YFII)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest discussion in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s community was around the &lt;strong&gt;emission schedule&lt;/strong&gt;: while it was initially planned for a week, there were discussions about extending it - most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yips.yearn.finance/YIPS/yip-8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YIP 8&lt;/a&gt; which proposed a longer emission schedule halving weekly. &lt;strong&gt;Despite support from the Yearn Community, the proposal did not meet the quorum and was not implemented&lt;/strong&gt;, which lead to the YFII fork** - a fork of YFI implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;instead of having a week-only distribution, YFII opted for a longer schedule, still ongoing.&lt;/strong&gt; It started July 27 and will end on October 5. The farming pools proposed are very similar to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s: staking the yCRV token or staking the Balancer pool token (98%DAI / 2 % YFII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of this base differentiation, YFII develops an interesting angle with a &lt;strong&gt;strong presence in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: the DFI.Money website was quickly translated into Chinese and soon other languages. There is also a strong &lt;strong&gt;focus on UX&lt;/strong&gt; to make the experience as easy as possible to onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/dfi-money.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Overview of the DFI.Money Vaults&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stats.dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can view the stats here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 14, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DfiMoney/status/1305339433638531072?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money launched the v2 of their vaults&lt;/a&gt;, supporting ETH, USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD, HBTC, &amp;amp; yCRV. As this piece was written, there was a total of $70M deposited into DFI&amp;rsquo;s vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is not an exhaustive overview of YFI forks. There were other forks of Yearn with minimal changes that are not covered, such as YFFI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yflink-yflhttpyflinkio&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yflink.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink (YFL)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFL is another one of the early forks of YFI. Here, the twist is simple:** LINK was used as the base token of the system** - the one to deposit for the initial liquidity mining phase. The farming pools structure was similar to YFI/YFII, but with LINK/aLINK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial vision was to create a farming collaborative for LINK holders. YFL was developed by 5 anonymous teams working together and initially released on August 7 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/Linkswap.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFL LinkSwap&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth was quick and the plan soon refined! YFLink is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@linkswapco/yf-link-ecosystem-linkswap-development-update-44f8413721c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;now working on LINKSwap&lt;/a&gt;, a community-governed Automated Market Maker (AMM), focusing on safety and value capture for LINK holders. LINKSwap explores novel ideas to increase investors&amp;rsquo; safety - for instance, the RugLock feature, designed to avoid rug pulls - when the token’s creators drain the liquidity pools, leaving holders with a sizeable bag of worthless coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfvalue-yfvhttpyfvfinance&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFValue (YFV)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue adds several more twists, with a similar goal of providing a service facilitating yieldfarming and making it more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the farming pools were mostly 98% ERC20-token / 2% YFV Balancer pools and the emission schedule is much longer (5 to 20 weeks) - it&amp;rsquo;s still ongoing while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/yfv-bringing-true-value-to-yield-farming-bddc4edf889a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFV launched mid-August.&lt;/a&gt; There is also a &amp;ldquo;seed pool&amp;rdquo; accepting stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV was one of the first project to provide credible earning opportunities on tokens such as BAL, YFI, BAT, REN, KNC, BTC, WETH, or LINK: it really helped to attract liquidity — there are around $470 M deposited on YFV as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/yfv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFV Staking Interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV&amp;rsquo;s core product, the Governance Vault was just &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/roadmap-update-value-contract-governance-vault-e226ad2f909e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;launched on September 15&lt;/a&gt;. YFV Holders can stake their token for several benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting power in the governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A return paid in vUSD and vETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV token from the emission schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from the strategy implemented with the Governance vaults funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from buying back YFV with 6.8% of the profits made with the vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV is a highly ambitious project. The vaults (wETH, wBTC, renBTC) are expected shortly. On top of the existing farms and governance structure, the team is working on transitioning to an AMM/farming collaborative called Value Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue is in the process of transitioning to VALUE (token) and Value Liquid (name of the exchange/service). You’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/faq-yfv-and-value-migration-af3a5a5c2190&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more information on this rebranding and transition here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfinspired---harvestfinance-farmhttpsharvestfinance&#34;&gt;YFInspired - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance (FARM)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Harvest.Finance is technically not a fork of Yearn, one could say it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;fork in spirit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, Harvest ambitions to streamline yieldfarming to make it more accessible &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s quite a success: Harvest is now home to more than $200 M (+200 M) of diverse assets farming with no stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience on Harvest is quite straightforward, just like with the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault. &lt;strong&gt;Users deposit tokens into the strategy of their choice to put them to work&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, they deposit their DAI to get fDAI, DAI currently farming on Swerve.fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/harvest-finance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once they own fDAI (or other fTokens), users can stake them to earn FARM - the native token of the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; They can also provide liquidity to the fDAI/DAI pair on Uniswap which facilitates the entry and exit of smaller capitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvest.Finance launched on September 15 a new vault accepting for wETH. The community is highly active and committed, and it shows in the reactivity of the team: to better the yield, the stablecoin farms (DAI, USDC, USDT) switched from the Curve strategy to Swerve barely 16 hours after &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://swerve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Swerve&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yfi-fork-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;The YFI-Fork Secret Sauce?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope these quick introductions will help to better understand the recipe for a successful YFI fork. Considering the sample size (3+1), it’s hard to draw some conclusions but allow me to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I see a YFI-Fork scoring some resilience points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;focuses on a clearly identified community&lt;/strong&gt; (ex: LINK holders for YFLINK).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol parameters (pools, tokens, etc.) are adjusted to match the target community wants and needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A one-week emission schedule was a luxury only affordable by the first Waifu,&lt;/strong&gt; mother of all others (YFI). Successful YFI-forks tend to need a longer schedule (5-20 weeks) to gather and structure their community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A farm by itself is not enough, there is a real need for &lt;strong&gt;a convincing vision for the project in the long-run&lt;/strong&gt;, such as an AMM (YFL/YFV), or going above and beyond on the farming front (Harvest), and more than anything a driven and dedicated community to support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Thanks to Ashitaka#4868 from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RheJ78p&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance Discord&lt;/a&gt; for the amazing cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-disclaimer&#34;&gt;NECESSARY DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;NOT investment advice&lt;/strong&gt; or a recommendation to purchase any of the token mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not a financial advisor. I have no formal financial advising training, certification, nor experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a DeFi native sharing my insights, do with it as you may, but please think twice and avoid impulsive decisions at all cost: they are usually the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚜 Merry Farming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/wifeys.jpg" alt="Featured image of post YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Yearn v2 release and the launch of the YFI token (pronounced &amp;ldquo;Waifu&amp;rdquo;) shook decentralised finance. Indeed, the whole recipe was there: Yearn is like a robo advisor, it helps you save and grow a capital - obviously one of the most thought after use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the product itself, core to defining what Yearn became was its founder Andre Cronje, &lt;strong&gt;his choice of fully opening the governance&lt;/strong&gt;, and the amazing community that soon federated around the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this piece today, I want to share some pointers to understand why Yearn came to be, how it works, and why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-yearn&#34;&gt;What is Yearn?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first version of Yearn started with a simple promise: it &lt;strong&gt;helped you get the best lending rate available at any time on a given stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed as there were more and more options to lend stablecoins (Compound, Aave, dYdX, etc.), yield optimization quickly became essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn v2 already brought a new product to the market, the yVaults: they go beyond yield optimization (rebalancing stablecoins between several lending platforms) to provide more returns. Let’s see how this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-user-perspective-deposit-wait-money-go-up&#34;&gt;End-User Perspective: Deposit, Wait, Money go Up
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we go in the specifics, here it&amp;rsquo;s how it works for an end-user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You own a token supported in the yVaults, such as LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can deposit your LINK in the yVault to start earning. Entry and exit to the vaults are gas optimised (usually ~$2-3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re done, you exit the pool. 0.5% of the &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; value is taken by the system to cover all the fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given &lt;strong&gt;enough time spent in the vault to make up for the exit cost&lt;/strong&gt;, investors walk out with a profit paid in the token they entered (ex: more LINK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: yVaults are still highly experimental. Make sure you know what you are getting into. Andre has quite an interesting approach, stated in his twitter bio &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1291252150635560960?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;I test in prod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-happening-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;yVaults are amazing because &lt;strong&gt;they abstract an immense amount of complexity for the users,&lt;/strong&gt; and do it better than most of us. Going back to our yLINK vault, here&amp;rsquo;s what happens to provide the yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINK are deposited on Aave (Credit Delegation) and used as collateral to open positions. The positions are maintained within a safe range using an safety mechanism (funded on the returns).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stablecoins are borrowed and put to work to provide a return. The latest strategy farms the mUSD/USDC MTA Balancer Pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any actual returns of the farming portion of the position (stablecoins earned above the debt) are sold for LINK, increasing the effective returns of the whole position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist of yVaults is that &lt;strong&gt;they harness DeFi synergies to provide yields on autopilot.&lt;/strong&gt; They are designed to be flexible with their capital allocation - so that it can easily be re-allocated to follow a different strategy with better yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each vault has a different strategy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a neat explainer graphics made to explain the yCRV vault strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yCRV-vault.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance yCRV vault strategy explained&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining this one would be another article by itself, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let you dig the graph and join the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/HFK5uea&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Discord&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yearn-is-unlike-anything-else-before&#34;&gt;Why Yearn is unlike anything else before
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is DeFi on steroids, and made possible by developments that occurred over the last year. Yearn is harnessing synergies between several &amp;ldquo;DeFi legos&amp;rdquo;. Without going too deep in, here are the key ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aave recently launched the Credit Delegation feature&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling a contract to open a position on your behalf. This feature was necessary for the yVaults to function as they do now, as they enable the first part of most strategies - getting leverage.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEX &amp;amp; Automated Market Makers - especially &lt;strong&gt;Curve.fi&lt;/strong&gt;, an obvious dependency for the yCRV Vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall &lt;strong&gt;dynamism of the stablecoins markets&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to new entrants such as mStable or the COMP token release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is the perfect example of DeFi composability!&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-as-little-as-possible--assembling-legos&#34;&gt;Building as little as possible &amp;amp; assembling legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why am I focusing on this? Because as someone working in the DeFi space for two years, I can tell you that the biggest operational mistake I see ALL THE TIME - is simple: &lt;strong&gt;teams re-building the wheel - reinventing what already exists and working&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think DeFi projects (like most startups) would gain immensely from actively trying to reduce the scope of work they undertake - here are two amazing questions that should be asked more often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is the unique value delivered by our product?&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do we need to deliver it? Can we harness existing solutions to achieve this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s structural design demonstrates a keen eye to identify high-potential DeFi projects and harness their synergies. In short, by &lt;strong&gt;assembling several DeFi legos together in an unprecedented way&lt;/strong&gt;, Andre efficiently delivered a brand new use case if not a new subset of the whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-defi-100-community-driven-project&#34;&gt;The first DeFi 100% community-driven project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This headline is not at attention grab, I stand by it as there is meat on the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first, let us restress than &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has been a working product handling significant volumes for a while before the YFI token&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, you can add to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% of the tokens distributed to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a novel liquidity mining approach, pertinent to the product (yCRV pool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community was quick to step up and is booming with well-articulated ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andre relinquished control of the main contracts governing the service, in favour of a multisig with reputable actors of the space.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I regard and value an open governance process as a net positive, at least in the long-run, this is also a risk - and &lt;strong&gt;this is usually how people in the industry reads it&lt;/strong&gt;. An open governance can be hijacked in a direction that does not match the best interest of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;defiweb3---communities-hegemonize-brands&#34;&gt;DeFi/Web3 -&amp;gt; Communities Hegemonize Brands
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might not be on board yet, but for me, building and growing communities - that’s essentially my life. In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it, I found no secret sauce yet I &lt;strong&gt;uncovered an obvious truth: communities &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; brands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of DeFi, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the &lt;strong&gt;clash of brands&lt;/strong&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re about to witness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the one hand, VC-funded brand-companies tend to lack personality and have a harder time bolstering dynamic organic communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, a community-driven project is &lt;strong&gt;a story writing itself every day.&lt;/strong&gt; And when it comes to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s brand, we see it growing fast: the swag is already there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yearn-swag.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance Swag&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feeling-the-yearn&#34;&gt;Feeling the Yearn
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is so much more than yVaults! I focused this explainer on them for clarity, but there are several other Yearn products being developed. Without diving too much in, here some promising ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yborrow.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yBorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a generalised credit delegation interface using Aave. What makes it amazing is the synergy with the vaults, it will enable anyone to access vaults like yCRV from an ERC-20 token they like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ySwap: a novel automated market maker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mysterious leveraged stablecoin-farming solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yearn-toolbox&#34;&gt;The Yearn ToolBox
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools and resources developed by the community that proves super helpful if you are exploring or using Yearn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LearnYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A comprehensive Yearn wiki frequently updated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://feel-the-yearn.vercel.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FeelTheYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple page to get the current status of the vaults: assets locked in, assets deployed and the strategy used for each vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ycosystem.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YCosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A community aggregator to find all the useful links, from docs/YIP to where to purchase Yearn swag!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you are interested in Yearn, I URGE YOU to give the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;governance forum&lt;/a&gt; a read - you are forever invited to read and partake in the discussions shaping Yearn. This time, there is no VC, no BS - just a DAO and a one-man-army named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre Cronje&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wifeys-family&#34;&gt;The Wifeys Family
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it would be dishonest to cover Yearn/YFI &amp;amp; without mentioning that YFI sparked a whole movement - there are now dozens of forks, more or less credible. While the first few ones where just &amp;ldquo;miners fork&amp;rdquo;, adjusting a few parameters, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing more creative approaches. Indeed, Yearn is open source so easily forkable, and Andre even invited the community to get creative with it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some communities are forking YFI to create their own pooled earning system, with a longer-term vision. It&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning but I think we will see fascinating development in that space. I think we will see communities reappropriating themselves parts if not the whole YFI system - remember the Wifeys family earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already starting! I&amp;rsquo;m following closely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/yflink/the-idea-of-yflink-is-born-aa520921a4a3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink&lt;/a&gt;, a YFI fork adjusted for the needs of the LINK community. Right now, it looks like a farming cooperative, but the end game might be a community staking node - the perfect match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to the Yearn and its family grow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn vaults are novel DeFi products integrating many others meaning the failure risks are compounded. I am not a financial advisor - you make your own decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am NOT responsible for &lt;u&gt;YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, may they bring you Lambos or bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1280500969986498561?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s Stani (Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO) giving you a rundown of why this is big!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre himself is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1290845154430025731?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the first to acknowledge&lt;/a&gt; what made Yearn possible and the importance of composability.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol governance now lies in the hands of YFI holder. The access to the main contracts are held by a multi-sig, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1285427748761198594?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a key&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1289959986190147585?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;If you do clone /and you are welcome to/, please change a few things so we get new data from the experiment. Repeating the same experiment isn&amp;rsquo;t fun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/eth-exposure-or-defi-yields-why-choose/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/eth-exposure-or-defi-yields-why-choose/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/leveraging-ETH.png" alt="Featured image of post 🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Ether giant seems to be waking up, you might be considering your &lt;strong&gt;options to recenter your exposure on ETH&lt;/strong&gt;. This is precisely what I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at and executed on lately, and now is the time for the feedback session!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, DeFi is heating up and yields are attractive. However, &lt;strong&gt;even crazy liquidity mining returns (on stablecoins) might not beat the ETH price appreciation once its time comes.&lt;/strong&gt; So, instead of having to choose, why not have not both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this one goal in mind, the most obvious solution was &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt;. The position can, of course, be achieved using other services; I consider them at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have the base idea: instead of investing directly in ERC20 or stablecoins and putting them to work, you maintain an ETH base, use it to generate DAI and then diversify into your positions. This way, you maintain a healthy ETH exposure - the tradeoff being the additional risk, including liquidation that are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;re-investing-the-minted-dai&#34;&gt;Re-investing the minted DAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The options to re-invest your DAI are pretty much infinite, so I will focus on these that make the most sense - aka the best at harnessing the current DAI premium. Feel free to check my previous publications covering incentivised liquidity pools investment opportunities &amp;amp; the useful tools to harness them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So essentially when it comes to what makes of the DAI, you have several options, here are the broad categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIMPLE STABLECOIN RETURNS&lt;/strong&gt; - Put your DAI to work, with a simple deposit on Compound or Aave, or using a yield optimiser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADV. STABLECOIN RETURNS&lt;/strong&gt; - Invest in Curve Ypool for decent returns + extra earning opportunities on your pool tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ERC20 EXPOSURE (+LP)&lt;/strong&gt; - Purchase ERC20 tokens and hold or purchase ERC20 tokens and provide liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE ETH LEVERAGE&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the DAI to buy more ETH. Can be potentially repeated for more leverage (CAREFUL). This obviously makes the most sense when you&amp;rsquo;re expecting positive price action on ETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAI is currently trading at a premium ($~1.03), some strategies are better than others to harness the impact of this spread. I detail them in the last section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vault-management-how-to-increase-gas-efficiency&#34;&gt;Vault Management: How to Increase Gas Efficiency?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to making sure you&amp;rsquo;re not burning yourself on the gas costs, I&amp;rsquo;ve already covered several critical tools that we won&amp;rsquo;t detail again, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://zapper.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.Fi&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://paraswap.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt; for some token swaps. Today, I want to discuss services that are helpful to manage Maker vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While interacting with your vaults, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself make series of transactions (deposit ETH -&amp;gt; mint DAI -&amp;gt; do something with the DAI). To reduce your gas costs, you can &lt;strong&gt;use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://furucombo.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FuruCombo&lt;/a&gt; to build your series of operations and execute it in one transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might find yourself in need of a &amp;ldquo;flash capital&amp;rdquo; to close a position somewhere and re-open it somewhere else. If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, an Aave flash loan will be useful. Now for the best part: &lt;strong&gt;flash loans are available on FuruCombo!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/furucombo.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Collateral swap using Furucombo&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that in these times of high gas cost, each interaction is costly. To reduce the impact of gas on your strategy, try to minimize the amount of operations you&amp;rsquo;re doing - FuruCombo is simply amazing for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have many positions to close/open, you might also want to wait for an opportunistic time to do so, where gas costs are low. The weekend evenings (Europe time) are usually best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-please-read-how-to-not-get-liquidated&#34;&gt;🚨 PLEASE READ: How to not get liquidated?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-makers-liquidation-mechanism&#34;&gt;Understanding Maker&amp;rsquo;s Liquidation Mechanism
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you get liquidated, (a part of) your collateral is seized to cover your debt. &lt;strong&gt;The existence of liquidation on Maker means you could lose potentially all of your ETH&lt;/strong&gt; if you are careless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my tips and recommendations to make sure this does not happen to you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are just starting with leverage, maintain a very healthy collateralization ratio&lt;/strong&gt;. I’d recommend &amp;gt; 300 % for new users, simply for peace of mind during your discovery phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t put all of your eggs in one basket&lt;/strong&gt;: on Maker, you can open as many vaults as you want. While you don’t want to open hundreds of positions to keep the gas costs in check, you might also want to consider splitting your stash to not put all of your ETH under the same risk and be able to more gradually manage the positions as they grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Vault Management&lt;/strong&gt;: if you&amp;rsquo;d like a less stressful approach, you can use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt; to make sure your vault is automatically kept at a certain ratio with the Save function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/defisaver-automation.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Automating Maker Vault Management with DeFi Saver&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advanced-vault-management&#34;&gt;Advanced Vault Management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have several vaults, you can use a tool to re-distribute capital between them in one transaction, again with FuruCombo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Mint DAI on Vault1 (currently safe) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; Burn DAI on Vault2 to lower its risk
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using a flash loan, you can even fully close a vault “into” another vault for instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Flash loan DAI (=debt of Vault-1) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; Burn on Vault-1, to free the ETH 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Deposit the ETH in Vault-2 (the one you keep) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Mint DAI on Vault2 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Pay back the flash loan.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be mindful with what you do with the DAI you mint: it&amp;rsquo;s a debt.&lt;/strong&gt; Prefer safer investment options. If you invest in something stupid &amp;amp; get rekt at the same time the ETH price is depreciating, you could be putting your ETH at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-maker-is-the-best-service-to-leverage-eth-right-now&#34;&gt;Why Maker is the best service to leverage ETH right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to focus this article on Maker only, considering the angle is to leverage ETH and Maker is currently the best platform to do so, as well as probably the safest (running track record). Here are my main three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fits the bill&lt;/strong&gt; - It enables you to keep an ETH exposure while generating extra DAI to re-invest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0 fee if not liquidated - (⚠ gas costs)&lt;/strong&gt; The current stability fee is 0 (on ETH) - it costs you nothing but gas to open a position on Maker.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAI Premium -&lt;/strong&gt; DAI is frequently trading at $ 1.02-1.03 meaning minting DAI can result in a 2-3% instant profit on the amounts reinvested (more on this later - DAI premium section).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that &lt;strong&gt;this is NOW&lt;/strong&gt;, several weeks from now there might be better options for such positions, as Aave implements its new tokenomics for instance. A similar position could already be achieved today using Compound, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem profitable to do so right now (vs Maker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-this-strategy-for&#34;&gt;Who is this strategy for?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s quite a flexible strategy, &lt;strong&gt;it can be used by pretty much anyone owning ETH and looking for a way to put them to work.&lt;/strong&gt; However, allow me to highlight some use case scenarios that should give you ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve entered the markets recently (2019), and made profits but not really on ETH. While your ERC-20 positions are up, you might be wary about missing on ETH gains. To increase your exposure to ETH, you could settle some of your positions to ETH, open a vault, and reopen up to ⅔ of the closed ERC-20 positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been harnessing neat gains on the stablecoins farming lately, but even the best yields can&amp;rsquo;t beat a waking giant. You might consider buying ETH with your stablecoins, to then open a vault and reopen part of your stablecoin position - you keep some of your yields while adding a sweet exposure to ETH&amp;rsquo;s price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;harnessing-the-dai-premium&#34;&gt;Harnessing the DAI Premium
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To conclude, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the best options if your goal is to make the most of the current DAI premium - what does it impact most?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s very nice for ETH-leveraged long. Indeed, if DAI trades at $1.03, buying ETH from DAI is more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering investing in the Curve y pool, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend going 100% from DAI. You&amp;rsquo;ll save gas cost massively on the swaps that are not required (+ less deposit and approve tx). On top of these savings, entering the Curve y pool fully in DAI usually has a positive price slippage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently it sits ~1.5% over 5000 DAI: that is 1.5% instant profit as you enter the position, quite attractive right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/curve-dai-premium.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve DAI Premium&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your risk preference and your capital, you might want to time your entry. I was able to harness up to a 3.5% positive bonus entering the ypool, so waiting can be worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Grégoire for proof reading this content &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; for suggesting &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, try it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://oasis.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;put your ETH to work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, without selling them! Try out with a first safe (&amp;gt;300%) position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liking it? Start exploring other strategies but remember to account for gas costs. Use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://furucombo.app&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FuruCombo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to build more complex flows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using vaults more and more? It might be a good time to consider &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to reduce your risk and manage your vault without stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MakerDaiBot/status/1290243544670785536&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Stability Fee is now = 0&lt;/a&gt; for all collaterals on Maker.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post 💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeFi is like a layered yield cake. When you first walk through the door, making a deposit on Aave and seeing your balance grow puts you in awe. Shortly thereafter, through your own research or discussions with the community, you realize there is more to it &lt;strong&gt;- there could be icing on the cake too!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you could find several streams of yields on a given capital utilizing Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. &lt;strong&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll exclude out of the box any strategy involving leverage&lt;/strong&gt; - the easiest way to achieve such a feat. There are still a lot of high-quality crops to plant, even without leverage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, capital efficiency is increasing at a rapid pace in DeFi thanks to novel financial primitives like Compound, Balancer or Curve. It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to &lt;strong&gt;achieve up to 3 layers of returns&lt;/strong&gt;, and there are pools for any risk appetite, from pure stablecoins ones to 100% ERC-20 tokens exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Liquidity Wars are merely beginning.&lt;/strong&gt; Follow the governance of the protocol you&amp;rsquo;re invested in closely, it&amp;rsquo;s even more critical now. Meanwhile, since DeFi feels more and more like gaming, allow me to import a concept inherited from there: tier list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In video games, tier lists are useful to navigate the different types of characters or builds. They establish both a typology and a ranking. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll bring this concept back to DeFi to arrange the most attractive liquidity pools into coherent groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-we-start&#34;&gt;BEFORE WE START
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ℹ Please note - This content assumes a basic understanding of the world of Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. Refer to my earlier articles if that&amp;rsquo;s the first time you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This piece will not cover basic DeFi investment strategies, detailed in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 DeFinancial Services Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information regarding the tools you can use to implement and manage these strategies, please check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not investment advice and reading this document as anything more than a structured list of incentivised liquidity pools would be a misrepresentation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suggest-yours&#34;&gt;Suggest yours!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post can be a living document. Feel free to suggest incentivised pools I&amp;rsquo;ve missed. If you are familiar with Github, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/TokenBrice/blog/blob/master/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;you can do a pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If not, just reach out and share documentation about the pool and its incentive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, allow me to make the distinction between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining&lt;/strong&gt;: a base action of the platform (such as supply liquidity) is rewarded with the platform native token (ex: BAL on Balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Incentive Programs&lt;/strong&gt;: a specific liquidity pool is eligible for extra rewards, through staking of the pool token or weekly distributions (ex: Wednesday for JRT Balancer pools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is: you can stack both! Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/yield-farmer-tier-list.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TokenBrice-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List-DeFi&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-1-defi-yield-trifecta&#34;&gt;Tier 1: DeFi Yield Trifecta
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I walk you through the main earning-staking opportunities I&amp;rsquo;ve found, I will also share broader considerations about providing liquidity on AMMs, such as thoughts on the pool weighting to help you make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we chase our wildest dream, the highly-thought-after yield trifecta, let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to consider what it looks like. When it comes to yields, the cream of the crop is usually an incentivised &amp;amp; balanced Balancer pool with low fees, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s eligible for the maximum amount of BAL liquidity mining rewards, on top of the liquidity incentive program (&amp;amp; the commissions on swaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is exactly one Balancer pool matching these criteria with 2 stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; to my knowledge, so this is where we start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-50-musd--50-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;The 50% mUSD / 50% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mstable&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a meta-stablecoin. You can go on their app to lock your USDT, USDC, DAI &amp;amp; TUSD to mint mUSD. Once you own mUSD, several earning opportunities are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most direct one is the &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; feature on the mStable app. It will lock your mStable tokens and generate a return through lending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/mstable.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s a simple yield and won&amp;rsquo;t deserve a feature here by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect introduction to the Balancer mUSD/USDC pool, our first trifecta of the day. What&amp;rsquo;s a trifecta you ask? Pretty simple: 3 layers of yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commissions on swaps&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s a liquidity pool facilitating trades and earning a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAL liquidity mining&lt;/strong&gt;- this is a balanced 50/50 pool with low fee (5 bps) earning the maximum amount of BAL possible (mining factor = 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/mstable/introducing-meta-mta-mstables-protocol-token-6e1032291ccf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MTA liquidity incentives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; program on this pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% USDC&lt;br/&gt;50 %mUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;MTA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 26 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;?? BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 000 MTA/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Native rewards = earned in the same token as the exposure (usually a commission fee taken on trades facilitated)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: The respective ratios of four stablecoins backing the mUSD (half of the exposure) can vary, go to the m stable app&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to view it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/musd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable-asset-distribution&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is particularly attractive because the exposure is 100% stablecoin-based, despite a very solid yield thanks to the max BAL mining ratio + the incentive program paid in the highly anticipated MTA token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note/Warning: 💬 Discussions are ongoing in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/ARJWaeF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Balancer Discord&lt;/a&gt; governance channel to lower the BAL mining ratio on this pool. It was lowered to 0.1 for tokens tracking the same asset.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9010-incentivised-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;90/10 Incentivised Balancer Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;90-snx--10-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;90% SNX / 10% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel like you missed out on SNX rise? For medium capitals (&amp;lt; 5000 SNX) it makes little sense to stake if you account for the gas costs. This pool is a great alternative for a bullish SNX exposure with great yield potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% SNX&lt;br/&gt;10% USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5 Jun 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DONE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, since the pool is heavily skewed towards SNX, the BAL mining is not maximized. Remember the factor of 1 for the BAL mining on the mUSD pool? Here it&amp;rsquo;s 0.36: you get about a third of the amount of BAL you would mine in a 50/50 &amp;amp; low-fee pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 90/10 pools are great to heavily minimize impermanent losses risk if you believe the token has a lot of upside potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/balancer-snx-usdc-liquidity-trial/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;incentive program on this pool is now over&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s back to being a regular twofecta pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;jrt-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;JRT Balancer Pools
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jarvis Network offers an incentive program over three pools, all 90 % JRT + 10% DAI, ETH or USDC. The reward model is similar to the previous pool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% JRT&lt;br/&gt;10% ETH, DAI or USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;JRT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Jun 17 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;70 000 JRT/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/jarvis-network/liquidity-program-with-balancer-db23aa0ce10&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: JRT price&amp;rsquo;s action has been quite explosive lately. DYOR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚡ Update (&lt;em&gt;July 08&lt;/em&gt;): JRT rewards are now distributed to ANY Balancer pool (whitelisted):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ampl-geyser&#34;&gt;AMPL Geyser
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AMPL is a beast of its own, so I invite you to read more on it &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; before you dive into this one. Here, the exposure is 50 % ETH and 50 % AMPL. On top of your commissions, you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for extra AMPL &amp;amp; as well as the AMPL rebalances (on your AMPL = 50% of the exposure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 % ETH&lt;br/&gt;50 % AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;April 21st 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable - AMPL Rebalances&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;36 911 AMPL/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ampltalk.org/app/forum/ampl-geyser-19/topic/about-the-geyser-21/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 AMPL Geyser Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebalances compounded impact can be hard to calculate. This spreadsheet recently emerged to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.publish0x.com/canuhodl/ampleforth-dollar-ampl-calculator-spreadsheet-for-investors-xmdjxvy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧮 help AMPL investors calculate the impact of the rebalances.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ampleforth-geyser&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geyser code is audited&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and insured on Nexus Mutual&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The reward calculation here takes into account the time staked - so this pool is best utilised over the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-2-how-many-fecta-can-there-be&#34;&gt;Tier 2: How many fecta can there be?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synthetix-incentivised-pools&#34;&gt;Synthetix Incentivised Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Synthetix has been pioneering liquidity incentive programs with the early Uniswap sETH/ETH pool (+SNX incentives). Synthetic pools are still highly attractive, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider the two main ones of interest for yield stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note the Curve&amp;rsquo;s token (CRV), one of the liquidity mining rewards of both pools presented below, is not live yet. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/curvefi/curve-dao-contracts/blob/master/doc/readme.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CRV currently documented mechanisms&lt;/a&gt; can change before the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-og-curve-susd-pool&#34;&gt;The OG: Curve sUSD Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the mUSD/USDC pool, this pool exposure is 100% in stablecoins, yet the rewards are paid in SNX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;31.58 % USDT&lt;br/&gt;30.67% USDC&lt;br/&gt;24.62% suSD&lt;br/&gt;13.13% DAI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Aprill 22 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;CRV (not live yet)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;48 000 SNX / week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/new-curve-pool-launch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is one of the earliest liquidity mining programs there is yet still quite competitive. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous guides, you know about this already&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-btc-og-variant-curve-renbtcsbtcwbtc&#34;&gt;The BTC-OG Variant: Curve renBTC/sBTC/wBTC
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/curve-btc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-synthetix-balancer-ren-btc-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is similar to the first one, with different tokens. Here, your price exposure is 100% in BTC, while your liquidity mining rewards are made of four hot DeFi tokens: BAL, SNX, REN &amp;amp; CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;44.54% renBTC&lt;br/&gt;32.21% wBTC&lt;br/&gt;23.26% sBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX, REN, BAL &amp;amp; CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 19 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;10 000 SNX/week&lt;br/&gt;25 000 REN/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/btc-yield-farming-pool/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because these two Curve pools have full exposure in a stable (USD) or relatively stable assets (BTC), they are a great resource to &amp;ldquo;park&amp;rdquo; profits realised on more risky ERC-20 based pools. You still &lt;strong&gt;maintain a decent APR on the base asset (~3-5%) while having a nice upside potential on the liquidity mining rewards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-3-twofecta-are-nice-too&#34;&gt;Tier 3: Twofecta are nice too!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-favorite-erc-20-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;Your Favorite ERC-20 Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Balancer exchange comes with built-in BAL mining incentives. They apply to any pool involving whitelisted tokens. Therefore, any Balancer pool is already a twofecta: you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for commissions on the swaps facilitated + the BAL mining rewards. Please keep in mind that the pool weighting (ideally balanced) and fees (ideally low) affect the BAL mining ratio. The table below assume a ratio of 1, observed for instance on 50/50 pairs with 5 bps fees (0.05%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the return profile generic Balancer pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% wETH&lt;br/&gt;50% ERC20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~60% for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Balancer, Liquidity incentives programs are getting into fashion, expect more to be revealed, as well as liquidity mining programs. You can &lt;strong&gt;use a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pools.fyi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool FYI&lt;/a&gt; which now has an &amp;ldquo;Incentivised&amp;rdquo; tag to check for the best opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. For Balancer, use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/balancer/%5B%5D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; to explore the pools and check their BAL mining factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compound-deposit&#34;&gt;Compound Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of COMP, a Compound deposit could also be considered a twofecta. Indeed, on top of the base APR the deposit is earning, users are also now eligible for COMP rewards. You can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/compound/None&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;calculate them here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Depends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable in COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-risk-breakdown---read-this&#34;&gt;⚠ RISK BREAKDOWN - READ THIS
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each pool comes with its own sets of risk, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview to help you account for them. When you invest in a liquidity pool, you&amp;rsquo;re assuming the following risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ The base Ethereum network risk (51% attack, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ You&amp;rsquo;re also assuming the risk carried by the token contracts of any token involved in the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ As well as the risk involved to the exchange&amp;rsquo;s contracts, which can be hacked or faulty to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ An economic risk, the impermanent losses (loss vs raw holding) - that will be heavily affected by your token choices &amp;amp; the pool weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/WHILE ENTERING &amp;amp; EXITING/ The risks associated with any service you use, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;, for the time of the transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will walk you through the risk profile of one of the pools to help you model it: the mUSD/USDC pool. Just like the returns, the risk profile is a cake with many layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t develop on the Ethereum network risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we have two tokens in the pool: mUSD &amp;amp; USDC. To compute the risk, we need to look at what&amp;rsquo;s backing mUSD - unwrapping, we&amp;rsquo;re exposed to: USDC, USDT, TUSD. Each of these tokens carry their own risks, since for instance &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://support.usdc.circle.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001314526-Circle-USDC-Risk-Factors&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Circle can freeze USDC balances of any account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we&amp;rsquo;re using Balancer. Their contracts were audited by Trail of Bits recently&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Still, the protocol is quite recent. We&amp;rsquo;re also relying on mStable contracts for the mUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re lucky on the impermanent losses - considering the pool involves two stablecoins, the risk is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It all depends on the tools you&amp;rsquo;re using here. Bear in mind that you&amp;rsquo;re also assuming a risk associated with mUSD/Mstable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gregoireljda&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Grégoire&lt;/a&gt; for his help proofreading this article.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; for his careful review of the FR translation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mstable.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;meta stablecoin&amp;rdquo; aggregating several stablecoins together (USDC, USDT, TUSD &amp;amp; DAI) under the mUSD token, while the underlying supply is mobilised similarly to Curve (lending and liquidity providing).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the current mUSD underlying distribution on the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.mstable.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable app&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://ampleforth.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ampleforth (AMPL)&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;adaptive money built on sound economics&amp;rdquo;. It intends to provide a new type of asset which price movement is uncorrelated from any other.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ampleforth/ampleforth-audits/blob/master/token-geyser/v1.0.0/CertiK_Verification_Report.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Certik - Audit Report 28 Feb 2020&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently 51 643 NXM staked on the AMPL Geyser Contract &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;code&gt;0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser-insurance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;cover-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List&#34;
	
	
&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curve sUSD pool was already mentioned as part of a DeFi investment strategy built on an SNX stake in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/#5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFinancial Service Guide&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-definancial-farming-toolbox/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-definancial-farming-toolbox/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post 🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy farmer,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it here, we will assume a shared basic understanding of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethereumprice.org/guides/article/yield-farming/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;what yield farming is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might even have tried it by yourself, or heard the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiweekly.substack.com/p/tales-from-a-yield-farmer&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tales from a yield farmer&lt;/a&gt;: amazing! Today, it’s my turn to share key concepts &amp;amp; a curated list of tools to help you make the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If by any chance you landed here without any idea of what &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethhub.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is, please click these links. This is not a guide, I keep it short &amp;amp; sweet with pointers only - Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organic-defarming&#34;&gt;Organic DeFarming
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farming used to be simple: you planted some seeds and hopefully collected yields. Nowadays, we have some &lt;strong&gt;super crops&lt;/strong&gt;, landing extra yields on top of usual commissions on the swaps facilitated or fees collected on lending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Essentially because &lt;strong&gt;some DeFi platforms like Compound or Balancer are now incentivising users to perform actions critical to the service;&lt;/strong&gt; such as supplying liquidity and borrowing for Compound. Their users are rewarded with their native governance token (COMP in this case). Pricing such token is a hard task the markets are currently crunching on. Price stability of these token may take time as they are currently in price discovery mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we go any further, it’s time to hear a tale from Stani, an organic farmer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is needed is sustainable farming. In essence, farmers should farm quality crops by bringing quality liquidity for long term and keeping the seeds of these crops to expand their farms to new lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stani Kulechov, Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1276093091624226816?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll dive deeper into this later, but the overall &lt;strong&gt;high average gas prices are incentivising you to pick solid crops and stick with them&lt;/strong&gt; instead of foraging all around. For more context on liquidity mining, I’d also recommend reading this piece about the SAFG framework:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally the SAFG shifts us from a world of “buying to own” to one of “participating to govern,” which can ultimately result in more successful protocols and healthier communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/ideo-colab/meet-the-safg-defis-emergent-framework-for-participatory-investing-and-protocol-development-62286a576fb5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Intro - SAFG Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-mining-sources&#34;&gt;Liquidity Mining Sources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the main liquidity mining sources, ordered by the share of tokens available through liquidity mining:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balancer Labs - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/balancer-protocol/proposing-balancer-liquidity-mining-cab4503972fa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL&lt;/a&gt; - 100M total supply, 75M distributed through liquidity mining (75%), since June 1 - includes some externally incentivized pools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve Finance - CRV ??? - there is currently little to no public information available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound Finance - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/compound-finance/expanding-compound-governance-ce13fcd4fe36&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;COMP&lt;/a&gt; - 10M total supply, ~4.2M through liquidity mining (42%), since June 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Market Access - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defirate.com/safg/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;UMA&lt;/a&gt; ~ 35% of the supply through mining (details TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthetix &amp;amp; other incentives program (like JRT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jarvis x Aave &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sponsoring.jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Onramp Sponsoring Program&lt;/a&gt;: redirect interest earned form your stablecoins on Aave to earn JRT tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/synthetix-liquidity-mining.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;synthetix liquidity mining programs&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adapting-the-strategy-to-your-budget&#34;&gt;Adapting the strategy to your budget
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we see how to get in and out of such positions, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a quick discussion on gas prices. They have been pretty high lately in a 25-35 gwei/fast range. Here&amp;rsquo;s roughly what it means for common operations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Compound ($2-3 gas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Liquidity Pools @Zapper, an all-in-one tool to handle your liquidity providing positions, more on this below ($3-5 + swap fees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Liquidity Pools &amp;ldquo;manually&amp;rdquo; ($0.3 (approve) + $2-3 as many times as tokens as in the pool)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exiting also has a cost, as well as any token swap required (like selling your COMP while exiting your position) $1-3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-cold-hard-look-at-gas-cost-impact-on-medium-capitals--2000&#34;&gt;A cold hard look at gas cost impact on medium capitals ($ 2000)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the returns over time of a 2 000 USDT Deposit @Compound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep this simple, we assume the current parameters will stay as such for the next year. &lt;strong&gt;This is obviously unrealistic - take this as a thought experiment.&lt;/strong&gt; Here were the parameters at the time of writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4% APY on USDT on Compound = $80 for a year on the capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.66 COMP/year =~$150 produced by our capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the table below, the &amp;ldquo;Actual Profits&amp;rdquo; column corresponds to a total exit of the position (back to USDT), which means effectively 3 transactions overall for the operation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplying on Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Withdrawing on Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling the COMP tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we look at this position with these assumptions over several time frames, here is what we get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Timeframe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Total Return ($)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Actual Profits ($)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Effective % return over the timeframe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$0.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-$8.37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-0.42%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$4.42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-$4.58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-0.23%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$23.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$14.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;0.70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;3 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$57.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$48.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2.43%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;6 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$115.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$106.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5.30%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;A year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$230.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$221.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;11.05%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: This simplistic scenario ignores the opportunity cost on ETH price. $5 of gas (=ETH) paid today might be worth $10 a year from now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning here I wanted to share is that &lt;strong&gt;for such capitals, considering the current gas costs, it will probably be better to stick to a position for months instead of trying to chase the best currently available yield&lt;/strong&gt;. Decent profits (~0.81 % /month) starts around the 3-months timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, remember Stani the farmer? You need to pick your crops wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;whales-playground---10-000&#34;&gt;Whale&amp;rsquo;s Playground (&amp;gt; $ 10 000)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now if you have more skin in the game and are willing to take more exposure, gas costs become less prohibitive and there are more options available to you. I won&amp;rsquo;t expand on these, some pointers will be enough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, you can leverage your Compound exposure to maximize your effective COMP mining (through supply/borrow). It obviously comes with a risk of liquidation. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dsa.instadapp.io/compound&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;InstaDapp&lt;/a&gt; helps you maximize COMP returns by folding your position up to 4x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous article, I&amp;rsquo;ve detailed a strategy built on the Synthetix platform which included another form of small leverage. It observed impressive returns (~200% effectively) since &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/#5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;introduced 5 weeks ago&lt;/a&gt; - mostly due to a significant appreciation of the price of SNX, the largest exposure in this strategy and the very high level of activity on the Curve sUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/yieldburger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Synthetix-Yieldbuger-TokenBrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough prep - you are now an advised farmer - congrats! Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the tools used to plant your seed, secure your crops and harvest your yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-and-out-of-positions&#34;&gt;Getting in and out of positions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can get into liquidity pools “manually”, that is directly on each platform. It will require several transactions and a proportionate amount of a least two tokens, to begin with. If not, you will also have to swap accordingly beforehand, using a service like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. ParaSwap also helps you get into tokens like cDAI (interest-bearing DAI from Compound) from any other ERC20 with gas and price-efficient paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Balancer just add the option to enter a liquidity pool from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jbrukh/status/1276958110024896514?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;just one token&lt;/a&gt; (-&amp;gt; getting up to 8 tokens from 1, watch for slippage!).&lt;/em&gt; 🔥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not the most familiar with Ethereum yet, the easiest way for you to partake in this feast would be to use tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/zapper-fi.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zapper.Fi-zap-in-liquidity-pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting in and out of pools&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;: in the Invest tab, Zapper lets you conveniently get into/out of pools on Balancer, Curve, and Uniswap, from ETH, DAI and a few other tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying ETH &amp;amp; using DeFi services&lt;/strong&gt; like Aave (gas free on Aave for now!) - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending ETH &amp;amp; stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt;. Now with ParaSwap built-in for swaps and soon an on-ramp to buy ETH/ERC-20 from your bank account!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/monolith.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;monolith&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re at it, here’s a quick tip because I see this way too much.
&lt;strong&gt;You should never claim on Compound.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s costly and your COMP tokens are automatically claimed every time you adjust your position by depositing or withdrawing assets (minimal amount of COMP claimable required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definancial-farmers-essential-toolbox&#34;&gt;The DeFinancial Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Essential Toolbox
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve explained  the basics dear organic farmers, it’s time to finally have a look at that promised toolbox. You&amp;rsquo;ll find below tools that help you track your positions and the markets &amp;amp; analyse the potential returns of strategies you think about applying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of helping you zap in/out of pools, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing all-in-one DeFi position tracker. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zapper.fi/synthetix?address=0x4E60bE84870FE6AE350B563A121042396Abe1eaF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Zapper of the wallet&lt;/a&gt; of the legendary farmer &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DegenSpartan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DegenSpartan&lt;/a&gt; - seems like he took a bite into that juicy yieldburger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/degen.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zapper.fi - DegenSpartan&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to look at a wallet from a historical perspective, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zerion.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zerion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more holistic market view, you can check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://defimarketcap.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiMarketCap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see the main DeFi tokens and the prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://defipulse.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DefiPulse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see the main platforms ranked by total assets locked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.tokenterminal.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Token Terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for an overview of the earnings and P/E ratio of DeFi protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://explore.duneanalytics.com/public/dashboards/c87JEtVi2GlyIZHQOR02NsfyJV48eaKEQSiKplJ7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This &lt;strong&gt;Dune Analytics&lt;/strong&gt; dashboard&lt;/a&gt; giving you an overview of the volume on DEXes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/DEX.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DEX volumes overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⛽ You can also use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HAL_team&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt; to create notifications on different situations, like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mattiascaricato/get-notified-when-gas-price-is-cheap-%EF%B8%8F-2a157a3d18b9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;when gas prices are below a certain threshold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;platform-specific-resources&#34;&gt;Platform-specific resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synthetix / Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many pools and opportunities, it can be hard to keep track! Luckily, some really neat yield farmer tools are being developped. For Synthetix and Yearn.Finance especially, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarming.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yieldfarming.info&lt;/a&gt; is a neat ressource&lt;/strong&gt; to keep track of both platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://explore.duneanalytics.com/public/dashboards/JMB9bYfVUtMAPHM5moj7aIjLaDwos2k9JjJTtk64&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;overview of the COMP tokens mining &amp;amp; claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; here. Use this tool to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/compound/None&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;calculate the expected COMP returns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; obtained by supplying or borrowing tokens on Compound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Compound, you can estimate your BAL mining: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/balancer/%5B%5D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL Distribution Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you intend to use Balancer, I&amp;rsquo;d also recommend brushing up on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygwei.substack.com/p/striking-a-balancer-the-daily-gwei&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL token distribution early shenanigans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RealT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquidity mining returns are quite variable, so on the side you might want to consider tokenised real estate for more predictable returns with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;. Here are two main helpful resources: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt-dashboard.co/portfolio/0x51a7ead10340af963c3124b026b86dd2807c2b1c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;see owners &amp;amp; earnings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.sigri44.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Amazing Google Sheets to help you track your profits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - both are made by the community so feel free to thank their creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aavewatch.now.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;follow Aave&amp;rsquo;s market using AaveWatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are a TokenSet user, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://tokenviz.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenViz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will help you make sense of the sets&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keeping-track-with-the-defi-news&#34;&gt;Keeping track with the DeFi news
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To learn more on DeFi, here are a few resources I&amp;rsquo;d recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Podcast, Livestream, discussions: all of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygwei.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Daily Gwei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a short and sweet daily read on a key event/release
-&amp;amp; you can find me discussing DeFi every week with my friend Abel here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://abelsabstracts.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abel Abstracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parting-words&#34;&gt;Parting Words
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s Gitcoin grant season so please indulge this closure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a bit, hopefully even making some profits? How about sharing a small share back, let&amp;rsquo;s say 2 %, to critical infrastructure projects and to support your favourite DeFi services or content producers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your contributions are immensely appreciated and can have a great impact, even for just 1 DAI thanks to the CLR matching. So if you liked this piece or my contributions to the DeFi space overall, feel free to have a look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/811/tokenbrice-shining-light-on-ethereums-defi-en-fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my Gitcoin grant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will help me fund more initiatives for the French community &amp;amp; help to go on with content production efforts like this one. Every contribution makes a difference, even 1 DAI (currently matched +5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you are on Gitcoin with a grant in your basket, why not add more? Feel free to look around and support critical initiatives, from vulgarisation efforts to core research. Remember the gas struggles? You can &lt;strong&gt;donate to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/946/project-title-eip-1559-community-fund&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EIP 1559 Community Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to help on that front too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading &amp;amp; happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; who helped make sure this article is as clear as it can be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OtherBright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; for his help proofreading this article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AntoineMouran?s=09&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Antoine&lt;/a&gt; for his various suggestions to improve this content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>📖 How to make DeFinancial products work for you</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-definancial-products-work-for-you/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-definancial-products-work-for-you/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post 📖 How to make DeFinancial products work for you" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new economic paradigm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you landed here, you probably already have heard about Ethereum and even decentralised finance (DeFi). That&amp;rsquo;s great - today we take it to the next step: how to use DeFi to better your personal finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article walks you through 6 base strategies and their variants that harness the most relevant DeFinancial services. We start with the &amp;ldquo;set and forget&amp;rdquo; strategies and progressively move down the stack towards the more complex but also lucrative ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the strategies, I URGE you to read attentively the primer on gas below &amp;amp; as well as the disclaimers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is not investment advice. I am not an accredited investor or asset manager. I am just a 27 year old dude using DeFinancial services abundantly and highly active in the space.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU ARE THE ONLY ONE RESPONSIBLE FOR YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-primer-on-gas&#34;&gt;A primer on gas
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ If you know what gas is, feel free to ignore, else - please read this:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All strategies described here are enabled thanks to decentralised finance services and executed on the Ethereum network. &lt;strong&gt;To interact with DeFi services, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay for the commons of the Ethereum network - and that&amp;rsquo;s what gas costs are.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas costs are paid in gwei, a subunit of ETH (1 gwei =  0.000000001 ETH). Most Ethereum wallets will suggest a default gas price. That&amp;rsquo;s usually enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as you dive deeper into the arcane of DeFi, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself coming back to gas to understand it better and optimise your transaction costs. Indeed, depending on the gas cost you pick (vs network observed one), your transaction will clear quickly, slowly, or not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/gas-station.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;eth-gas-station&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethgasstation.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check recommended gas prices on ⛽ EthGasStation&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.ethhub.io/using-ethereum/transactions/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📑 EthHub Docs on Ethereum Transactions&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Some strategies listed below (1, 3 &amp;amp; 4) are applicable without having to worry about gas, using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re almost ready to go in! I just have some necessary disclaimers to share with you to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re on the same level &amp;amp; you understand the content presented below for what it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-reminders---please-read&#34;&gt;Necessary reminders - PLEASE READ
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All returns discussed in the articles are yearly APR (Annual Percentage Rate)&lt;/strong&gt; - to realise these APR (assuming the estimation is accurate), you need to hold your position for a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are no objective measurements of complexity or risk&lt;/strong&gt; - the parameters I present you with while introducing a strategy are here for understanding only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;risk&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; represent? A chance of losing your assets due to market events or your own shortcomings (usually stemming from a lack of understanding)  &lt;br&gt;
The &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;complexity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; score gives you an idea of how technical and hard the risk is to understand and estimate.
&lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Please note: the risk of a failure at the Ethereum network-level is not equal to 0. I do not mention this risk again below - it&amp;rsquo;s implied as a base-level of risk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no free lunches: be sensible with your decisions, here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;quick rule of  thumb &amp;ldquo;the higher the APR, the higher the risk&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When markets go wild (either way), some products are affected more than others. While a sudden ETH price variation doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact RealT&amp;rsquo;s APR (2) - it can translate into significant losses for users of TokenSets or liquidity providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, keep in mind that most of the APR mentioned below change quite often. Don&amp;rsquo;t take them as such, especially if you read this piece weeks after its release: double check by yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering committing capital to a given project, &lt;strong&gt;I URGE YOU&lt;/strong&gt; to check the following ressources to learn more on their risk model &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiScore&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiwatch.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiWatch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/defiscore.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-score&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;passive-definancial-services&#34;&gt;PASSIVE DEFINANCIAL SERVICES
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Products 1-4 are &amp;ldquo;set and forget&amp;rdquo; (please monitor your positions still). What&amp;rsquo;s meant is that entry is usually done through a simple purchase/swap - and so is the exit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meanwhile, in between the two, you have nothing to do to earn your yield - it&amp;rsquo;s paid to you without requiring any intervention (claim or other).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;with-stable-assets&#34;&gt;With Stable Assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some passive investment products involve only stablecoins - these are tokens tracking the price of a stable currency, usually the dollar. Considering the minimal amount of work required to use them, and the lower overall risk (mostly technical failure) these products are the best to get you started with decentralised finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-stablecoins-yield&#34;&gt;1/ Stablecoins Yield
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own an Ethereum-based asset tracking the price of the dollar (ex: DAI). You find a way for this asset to earn interest: lending (ex: aDAI) or liquidity providing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1 = lowest, 5 = highest)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/1-stablecoin-yield.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;1-stablecoin-yield&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yield-bearing stablecoins are the gateway drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can provide decent returns (up to 8-9% APR), are convenient to use and also not too complex so they are a good start to understand some fundamentals about DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in and out is as easy as swapping a token. So, if while considering this approach, you only have three things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk: base stablecoin risk (on DAI) + any service on top of it (ex: Aave for aDAI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return: there are some neat ressources to keep track with the yields, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://loanscan.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LoanScan&lt;/a&gt; for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas costs to get in &amp;amp; out (especially &lt;strong&gt;if you invest small amounts, or while the network is busy&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement this first strategy, you have several options: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;, etc. You can acquire their corresponding tokens (cDAI, aDAI, iDAI) using a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;. In terms of APR, historically, aDAI has been consistently topping the charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to expand on top of the base concept, you have several options offering better returns (meaning more risk):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-a-implementing-a-basic-stablecoin-yield-based-strategy&#34;&gt;1-A/ Implementing a basic stablecoin-yield based strategy
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RECAP: You own an Ethereum-based asset dynamically rebalancing between several stablecoins providing yields to optimise your return.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said above, there are several services offering stablecoins providing returns thanks to lending pools. You can manually chase the best rate yourself, but will require you to monitor the rates and do the rebalances yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead, why not use an Ethereum native service to do that for you in full transparency? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://idle.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Idle Finance&lt;/a&gt; is the leading solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/idle-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;idle-dai&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-b-stablecoins-liquidity-providing-curve-pools&#34;&gt;1-B/ Stablecoins Liquidity Providing: Curve Pools
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own several Ethereum-based stablecoins and help facilitate trades on Curve (= liquidity provider). You earn a commission on each trade corresponding to the prorata of your share of the pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have a dedicated section about liquidity pools below but I had to mention the Curve Pools here. In a gist, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve&lt;/a&gt; is a service made to optimize stablecoin swaps. Providing liquidity on Curve can be quite attractive since the base assets are all stablecoins &amp;amp; the returns provided by the commissions collected on the swaps (&amp;amp; lending) are decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-c--no-loss-lottery-pool-together&#34;&gt;1-C / No loss lottery: Pool Together
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You lock a stablecoin (DAI or USDC) for a week or a month. They are pooled with other users&amp;rsquo; to generate interest (-&amp;gt;Compound). At the end of the week/month, the winner gets all the interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this one because it&amp;rsquo;s both surprising to see it here and amazing. So first, let me clear the air: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is not a financial product per-se - their vision is more pedagogic: PoolTogether is a money game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is quite simple, as described in the recap. Since all the profits of the winner are generated on the interests of all players, nobody loses any money with PoolTogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However please rest assured, the addition of PoolTogether in this list is not ideological: **average returns are superior to Compound. &lt;strong&gt;The reason why is quite simple: PoolTogether uses Compound to generate its return (= same APR) + each pool has some &amp;ldquo;sponsored&amp;rdquo; ticket - tickets contributing to the interest accrual, but without winning chances.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/pt-sponsored.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pool-together-sponsored-balances&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with the average APR is higher, please bear in mind that PoolTogether is much less regular - most of the time you&amp;rsquo;ll get nothing, but if you win you get the equivalent of years of interest on your capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoolTogether essentially provides a new flavor of interest distribution on top of Compound&amp;rsquo;s return: PT&amp;rsquo;s returns are much more random but also potentially massive (if lucky).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/pooltogether/winning-more-prizes-185bad7f6d63&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether released the pods&lt;/a&gt; - a new option for users to play as a group. Users can now share their odds and their gains - which makes the wins less significant but much more frequent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can play the PoolTogether lottery directly from their website.&lt;/a&gt; You&amp;rsquo;ll need some DAI or USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-tokenized-real-estate---realt&#34;&gt;2/ Tokenized Real Estate - RealT
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own shares of tokenized properties (securities). You earn your share of the rent daily (currently in USDC) + extra earning opportunities (liquidity providing, incentive programs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/2-tokenised-real-estate.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;2-realt-tokenised-real-estate&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt; is a totally different beast from anything else in that list, at several levels&lt;/strong&gt;. Since RealT tokens represents real estate in the real world, the risk profile is also totally different (~~&amp;gt;  less Ethereum risk, more real-word risk).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into what makes RealT tokens so interesting, let&amp;rsquo;s make sure we are clear. &lt;strong&gt;RealT tokens are securities - you have to go through a KYC process to be able to purchase them&lt;/strong&gt; (whitelist + lease agreement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/realt.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RealT-tokenised-real-estate&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more work than for interest-bearing stablecoins, but you have several benefits to gain here compared to strategy 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Returns&lt;/strong&gt;: depending on the property, APR ranges from 8% to 12.5%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily payment of returns&lt;/strong&gt;: once you have some RealT tokens in your wallet, you will receive your corresponding** share of the rent, daily, in USDC**.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hedging&lt;/strong&gt;: you have a yield based on real estate - AKA less correlated to the rest of the crypto markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;: you can add more to this strategy to increase the return. To do so, consider providing liquidity on Uniswap - generating some returns. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/realtplatform/announcing-the-uniswap-incentive-program-f82f721cf63a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Providing liquidity on RealT tokens is currently incentivised&lt;/a&gt; - landing even more returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;with-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;With Volatile Assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-automated-trading-strategies---tokensets&#34;&gt;3/ Automated Trading Strategies - TokenSets
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own a &amp;ldquo;set&amp;rdquo; representing a stake in an automated trading strategy based on a technical indicator or another trader (social sets) a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Holding on autopilot&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/3-tokensets.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3-tokensets-automated-strategies&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.tokensets.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenSets&lt;/a&gt; are the holders&amp;rsquo; best friend&lt;/strong&gt;. While the service is definitely not the easiest to understand or the less risky, it currently provides significant utility. Indeed, if you are a long term holder of ETH for instance, TokenSets is one of your best options to grow your ETH stash (against ETH).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sets are automated trading strategies represented by a token. Each set trades a given pair (ex: ETH/cUSDC) following a pre-set of rebalancing rules triggered by the cross with the set technical indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/tokenviz.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Tokensets performance visualised with TokenViz&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Wondering which set to pick? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenviz.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenViz&lt;/a&gt; provides a neat dashboard to help you chose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as a user who is not willing to look at charts all day, TokenSets is an excellent option. Indeed, most people trying to trade tend to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;With the sets, the emotions are out &amp;amp; machines rule.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the regular sets following a technical indicator (such as ETH 20 Days Moving Average), there are now social sets. It&amp;rsquo;s the same mechanism, but your set will follow another&amp;rsquo;s trader strategy instead of simple technical indicators: aka &amp;ldquo;copy-trader&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-simple-yields-to-chase-on-erc20-tokens&#34;&gt;4/ Simple yields to chase on ERC20 tokens
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially the ERC-20 version of strategy 1: you own an ERC-20 (non-stable) token producing some form of returns, usually through lending or liquidity providing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/4-erc20-yields.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;4-erc20-yields&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we explore the more active approaches, allow me to introduce one more passive approach, this time based on ERC20 tokens (not stablecoins.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Aave offers aTokens on up to 15 different ERC-20 tokens, it might be worth for you to keep an eye on them - with a tool like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aavewatch.now.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AaveWatch&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/aavewatch.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;AaveWatch - overview of lending opportunities offered on Aave&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among them, I think the following are the most interesting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aSNX: base rate around 7%, can spike quite high for a bit - keep a very close eye to this one on Wednesdays, especially if prices of ETH/SNX crashed during the week: we observe SNX borrowing surges during certain claim periods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asUSD: can spikes quite hard too, especially lately (~12% APR over the last month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aZRX: rates can spike, read more about ZRX to know when&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aMANA: same here - decentish rate (1-2%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-definancial-services&#34;&gt;ACTIVE DEFINANCIAL SERVICES
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing nothing is amazing - and when it comes to investing it’s a strategy that can be surprisingly effective&lt;/strong&gt;. Being able to stand still and do nothing, even in the middle of a marketstorm is truly an art you would gain to master. However, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise for you: the best yield will require effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/nothing.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Doing nothing - the best strategy of them all?&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how I didn&amp;rsquo;t say work? Sometimes, the &amp;ldquo;efforts&amp;rdquo; can simply be that you accept to stomach a risk others wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, and get paid nicely for it &amp;mdash; &lt;strong&gt;the investor equivalent of a stunt double.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next strategies will require a more precise understanding of what you are doing. Indeed, at their core, all strategies would benefit immensely from your market acumen. So before we explore such strategies, allow me some reminders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information is power.&lt;/strong&gt; More specifically for DeFi investing: the information you have &amp;amp; understand is the main thing driving the alpha (returns) you&amp;rsquo;re extracting from the markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take it slow, be safe, it&amp;rsquo;s not a race&lt;/strong&gt;. Despite writing this article (with many people advising), I have yet to use strategy 6 with serious amounts of capital for instance. It&amp;rsquo;s wise to double-check your understanding of a given platform every time you increase your stake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to quickstart the process? Go in with $50.&lt;/strong&gt; Small amounts are amazing to help you understand a protocol and be involved without taking too many risks and stressing about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-pointers-on-passive-vs-active-styles&#34;&gt;Some pointers on passive vs active styles
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to give an accurate representation of the potential earning spread between an average DeFi passive investor and an active one. However, a combination of services reproduces a similar situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthetix: SNX staking model to collateralise synthetic assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave + Synthetix = aSNX Passive (type 4) investment asset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Actions Required&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Expected Yearly Return &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Passive Style (aSNX)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;None (once you own aSNX)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;~10%&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Active Style (SNX stake managed through mintr)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;Weekly claim of reward (1y escrowed) + sUSD + synths management strategy (trading, liquidity+staking)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;~80% &amp; more (up to you)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-synthetix&#34;&gt;5/ Synthetix
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start with a stake of SNX (Synthetix token). You stake (lock) them which already generates a neat SNX return but vested for a year (+weekly sUSD non-vested). Thanks to your stake, you can then mint synthetic tokens - that expose yourself for up to 1/8 of the initial SNX value &amp;amp; offer additional earning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/5-synthetix.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;5-synthetix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before anything else: what I say below is NOT ENOUGH to understand Synthetix+SNX if you are just discovering it. &lt;strong&gt;Do not rush it!&lt;/strong&gt; Synthetix is definitely a next step in terms of complexity, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of all the new things you will have to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a secured wallet - &lt;strong&gt;will you be able to access your wallet in a year?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;
SNX rewards are escrowed a year: you claim them today, but you can only move them out of Mintr (Synthetix platform) a year after the claim date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claim reward weekly&lt;/strong&gt; (SNX vested for a year + sUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor&lt;/strong&gt; your collateralization ratio and adjust when need to be able to claim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decide&lt;/strong&gt; which Synth you&amp;rsquo;re exposing yourself to and when&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Synthetix is really flexible, allow me to stick to a strategy I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully implemented. Other approaches are possible, and my choice is suggestive. However, I think this strategy does a good job at highlighting the different synergies available with Synthetix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;&gt;5-A/ The Synthetix/Curve YieldStack (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;the 4-steaks yieldburger&amp;rdquo;)
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use Synthetix (+SNX) to mint sUSD, a stablecoin, and supply this stablecoin to an incentivised liquidity pool for extra returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not beat around the bush: this is much harder, much more work than 1-4, but the returns are an order of magnitude higher if done right. Your position is also more complex to monitor since you are exposed to several types of assets, getting returns in several kinds of assets too, and the timeline of the returns are not the same either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/yieldburger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Synthetix-Yieldbuger-TokenBrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stake? Steak? Does it matter as long as there is meat on the bone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the base of the yield stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staking SNX + SNX reward&lt;/strong&gt; ~ 50% APR, in SNX, paid weekly (claim required) &amp;amp; vested for a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sUSD Staking reward&lt;/strong&gt; - variable sUSD reward (based on exchanges volume), paid weekly, claim required, no vesting period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Provider Curve sUSD pool&lt;/strong&gt; - 3 to 5% APR, earned while exiting the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incentive Program&lt;/strong&gt; for that pool (accessed by staking the pool token)-  25% APR, in SNX, paid weekly (claim required), no vesting period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The Curve sUSD pool ran into some issues, and the current live version is not the most optimised one for returns. A new version of the sUSD pool is coming up, harnessing Aave to optimize it even farther. This strategy might get even more compelling as soon as this ships!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious ? Here is a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://synthetix.community/docs/intro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;comprehensive overview to get started with Synthetix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-liquidity-provider-not-on-stablecoins&#34;&gt;6/ Liquidity Provider (not on stablecoins)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use a capital equally split into to tokens (ex 50% ETH 50% DAI) to supply a liquidity pool, which generates commissions on the trade you help facilitate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/6-liquidity-provider.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;6-liquidity-provider&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially a riskier variant of the strategy 1-B. In this scenario, you are still providing liquidity but this time you move to another kind of pair - the ETH based ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you provide liquidity on a decentralised exchange, the main risk you face (on top of the usual) is what we call &amp;ldquo;impermanent losses&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;. (confusing name, they are very permanent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t explain the full concept here, but here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap: &lt;strong&gt;impermanent losses usually stem from a sudden variation between the relative prices of the two assets you&amp;rsquo;re providing liquidity to&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So if the two assets are tracking the same price (ex ETH/sETH), the impermanent loss risk is minimized&lt;/strong&gt;. So, from the lower level of risk, to greater, you have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on stablecoins: both assets prices are relatively stable, and they track the same price =&amp;gt; the impermanent losses risk is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on assets that are not stable but tracking the same price, such as ETH/sETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on an ETH/stable pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on a ETH/ERC20 (both non stable &amp;amp; not tracking the same price) - this is where the risk is greater, since both assets can move - if both assets price were to suddenly move in opposite directions you can suffer significant impermanent losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering providing liquidity on AMMs, please read more on the topic: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.bancor.network/beginners-guide-to-getting-rekt-by-impermanent-loss-7c9510cb2f22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Risk/Reward of liquidity provision in AMMs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit (07/16)&lt;/em&gt; - If you are curious about liquidity providing, here is another guide covering the main incentivised opportunities: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think this is a good place to call it a run and keep this guide digestible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re ready to jump-in, here are some solutions that will make it easier for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent Wallet&lt;/a&gt; Secure wallet offering one tap access to Aave tokens, PoolTogether &amp;amp; TokenSets presented in this article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith Visa Debit Card&lt;/a&gt; You&amp;rsquo;ve made some profits in DeFi you&amp;rsquo;d like to cash out in the real world? This is the only no-compromise solution allowing you to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what could be your next steps, here is are some of your potential ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opening vaults on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt; or using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt; to get leverage (⚠ liquidation risk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using options like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://opyn.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Opyn&lt;/a&gt; or insurance service such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nexusmutual.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nexus Mutual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Flash loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this was an insightful read and you&amp;rsquo;ve figured a few ways to make DeFinancial services work for you. If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://t.me/de_fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi community on Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, or their variants in your native language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was made possible thanks to a tremendous amount of support from people in the community who shared their suggestions, insights and proofread it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these amazing people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy Ragosa - follow him on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, his meme game is woke 👌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lemiscate&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Marc Zeller&lt;/a&gt; - dev advocate @Aave, do I need to say anything more?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marouane - he&amp;rsquo;s coming after your risks, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UnslashedF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;watch out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:victor@function.media&#34; &gt;Viktor&lt;/a&gt; who worked on the graphics of this article and indulged my terrifying napkin diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as people who did not contribute directly to this specific article but were key in helping me understand DeFinancial services better - allowing me to be in a position to write this guide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pscltllrd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pascal Tallarida&lt;/a&gt;: founder of Jarvis Netowrk, proeminent onboarder and vulgariser in the French community. He&amp;rsquo;s the one who helped me (and MANY others) grasp their heard around synthetic assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mounibec&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mounir&lt;/a&gt;: founder of Paraswap.io, the OG-est of DEX aggregator and still the only one that can fetch a price &amp;lt;1-2s without melting your laptop. Mounir is a one-man-army and an incredibly helpful actor in the French &amp;amp; international communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AbelsAbstracts&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abel&lt;/a&gt;: this guy keeps up with everything and he&amp;rsquo;s my go-to person to discuss new releases and see through the marketing. Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/show/6NO8M2R4u9YSgAdz5TA4ZA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;his amazing podcast&lt;/a&gt; - we do a DeFi catchup every week together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
