<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Yearn Finance on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/yearn-finance/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Yearn Finance on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/yearn-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/defi-vs-inflation-tokenbrice-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation is more than ever at the center of discussions and concerns: no one understands much about it, no economist has really anticipated it, but we all have an opinion about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we leave economics and politics aside to focus on what matters for your wallet: in decentralized finance, all kinds of protocols are developed, and a good part of them &lt;strong&gt;provide credible and innovative tools to preserve and develop the purchasing power of a portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;, even when the macroeconomic context is most uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to evaluate strategies involving different assets and protocols, all with the same goal: to preserve and develop the effective purchasing power of a given portfolio. Nevertheless, we have to start with the basics, level 0: what is inflation and why should we, DeFians, care about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover image was made by a generous anonymous contributor and features the majestic &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/valkyre/created&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Valkyr-E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;α-tutorial-understanding-the-impact-of-inflation-on-a-crypto-portfolio&#34;&gt;α/ Tutorial: Understanding the impact of inflation on a crypto portfolio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t venture into the details of inflation for fiat currencies here, but the basic concept is known to anyone familiar with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the term: here is how the INSEE (Institut National de la Statistique et des Études Économiques) defines inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation is the loss of purchasing power of money that results in a general and lasting increase in prices. It must be distinguished from the increase in the cost of living. The loss of value of money is a phenomenon that hits the national economy as a whole (households, businesses, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just remember that, &lt;strong&gt;just like in DeFi where each token is associated with a protocol and potentially even an ecosystem, each fiat currency is also based on an economy as well as a set of rules&lt;/strong&gt; (legal system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-macro-point-of-view-scale--country&#34;&gt;Inflation, macro point of view (scale = country)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation corresponds to the production of new money, the important thing is not so much the quantity of money created, but more &lt;strong&gt;what is done with&lt;/strong&gt;. We all understand this rather well with two caricatural examples at each extreme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country A issues a large amount of money in order to invest massively in its transport infrastructure and its energy supply (= long-term investments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here, inflation can be controlled because the new money issued is used to finance investments that develop the country&amp;rsquo;s economic potential in the long run (-&amp;gt; compensation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country B issues a large amount of money to finance an emergency plan to compensate for the foreseeable consequences of previous pseudo-sanitary measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second scenario, the new money is used to cover a &amp;ldquo;current expense&amp;rdquo; of the government. The personal equivalent would be to go into debt every day to pay for lunch. This is obviously unsustainable in the long run. In this scenario, inflation can only be massive as a large amount of new money is issued, while the economic potential of the country in question stagnates or deteriorates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluating-future-inflation&#34;&gt;Evaluating future inflation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough about the macro, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our scale, with things we know well. Here is the evolution of the M1 money supply on the dollar, this allows us to visualize its &amp;ldquo;marketcap&amp;rdquo; in a way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/USD-m1-supply.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;USD M1 Supply&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we only look at M1 for simplicity but the trend is similar on M2 and M3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested here in the dollar which, although challenged, remains the fiduciary currency that sets the tone. As you can see, the curve has been going vertical since the beginning of the Covid crisis. The curve is now much scarier than the worst shitcoins I have ever seen. Doubt it? Consider the same information, presented in this light:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dollar has been around since 1914. 20% of all dollars in circulation were created in 2020. At the current rate, the total amount of dollars in circulation doubles about every 4-5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare with crypto, many are concerned about inflation / new token issuance on Curve Finance (CRV). The 4 year issuance curve looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/crv-release-schedule.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-release-schedule&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no economist, but I know my shitcoins. The official US inflation figure we are given is 7.5% per year. Like unemployment figures, it&amp;rsquo;s a highly political metric that&amp;rsquo;s hard to really appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7.5% figure may seem high, but it is still low when compared to the unprecedented money creation to deal with Covid. So I expect to see this inflation rise further, or else to be sustained over an extended period of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So inflation is here, at 7.5% minimum for several years at least. Enough with boomers&amp;rsquo; macro, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the range of tools that the DeFi offers us to face it and overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-beating-inflation-with-classic-stablecoin-returns&#34;&gt;I/ Beating inflation with &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; stablecoin returns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first approach is as always the simplest, &lt;strong&gt;the brute force method&lt;/strong&gt;: an inflation of 7.5% means that USD left as is will lose 7.5% of their value over the year. The point here is to find a source of return higher than inflation: the difference between the two is the effective return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inflation at 7.5% on the USD, I think it is prudent to make sure to &lt;strong&gt;reach at least 1.5x this figure in yield&lt;/strong&gt; to really consider yourself inflation-proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the game is simple and the rules fairly easy to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with a position in a given stablecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to make it productive, without assuming IL risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a return that exceeds the inflation figure, once the gas costs have been amortized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-stablecoin-deposit&#34;&gt;Simple stablecoin deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we would aim for &lt;strong&gt;a 10.875% annual return on stablecoin $ at the very least&lt;/strong&gt;. With recent declines and yield compression this is increasingly difficult, but still findable even with a single stablecoin deposit without IL risk. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coindix.com/?kind=stable&amp;amp;sort=-apy&amp;amp;chain=ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Coindix&lt;/a&gt; can help you find the vault of your dreams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/coindix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coindix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, &lt;strong&gt;not all vaults are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;! For example, we see nice returns on Bancor on the screenshot: don&amp;rsquo;t forget to consider the volatility of these returns as well as the fees in gas to deploy the position (a Bancor LP is notoriously more expensive than a Yearn deposit for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention it here only to forget it just as quickly afterwards: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.anchorprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Anchor protocol&lt;/a&gt; also offers you a &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; return close to 20% on UST stablecoin. Such a guaranteed rate does not come, of course, without serious compromises that raise real questions about the sustainability of this whole ecosystem (Terra/Luna).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;provision-of-liquidity--time-commitment&#34;&gt;Provision of liquidity + time commitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still in dollars, but a bit riskier, we can consider different types of commitments, with very controlled / no IL risks. For example, a liquidity provision between FRAX and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/DAI LP opportunities on Frax&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax Finance&lt;/a&gt;, the prime rate (x1) is just our minimum target, but it is possible to reach up to x5 with two types of commitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X3 by locking LP tokens for 3 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X2 by using your veFXS (much harder to reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective return on a position locked in for three years corresponds to about 3 times our minimum target, thus offering a credible protection against the loss of value due to the consequences of inflation, but you still have to be able to assume the three-year commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is taken here on DAI, but the situation is similar on the other major stablecoins; for example, here are the FRAX/USDC pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/USDC LP opportunities&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex for Frax is coming (optimizing Frax LP farming via Convex), if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own veFXS, it&amp;rsquo;s probably pertinent to wait until the service is released to make a decision with all the cards in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenizing-and-speculating-on-future-yields&#34;&gt;Tokenizing and speculating on future yields
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To beat that famous 10% return on the dollar, there are still many other options. I present you one last one here to help you consider the other possible strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, we rely on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol that allows the tokenization of future yields on productive assets. The principle is both simple and complex: depositing an asset on APWine allows to separate its future yield (FYT: Future Yield Token) from the underlying principal (PT: Principal Token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, different strategies are possible, such as immediately selling the future yield (FYT) in order to increase the quantity of the productive principal. Such a tool enables better risk management considering the volatily of yields observed in DeFi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and still well above the 10% requirement: let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on the aUSDT vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apwine-USDT-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine aUSDT vault&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automatically exclude the PT/FYT pool which is more complex to understand and has much higher risks than the PT/Underlying offering a 44% return in APW anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the strategy is simple, but you have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the important gas costs linked to the use of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;. To implement the strategy using USDT in the wallet, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit a part of them on Aave (I&amp;rsquo;d recommend 55% of the total maximum for this specific strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit the aUSDT obtained in 1 on APWine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow (x2) + Deposit the PT and Underlying (USDT) tokens as liquidity providing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Stake of the LPs PT/Underlying tokens to obtain the return in APW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget also the gas fees related to the APW claims + unwinding of the position at the end of the period (or before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore better to wait for a day when the transactions clear under 30 gwei so as not to suffer too much from the gas costs on such a strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage here, compared to Frax for example, is that &lt;strong&gt;the position is much more liquid&lt;/strong&gt;. APWine works with an epoch logic that lasts 90 days. Thus, to more easily amortize the costs in gas it is preferable to deploy the strategy at the beginning of the epoch: this is also when the returns are generally the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third winelisting (where the next tokens supported on APWine are decided) has just ended, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apw-winelisting3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine - Winelisting 3&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APWine is still a young protocol, but the governance is dynamic. The next step is approaching: as on Curve, it will soon be the veAPW holders (locked APW) that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.apwine.fi/t/apgp-2-enable-gauges-for-apw-rewards/171&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;will decide on emissions&lt;/a&gt; for each given vault. A redistribution of the cards is to be expected, plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-hedged-productive-positions-with-various-alternative-stablecoins&#34;&gt;II/ Hedged productive positions with various &amp;ldquo;alternative&amp;rdquo; stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have stayed for now on the dollar, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to begin with. Although dollar stablecoins are still largely dominant, there are now &lt;strong&gt;many stablecoins based on other fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt; such as EUR, JPY (Japanese Yen), CHF (Swiss Franc), KRW (Korean Won) or even CAD (Canadian Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the few centralized stablecoins (EURS or EURT), this market is mostly covered by protocols that offer to create synthetic stablecoins backed by other stablecoins. This is the case for example with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jarvis Network&lt;/a&gt;, which uses USDC to collateralize different types of stablecoins: jEUR, jCHF, jKRW, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-deposit&#34;&gt;Single deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yield opportunities with no/low IL for such stablecoins are still quite rare, and usually found on Curve: providing liquidity against other stablecoins based on the same fiat currency, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/curve-chf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CHF pool on Curve Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few stablecoins have lucrative single deposit options jEUR, jCHF, jJPY. They are based on the corresponding Curve pools, with additional incentives offered by Jarvis and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via Jarvis (also available farmed by Harvest), it is also possible to generate a return without IL on jCAD and jJPY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiatafiatb-liquidity-providing&#34;&gt;FiatA/FiatB Liquidity Providing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a slightly different approach, more risky, but also potentially more protective against inflation: providing liquidity on two stablecoins representing two different fiat currencies, for example EURT/3pool (USD) still on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, especially for smaller portfolios, many alternative stablecoins are available on Polygon or Avalanche, with a fairly dense ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarvis offers jCHF-USDC, jEUR-USDC or jCAD-USDC pools with returns above 20%. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beefy.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Beefy.Finance&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to automatically compose the returns obtained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/harvest-jarvis-2-stables.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Network Jarvis jFIAT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: depending on your base asset (e.g. USDC), exposure to EUR (or other currencies) can be lucrative or costly - depending on the evolution of the USDC/EUR exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the more adventurous among you, you should know that APWine is also available on Polygon and already supports several Jarvis tokens, such as the MooJarvis_4eur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity contribution on Curve (4eur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed by Beefy Finance (moo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which compounds return that Jarvis offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the addition of tokens voted during winelisting 3 will open new doors with the upcoming arrival on APWine/Polygon of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooKyber_USDC-jEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooMai_USDC-MAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forex-borrowing&#34;&gt;Forex Borrowing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if liquidations don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, know that a Fuse pool on Polygon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://polygon.market.xyz/pool/7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool7 - Jarvis Forex Market&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to use different jFiat as collateral as well as to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/fuse-pool7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Fuse pool 7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a service, almost anything is possible, here are some examples to inspire you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long USD + short EUR = MAI in collateral, borrow jEUR then sell jEUR and potentially loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short GBP via CHF = jCHF in collateral, borrow jGBP then sell and potential loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also note that the productive stablecoins m2CAD and m2JPY are available as collateral while keeping their yield: they can be interesting for more traditional leverage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding your balance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than just one magic position, what I like about Jarvis stablecoins is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;diversify easily into different types of fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to the low transaction fees on Polygon, it is quite possible to mix several different currencies and positions to make a coherent whole and well protected against its local inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a European (= spending €):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in stable productive € without IL, for example MooJarvis_4eur (+APWine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in jEUR/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% in stable productive dollar (e.g. aUSDT APWine strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Diversification: 15% jCHF/USDC + 15% jGBP/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject of &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; stablecoins, you should know that there are also a few that track gold or silver - they can be relevant from this perspective too. For example XAUT (with Pool Curve XAUT/3crv). Gold and silver remain &lt;del&gt;barbaric&lt;/del&gt; boomers&amp;rsquo; relics, personally I see very little interest in them for a competent DeFian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-inflation-resistant-stablecoins&#34;&gt;III/ Inflation resistant stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beating inflation is nice. Hedging it? Even better. But &lt;strong&gt;why not just abstract it&lt;/strong&gt;, using products that are naturally resistant to it? There are still very few stablecoins that are not tracking fiat currencies, but the supply is growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-the-first-dollar-free-stablecoin&#34;&gt;RAI, the first dollar-free stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast, the very first &amp;ldquo;unpegged stablecoin.&amp;rdquo; Launched at a value of Pi in USD (3.14) in 2021, it has been moving between 3.02 and 3.06 almost since its launch. Given its recent arrival (just over a year), it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how RAI will perform in a period of prolonged inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, diversifying a portion of your stablecoins into RAI may be an attractive option. In addition, there are different return options available on RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple deposit without IL risk: Idle Finance deposits your RAI in Fuse/Aave to optimize the native return + incentives in FLX from Reflexer + incentives in IDLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle-0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Additional FLX incentives for RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By assuming IL risk via liquidity provision on Curve vs. 3pool, a better return is possible. The crvRAI can then be staked directly on Curve or via Convex or Yearn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is based on a mechanism inspired by Maker MCD but with many modifications to make it possible. To understand how it works, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Signals that the mentioned protocol is still under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-inflation-resistant-stablecoin-the-frax-fpi&#34;&gt;🚧 An inflation-resistant stablecoin? The FRAX FPI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Frax Price Index is a new protocol that should arrive soon within the Frax ecosystem. The goal is to offer a new stablecoin, which would follow the CPI (Consumer Price Index) to protect against inflation. Just like Frax, &lt;strong&gt;the system is based on two tokens&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stable - Frax Price Index (FPI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the governance token - Frax Price Index Share (FPIS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/frax-price-index/inflation-hedge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax documentation&lt;/a&gt; offers some information about the upcoming token. &lt;strong&gt;An airdrop of FPIS is planned&lt;/strong&gt; for veFXS or cvxFXS holders. Thus, the protocol will be independent of FRAX/FXS, although a value capture mechanism to FXS is planned beyond the initial airdrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to project solely on a mere design, but it is clear that a stablecoin that would maintain its value despite inflation is a very desirable product. &lt;strong&gt;There are several questions as to whether the peg on FPI can be maintained&lt;/strong&gt;: to keep its equilibrium, people will have to take the opposite trade to FPI, i.e. &amp;ldquo;short inflation&amp;rdquo;. However, in the current context of galloping inflation, it is hard to imagine who could assume such a position and massive incentives might be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the arrival of the FPI is imminent. Traces of the token &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/token/0xdb68c6264e9d0f8a6df1fa5a89f205da38698d15&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FPIS on EtherScan&lt;/a&gt; can be found as early as early March. I look forward to seeing the Frax team&amp;rsquo;s proposed design to address these consequential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-inflation-resistance--degen--volt&#34;&gt;🚧 Inflation resistance + degen = VOLT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI, there is another project I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely, waiting for a long time and holding high hopes for. The high-level concept is very simple: an Abracadabra-like product that would not be a walking security loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Abracadabra allows borrowing from various productive collaterals, which makes the service desirable. Nevertheless, the infrastructure is close to a hack and the actions of the team members make Abracadabra a second or third grade money market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here, with Volt, is to cover the same vertical using a proven infrastructure: the base offered by Reflexer (RAI). Three main changes are expected on this model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Reflexer, which only accepts ETH as collateral, Volt will diversify the available options, notably with productive collateral such as wstETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of VOLT, the system&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, will be indexed to Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI. The Reflexer infrastructure will be reused (PID controller adapted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Volt team is also working in collaboration with Fuse and Olympus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow Volt, as always, the alpha lives on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dGhvDmCNGr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I describe here the initial design of Volt Protocol, which has since evolved. The vision of creating a borrowing service with an inflation-proof stablecoin remains, but the technical choices have evolved. Read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/volt-protocol/whitepaper/blob/main/volt.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper available here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-beating-inflation-with-returns-on-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;IV/ Beating inflation with returns on volatile assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a world where nothing holds and value leaks, what&amp;rsquo;s left? How about good, proven DeFi assets backed by protocols with massive, recurring revenues shared directly with their holders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few of them, very few. We will detail them one by one, as well as the different options available on them to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-the-origin-and-the-end&#34;&gt;ETH: the origin and the end
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is of course ETH, which has many different sources of return - just like stablecoins, there is nothing to stop you from diversifying your ETH exposure with several sources of return, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH staked with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lido.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lido Finance &lt;/a&gt;(low yield, but a priori the safest) [~5%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rocketpool.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rETH&lt;/a&gt; on Curve (more innovative, more lucrative, more risky) [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vault covered call options on ETH via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stakedao&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ribbon.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ribbon Finance&lt;/a&gt; [~25%, risks!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-chain liquidity on a Bridge, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cbridge.celer.network/#/liquidity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celer&lt;/a&gt; [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A position balanced in this way tracks/exceeds inflation slightly with the returns obtained on ETH. The profitability of the position over the long term depends of course mainly on the average entry price on ETH and its evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crv-cvx-and-fxs-the-three-fates-of-the-defi&#34;&gt;CRV, CVX, and FXS: The three Fates of the DeFi?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Romans, the Fates are three goddesses who govern the lives of humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clotho weaves the thread of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lachesis unwinds it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atropos cuts it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi also knows these Fates: three protocols that play a critical role in the survival and growth of potentially any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in addition to ETH, there are several DeFi projects that have already proven themselves, control substantial revenue streams, and offer a truly relevant service in a macro context of prolonged inflation; I see three essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve Finance - CRV&lt;/strong&gt;: the mother of all yields in DeFi + peg machine and liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convex Finance - CVX&lt;/strong&gt;: an option on CRV, which controls almost 50% of all locked CRVs and adds real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frax Finance - FXS&lt;/strong&gt;: innovative stable project, native DeFi, very productive via AMOs + arrival of FPI + Frax has a big position on CVX &amp;amp; some other protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being tokens backed by key protocols in DeFi, there is no shortage of return options on these three tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV -&amp;gt; Deposit on Convex in CvxCRV then stake or LP cvxCRV/CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVX -&amp;gt; Locked vote on Convex in vlCVX -&amp;gt; Return in cvxCRV + bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FXS -&amp;gt; Direct deposit on Frax (veFXS) or management via Convex (cvxFXS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-promising-tokens&#34;&gt;Other promising tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still other projects that have not yet reached the profitability of Curve or Convex but represent credible bets. In a world where inflation is here to stay, the tools that will allow us to protect ourselves from it can become very popular: I propose you some other theses related to what has been already mentioned in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apwinefi-apw-betting-on-the-advanced-defi-infrastructure&#34;&gt;APWine.fi (APW): betting on the advanced DeFi infrastructure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When inflation goes up, everyone is looking for yield. Let them run behind the %, and instead target the pick sellers in this gold rush. This is the main thesis behind a bet on APW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the article already, APWine offers interesting products to bet on the evolution of yields or even realize a future yield immediately. As DeFi develops, the demand for a product like APWine will keep growing. Will it be APWine, or another one? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the APWine Wars coming up, it&amp;rsquo;s not a stretch to envision bribes similar to what we see on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflexer-flx-a-bet-on-degovernance&#34;&gt;Reflexer (FLX): a bet on degovernance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the very interesting technical approach, Reflexer also innovates on another level. Indeed, since the launch of the protocol, the team has presented a &amp;ldquo;De-governance Plan&amp;rdquo; aiming at progressively minimizing the team&amp;rsquo;s control over the protocol through two main means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of everything that can be automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management by FLX holders for situations still requiring manual analysis/decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;Reflexer now exceeds RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The Money God League is a set of projects building using the Reflexer infrastructure, with the support of the team. So it seems quite natural to consider an airdrop of the governance token of these new projects, including VOLT, to FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last tip: the stakers of the FLX/ETH LP in the Reflexer Safety Module are the last resort to guarantee the solvency of the protocol. If I were to consider an airdrop to thank the Reflexer community, I would probably target them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looksrare-looks-bet-on-nfts&#34;&gt;LooksRare (LOOKS): bet on NFTs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of LOOKS as an option on the NFT market. In fact, LooksRare is the first NFT marketplace that shares revenue. This translates into &lt;strong&gt;an ETH yield for stakers on LOOKS that reached 3 digits sustained during the first few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/looks-eth-farm.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ETH yields on LOOKS staking&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, trading volume has dropped and the ETH yield with it, but &lt;strong&gt;the staking LOOKS is still one of the biggest ETH yields out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with these three suggestions, but of course there are other options - you be the judge. For example, the QI Wars have started and the protocol has good traction. Be careful, however, not to fall into the trap of thinking that all protocols that adopt the ve + bribes model will be as successful as Curve and Convex. ve tokenomics will multiply: it&amp;rsquo;s about making the right choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-and-happy-harvesting-&#34;&gt;Good luck and happy harvesting 🚜
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be tempted to apologize for the length of this article, but I remain confident that it&amp;rsquo;s worth a read and will be informative even for the most knowledgeable DeFians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have considered other useful strategies or protocols for protecting against inflation, please feel free to suggest them to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further reading, here are some recommended related articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-wars/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Curve Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Reflexer RAI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, for the practice, which remains ESSENTIAL, your best bet to warm up is to try with small amounts on inexpensive sidechains/L2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The APWine protocol on Polygon to familiarize yourself with these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting jFIAT / Liquidity contribution on Curve + farming to discover Jarvis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long/short on Forex with jFiats + Fuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: I have invested in APWine pre-sale and I am a big user of the protocol. I am a user and frequent holder of almost all the protocols mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice, I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing my research to help you do yours!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt; for their careful proofreading and their suggestions to help improve this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Janus: the new sworn enemy of DeFi protocols?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-janus/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-janus/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/defi-janus-cover-en.png" alt="Featured image of post Janus: the new sworn enemy of DeFi protocols?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mythology is often used to illustrate DeFi. For example, the Canaanite god Moloch is often mentioned to symbolize coordination issues. Today, I will identify with you a new deity from the DeFi pantheon: Janus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we analyze the mechanisms of open governance of DeFi protocols that can lead to the emergence of a new kind of challenge for DeFi, a sworn enemy that I propose to you to embody in the Roman deity Janus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the two-faced god, &lt;strong&gt;a Janus protocol suffers from a deep ambivalence&lt;/strong&gt;: although it can be an unquestionable success in terms of use, it faces serious antagonisms between its various stakeholders who involve the sustainability of the protocol (users, holders, investors, team and extended community).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To understand the Janus, you have to understand the inherent complexity of DeFi and how it can accommodate &lt;strong&gt;consensus on decisions that are deleterious or not optimal&lt;/strong&gt;. Once the context is set, we can analyze three Janus, each in their own way: MakerDAO, Yearn Finance and Uniswap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;complexity-and-governance-issues-fertile-ground-for-janus&#34;&gt;Complexity and governance issues: fertile ground for Janus
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The emergence of Janus protocols in the current situation is due to many factors that are difficult to prioritize. I have grouped them into three themes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-and-voting-mechanisms&#34;&gt;Governance and voting mechanisms
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The governance of DeFi protocols takes place &lt;strong&gt;in an open and transparent&lt;/strong&gt; way, in several stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During discussions on different media such as Discord, the community converges on different ideas that can lead to proposals. Proposals are formalized, usually on governance forums and amended before reaching &lt;strong&gt;informal consensus&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signaling&lt;/strong&gt; mechanisms (Snapshot) make it possible to identify the most relevant proposals. They are then &lt;strong&gt;submitted to the vote of the token holders&lt;/strong&gt; via the main governance mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most governance systems still operate on the logic of &lt;strong&gt;1 token = 1 vote&lt;/strong&gt;, thus assigning the same weight to all token holders regardless of their attitude towards the project or level of commitment by compared to this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/influence-governance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;influence-governance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Measure the influence in the governance of DeFi protocols -&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Lsquaredleland/status/1411031620748943360&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, some protocols have succeeded in challenging this approach by adding a logic of time commitment: interacting with Curve&amp;rsquo;s DAO requires engaging its CRVs for a period ranging from 1 to 4 years. A long-term commitment increases the effective voting power obtained (vCRV).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, &lt;strong&gt;participation is generally low&lt;/strong&gt;, even when delegation mechanisms are used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;complexity-of-decisions&#34;&gt;Complexity of decisions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To evaluate governance proposals for a decentralized finance protocol, one must have &lt;strong&gt;an understanding of a whole set of basics relating to Ethereum&lt;/strong&gt;, blockchain and DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, ideally, you need a thorough understanding of the protocol in question, as well as its &lt;strong&gt;interactions with other protocols, synergies&lt;/strong&gt;, etc. We can also now add to this all the additional complexity linked to the multiplication of scalability solutions: sidechains and L2.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, the formulation of proposals on governance forums is generally quite technical, which &lt;strong&gt;makes their understanding&lt;/strong&gt; difficult and opens the door to manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, governance suffers from a real mass effect: as protocols develop, the amount of information to digest to have an informed vote increases accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A member of the MakerDAO governance forum estimated his weekly monitoring and participation work to be around 40 hours per week, steadily increasing:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/maker-governance-overhead.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;maker-governance-overhead&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;governance-supports&#34;&gt;Governance supports
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although governance is open and transparent, &lt;strong&gt;it still often relies on various proprietary services and therefore administered&lt;/strong&gt;, most often by the team itself. This causes serious problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So governance-related discussions are usually done on Discord and the Governance Forum - both &lt;strong&gt;mediums are usually moderated directly by the project team&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the team may have &lt;strong&gt;control over reporting mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt; like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://snapshot.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Snapshot&lt;/a&gt;. The accumulation of all these limitations of decentralized governance systems can lead to situations observed recently, where token owners do not vote in their best interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This quick tour of the current limits of governance systems was necessary to have the context for what follows. So let&amp;rsquo;s see the three Janus that I spotted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uniswap-1m-uni-here-1m-uni-there&#34;&gt;Uniswap: 1M UNI here, 1M UNI there
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;proposal-05-in-summary&#34;&gt;Proposal 05 in summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A rushed vote which resulted in the signing of an almost blank check from 1M UNI for a group of legal directors of large decentralized projects responsible for deploying a DeFI lobbying strategy. Very few transparency mechanisms have been deployed and the influence of the UNI holder community on the funded group is limited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.uniswap.org/t/governance-proposal-005-defi-education-fund/12963&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Proposition 05 Uniswap Gouvernance - DeFi Education Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compression-of-governance&#34;&gt;Compression of governance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the case of Uniswap, it was all there. It all started with a rushed vote as members of the community had &lt;strong&gt;many, many questions ignored&lt;/strong&gt;. The community is concerned about the lack of control over the funds allocated without any conditions. Chris Blec has gathered the main questions and concerns in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ChrisBlec/status/1409857319144394758&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a letter&lt;/a&gt; and managed to get some responses from the team in a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://odysee.com/@ChrisBlec:8/chrisblec-june24-twitterspace:9?r=DeLsAYctGhcLFvkGBKYgE2tN17fUXA9u&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Twitter space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;the organization that will receive the 1M UNI is made up of close members of the Uniswap team&lt;/strong&gt; and project investors such as a16z are also suspected of having been decisive in the adoption of the decision. The proposal also had direct support from the team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 17 edit: quickly after receiving the funds, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedefiant.io/sale-of-usdc-raises-concerns-regarding-newly-formed-defi-education-fund/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the multisig sold half of the total balance (500 000 UNI)&lt;/a&gt; for USDC, currently sitting idle in the wallet - not even farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the proposal wants to be broader than Uniswap since they are officially mandated to lobby DeFi, but we can ask the question of the vision of DeFi carried by such profiles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transparency-maybe-control-hell-no-&#34;&gt;Transparency? Maybe. Control? Hell no !
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the reactions to the first iterations of the proposal, different mechanisms have been added to bring more transparency to the actions of the DeFi Education Fund. The team is also committed to implementing &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/withtally/safeguard&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FailSafe&lt;/a&gt; as soon as possible. This would allow the DAO (UNI holders) to be able to exercise a veto on the transactions carried out by the multisig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However at the present time &lt;strong&gt;the effective control of the DAO remains limited&lt;/strong&gt;: the vote has passed and the 1M UNI are now allocated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This episode corresponds for me to the equivalent of an embezzlement of public funds, except that here the funds come from a DAO. The adventure and its adventures also shed light on the effective power exercised by the various stakeholders in the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;makerdao-imbalance-of-competing-interests&#34;&gt;MakerDAO: imbalance of competing interests
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem with Maker is more general and goes back much further. It is a common problem in DeFi of aligning the divergent interests of different participants. In addition, to respond quickly to the growing demand for DAI, &lt;strong&gt;the multiplication of collateral (MCD update) has greatly impacted the trustlessness and effective decentralization of DAI.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over 60% of DAI collateral is tokens that require some form of trust like USDC, wBTC or TUSD. The problem has been around for a long time and is not going to be resolved, if ever. I have already discussed this problem on this blog, I refer you to this article&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/pegged-assets.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp;amp; endgame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abusive-user-fees&#34;&gt;Abusive user fees
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, we will rather dig into the problem of excessive fees which illustrates &lt;strong&gt;a classic case of rent maximization on customers thought to be captive&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; DAI being a synthetic stablecoin struck directly by the user, its annual borrowing fees should not exceed 2-3% and this is still costly. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt;, an alternative to Maker, charges 0.5% annually fees on borrowed LUSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to the last update, the main maker ETH vault (ETH-A) was charging 5.5% annual fees. It&amp;rsquo;s now down to 3.5%, but the fees on the vault closest to Liquity&amp;rsquo;s borrowing conditions (ETH-B, minimum collateralization = 130% // 110% on Liquity) remains at 9% annually, or &lt;strong&gt;18 times more expensive than its alternative&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquity is built with a governance minimization approach, unlike Maker, which may explain part of the huge gap observed between the fees charged by the two platforms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-annuity-for-mkr-holders&#34;&gt;An annuity for MKR holders?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;MakerDAO fees are usually high, even though they&amp;rsquo;ve been at zero or close for short periods of time to stimulate demand. So &lt;strong&gt;why does the DAO Maker systematically vote excessive fees&lt;/strong&gt;? The answer is as simple as 1 + 1 = 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fees taken from Maker vaults are used to buy MKR tokens in the markets and burn them, making the MKR token rarer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are voted by Maker&amp;rsquo;s DAO, in proportion to the MKR tokens owned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The very design of the protocol thus encourages MKR owners to vote for &lt;strong&gt;extracting the maximum fees tolerated by users&lt;/strong&gt;, and not a penny less. Indeed, each base point &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; in additional costs translates into more MKR burned and therefore a priori a capital which is appreciated for the owners of the token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may sound fabulous in terms of tokenomics because it optimizes for the best possible price on MKR (theoretically), but &lt;strong&gt;it is done to the detriment of the users of the service&lt;/strong&gt; that the platform offers - and therefore goes against the long-term interest- term of the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also keep in mind that unlike most protocols, Maker has never implemented a mechanism to turn its users into holders (liquidity mining). So I hardly see how Maker can be competitive with such a structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-ambiguous-case-of-yearn-finance&#34;&gt;The ambiguous case of Yearn Finance
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is arguably the simplest and most straightforward example of a Janus. In barely a year, Yearn has become a &lt;strong&gt;major DeFi protocol with $ 4B in assets deposited&lt;/strong&gt; and above all &lt;strong&gt;delusional profitability&lt;/strong&gt; that the team likes to highlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the story is not so rosy depending on your perspective. We are therefore going to study Yearn&amp;rsquo;s situation from 3 angles: from a user&amp;rsquo;s point of view, for another protocol and for the Yearn DAO itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crazy-fees-for-users&#34;&gt;Crazy fees for users
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s success comes at what cost? Again, essentially &lt;strong&gt;users who are literally being robbed by Yearn&lt;/strong&gt; - fees are among the highest seen for a DeFi asset manager, yet complex:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yearn takes &lt;strong&gt;2% annual management fee on the entire deposit&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yearn also takes a 20% performance fee: 20% of all farmed assets go into cash. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first charge is the most problematic since it means that Yearn&amp;rsquo;s excessively greedy charges lead to vaults that… lose money!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, any vault that does not achieve a minimum of 2% annual return on Yearn ends up in the red once the management fees are taken, without even taking into account the performance fees &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;protocol-side-yearns-hug-of-death&#34;&gt;Protocol side: Yearn&amp;rsquo;s hug of Death
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn allows its users to farm different protocols like Curve by automatically managing the composition of their yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is practical for the user, but it also means that ** Yearn systematically sells all the tokens farmed ** by his vaults: we can therefore ask the question of the impact and relevance for the farmed protocol, which is therefore under selling pressure on its native token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The arrival of Convex has shown that a better structured protocol in terms of tokenomics and specific to Curve can offer a synergistic alternative where the returns are much higher, while avoiding the systematic sale of farmed tokens. I analyze the Convex &amp;ldquo;flywheel&amp;rdquo; in this article:&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/defi-flywheel.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🎡 DeFi Flywheel : engineering protocol to protocol synergies through tokens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thereby, it confronted Yearn with its contradictions and Yearn essentially capitulated by integrating Convex to optimize the performance of its vaults. This now means that &lt;strong&gt;Yearn users pay a fee to Convex and help the protocol accumulate more VeCRV&lt;/strong&gt; and thus widen its gap with Yearn - checkmate for Yearn on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/vecrv-par-dao.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;vecrv-par-dao&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Overview of the veCRVs owned by the different DAOs - source&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://duneanalytics.com/banteg/misc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dune Analytics / Banteg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;concerning-yearn-dao&#34;&gt;Concerning Yearn DAO
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite this rather worrying fundamental situation since Yearn now offers &lt;strong&gt;essentially non-competitive products&lt;/strong&gt; (all Curve vaults), Yearn presents itself as one of the undeniable successes of DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the team seems to measure the success of the protocol by the volume of fees collected by it. The indicator is obviously dangerous since with the management fees at 2% per year, any deposit in Yearn systematically pays fees even if little or no profit is made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than taking the fees charged as an indicator and therefore a measure of success, the protocol could be optimized on the basis of the profits generated for depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, and even if it is a more subjective topic, the communication around the project is muddled or even almost disturbing at times, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedefiant.io/yearn-revenues-projected-to-surpass-tradfis-fueled-by-thriving-community/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;when Yearn is compared&lt;/a&gt; to traditional asset managers like WealthFront or BlackRock - I find that quite unbalanced since Yearn charges similar fees to these structures but operates in a much more dynamic market. In addition, are such companies really relevant models to have in DeFi?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/yearn-comp.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;yearn-comp&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Yearn compares to asset managers, it may be because the comparison with its DeFi peers is clear:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/defi-asset-manager.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-asset-manager&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, where Convex works to allow cvxCRV holders to vote in decisions of the DAO Curve, Yearn is taking control over the voting power associated with CRVs deposited by its users on the yveCRV. The same approach can be observed with the airdrops allocated to VeCRV holders: Yearn grants them to buy CRVs and sponsor their yveCRV vault, while Convex makes them accessible to its depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-the-janus-defensible&#34;&gt;Are the Janus defensible?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we have set the scene with three Janus, the question of their defendability remains. All three have credible alternatives, often more recent and with more balanced tokenomics. So let&amp;rsquo;s see how our Janus evolve in relation to these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just two months of existence, Convex has already surpassed Yearn in terms of the total value of assets deposited. So far, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s feedback has failed to turn the tide, and I think &lt;strong&gt;only a major overhaul of the model will allow the protocol to remain competitive in the long run&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless &lt;strong&gt;the machine is launched&lt;/strong&gt;: Convex already has more than twice as many CRVs as Yearn and accumulates more quickly. And even though Yearn has lots of other protocols, it seems unlikely to me that he will ever be able to compete again on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Marker side, more and more people are starting to point out the absurdity of the current situation on DAI, and the alternatives are gaining ground. In a few weeks and with only ETH as accepted collateral, Liquity has already attracted the equivalent of more than 40% of the total value deposited in MakerDAO:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-janus/tokenterminal-tvl-maker-liquity.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;tokenterminal-tvl-maker-liquity&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Liquity, borrowing costs are much lower, clearer, and distributed directly to LQTY stakers. The service is thus more open and participatory than MakerDAO while being brutally more efficient. Here again, I think a major overhaul of MakerDAO would be necessary for the protocol to regain its relevance and competitiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for Uniswap, the competition is even fiercer. The protocol is evolving in the face of mature tokenomics like Curve, which has a protocol revenue sharing mechanism active for almost a year, while nothing is yet offered on UNI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On all three fronts, I think the situation will force Uniswap, Maker and Yearn to renew themselves. However, with the pace of the industry, the noose is tightening and their more open, efficient and synergistic alternatives are rapidly gaining ground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the DAOs of the three protocols fell out of sync with their users, the latter reminded them where their interests lay in the simplest and most effective way we know of: with consistent capital movement. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what happens next!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forum.makerdao.com/t/mip33-maker-stability-price-module/5943&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this pre-proposal taken at random from the MakerDAO governance forum&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAI is still seen by many as a decentralized stablecoin that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require trust, although it no longer does. There are still few stablecoins that rely only on trustless (ETH) and credibly decentralized (or on track) collateral: I know of two - Liquity&amp;rsquo;s LUSD and Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s RAI.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial services fees are often measured in basis point (bps / basis point). A basis point is one hundredth of a percent: 1 bps = 0.01%.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.yearn.finance/yearn-finance/yvaults/overview#yvault-fee-structure&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance documentation - Fee structure&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🎡 DeFi Flywheel : engineering protocol to protocol synergies through tokens</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-flywheel/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-flywheel/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/defi-flywheel-cover-en.png" alt="Featured image of post 🎡 DeFi Flywheel : engineering protocol to protocol synergies through tokens" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In three weeks, the Convex protocol attracted over $3 billion in deposits, while becoming the largest 🐳 whale of CRV, today and probably forever. Luck is never a negligible factor, but with such a smashing entry into DeFi top protocols, we must look much further. Indeed, the key to understanding the meteoric rise of Convex is tokenomics, and this is our topic of the day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, besides the technical, you also have to be a fine sociologist, or rather a &amp;ldquo;game theorist&amp;rdquo; as we say around here: to know how to anticipate the reactions of crowds to a given set of rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of liquidity mining programs last year showed that the right set of rules can move huge amounts of capital. The question now is how to do it wisely, i.e. with an awareness of what is at stake &lt;strong&gt;in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, liquidity mining by itself only attracts &lt;strong&gt;mercenary and opportunistic deposits&lt;/strong&gt;. In fact, liquidity mining is more a tool to make a project known than to perpetuate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To last in DeFi, it is a matter of tokenomics: i.e. the mechanics of the native tokens of protocols. &lt;strong&gt;Tokenomics is in a way the gameplay of a DeFi protocol&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, I am a big fan of the CRV model. It&amp;rsquo;s perfect, since the game around the CRV token has never been as lively as it has been in the last few weeks. Some people even talk about #lockening to describe &lt;strong&gt;the race to accumulate CRVs&lt;/strong&gt; that Convex, Yearn and StakeDAO are engaged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go into details to understand the concept of flywheel with the example of Convex / Curve. I will finish by analyzing protocols that could be used in a similar scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-rise-of-the-first--defi-flywheel&#34;&gt;The rise of the first 🎡 DeFi flywheel
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the launch of Convex, a new term began to be used to describe its operation and tokenomics: 🎡 flywheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There isn&amp;rsquo;t a precise definition yet, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try one: it describes a protocol that achieves a winning trifecta:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A tokenomics that offers interesting opportunities to token owners optimistic about the future of the model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A protocol that is itself relevant and meets a real need, ideally in direct synergy with another protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A liquidity mining program (+airdrop) to start the loop and attract the first token owners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I generalized the Convex model, but it has an additional feature: Convex is a kind of &amp;ldquo;meta-protocol&amp;rdquo;: it is &lt;strong&gt;built entirely on top of Curve Finance and in synergy with it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the forerunner of the flywheel would probably be found among protocols built in synergy with others. For example, although it is built on top of BSC and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rekt.news/pancakebunny-rekt/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;suffered a significant attack recently&lt;/a&gt;, the Bunny protocol helped the DEX PancakeSwap to develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bunny offers to manage Pancake liquidity provider positions, while issuing its own token based on the returns generated. This simplifies the management of liquidity providers positions on Pancake while generating an additional source of return (BUNNY token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to fully understand the concept of 🎡 flywheel, let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the best one we&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to see so far: Convex. It turns out to be a bit more complicated because it relies on Curve, so you first need to understand the curve tokenomics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crv-a-tokenomics-for--flywheels&#34;&gt;CRV: a tokenomics for 🎡 flywheels?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve Finance&amp;rsquo;s tokenomics is almost a year old and yet it is still often misunderstood&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The great elegance of the CRV tokenomics resides in &lt;strong&gt;aligning the interests of several actors better than any other tokenomics known to date&lt;/strong&gt;: the liquidity providers, the CRV holders and the Curve protocol itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the model tends over time to merge the two populations (CRV holders and LP) through two mechanics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity providers are incensitivised in CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV stakers (VeCRV holders) can &amp;ldquo;boost&amp;rdquo; the CRV yield of their liquidity provision on Curve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model creates an interesting path for protocol users, who are &lt;strong&gt;strongly encouraged to make a long-term commitment&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, locking CRVs into VeCRVs becomes more and more efficient the longer the commitment is - the maximum being 4 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go further, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakecapital.substack.com/p/curve-tokenomics-and-first-mover&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/crv-tokenomics.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-tokenomics&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the CRV model also has its limitations, the most obvious one being the impact of Ethereum transaction fees: large sums of money can be required for the game to start making sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, for a long time now, the biggest contributors of liquidity on Curve have not been users but &lt;strong&gt;other protocols&lt;/strong&gt;. Pooling funds reduces the impact of gas fees while potentially developing a VeCRV accumulation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, various solutions have emerged to &lt;strong&gt;manage liquidity positions on Curve&lt;/strong&gt;, the best known being Yearn, but there are also Harvest and StakeDAO. While they can be useful for depositors, they suffer from two major limitations: high management fees and a parasitic approach. Yearn, Harvest or StakeDAO immediately sell any farmed tokens. This results in increasing selling pressure on the native token of the protocols used to produce the return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-convex-model--the-first-flywheel-&#34;&gt;The Convex model : the first flywheel 🎡
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Convex way to operate offers a &amp;ldquo;Yearn-like&amp;rdquo; service  to liquidity providers on Curve: automated management of their position to maximize returns. Like Yearn, Convex has a VeCRV accumulation strategy to maximize the return of depositors in CRV through the boost mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the underlying approach is totally different from Yearn and is part of a virtuous synergy with Curve :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No systematic selling&lt;/strong&gt;: unlike Yearn, Convex does not sell the tokens it farms. Liquidity providers are thus remunerated in CRV but also in CVX, the native token of Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fees collected by Convex are 100% dedicated to the protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, while Yearn for example pays strategists - obviously quite redundant on a simple strategy like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the distribution of the collected fees, Convex creates two &lt;strong&gt;interesting staking opportunities&lt;/strong&gt; to compose its returns, detailed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;the liquidity&lt;/strong&gt; on the token that represents a CRV in Convex (CvxCRV) is more optimal than the Yearn equivalent: CvxCRV trades in a pool directly against the CRV, with an incentive program in CVX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fees--the-lifeblood-of-success&#34;&gt;Fees : the lifeblood of success
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the fee structure is key to get what has happened with Convex. The protocol now controls over 32M VeCRVs, which is &lt;strong&gt;almost twice Yearn&amp;rsquo;s total, and that&amp;rsquo;s just after three weeks of existence&lt;/strong&gt;.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/convex-curve-stats.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;convex-curve-stats&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convex charges a total fee of 16% on all CRVs farmed on the protocol (compared to 20/2 on all tokens for Yearn, or 30% for Harvest for example). Of the 16%, 1% is used to cover operational costs such as the gas cost of collections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/convex-synergies-CRV-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;convex-synergies-CRV&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most interesting part is the redistribution of the remaining 15%, i.e. 15% of all CRVs farmed by Convex (&lt;strong&gt;over 400,000 CRVs per day&lt;/strong&gt; You can view the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/pools?see=0x989aeb4d175e16225e39e87d0d97a3360524ad80&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Convex Curve position via CurveMarketCap here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two staker populations are eligible for this juicy pie:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10% is paid back to CvxCRV&lt;/strong&gt; stakers, in CRV, in addition to their return in 3pool and CVX tokens (+airdrops VeCRV holder). Owning CvxCRV becomes much more attractive than VeCRV for a simple depositor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5% is returned to the CVX stakers&lt;/strong&gt;, in the form of CvxCRV. This means that 5% of all CRVs farmed by Convex are captured and locked within the protocol. This mechanically increases the pool of VeCRVs even if no third party CRV deposits are made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The situation is still ongoing and there are still surprising gaps: for example, at the time of writing (June 07) the total capitalization of the CVX token is not even half of the value of the CRVs that the protocol has ($30M vs $80M). I think the situation will harmonize in the long run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-anticipate-the-next-flywheels&#34;&gt;How to anticipate the next flywheels?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With some notions about Curve and an analysis of the flywheel 🎡 Convex, we now have the cards in hand to venture into the game of foresight. Before that however I propose instead to go look into the past to analyze an almost failed flywheel : Pickle Finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pickle-finance--the-wrong-timing&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance : the wrong timing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On paper, Pickle has all the makings of a flywheel: it is a system to increase the returns on Yearn deposits through the additional issue of PICKLE tokens. PICKLE has elements of the VeCRV system, with a locking mechanism (DILL) that allows to boost PICKLE returns on deposits on Pickle Finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that&amp;hellip; Pickle does not technically add anything to Yearn, apart from issuing PICKLE. Moreover, Pickle does not specialize: farms are offered on Yearn vaults but also some Sushi pairs. Unlike Convex, Pickle is therefore not able to develop a unique advantage (moat) on farmed services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, nothing is definitive. Pickle&amp;rsquo;s situation could evolve, if the tokenomics of the underlying protocols (YFI and SUSHI) evolve. Both protocols seem to be moving towards a reappropriation of the VeCRV model, so it is quite possible. A model that combines the Adamant/Ellipsis burn logic and the Curve boosting has even been proposed for Sushi: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forum.sushi.com/t/sushinomics-introducing-osushi/4055&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;oSUSHI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/veYFI.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;veYFI&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adamant-finance---a-flywheel-on-polygons-lp-&#34;&gt;Adamant Finance : 🎡 a flywheel on Polygon&amp;rsquo;s LP ?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adamant is a still new protocol that exists on the Polygon sidechain. It allows the easy management of liquidity positions on the main exchange services: QuickSwap, Cometh, SushiSwap, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to automatic compounding of returns, Adamant also offers additional ADDY rewards (based on profits generated). All ADDY earned are vested (locked) for 3 months and can be withdrawn earlier with a 50% penalty. This is redistributed to those who agree to staker + lock their ADDY for 3 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, all ADDY stakers (even vested ones) benefit from a share of the fees collected by the platform, distributed in wMATIC. The protocol thus has a tokenomics already quite elaborate with different retention mechanisms, but it still has some improvements to find to become a flywheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first one would be to introduce a greater incentive to lock in ADDYs through a boost system similar to Curve. Depositors with ADDYs in stake+lock will have a better return in ADDYs on their LP position. This is already under discussion or even in development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adamant still has to develop a synergy with the farmed protocols as strong as Convex with Curve. This is difficult or impossible for the moment because none of them have tokenomics as subtle as CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-x-liquity-service---money-market-flywheel&#34;&gt;An &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; Liquity service : 🎡 money market flywheel
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we have discussed flywheels built on decentralized exchange services, which seems the most obvious. Nevertheless, we can consider similar models on other types of services, like money markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I propose to finish with a theoretical flywheel of my own. To my knowledge, such a protocol does not exist yet: it&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic equation is simple:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a strong demand for &amp;ldquo;ETH passive&amp;rdquo; products - products that develop strategies on ETH in order to accumulate ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One option is to borrow stablecoins using ETH as collateral. This way, stablecoins can earn an additional return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this strategy, Liquity would be &lt;strong&gt;the platform of choice without question&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the cost of borrowing is the lowest in the market (almost 12x cheaper than Maker over a year) and there is no shortage of opportunities for yield on the LUSD stablecoin.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/defi-flywheel/protocole-x-liquity-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;protocole-x-liquity&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge of such a pooled strategy is to &lt;strong&gt;manage the collateralization ratio&lt;/strong&gt; and to be able to balance it quickly if the market moves. Here again, Liquity lends itself well to this since the stability pool offers an attractive return on the LUSD while allowing &lt;strong&gt;the rapid mobilization of LUSD to repay the debt if necessary&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The X protocol in question would offer &lt;strong&gt;a passive ETH investment product&lt;/strong&gt; for users who would not have to manage the position themselves. We can also consider that the X protocol has its own token with a tokenomics that addresses one of the main dangers of the strategy: the lack of predictability. Thus the native token of protocol X could be used to encourage long deposits of a predictable duration (users lock their ETH over 3/6/9/12 months for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long term commitments also allow to &lt;strong&gt;develop a strategy on the LQTY farmed by the LUSDs.&lt;/strong&gt; By committing ETH for one year in the protocol for example, the user will be able to claim a portion of the LQTYs farmed by the whole protocol, and benefited, for life, from the LUSDs and ETHs they generate. The synergy of the protocol with Liquity as well as the long term returns are maximized if protocol X does not sell any LQTY, as is the case in the concept proposed above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article will help you better understand what has been going on with Convex, Yearn and Curve over the past few weeks and use the lessons learned from this episode to identify similar opportunities in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about different incentive mechanisms is that they precede action. In game theory, there are no certainties, but some behaviors are almost mechanical - for those who really understand incentives and their issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it for yourself !&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🗡 Risk? Yes please, but exactly how I like it</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/risk-tranching-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/risk-tranching-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/cover.gif" alt="Featured image of post 🗡 Risk? Yes please, but exactly how I like it" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeFi has grown tremendously over the past year, partly thanks to the appearance of more streamlined investment products such as Yearn&amp;rsquo;s or Harvest&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/vaults.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;vaults&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to their architecture, they facilitate the mutualization of capital which enables smaller yet profitable investments on money markets and other DeFi services like Curve or SushiSwap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a necessary and much-welcomed layer, and several improvements are still to be made to streamline things even further and increase gas efficiency. However, I believe the bulk of the innovation this year will come from another front: risk management on the vault-type products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, several definancial primitives have been developed to provide more options to segregate and hedge risks. There are now credible insurance options available for DeFi, as well as a new approach (in DeFi) to better distribute the risk between consenting and informed actors: tranching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll dive right in, but just before that, I think it&amp;rsquo;s apt to examine the terminology too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-lending-protocols-to-money-markets&#34;&gt;From Lending Protocols to Money Markets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve been reading me for a while, you might have seen the term &amp;ldquo;lending protocol&amp;rdquo; being used. While it was suited to describe their first purpose, I believe the concept has now outgrown the word, so I&amp;rsquo;ll refer to them as money market from now on. Indeed, &amp;ldquo;lending protocol&amp;rdquo; fails to capture all the subtleties now offered by services like Aave — I&amp;rsquo;m actually a bit late to the party of this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a sense, the change of nomenclature reflects the different stages of evolution of these money markets. In their first months of existence, there was &lt;strong&gt;a liquidity imperative&lt;/strong&gt;: it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a fight to grow to a sizeable size, big enough to justify interest from other projects to integrate with the money market fuelling a positive growth loop as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen on Aave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/aave-debank.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Aave TVL Growth - Debank&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the critical mass is reached, &lt;strong&gt;the focus can and must evolve&lt;/strong&gt;. To further expand, the money market must extend its range of features - again, like we&amp;rsquo;ve seen Aave do with flashloans and fixed rate loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems clear now that &lt;strong&gt;the second phase of growth of the money markets will be feature-driven&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the base features available on the money market are essential, as these markets are more integrated into other DeFi protocols. The money markets with the most flexibility at the base layer will be able to handle more intricate use cases, such as credit delegation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But today, I want to focus this piece on a risk management concept that hasn&amp;rsquo;t found its way to a mainstream money market yet: &lt;strong&gt;tranching&lt;/strong&gt;. Let&amp;rsquo;s see what it can enable!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tranching-would-you-like-another-slice-of-risk&#34;&gt;Tranching: would you like another slice of risk?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To begin, let&amp;rsquo;s start with &lt;strong&gt;the most straightforward &amp;ldquo;risk alteration&amp;rdquo; there is - tranching&lt;/strong&gt;. The idea here is quite straightforward: the different risk layers taken by the depositor of a given money market are tranched - meaning segregated one from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each depositor can choose his preferred exposure. It enables, for instance, a confident degen to &lt;strong&gt;bear all available layers of risk to maximize his APY&lt;/strong&gt; while a more conservative whale could &lt;strong&gt;downsize its risk perimeter&lt;/strong&gt; by exposing oneself to the technical risk only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the core idea, but let&amp;rsquo;s not forget we&amp;rsquo;re talking about decentralized finance here, so &lt;strong&gt;composability is key&lt;/strong&gt;. What makes tranching so exciting is its future as a &lt;strong&gt;financial primitive&lt;/strong&gt; - a building block that other apps and projects can use to deliver new services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore more in-depth what tranching as financial primitive entails right after we consider how it currently works in practice, and examine the broader context of risk hedging and APY fixation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to DeFi or even finance in general, you might wonder why we care so much about these different flavors of risks?
You can picture these mechanisms enabling diverse types of risk exposure as building blocks making it possible to &lt;strong&gt;build end-user products fitting all ranges of risk appetite&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explain why tranching matters more explicitly in the last part of this article where we consider some end-game scenarios for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-tranching-in-practice&#34;&gt;Risk tranching in practice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This whole article was actually inspired by a tweet I published where I shared what a tranched aDAI could look like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of today, there is mostly one product delivering tranching on mainnet I&amp;rsquo;m looking at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://saffron.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Saffron Finance&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a tranching abstraction layer built on top of the Compound DAI market. The risk segregation is straightforward with two main tranches + one:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;AA tranche&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;covered in case of platform failure&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;A tranche&lt;/strong&gt;, supplying the cover for the AA tranche (= slashing if a failure occurs) but earns a much &lt;strong&gt;more favorable APY&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a third tranche - the &lt;strong&gt;S tranche&lt;/strong&gt;. However, it is simply rebalancing between the two others as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/saffron.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The different tranches available on Saffron Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tranching occurs on an epoch-basis, currently set at two weeks. So if you supply the A tranche, for instance, you are bearing the risk of platform failure for the AA tranche for a 2 week period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the excitement that followed the launch, Saffron grew to close to $60M assets deposited. Since then, the dust settled around a low bar of roughly $15M of assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/saffron-debank.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Saffron Finance TVL - Debank&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the charts, we can see some sharp withdrawals: it&amp;rsquo;s due to the epoch-based logic of Saffron. At the end of every epochs, depositors are not earning rewards anymore until they pull out and deposit in the next epoch tranches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saffron is looking to expand to other money markets, most obviously Aave and expand their token coverage (currently only DAI). Other projects are exploring the idea of tranching, most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://barnbridge.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BarnBridge&lt;/a&gt;, but their current achievements are less enticing in my book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last minute edit: BarnBridge &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/CoinbaseCustody/status/1348739247277268997&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BOND token is now listed on Coinbase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a more practical understanding of tranching and how it can work, let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back to understand what it provides in the broader context of risk management in decentralized finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-the-broader-context-of-risk-management-in-defi&#34;&gt;Understanding the broader context of risk management in DeFi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve focused on the sole risk related to the definancial product itself: mainly smart contract risks, oracle, and economic attacks. We&amp;rsquo;ve left at least two layers of risk untouched:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;APY Variation&lt;/strong&gt;: The APY of the service used is usually variable, so there is an additional layer of exposure there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token Price Fluctuation&lt;/strong&gt;: Sometimes, the returns are paid in token different from the ones deposited. If the payout token is not a stablecoin, its price can vary - meaning there is yet an additional layer of exposure to consider here if we want to be exhaustive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, to fully understand the broader context, let&amp;rsquo;s not forget that there are several distinct &amp;ldquo;temporal approaches&amp;rdquo; to risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using an approach such as tranching, you can be &lt;strong&gt;proactive&lt;/strong&gt;, splitting the risk &lt;strong&gt;beforehand&lt;/strong&gt; between participants that understand their exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can also go hand in hand with more &lt;strong&gt;reactive approaches&lt;/strong&gt;, such as insurance - a system providing payout &lt;strong&gt;afterward&lt;/strong&gt; in the event of a failure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurance markets are another fascinating topic by themselves, so we&amp;rsquo;ll stick to this simple mention for now and go back to our yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While we&amp;rsquo;re talking about insurance, a fascinating project just launched - Unslashed Finance. It&amp;rsquo;s made in France by a builder I admire, so I&amp;rsquo;m a little biased, but feel free &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/unslashed/manifesto-for-a-decentralised-crypto-insurance-unslashed-finance-873078fd0ddd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;to read their manifesto&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more about their vision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;another-take-on-risk-management-for-yields-apy-fixation&#34;&gt;Another take on risk management for yields: APY-fixation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we were saying, the APY of the different yield products available in decentralized finance are constantly fluctuating. It makes for a less predictable income and prevents the entry of investors who are not willing to stomach several layers of risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this issue, another layer of meta-financial services is emerging - the base value proposition as an investor is quite simple: they offer a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY on depositors&amp;rsquo; investments&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially another flavor of &amp;ldquo;insurance&amp;rdquo;: you&amp;rsquo;ll get overall a bit of a lower yield, but it&amp;rsquo;s predictable. It&amp;rsquo;s very similar to a stable-interest loan on Aave (vs variable rate).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buyer side of such services is super interesting: picture it &lt;strong&gt;like a prediction market, for the yield of a given vault or investment product.&lt;/strong&gt; Buyers deposit some assets and place a bet on the expected average yield: the closer their prediction is, the better is the return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t see the buyer side becoming mainstream anytime soon, but it provides the backbone to yet another useful financial primitive useful to provide services more suited to more risk-averse investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;apy-fixation-in-practice&#34;&gt;APY-Fixation in practice
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, there are two projects working on delivering fixed-APY yield on popular decentralized investment products such as the Yearn vaults: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://88mph.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;88mph&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Saffron, 88mph is another abstraction layer built on top of Compound, Aave, and Harvest deposits. It provides a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY for depositors&lt;/strong&gt;, while on the other side of the market buyers of floating-rate bonds are bearing the risk of the fluctuations of the APY of the underlying investment product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/risk-tranching/88mph.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;88mph main interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-does-the-endgame-look-like&#34;&gt;What does the endgame look like?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s wrap this up with a little thought experiment. We&amp;rsquo;re now leaving the present and what is currently live on the Ethereum mainnet to extrapolate a bit and consider what tranching &amp;amp; other risk management approaches can enable in DeFi a few months or years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An investment product built, for instance, on the Aave money market:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a Saffron-like product integrated into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also with an 88mph-like service integrated into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, an insurance such as Unslashed also natively integrated for the DAI peg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could envision &lt;strong&gt;the first &amp;ldquo;risk-free&amp;rdquo; DeFi investment&lt;/strong&gt;, which would be a wrapped deposit of say DAI on Aave, coming along with tranching to only bear the price risk hedged by a coverage against DAI losing its peg on Unslashed earning a fixed APY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s insane to consider the different steps of the evolution of let&amp;rsquo;s say DAI we witnessed or are about to witness in barely two years:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest-bearing&lt;/strong&gt; DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a &lt;strong&gt;fixed APY&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a fixed APY &lt;strong&gt;not bearing the technical risks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interest-bearing DAI with a fixed APY not bearing the technical risks &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;covered against DAI losing its peg&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aFIXEDAPYDAI_PEGINSURED: our new monetary overlord? The actual name will be way more catchy, rest assured!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you ready to witness &lt;strong&gt;the future of money unfolding methodically before your very eyes as your assets receive software updates&lt;/strong&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one cannot wait: I&amp;rsquo;ve been prepping for the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Waël for making the cover image featured at the top of this article (as well as the TokenBrice emblem).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-merger-spree/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/y-among-us.gif" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Merger Spree" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn Finance has been making headlines lately with the announcement of &lt;strong&gt;several acquisitions&lt;/strong&gt; like Pickle Finance or SushiSwap. The Yearn team has joined its development forces with five other DeFi projects already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To grasp what&amp;rsquo;s happening, we&amp;rsquo;ll look back at the main events since September and how each of the different sub-projects is now working to achieve a shared goal. While Yearn is still relatively new, there are already many chapters to its story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So to better understand the latest events - the merger spree, let&amp;rsquo;s first quickly consider the three phases of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development and how they led to today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The beginnings of Yearn with the fair launch of the YFI token&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How YFI&amp;rsquo;s launch became a template with the waifus (forks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The development of the Yearn Ecosystem: Yearn beyond the vaults&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-backstory-launch-waifus--the-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Backstory: Launch, waifus &amp;amp; the ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last June, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s token launch was a unique moment, initiating what is now called a &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Essentially, the &lt;strong&gt;YFI token was distributed over a week to users&lt;/strong&gt; depositing to several pools related to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s products. Feel free to check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my first story on Yearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to learn more about this moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It translated into a growing awareness for the project, a rapid price appreciation of the token, and attracted involved DeFi users to contribute to Yearn through the DAO&amp;rsquo;s discussions. The launch was so successful that it actually became a template replicated more or less successfully by many other projects: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-waifus.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s waifus (forks)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, Yearn was focusing on its own products, the main ones being the vaults enabling streamlined implementations of farming strategies. The vaults too grew beyond Yearn to become a product offered by many DeFi services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The direction was not exactly clear back then. Indeed, there were many products being worked on, such as yBorrow, ySwap, yinsure, or the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decrypt.co/43292/eminence-finance-exploit-leads-to-degen-soul-searching&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Eminence exploit&lt;/a&gt;. However, the core product, the vaults saw little improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the last few months, the vision for Yearn&amp;rsquo;s development evolved. Instead of an inward-facing plan focused on the ecosystem, the Yearn team started to look outward. At the same moment, Yearn&amp;rsquo;s DAO was structuring its processes and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/yip-54-formalize-operations-funding/7956&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;formalized operations fundings&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It leads to the current merger phase - joining development efforts with other DeFi projects on relevant areas of expertise. Token-wise, nothing is changed, each project keeps its own token and sovereignty over it. So let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yearns-mergers&#34;&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s Mergers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the context set, let&amp;rsquo;s now look at the different projects joining forces with Yearn and how they contribute to add value to the offering. We&amp;rsquo;ll consider them as they happened, in their chronological order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Some of these mergers are still pending a token holder vote to be validated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A NFT was made to immortalize this moment of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s history: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.rarible.com/token/0xd07dc4262bcdbf85190c01c996b4c06a461d2430:90731:0xac6d5c44c7a089101c53735211b12f5f722c7688&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yAmong us, by Cryptouf - available on Rarible&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;pickle-finance-1124&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance (11/24)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: PICKLE&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;symbiotic relationship&amp;rdquo; with Pickle Finance was the first to be introduced on November 24. The idea is to merge the efforts of the two projects currently offering similar products. Pickle will now deliver an &lt;strong&gt;incentive mechanism on top of the Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; through gauges, similar to Curve&amp;rsquo;s current model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By joining forces, it creates additional options for Yearn vaults depositors while securing the assets deposited in the Pickle jars, one of which was subject to a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cointelegraph.com/news/pickle-in-a-pickle-as-attacker-swipes-20-million-in-evil-jar-exploit&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;$20 million exploit &lt;/a&gt;shortly before the merge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cream-finance-1126&#34;&gt;Cream Finance (11/26)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: CREAM&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Money Market - Lending &amp;amp; Borrowing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger with Cream is even more exciting as it would expand the range of strategies Yearn vaults could use. Cream is a lending platform, a fork of Compound with several changes including the collateral accepted. yUSD (Yearn yCRV vault share) has been supported as collateral for a few months already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two teams teaming up mean a more systematic approach, eventually &lt;strong&gt;paving the way for leveraged vaults&lt;/strong&gt;: the vault token share being used as collateral on Cream to borrow more stablecoin and increase exposure. Cream would eventually become the lending arm of the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cream-v2-merger-e9fa6c6989b4&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;More info in the announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;cover-protocol-1128&#34;&gt;Cover Protocol (11/28)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: COVER&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Peer to peer coverage market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn has been trying to provide coverage and insurance for its products, with projects like yInsure. So working with another project on this front is highly synergistic, since it could enable &lt;strong&gt;coverage for Yearn vaults&lt;/strong&gt; while allowing the team to focus on its core offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/iearn/yearn-cover-merger-651142828c45&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the announcement here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;akropolis-1130&#34;&gt;Akropolis (11/30)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: AKRO&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Streamlined investment products (vaults)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won&amp;rsquo;t expand too much into this one, as it&amp;rsquo;s very similar to Pickle. Akropolis was providing services similar to the vaults, so &lt;strong&gt;joining forces allow increasing TVL&lt;/strong&gt; by creating another frontend for Yearn/Pickle while beefing up the security of Akropolis, as it too suffered &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://news.bitcoin.com/hackers-drain-2-million-in-dai-from-defi-protocol-akropolis/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an exploit for $2M&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sushiswap-1201&#34;&gt;SushiSwap (12/01)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Token&lt;/em&gt;: SUSHI&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Service&lt;/em&gt;: Decentralized Exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sushi is now &lt;strong&gt;the second DEX by volume&lt;/strong&gt; with roughly half ($889M) of the total value locked of Uniswap. To attract liquidity to the platform, Sushi distributes its token to the providers of liquidity on certain key pairs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could allow Yearn to &lt;strong&gt;incentivize liquidity providing for critical pairs of the Yearn ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;, such as a CRV &amp;lt;&amp;gt; yyveCRV to drive deposit into this vault which can provide additional returns for other Yearn deposits on Curve. The team joins efforts so that Sushi/0xMaki can lead the AMM efforts amongst the ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-does-it-mean-for-yearn&#34;&gt;What does it mean for Yearn?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While this merger spree is a &lt;strong&gt;massive increase in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s firepower&lt;/strong&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s also a &lt;strong&gt;form of recentering&lt;/strong&gt;: some key parts of the ecosystem are delegated, such as the AMM (swaps) to Sushiswap&amp;rsquo;s team, or the lending markets to Cream. It should enable the team to move faster on its core products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are now so many mergers announced that CoinGecko created a category to track them: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.coingecko.com/en?category_id=yearn-yfi-partnerships-mergers&amp;amp;view=market&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🦎YFI Partnerships &amp;amp; Mergers Coins by Market Capitalization&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, composability is key and Yearn is yet another demonstration of what it can achieve. Indeed, there is one last dimension to stress with these mergers: liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-merger/yearn-merger-tvl.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn-Merger-TVL-Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With these 5 acquisitions, Yearn will roughly triple its total value of assets locked across its ecosystem. Along with the synergies, it could help Yearn develop a moat that will be hard to beat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🤖 Vaults: DeFi Investing Streamlined?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/vaults-defi-investing-streamlined/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/vaults-defi-investing-streamlined/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/vaults/harvest.gif" alt="Featured image of post 🤖 Vaults: DeFi Investing Streamlined?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the ecosystem of decentralized financial services on Ethereum grows and matures, the service offering is becoming more dense and sometimes hard to understand. While the most technically savvy users can chase the latest releases and hedge their risk appropriately, less-seasoned investors might feel left out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there are DeFi services made to match the diverse set of investors exploring the space. Yearn Finance was the first platform to pioneer a passive-type of investment products: vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The base idea is simple as 1, 2, 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vaults are &lt;strong&gt;tokenized investment strategies&lt;/strong&gt;: your deposit is represented by a token (for instance, yCRV in Yearn’s Vault -&amp;gt; yyCRV/yUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The vault frequently harvest and re-invest the profits&lt;/strong&gt; (here CRV) to purchase more of the base asset supplied, compounding the returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fees are streamlined&lt;/strong&gt;: the depositors do not pay for the gas costs of the vaults operation (such as harvesting). Fees are usually charged while exiting the vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you&amp;rsquo;d like to &lt;strong&gt;avoid the headaches&lt;/strong&gt; of chasing the latest farm, managing the claim of the profits you earn, when and how to reinvest them, without forgetting, of course, to account for the gas costs of all these operations in the calculation of your profits, vaults are a credible alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vaults are made to &lt;strong&gt;abstract the complexity for the end-users&lt;/strong&gt;. You deposit some tokens and wait while they are farming a set strategy for you. So let&amp;rsquo;s see what options are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is straight to the point and highlights the different vaults available. To learn more about Yearn Finance debuts, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;read this piece&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. For more context on Yearn’s forks, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-waifus.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;check this one&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;simplest-basic-vaults&#34;&gt;Simplest: Basic Vaults
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vaults use the token you deposit (DAI for instance) to farm a given strategy, produce a return and re-invest it automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pioneer is of course Yearn with the yCRV vault, but several options are now available or progressively rolling out. This article provides a structured overview of the main earning opportunities enabled by vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, you deposit a given token to earn more of it over time, and potentially additional reward. The tokens you are supplying are not used to provide liquidity on decentralized exchanges, &lt;strong&gt;so there is no exposure to impermanent losses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;as more and more vault-types products are being released, you want to take the time to understand what&amp;rsquo;s happening with the one you choose&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below you will find tables summarizing the main vaults that I know of, with the tokens they accept, the service they farm, and how the return is denominated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mention &amp;ldquo;returns normalized to the base&amp;rdquo; means that the strategy generates a return frequently settled for the base token supplied - this operation is sometimes referred to as “harvesting”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The frequency of the harvest is important as it will influence the compounding factor of the overall position, as well as level of risk taken on the price of the farmed token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins--btc-vaults&#34;&gt;Stablecoins &amp;amp; BTC Vaults
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to Vaults, the most common tokens accepted as deposits are stablecoins. Such vaults will deploy your capital on Curve Finance pool to earn CRV tokens, usually the Y pool, . More recent projects, such as Pickle Finance also enables farming from the Curve sUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/vaults/pickle-pjar0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pickle-finance-pjar0&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pickle Finance pJar 0 explainer infographics &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@picklefinance/introducing-picklejars-70a311ab65c5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, some services like Harvest or YFV have an incentive model on top of their vault: depositors earn the governance token of the platform (FARM or YFV) on top of the base return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKENS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV (Seed Pool)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Value&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV/VALUE staking reward&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;yCRV, DAI, USDC, USDT, TUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;pJar 0 + psCRV pool (Curve sUSD)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve/Pickle&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to sCRV + PICKLE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Curve also supports tokenized BTC pools, there are now vaults for them too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;wBTC, renBTC &amp;amp; CRVRENWBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;hBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Curve?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Rewards normalized to the base&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Harvest.Finance, you can deposit wBTC or renBTC directly, or the CRVRENWBTC token, which represents a deposit in Curve&amp;rsquo;s Pool 5 (RenBTC &amp;amp; wBTC pool).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-based-vaults&#34;&gt;ETH-Based Vaults
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;BTC &amp;amp; Stablecoins positions are interesting, but maybe you&amp;rsquo;d like to keep an exposure to the price ETH?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can achieve such a result by yourself by leveraging your ETH. You&amp;rsquo;ll use them as collateral to mint or borrow stablecoins/wBTC that are then deployed to produce a return superior to your borrowing cost: here&amp;rsquo;s an article I wrote providing tips and tools to leverage ETH efficiently - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/leveraging-ETH.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, with such a position, you can be exposed to liquidations if the price of ETH was to drop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, Yearn was the pioneer here with the release of the wETH vault that automated this whole process. However, the volume of deposit was massive and the service ran into some technical issues currently being worked on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of waiting for the re-release of Yearn&amp;rsquo;s wETH vault, why not consider the &lt;strong&gt;existing available options&lt;/strong&gt;? They are not as intricate as Yearn&amp;rsquo;s wETH, since they do not leverage your ETH; the ETH is simply deposited somewhere to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FARMS ON&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Maker + Curve&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Normalized to ETH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Cream Deposit&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Cream returns normalized to wETH + FARM return (fwETH staking)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Soda&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Soda returns normalized to wETH + VALUE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;?&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Returns normalized to wETH&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve stuck to &amp;ldquo;simple&amp;rdquo; vaults where you deposit a given token, let it sit for a while, and hopefully walk out of there with more of it (+potentially some governance extra tokens). Yet, the release of Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s UNI token, another kind of riskier vault is available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;riskier-uniswap-uni-farming-vaults&#34;&gt;Riskier: Uniswap UNI-farming Vaults
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;uni-farming-basics&#34;&gt;UNI farming basics
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with the release of the UNI token came a distribution program instauring UNI incentives on specific pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/USDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/DAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH/wBTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you provide liquidity on any of the pools listed above, you can stake your liquidity pool token for an additional UNI income directly on Uniswap&amp;rsquo;s website. You&amp;rsquo;ll be earning UNI continuously. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to manage the position yourself, which means claiming the UNI (and pay the associated gas costs), as well as selling and reinvesting them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These strategies are riskier than ETH/BTC/Stablecoins vaults. Indeed, while farming UNI tokens you are providing liquidity on Uniswap, which comes with a risk of impermanent losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But why face the hassle of &amp;ldquo;manual farming&amp;rdquo; when you can &lt;strong&gt;let a vault do the hard work for you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;uni-farming-using-a-vault&#34;&gt;UNI farming using a Vault
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, quickly after the launch of Uniswap, several services started offering vault-type products to streamline the farming of UNI. Here&amp;rsquo;s an overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SERVICE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TOKENS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;REWARDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Harvest&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/USDC, ETH/DAI, ETH/USDT, ETH/wBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + FARM&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/DAI, ETH/USDC, ETH/USDT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + PICKLE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;YFV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;ETH/USDC, ETH/wBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;UNI returns normalized to the base + VALUE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This list is not exhaustive. Only vaults are included - services which automatically re-invest the profits for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other opportunities exist to farm UNI, but they require more intervention from your end. For instance, with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://sakeswap.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Sake Swap&lt;/a&gt; you can stake your ETH-Stable Uni-V2 LP tokens to earn both UNI &amp;amp; SAKE tokens. However, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to claim and manage the SAKE &amp;amp; UNI tokens earned yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about a given vault and how they operate, feel free to check their resources. Yearn and Harvest Finance have great documentation with infographics explaining their vaults:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://farm.chainwiki.dev/en/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farm Wiki&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is not investment advice, stay sharp and do your own research.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services mentioned:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yearn Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harvest Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pickle.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pickle Finance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;DFI.Money&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;YFV&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merry Farming! 🚜&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearn-finances-forks-the-state-of-the-waifus-family/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Yearn Finance&#39;s Forks: The State of the Waifus Family" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every day a new Yearn fork is popping up: how to keep track with them? There is no simple answer to this dilemma, however, I believe I can &lt;strong&gt;provide you with some clues to help you spot YFI fork with high potential.&lt;/strong&gt; To do so, I’ll cover three (+1) YFI forks and try to pinpoint the changes to the secret sauce that made them stick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is more than Yearn.Finance product itself: it became a template to kickstart a project, sometimes called &amp;ldquo;fair launch&amp;rdquo;. Yearn pioneered the method which stands on three key elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining Fair Launch&lt;/strong&gt;: the initial distribution of the token of the platform (ex: YFI) happens through liquidity mining. Supporters can stake tokens like yCRV to earn the governance token.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community-Driven Development&lt;/strong&gt;: the decisions regarding the development of the project are taken by the community of token holders, through informal and formal (on-chain) votes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pooled Investment Strategies (Vaults)&lt;/strong&gt;: the Yearn-inspired projects usually also try to replicate this core feature of Yearn: they offer tokenised investment strategies. The vaults are essential for the long-term success of the project past the initial liquidity mining phase.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Vault&amp;rdquo; is used to cover two vastly different reality:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Basic Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where tokens are collected and stake to produce a yield. The yield produced is frequently settled for stablecoins (no leverage).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Delegated Vault&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;, where once tokens are deposited, they are used as collateral (thanks to credit delegation) to borrow stablecoins then used to produce a return.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delegated Vaults are much more complex to develop and implement, while basic vaults can be sprung quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfi-wifey-wai-fu&#34;&gt;YFI? Wifey? Wai-fu?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early days of Yearn, people were unclear on how to pronounce &amp;ldquo;YFI&amp;rdquo;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/t/make-yfi-pronounced-waifu/552&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A discussion on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; settled for &amp;ldquo;Wai-fu&amp;rdquo; (/waɪfu/). From this point onward, there was only one wai-fu but plenty of wifeys: the YFI forks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, despite being barely a few months old, &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has already been forked, a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. There is now a whole family of wifeys built upon similar premises, each project adjusting different parameters to attempt to better fit their envisioned use case. Many of these forks were unnecessary, however, &lt;strong&gt;several managed to bring something new and exciting to the table&lt;/strong&gt; —  the ones we will consider today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This content assumes an understanding of Yearn, to brush up on the topic I&amp;rsquo;d recommend &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yearn-finance-YFI.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;my previous article on Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dfimoney-yfiihttpdfimoney&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money (YFII)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the earliest discussion in Yearn&amp;rsquo;s community was around the &lt;strong&gt;emission schedule&lt;/strong&gt;: while it was initially planned for a week, there were discussions about extending it - most notably &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yips.yearn.finance/YIPS/yip-8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YIP 8&lt;/a&gt; which proposed a longer emission schedule halving weekly. &lt;strong&gt;Despite support from the Yearn Community, the proposal did not meet the quorum and was not implemented&lt;/strong&gt;, which lead to the YFII fork** - a fork of YFI implementing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;instead of having a week-only distribution, YFII opted for a longer schedule, still ongoing.&lt;/strong&gt; It started July 27 and will end on October 5. The farming pools proposed are very similar to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s: staking the yCRV token or staking the Balancer pool token (98%DAI / 2 % YFII).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of this base differentiation, YFII develops an interesting angle with a &lt;strong&gt;strong presence in Asia&lt;/strong&gt;: the DFI.Money website was quickly translated into Chinese and soon other languages. There is also a strong &lt;strong&gt;focus on UX&lt;/strong&gt; to make the experience as easy as possible to onboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/dfi-money.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Overview of the DFI.Money Vaults&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stats.dfi.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can view the stats here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 14, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DfiMoney/status/1305339433638531072?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DFI.Money launched the v2 of their vaults&lt;/a&gt;, supporting ETH, USDC, USDT, DAI, TUSD, BUSD, HBTC, &amp;amp; yCRV. As this piece was written, there was a total of $70M deposited into DFI&amp;rsquo;s vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article is not an exhaustive overview of YFI forks. There were other forks of Yearn with minimal changes that are not covered, such as YFFI.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yflink-yflhttpyflinkio&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yflink.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink (YFL)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFL is another one of the early forks of YFI. Here, the twist is simple:** LINK was used as the base token of the system** - the one to deposit for the initial liquidity mining phase. The farming pools structure was similar to YFI/YFII, but with LINK/aLINK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial vision was to create a farming collaborative for LINK holders. YFL was developed by 5 anonymous teams working together and initially released on August 7 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/Linkswap.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFL LinkSwap&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growth was quick and the plan soon refined! YFLink is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@linkswapco/yf-link-ecosystem-linkswap-development-update-44f8413721c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;now working on LINKSwap&lt;/a&gt;, a community-governed Automated Market Maker (AMM), focusing on safety and value capture for LINK holders. LINKSwap explores novel ideas to increase investors&amp;rsquo; safety - for instance, the RugLock feature, designed to avoid rug pulls - when the token’s creators drain the liquidity pools, leaving holders with a sizeable bag of worthless coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfvalue-yfvhttpyfvfinance&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://yfv.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFValue (YFV)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue adds several more twists, with a similar goal of providing a service facilitating yieldfarming and making it more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the farming pools were mostly 98% ERC20-token / 2% YFV Balancer pools and the emission schedule is much longer (5 to 20 weeks) - it&amp;rsquo;s still ongoing while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/yfv-bringing-true-value-to-yield-farming-bddc4edf889a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFV launched mid-August.&lt;/a&gt; There is also a &amp;ldquo;seed pool&amp;rdquo; accepting stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV was one of the first project to provide credible earning opportunities on tokens such as BAL, YFI, BAT, REN, KNC, BTC, WETH, or LINK: it really helped to attract liquidity — there are around $470 M deposited on YFV as I write this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/yfv.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;YFV Staking Interface&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV&amp;rsquo;s core product, the Governance Vault was just &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/roadmap-update-value-contract-governance-vault-e226ad2f909e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;launched on September 15&lt;/a&gt;. YFV Holders can stake their token for several benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting power in the governance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A return paid in vUSD and vETH&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV token from the emission schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from the strategy implemented with the Governance vaults funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;YFV tokens earned from buying back YFV with 6.8% of the profits made with the vaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YFV is a highly ambitious project. The vaults (wETH, wBTC, renBTC) are expected shortly. On top of the existing farms and governance structure, the team is working on transitioning to an AMM/farming collaborative called Value Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;YFValue is in the process of transitioning to VALUE (token) and Value Liquid (name of the exchange/service). You’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@yfv.finance/faq-yfv-and-value-migration-af3a5a5c2190&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;more information on this rebranding and transition here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;yfinspired---harvestfinance-farmhttpsharvestfinance&#34;&gt;YFInspired - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance (FARM)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Harvest.Finance is technically not a fork of Yearn, one could say it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;fork in spirit&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, Harvest ambitions to streamline yieldfarming to make it more accessible &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s quite a success: Harvest is now home to more than $200 M (+200 M) of diverse assets farming with no stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experience on Harvest is quite straightforward, just like with the Yearn&amp;rsquo;s vault. &lt;strong&gt;Users deposit tokens into the strategy of their choice to put them to work&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, they deposit their DAI to get fDAI, DAI currently farming on Swerve.fi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-waifus/harvest-finance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once they own fDAI (or other fTokens), users can stake them to earn FARM - the native token of the platform.&lt;/strong&gt; They can also provide liquidity to the fDAI/DAI pair on Uniswap which facilitates the entry and exit of smaller capitals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvest.Finance launched on September 15 a new vault accepting for wETH. The community is highly active and committed, and it shows in the reactivity of the team: to better the yield, the stablecoin farms (DAI, USDC, USDT) switched from the Curve strategy to Swerve barely 16 hours after &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://swerve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Swerve&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yfi-fork-secret-sauce&#34;&gt;The YFI-Fork Secret Sauce?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope these quick introductions will help to better understand the recipe for a successful YFI fork. Considering the sample size (3+1), it’s hard to draw some conclusions but allow me to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s how I see a YFI-Fork scoring some resilience points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It &lt;strong&gt;focuses on a clearly identified community&lt;/strong&gt; (ex: LINK holders for YFLINK).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol parameters (pools, tokens, etc.) are adjusted to match the target community wants and needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A one-week emission schedule was a luxury only affordable by the first Waifu,&lt;/strong&gt; mother of all others (YFI). Successful YFI-forks tend to need a longer schedule (5-20 weeks) to gather and structure their community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A farm by itself is not enough, there is a real need for &lt;strong&gt;a convincing vision for the project in the long-run&lt;/strong&gt;, such as an AMM (YFL/YFV), or going above and beyond on the farming front (Harvest), and more than anything a driven and dedicated community to support it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: Thanks to Ashitaka#4868 from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RheJ78p&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Finance Discord&lt;/a&gt; for the amazing cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-disclaimer&#34;&gt;NECESSARY DISCLAIMER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;strong&gt;NOT investment advice&lt;/strong&gt; or a recommendation to purchase any of the token mentioned above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am not a financial advisor. I have no formal financial advising training, certification, nor experience.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a DeFi native sharing my insights, do with it as you may, but please think twice and avoid impulsive decisions at all cost: they are usually the worst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🚜 Merry Farming!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/yearnfinance-defi-on-autopilot/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/wifeys.jpg" alt="Featured image of post YearnFinance - DeFi on autopilot?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Yearn v2 release and the launch of the YFI token (pronounced &amp;ldquo;Waifu&amp;rdquo;) shook decentralised finance. Indeed, the whole recipe was there: Yearn is like a robo advisor, it helps you save and grow a capital - obviously one of the most thought after use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than the product itself, core to defining what Yearn became was its founder Andre Cronje, &lt;strong&gt;his choice of fully opening the governance&lt;/strong&gt;, and the amazing community that soon federated around the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this piece today, I want to share some pointers to understand why Yearn came to be, how it works, and why it matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-yearn&#34;&gt;What is Yearn?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first version of Yearn started with a simple promise: it &lt;strong&gt;helped you get the best lending rate available at any time on a given stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed as there were more and more options to lend stablecoins (Compound, Aave, dYdX, etc.), yield optimization quickly became essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn v2 already brought a new product to the market, the yVaults: they go beyond yield optimization (rebalancing stablecoins between several lending platforms) to provide more returns. Let’s see how this work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;end-user-perspective-deposit-wait-money-go-up&#34;&gt;End-User Perspective: Deposit, Wait, Money go Up
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we go in the specifics, here it&amp;rsquo;s how it works for an end-user:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You own a token supported in the yVaults, such as LINK&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can deposit your LINK in the yVault to start earning. Entry and exit to the vaults are gas optimised (usually ~$2-3).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you&amp;rsquo;re done, you exit the pool. 0.5% of the &lt;strong&gt;total&lt;/strong&gt; value is taken by the system to cover all the fees.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given &lt;strong&gt;enough time spent in the vault to make up for the exit cost&lt;/strong&gt;, investors walk out with a profit paid in the token they entered (ex: more LINK).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: yVaults are still highly experimental. Make sure you know what you are getting into. Andre has quite an interesting approach, stated in his twitter bio &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1291252150635560960?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;I test in prod&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-happening-under-the-hood&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;yVaults are amazing because &lt;strong&gt;they abstract an immense amount of complexity for the users,&lt;/strong&gt; and do it better than most of us. Going back to our yLINK vault, here&amp;rsquo;s what happens to provide the yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LINK are deposited on Aave (Credit Delegation) and used as collateral to open positions. The positions are maintained within a safe range using an safety mechanism (funded on the returns).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stablecoins are borrowed and put to work to provide a return. The latest strategy farms the mUSD/USDC MTA Balancer Pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any actual returns of the farming portion of the position (stablecoins earned above the debt) are sold for LINK, increasing the effective returns of the whole position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gist of yVaults is that &lt;strong&gt;they harness DeFi synergies to provide yields on autopilot.&lt;/strong&gt; They are designed to be flexible with their capital allocation - so that it can easily be re-allocated to follow a different strategy with better yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each vault has a different strategy. Here&amp;rsquo;s a neat explainer graphics made to explain the yCRV vault strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yCRV-vault.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance yCRV vault strategy explained&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explaining this one would be another article by itself, so I&amp;rsquo;ll let you dig the graph and join the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/HFK5uea&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn Discord&lt;/a&gt; if interested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yearn-is-unlike-anything-else-before&#34;&gt;Why Yearn is unlike anything else before
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is DeFi on steroids, and made possible by developments that occurred over the last year. Yearn is harnessing synergies between several &amp;ldquo;DeFi legos&amp;rdquo;. Without going too deep in, here are the key ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aave recently launched the Credit Delegation feature&lt;/strong&gt;, enabling a contract to open a position on your behalf. This feature was necessary for the yVaults to function as they do now, as they enable the first part of most strategies - getting leverage.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEX &amp;amp; Automated Market Makers - especially &lt;strong&gt;Curve.fi&lt;/strong&gt;, an obvious dependency for the yCRV Vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The overall &lt;strong&gt;dynamism of the stablecoins markets&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to new entrants such as mStable or the COMP token release.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn is the perfect example of DeFi composability!&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;building-as-little-as-possible--assembling-legos&#34;&gt;Building as little as possible &amp;amp; assembling legos
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why am I focusing on this? Because as someone working in the DeFi space for two years, I can tell you that the biggest operational mistake I see ALL THE TIME - is simple: &lt;strong&gt;teams re-building the wheel - reinventing what already exists and working&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think DeFi projects (like most startups) would gain immensely from actively trying to reduce the scope of work they undertake - here are two amazing questions that should be asked more often:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is the unique value delivered by our product?&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;What do we need to deliver it? Can we harness existing solutions to achieve this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yearn&amp;rsquo;s structural design demonstrates a keen eye to identify high-potential DeFi projects and harness their synergies. In short, by &lt;strong&gt;assembling several DeFi legos together in an unprecedented way&lt;/strong&gt;, Andre efficiently delivered a brand new use case if not a new subset of the whole industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-defi-100-community-driven-project&#34;&gt;The first DeFi 100% community-driven project
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This headline is not at attention grab, I stand by it as there is meat on the bone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So first, let us restress than &lt;strong&gt;Yearn has been a working product handling significant volumes for a while before the YFI token&lt;/strong&gt;. Now, you can add to it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;100% of the tokens distributed to the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using a novel liquidity mining approach, pertinent to the product (yCRV pool).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community was quick to step up and is booming with well-articulated ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andre relinquished control of the main contracts governing the service, in favour of a multisig with reputable actors of the space.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I regard and value an open governance process as a net positive, at least in the long-run, this is also a risk - and &lt;strong&gt;this is usually how people in the industry reads it&lt;/strong&gt;. An open governance can be hijacked in a direction that does not match the best interest of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;defiweb3---communities-hegemonize-brands&#34;&gt;DeFi/Web3 -&amp;gt; Communities Hegemonize Brands
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might not be on board yet, but for me, building and growing communities - that’s essentially my life. In the years I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing it, I found no secret sauce yet I &lt;strong&gt;uncovered an obvious truth: communities &amp;raquo;&amp;gt; brands&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of DeFi, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see the &lt;strong&gt;clash of brands&lt;/strong&gt; we&amp;rsquo;re about to witness:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the one hand, VC-funded brand-companies tend to lack personality and have a harder time bolstering dynamic organic communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the other hand, a community-driven project is &lt;strong&gt;a story writing itself every day.&lt;/strong&gt; And when it comes to Yearn&amp;rsquo;s brand, we see it growing fast: the swag is already there!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yearn-finance-YFI/yearn-swag.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yearn Finance Swag&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;feeling-the-yearn&#34;&gt;Feeling the Yearn
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn is so much more than yVaults! I focused this explainer on them for clarity, but there are several other Yearn products being developed. Without diving too much in, here some promising ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yborrow.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yBorrow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a generalised credit delegation interface using Aave. What makes it amazing is the synergy with the vaults, it will enable anyone to access vaults like yCRV from an ERC-20 token they like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ySwap: a novel automated market maker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A mysterious leveraged stablecoin-farming solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-yearn-toolbox&#34;&gt;The Yearn ToolBox
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are some tools and resources developed by the community that proves super helpful if you are exploring or using Yearn:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.learnyearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LearnYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A comprehensive Yearn wiki frequently updated!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://feel-the-yearn.vercel.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FeelTheYearn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A simple page to get the current status of the vaults: assets locked in, assets deployed and the strategy used for each vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ycosystem.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YCosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: A community aggregator to find all the useful links, from docs/YIP to where to purchase Yearn swag!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether or not you are interested in Yearn, I URGE YOU to give the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.yearn.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;governance forum&lt;/a&gt; a read - you are forever invited to read and partake in the discussions shaping Yearn. This time, there is no VC, no BS - just a DAO and a one-man-army named &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre Cronje&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wifeys-family&#34;&gt;The Wifeys Family
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it would be dishonest to cover Yearn/YFI &amp;amp; without mentioning that YFI sparked a whole movement - there are now dozens of forks, more or less credible. While the first few ones where just &amp;ldquo;miners fork&amp;rdquo;, adjusting a few parameters, we&amp;rsquo;re now seeing more creative approaches. Indeed, Yearn is open source so easily forkable, and Andre even invited the community to get creative with it&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some communities are forking YFI to create their own pooled earning system, with a longer-term vision. It&amp;rsquo;s just the beginning but I think we will see fascinating development in that space. I think we will see communities reappropriating themselves parts if not the whole YFI system - remember the Wifeys family earlier?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s already starting! I&amp;rsquo;m following closely &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/yflink/the-idea-of-yflink-is-born-aa520921a4a3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;YFLink&lt;/a&gt;, a YFI fork adjusted for the needs of the LINK community. Right now, it looks like a farming cooperative, but the end game might be a community staking node - the perfect match!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to the Yearn and its family grow!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yearn vaults are novel DeFi products integrating many others meaning the failure risks are compounded. I am not a financial advisor - you make your own decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I am NOT responsible for &lt;u&gt;YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, may they bring you Lambos or bankruptcy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1280500969986498561?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s Stani (Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO) giving you a rundown of why this is big!&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andre himself is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1290845154430025731?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the first to acknowledge&lt;/a&gt; what made Yearn possible and the importance of composability.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protocol governance now lies in the hands of YFI holder. The access to the main contracts are held by a multi-sig, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1285427748761198594?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Andre doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a key&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AndreCronjeTech/status/1289959986190147585?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&amp;ldquo;If you do clone /and you are welcome to/, please change a few things so we get new data from the experiment. Repeating the same experiment isn&amp;rsquo;t fun.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
