<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Opinions on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/opinions/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Opinions on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 11:54:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/opinions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Nation as a Service and its fractional citizenship- a good idea?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-nation-as-a-service-and-its-fractional-citizenship-a-good-idea/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 11:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-nation-as-a-service-and-its-fractional-citizenship-a-good-idea/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/naas/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Nation as a Service and its fractional citizenship- a good idea?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;While nationalists movements seem to be thriving, an equally interesting counter trend is shaping itself quietly. Despite nationalists’ wish to provide the services of the nation only to the purest of their kind, others countries are turning to the opposite direction: they are starting to provide services to non-citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estonia is one of the pioneers reshaping role of the nation and what being a “citizen” even means. Since the launch of the e-residency program, close than 30 000 world citizens applied. Yet e-Estonia is only beginning: the country is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/happy-3rd-birthday-to-our-global-e-resident-community-7143adc73994&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;aiming to reach 10 millions e-resident by 2025&lt;/a&gt;, for a country counting 1.35 million “physical” citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we explore what a Nation as a Service entails, you’ll remark that all of its features already existing in regular nations. The NaaS simply take it so much farther than the nation itself become something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-birth-of-the-nation-as-aservice&#34;&gt;The Birth of the Nation as a Service
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first introduced the concept in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/the-demise-of-nation-states-introducing-the-nation-as-a-service-naas/&#34; &gt;a very raw article&lt;/a&gt; that went from my head to Medium in 90 minutes. It started with a tale to introduce the concept that scared some readers and hurt the political sensibility of others. While passion could be nice, I wanted to offer a more formal take on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first introduced the concept, I depicted the “4 cornerstones of the Nation as a Service” as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of nation state, as we use to know it, becomes obsolete. Regular nations are decomposing or powerless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the void, “digital nations” emerge. They might be tied to real nations (like Estonia), entirely virtual, or even raise money (ICO?) to purchase a land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These digital nations will offer the same services offered by our current nations, on a narrower scope: they will focus mostly on business regulations. Then, the most advanced ones might expand their scope: finance, currency, healthcare, education…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, citizens won’t be tied to a nation by birth anymore. Citizens will compare the offers from different nations and choose their fit. They might have to pay for the service (Estionian e-residency is 100€ one time cost). Nations will compete with one another to attract citizens, and extreme concentration is possible (winner-takes-all market): there are no limits anymore to contain the amount of citizens a nation can have. We’ll observe the birth of “Citizenship portability” — changing nationality will be easier than changing of internet service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still stand by them, but allow me to dive deeper today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-formal-definition-of-the-nation-as-a-servicenaas&#34;&gt;A formal definition of the Nation as a Service (NaaS)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s go straight to the point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nation as a Service (NaaS) provides a digital fractional citizenship under a subscription model.&lt;/strong&gt; The definition might be short but it’s quite dense, let’s unfold it methodically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-is-digital-native&#34;&gt;The NaaS is digital-native
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of NaaS emerged over the last few years. The first full-fledged NaaS is e-Estonia which opened up its e-residency 3 years ago. Since these new nations were born in a digital world from start, we observe a drastic paradigm shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It translates into the incorporation of digital concepts in the very nature of the state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital first&lt;/strong&gt;: all public services are available online and remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open data&lt;/strong&gt;: making public data accessible to all through APIs. This allow for the creation of third-party services for public infrastructure: the easiest example to grasp would be the app that gives the departure time of trains/metros/bus already available in most big cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data portability between public services&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need to resubmit information to every public service anymore. One submission to the relevant service is enough since the access is shared to other public services that might need it (with the citizens’ consent of course).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts might be hard to envision in practice, so let me take you to Estonia thanks to Kaspar Korjus (the managing director of the e-residency program). He depicts what it means in the real world while he talks about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/what-is-a-nation-children-born-today-will-grow-up-with-a-radically-different-answer-b31f14403c3c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the birth of his son Ruufus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information &lt;/p&gt;
\[The name, sex, date of birth and parents of the children, registered by the doctor at the hospital\]
&lt;p&gt; is really useful straight away because various parts of government would need it to better serve us as new parents, such as by scheduling health checks, supporting with child care and allocating our parental leave allowance. This would generate added hassle for new parents in most countries, but in Estonia the information begins flowing automatically between departments and agencies along our secure, decentralised information network known as the ‘X-road’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that e-Estonia is a digital nation built on top of a regular one. Now imagine what kind of efficiency a digital nation from start could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-offers-fractional-citizenship&#34;&gt;The NaaS offers fractional citizenship
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The citizenship offered by a NaaS is not a full-fledged citizenship. So far Estonian e-residents can open up an Estonian bank account and own a business, but they can’t settle in Estonia or vote. The choice was made for practical reasons: it’s much easier to start small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next years, we will see new features added to the service provided by NaaS. Since the idea of single citizenship status for all citizens is already shattered in pieces, the logic will be pushed even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be different tiers of citizens who have access to different services. The most bare bone tier being the only made only of the identity verification protocols while the most advanced one will eventually offer something similar to our current citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-is-available-under-a-subscription-model&#34;&gt;The NaaS is available under a subscription model
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The subscription model is the direct consequence of the fractional citizenship. Since the citizenship is now made of different parts citizens can choose to subscribe to or not, we can envision the establishment of a subscription model for the NaaS, with several different options ranging from a pure business citizenship to a full-fledged citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, in e-Estonia it’s a single 100€ fee to submit a candidacy. In the future, it might take the form a yearly/monthly subscription with different features. Here’s what I see, from the most basic to the most advanced one. The first two are already available in the Estonian e-residency in its current form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: provide a digital ID card allowing the holder to prove its identity to public or private services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: provide the ability to open a bank account and set up a business in the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: allows the benefactor to vote and participate in local (city/region) elections and create NGOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political citizenship:&lt;/strong&gt; allows the benefactor to vote at national elections and other public consultations such as referendums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription to the &lt;strong&gt;national Healthcare service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription to the &lt;strong&gt;national pension plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the &lt;strong&gt;full-fledged citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: All these different features will probably be gated behind conditions, such as being an e-citizen for X years, and an additional fee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;citizenship-portability&#34;&gt;Citizenship portability
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another direct consequence of all three characteristic of the NaaS depicted below is the notion of citizenship portability. Since citizenships become subscription based, what used to be an edge case — changing nationality — will become commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, with more and more fractional citizenships available under a subscription model, “prospects” might start to compare the offers essentially putting citizenships in competition with one another. Some might even stack or mix and match different citizenship offers. E-Nations will have to account for this new trend and provide services to facilitate the switch from one NaaS to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was written to be nothing more than an analysis giving you a framework to read the current shift happening on the very definition of a nation. I tried my best to avoid any judgement one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I think the ongoing shift I described in this article will have tremendous consequences, many of which are not yet envisioned. I still can’t really figure how to feel about this, I jump from curiosity to anger, or from fascination to despair. What about you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of an original (French) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EcoCrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Demise of Nation States: Introducing the Nation as a Service (NaaS)</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-demise-of-nation-states-introducing-the-nation-as-a-service-naas/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jun 2018 16:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-demise-of-nation-states-introducing-the-nation-as-a-service-naas/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/demise-ns/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Demise of Nation States: Introducing the Nation as a Service (NaaS)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether you believe or not in the idea of “the march of history”, there is an undeniable worldwide trend that is leading to a complete overall of the power structure: &lt;strong&gt;the progressive disengagement of the state from state affairs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this idea is slowly creeping into the public head space, what’s less discussed is what’s next? What happens once the decomposition is over and there is nothing left? That’s precisely what I’ll address today. I will also suggest a framework to consider the role of the state/nation in a post nation-state world: &lt;strong&gt;the Nation as a Service (NaaS)&lt;/strong&gt;. Before we dive in, let us agree on what “decomposition of the nation state” means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-long-and-methodical-process&#34;&gt;A LONG AND METHODICAL PROCESS
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to determine when the methodical deconstruction of the state started. Like all societal trends, there is no set starting date and each country/region follows it at its own pace. Only one thing is certain: no state can escape it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the chronology of the decomposition of a nation state so we might be able to pinpoint the start of the process more precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: What follows is merely a tale written to make you question the (shrinking) role of states.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It might hurt your political sensibility.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Feel free to jump straight to the second part of the article — Introducing the Nation as a Service.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-break-down-a-nation-state-a-step-by-steptutorial&#34;&gt;How to break down a nation-state? A step by step tutorial
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s go to a fantasy world that will get truer than reality as we depict it&lt;/strong&gt;. After a long a happy reign as king of BBLand (catchy name eh?), I’ve decided I’m done with it. It’s too much of a hassle, I’ve made enough money. How can I let it go? I can’t just shut off the “business”, I still have millions of citizens on my land. I’ll have to go slow. But I’m in luck, I’ve seen the process happening all around me, I just have to replicate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;first-i-must-destroy-or-sabotage-the-flows-of-information&#34;&gt;First, I must destroy or sabotage the flows of information
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If it does flow, people will know what’s happening and might revolt, I can’t chance it. I’ve got many ways to do this, but I think the most efficient is simply &lt;strong&gt;to allow an unprecedented level of concentration in the medias.&lt;/strong&gt; Eventually, I’ll have less than 10 individuals or companies owning them all, and those happy few will promote exactly the same worldview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now my citizens are left with partisan medias. Even better, those medias so concentrated they are easier to manipulate than ever before. &lt;strong&gt;Essentially, what I did is privatizing the attention of my citizens&lt;/strong&gt; — I’m a very modern ruler you see. Just to make sure there are no reliable information anymore, I’ll also make the advertising laws very lax, let lies and false information spread widely, and turn the political life into a TV show. Now we’re talking and by that I mean we’re not anymore, but that was precisely the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;then-i-must-get-rid-of-all-public-institutions&#34;&gt;Then, I must get rid of all public institutions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once again, I can’t do it overnight, I would risk an uprising. I’m gonna &lt;strong&gt;do it insidiously&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with something remote and easy — the prisons. Prisoners have no rights anyway, right? Even if they do, nobody’s gonna check, they’re hidden from the rest of society! It’s the perfect population to get started: low risk, high reward. So let’s privatize, the market will deal with it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, now I need a hack for the schools, health care, transportation systems and other critical infrastructure. Let’s cut spending. And cut some more. And some more. By the way, have you seen how inefficient the schools and hospitals have become? Shouldn’t we privatize them to make them efficient again? Excuse me?! I’m hearing a no? Cut! Cut! Cut! Is that a yes? See? When you think twice about it you finally see the light, good citizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Yes I’m a Frenchie and I am sincerely sorry for the citizens of the states that never knew what a public healthcare service was. You’re simply moving faster than us! Hurray, “progress”!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;now-i-leave-everything-to-themarkets&#34;&gt;Now, I leave everything to the markets
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I finally managed to get rid of public institutions, I want to finish the process, &lt;em&gt;optimize the efficiency&lt;/em&gt; of my country even more. What can I do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There must be some stuff we haven’t thought of selling yet? What about the forests? They can make money! And the beaches? People should pay for them! I’m seeing a free park? Are you out of your mind? Oh! We forgot to privatize the water distribution network? But all my citizens are users, that’s a potential goldmine! Let’s organize a tender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh and what about our work laws? Citizens are still thinking they entitled to stuff like “unemployment”. I even had a madman the other day who wanted to prosecute a big corporation for not being socially and ecologically responsible — what a lunatic! I’m gonna slash the work laws a dozen times, just to remind them &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Tripalium&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;what “work” used to mean: torture&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t even have to go this far, slavery will be enough. But don’t call it like this, no; remember: I’m a progressive ruler. I’m gonna leave them the freedom of choice: would you rather bike for UberEats or Deliveroo?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a rest and contemplate: I have markets everywhere, docile citizens with close to no job security and I’m finishing up on the demolition of the last public institutions. I’m getting there, but I feel like I’m missing something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;finally-from-people-togoods&#34;&gt;Finally, from people to goods
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don’t have a job? Don’t you know that unemployed people are parasites? They bring down the whole society! What am I hearing? You can’t find a job? Oh my dear, you need to learn how to market yourself, develop your personal brand. How else do you expect to be visible in such a competitive job market?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh yes, that’s very regrettable. It makes me angry too. Sadly I can’t do anything about it: it’s the market. If I start to promote progressive laws the jobs will go away. Our neighbor CCLand is taxing companies even less than us; we’ll bleed jobs!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-when-did-the-deconstruction-of-the-statestart&#34;&gt;So when did the deconstruction of the state start?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m sure our little trip to BBLand reminded you a thing or two about the real world. But in reality, all four processes are almost concomitant. Only the first one — the decomposition of the medias — seems to be a prerequisite of the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s even more surprising is how this process started to unfold roughly at the same time in the most developed countries: in the mid 70s. That could be a good starting date. But, I’m not here to talk about media concentration, it’s merely an argument to support my thesis. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.osce.org/fom/13870?download=true&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This topic is already covered&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introducing-the-nation-as-aservice&#34;&gt;INTRODUCING THE NATION AS A SERVICE
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Going back to BBland for a minute, what’s left of our state? Barely the minimal business regulatory infrastructure: companies can’t police themselves. Is there anything alike already in the real world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-to-e-estonia&#34;&gt;Welcome to e-Estonia!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you’ve never heard about the Estonian e-residency before, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://e-resident.gov.ee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;go have a look&lt;/a&gt; you’ll learn a lot. I know most of my dear readers won’t so here is a screenshot from the official website linked above:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/demise-ns/e-residency.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot for the Estonian e-residency official website&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Screenshot for the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://e-resident.gov.ee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Estonian e-residency official website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it seems that there are two essential features offered by the e-residency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A government issued global digital ID available to anyone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s not a citizenship, but you’re still &lt;strong&gt;enough of a citizen to own and operate an Estonian-based business&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, &lt;strong&gt;close to 30 000&lt;/strong&gt; “digital nomads”  and other entrepreneurs became e-Estonian residents. Yet the e-residency is just a first step. I wanted to learn more about this intriguing and unique e-country, so I went straight to the source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@kaspar.korjus?source=post_header_lockup&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Kaspar Korjus, managing director at E-Residency&lt;/a&gt;. Do read any of his article, it gives you an incredible insight on what’s happening. What follows is simply three insightful quotes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Estionia’s vision for its e-residency:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estonia’s e-Residency programme is also a fast growing startup — albeit a government startup — &lt;/p&gt;
\[…\]
&lt;p&gt;, often with &lt;strong&gt;best practices that we’ve taken straight from the private sector&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/estonia-could-offer-estcoins-to-e-residents-a3a5a5d3c894&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Estonia’s potential cryptocurrency, estcoin&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Estonia’s perspective, estcoins &lt;/p&gt;
\[Estionia’s cryptocurrency project\]
&lt;p&gt; were proposed as a way to raise money and support for the development of our digital nation from more people around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/happy-3rd-birthday-to-our-global-e-resident-community-7143adc73994&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;return on investment for the e-residency&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deloitte published an independent analysis, which revealed that every euro invested in e-Residency by Estonian taxpayers is projected to return 100 euros to the Estonian economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defining-the-nation-as-aservice&#34;&gt;DEFINING THE NATION AS A SERVICE
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Estionia is the perfect transition. When I hit publish, I might be coining the term “Nation as a Service”. But in reality, &lt;strong&gt;Estonia pioneered the concept, I simply gave it a name&lt;/strong&gt;. Kaspar pretty much defined it when he envisioned &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/what-is-a-nation-children-born-today-will-grow-up-with-a-radically-different-answer-b31f14403c3c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the future world of his three years old son Ruufus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But perhaps governments don’t have to ‘tax’ Ruufus by then anyway. **Governments can instead earn their main source of income by selling their services globally in the form of monthly subscriptions **— much like how Netflix currently delivers its service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since he wasn’t looking at it from my angle, allow me to put words on what I see behind this concept. Here are the four cornerstones of the Nation as a Service (NaaS):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The concept of nation state, as we use to know it, becomes obsolete. Regular nations are decomposing or powerless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the void, “digital nations” emerge. They might be tied to real nations (like Estonia), entirely virtual, or even raise money (ICO?) to purchase a land.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These digital nations will offer the same services offered by our current nations, on a narrower scope: they will focus mostly on business regulations. Then, the most advanced ones might expand their scope: finance, currency, healthcare, education…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, citizens won’t be tied to a nation by birth anymore. Citizens will compare the offers from different nations and choose their fit. They might have to pay for the service (Estionian e-residency is 100€ one time cost). Nations will compete with one another to attract citizens, and extreme concentration is possible (winner-take-all market). We’ll observe the birth of **“Citizenship portability” **— changing nationality will be easier than changing your internet service provider.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s simply a proposal, let me know what your think about the concept of Nation as a Service, and feel free to redefine it. Is this a disparition of the state, or just a transition to a new type of state? Probably a little bit of both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where do we go from here? Since Estonia is the most startupy of all the startup-nations, the development of the NaaS is viewed there with a very positive outlook. And indeed why not? So far it seems to have brought wealth and innovation to Estonia. I am the only one to wonder:  is this wealth really created, or simply taken from other countries’ taxes? We’ll know soon enough: &lt;strong&gt;the rat race has already started&lt;/strong&gt;— &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://ereforms.org/news/estonian_press_wrote_on_unbelievable_azerbaijan-246&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Azerbaijan just joined the party&lt;/a&gt; with its m-residency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;final-notes&#34;&gt;Final notes
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;My faithful readers know my strong interest for cryptocurrencies and decentralization, I kept myself in check all along the article so allow me to drift of a little bit now. I see many synergies between the NaaS concept and the blockchain: identity verification, taxes, contracts… Yet despite the synergies, a NaaS is a very centralized institution. I’m puzzled. Could one really help the other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I give you your attention back (I privatized it a while ago, it’s mine now, remember?), help me to answer this question: Should I cut the crap and start an ICO to raise capital for the first fully private NaaS? I could be the rattiest rat!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
