<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ecocrypto on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ecocrypto/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Ecocrypto on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 12:14:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ecocrypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is stability a necessity for cryptocurrencies mainstream adoption?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/is-stability-a-necessity-for-cryptocurrencies-mainstream-adoption/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 12:14:52 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/is-stability-a-necessity-for-cryptocurrencies-mainstream-adoption/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/stablecoins/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Is stability a necessity for cryptocurrencies mainstream adoption?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you talk about cryptocurrencies with people unfamiliar with it, the question of volatility is among the first to pop up. Quite often, it’s a low effort way to dismiss the whole world of cryptocurrencies and recent progress made with decentralization. Volatility does not affect all cryptocurrencies: some of them are made to be stable (price wise) — we call them the “stablecoins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get to that point, let’s state some necessary facts to understand this article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cryptocurrencies are much more than just the Bitcoin&lt;/strong&gt;. There are more than 1500 tokens listed on CoinMarketCap, which is only the tip of the iceberg: in reality, there are thousands of cryptocurrencies circulating. The sheer amount of tokens can be scary, but it’s positive in the long run. It means that for every problem cryptocurrencies can solve you have dozens of different teams exploring as many different approaches — no stone is left unturned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whatever the initial vision of Satoshi was, &lt;strong&gt;Bitcoin is unfit to become a mainstream currency&lt;/strong&gt;. Its technical limitation such as its low transaction speed or the issues with mining (energy consumption, centralization, etc.) makes it inapt for this use case. However, its persistence (Bitcoin is almost 10 years old!) as well as its reliability makes it a good “store of value”, just like gold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nevertheless, there are many projects with the ambition to become tomorrow’s mainstream currency. &lt;strong&gt;They answer the fundamental issue raised when considering Bitcoin as a currency: its volatility.&lt;/strong&gt; Those projects are called &lt;strong&gt;stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; and they will be the topic of this piece.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question of volatility highlights a vital characteristic of a currency: price stability is a necessity to have a currency people feel confident using. Indeed, creating a new currency requires a thorough understanding of both technical mechanisms as well as social dynamics. In order &lt;strong&gt;to become a currency, a good must be recognized as such by its users and gain their trust.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-fiat-goingsouth&#34;&gt;Are fiat going south?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We observe a strong correlation between the adoption of cryptocurrencies and the “weakness” of the national currency (called fiat currencies) in a given country. It’s hard to measure the adoption of cryptocurrency, but we can easily get figures on how many people are interested in buying some using Google Trends:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/stablecoins/buy-bitcoin.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Geographical distribution of the query “How to buy bitcoin” using Google Trends&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Geographical distribution of the query “How to buy bitcoin” using Google Trends&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ghanaian currency (the Cedi — GHS) went from roughly a dollar in 2008 to around 20 cents nowadays. Meanwhile, the Nigerian currency (the Naira — NGN) lost about half of its worth (measured against the dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/stablecoins/cedi.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The exchange rate of the dollar against the Cedi (left) and Naira (right) over the last ten years. Source: TradingEconomics.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The exchange rate of the dollar against the Cedi (left) and Naira (right) over the last ten years. Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tradingeconomics.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TradingEconomics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The devaluation happened fast enough for people living in these countries to see the impact of it. It could explain the strong interest we observe for cryptocurrencies in Ghana and Nigeria. However, the issue with the determining how much a given currency is worth is more complex than simply measuring it against the dollar. If we use the dollar as our reference point, we must question its stability: &lt;strong&gt;is the dollar itself even stable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without thinking twice about it, the “yes” seems like the go-to answer. The dollar hasn’t changed over these last 50 years — a $1 bill emitted in 1968 would still be recognized as such today. However, what about its worth? It is changing all the time. Is one 1968 dollar still worth $1 then? The answer is simply no — it would give access to a purchasing power corresponding to roughly 7 present days dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/stablecoins/inflation.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Evolution of the buying power of the equivalent a 1968 dollar from this date until now. Source: TradingEconomics.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Evolution of the buying power of the equivalent a 1968 dollar from this date until now. Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tradingeconomics.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TradingEconomics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main driver of the spread is of course inflation. The topic is sophisticated enough to have theses written about it, so we’ll leave it to others. Now that we have some context let’s get back to stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;whats-a-stablecoin&#34;&gt;What’s a stablecoin?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea behind the stablecoin is pretty simple, the challenge lies in the execution. &lt;strong&gt;A stablecoin is a cryptocurrency that trades at a fixed price against a good (such as gold) or a common currency (most often the dollar).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A stablecoin’s worth is not stable; it is merely its value that is pegged to a &lt;strong&gt;relatively&lt;/strong&gt; stable asset. Creating a reliable stablecoin is already a real challenge, so creating a fixed-worth currency is a wild dream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the question of having a stable value is interesting to consider. How would it look like? That one unit of the given currency is always worth one unit? That’s DOGE’s specialty!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/stablecoins/doge.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The DOGE is a parodical currency created out of a meme which is now taken more and more seriously as cryptocurrencies develop&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The DOGE is a parodical currency created out of a meme which is now taken more and more seriously as cryptocurrencies develop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to more serious matters: the stability of currency could be defined as the fact that one unit of it always grant access to the same value. This definition would be consistent with the definition of a currency proposed in a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/money-101-discarding-the-myth-of-bartering-to-understand-bitcoin-better-3b8e66cd2e77&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;previous piece&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is not a store of value, it’s a claim upon value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping the link between the currency and the actual value it gives access to is elegant, in theory. However, in the real world, it’s close to impossible to measure the buying power of a given currency exactly. It is why we’ll consider stability defined as a currency keeping a constant price in regards to other goods or currencies which have a &lt;strong&gt;relatively&lt;/strong&gt; stable value. Before we get to the different stablecoin projects there are, let’s examine their utility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-are-stablecoins-goodfor&#34;&gt;What are stablecoins good for?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We already have live and available stablecoins such as the USDT. They are mostly used by crypto exchanges and traders because they offer a way to avoid returning to fiat currencies and having to abide by all the legal framework that comes with it. Moreover, since their price is fixed against the dollar they are somewhat of a safe haven for traders: with them, they can get out of the market without really doing so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For now, stablecoins are mostly a traders’ gimmick used to get in and out of the market without bringing their money back into their bank account. Hence, &lt;strong&gt;in the short-term, they are mostly a speculative tool&lt;/strong&gt;. However, they can provide a real utility in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since cryptocurrencies have high volatility compared to fiat currencies, they are not really used as currency. Almost nobody is choosing to get their pay in cryptocurrencies, or using them to buy their groceries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a stable cryptocurrency well integrated with the rest of the ecosystem would provide a credible solution to address these needs. At first, stablecoins would be the gateway between the fiat and the crypto world. In the long run, they could become the “fiat of cryptos” themselves: &lt;strong&gt;they would become cryptocurrencies which are stable enough to become a preferred payment method&lt;/strong&gt;. It would provide a broader and more reliable access to the services offered by other (non-stable) cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-stabilize-a-cryptocurrency-liveexamples&#34;&gt;How to stabilize a cryptocurrency: live examples
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To fulfill their promise of stable exchange rate against a given fiat, stablecoins must offer a &lt;strong&gt;collateral&lt;/strong&gt;. As a result, several types of stablecoins emerged depending on the collateral mechanism they used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fiat-collateralized-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Fiat collateralized stablecoins
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the most direct and simple approach to make a stablecoin, but also the most centralized. In brief, there is a central entity minting the stablecoin who owns a reserve of dollar corresponding to the volume put in circulation. This dollar reserve offers guarantees regarding the solvability of the coin and allow to exchange the stablecoin back to a dollar at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even so, this approach comes with several issues. First, it’s &lt;strong&gt;completely centralized&lt;/strong&gt; since a single entity is emitting the stablecoin and backing it. There are no other choices but to trust it. Besides the approach is &lt;strong&gt;economically inefficient&lt;/strong&gt;, especially at scale, as it requires to “freeze” an amount of money equal to the number of stablecoins in circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;USDT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mechanism is used by the USDT, the most widespread stablecoin. Despite its adoption, &lt;strong&gt;the USDT is widely denounced&lt;/strong&gt; for its lack of transparency — there is no reliable method allowing its users to verify than Tether (the institution emitting USDT) actually possesses in its reserve a stock of dollar corresponding to the amount of USDT in circulation: around 2,8 billion currently. However, the ties between Tether and Bitfinex (the 4th cryptocurrency exchange regarding the trading volume) raise questions regarding the potential for market manipulation it allows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TrueUSD&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Created in answer to the lack of transparency of the USDT, TrueUSD uses the same mechanism while offering more guarantees. Rather than owning the token themselves, TrustToken (the institution emitting TrueUSD) works with a network of banks and financial institutions which keep the funds in escrow for them. One of them, Cohen&amp;amp;Company, publishes an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.trusttoken.com/trueusd-attestation-reports-86f693b90a4?gi=749091358366&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;independent audit&lt;/a&gt; twice a month to confirm that the financial partners of TrustToken do hold in escrow a number of dollars corresponding to the volume of TUSD in circulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guarantees offered seem more reliable than for the USDT, yet the problem is similar: this system requires its user to trust TrustToken and its partners, and particularly Cohen&amp;amp;Company to be honest. It works until it doesn’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;crypto-collateralized-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Crypto collateralized stablecoins
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While fiat collateralized stablecoins are fulfilling (so far) their promise of stability, they are doing a disservice to cryptocurrencies as a whole whose aim is to provide a decentralized alternative to the legacy financial and monetary networks. To answer this concern, another type of stablecoins emerged. They use other cryptocurrencies as collateral and a network of smart contracts to peg their exchange price to the underlying asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet this type of stablecoins is facing issues too, the main one being the volatility of cryptocurrencies used as collateral. To address them, they necessitate &lt;strong&gt;a collateral superior to the value of the stablecoins emitted&lt;/strong&gt;, which hinders their potential large scale usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MakerDAO — Dai&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dai is another stablecoin pegged to the dollar (1 Dai = $1). It has some interesting features, the main one being that it is fully decentralized. Indeed, the institution emitting the Dai is MakerDAO, a decentralized autonomous organization. It’s an &lt;strong&gt;organization which governing rules are automated and enforced through publicly auditable smart contracts&lt;/strong&gt;, making them transparent and unchangeable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dai works in pair with MKR, the governance token. Owners of MKR can vote to decide on the mechanisms used to stabilized the Dai. The system is quite complex and could deserve several articles by itself. Dai was launched on December 17th 2017 after three years of development. Since its launch, its price was in the same range of stability than fiat collateralized stablecoins (+/- ~10 %).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;un-collateralized-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Un-collateralized stablecoins
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;These stablecoins are the most promising in the long run as the address the main concerns raised by the two previous types: they propose a decentralized solution which could be used at scale. These projects are still in the development phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of them use algorithms which reduce or increase the amount of the given stablecoin in circulation to stabilize their price. If the price goes over the dollar, the circulating supply increases; if it goes below, the supply decreases. The two most prominent projects in this category are Basis and Carbon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basis wants to create an “algorithmic central bank” that would stabilize its price. Their system uses three different types of token which makes it quite complex. The goal is to reproduce a simplified version of the federal reserve system with the addition of investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carbon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Carbon is trying to execute an approached theorized in 2014 already by Robert Sams called the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/rmsams/stablecoins/blob/master/paper.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;seigniorage shares&lt;/a&gt;. The solution is mostly theory for now and has yet to see a working implementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stablecoins-a-gift-or-a-curse-for-cryptocurrencies&#34;&gt;Stablecoins: a gift or a curse for cryptocurrencies?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins are a recent yet fascinating innovation. There are many projects currently in development (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stablecoinindex.com/projects/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;non-exhaustive list&lt;/a&gt;) using diverse approaches. The typology proposed above is simplified: some projects mix several types of collateral while others use radically different mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, stablecoins are speculative &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/tools&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; more than anything else, but they can become one of the critical elements of the mainstream adoption of cryptocurrencies in the long run. Looking at the volume, the USDT is currently obliterating its competition, which creates a systematic risk for the whole cryptocurrencies market. If USDT was to fail, it could lead to widespread panic. Thus &lt;strong&gt;speculation pushed the market towards a highly centralized tool lacking any real transparency: a gentle irony for the future of decentralization.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources--deepdive&#34;&gt;Sources / Deep Dive
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bitcoinmagazine.com/articles/warning-signs-timeline-tether-and-bitfinex-events/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Warning Signs? A Timeline of Tether and Bitfinex Events&lt;/a&gt; — Amy Castor on Bitcoin Magazine, July 2nd, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coinjournal.net/the-rise-of-stablecoins/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The rise Of Stablecoins&lt;/a&gt; — Alex T. on CoinJournal, April 8th, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/stablecoins-carrying-the-way-to-the-crypto-promised-land-c124b2db8ea3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stablecoins — Carrying the Way to the Cryptocurrency Promised Land&lt;/a&gt; — Brian Quinlivan on Hackernoon, July 4th, 2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/stablecoins-designing-a-price-stable-cryptocurrency-6bf24e2689e5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stablecoins: designing a price-stable currency&lt;/a&gt; — Haseeb Quereshi on Hackernoon, Decembre 12th, 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://prestonbyrne.com/2017/12/10/stablecoins-are-doomed-to-fail/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stablecoins are doomed to fail&lt;/a&gt; — Preston Byrne on its personal blog, December 10th, 2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/makerdao/what-is-mkr-e6915d5ca1b3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;What is MKR?&lt;/a&gt; — MakerDAO’s blog, September 10th, 2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stablecoin projects mentioned in the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tether.to/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;USDT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.trusttoken.com/trueusd/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TrueUSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MakerDAO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.basis.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Basis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.carbon.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Carbon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/non-fungible-tokens-explained-with-blastoise-and-charizard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 12:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/non-fungible-tokens-explained-with-blastoise-and-charizard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Non-fungible tokens explained with Blastoise and Charizard" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Non-fungibles” — don’t let yourself be fooled by the mushroom-evoking name, fungibility is an old concept that is finding a second wind nowadays. It’s mostly about collectibles and video games for now, but it will soon outgrow these industries. Indeed, the potential of non-fungibles tokens is much more significant than this: from official documents to titles of ownership, their use cases are diverse and numerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start by establishing the basics about non-fungible tokens (NFTs from now on) thanks to Pokémon cards before we dive into their potential use cases and the future developments of the underlying technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;tokens-smart-contracts&#34;&gt;Tokens? Smart Contracts?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we explore NFTs and talk about Pokémons, let’s restate two definitions necessary to understand the rest of the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;: A smart contract is a computer protocol intended to digitally facilitate, verify, or enforce the negotiation or performance of a contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Token&lt;/strong&gt;: a token represents a particular tradable asset or a utility that is often found on a blockchain. Each token has specific properties that are defined to match its usage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-does-fungibility-evenmean&#34;&gt;SO, what does fungibility even mean?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A fungible good is a good defined by its belonging to a type: different units of fungible goods are interchangeable. “Fungibility,” as a concept, is used in several different academic disciplines; we’re addressing the economic definition only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s jump to the examples which make the concept much easier to understand. Our modern currencies, such as the dollar, are fungible: one $5 bill can be exchanged with another. Gold is also a fungible good: 1 ounce of (pure) gold is worth another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A fungible good is standardized: each unit of this good has no uniqueness, which is why we can exchange them with one another.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-about-non-fungible-goods-then-can-we-still-eatthem&#34;&gt;What about non-fungible goods then? Can we still eat them?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some goods are non-fungibles. They are goods which &lt;strong&gt;share common attributes but have their uniqueness&lt;/strong&gt;: each good has a unique set of values for each trait which is shared with the whole type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best example of non-fungible goods are… Pokemon cards of course! While we’re at it, let’s pick the one that used to be enough to crown you king of the playground: Charizard himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/charizard.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Pokémon card is made of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A name (and a level): Charizard, level 76,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Points (HP): 150,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A type: fire,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An ability: Energy Burn,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An attack and its cost: Fire Spin (4 fire energies),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weakness and Resistance: water and fighting,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A retreat cost: 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each Pokémon card is unique, but all follow this typology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s consider Blastoise for instance: he too has the 7 attributes we have already described, but he has different values for each which make him different from Charizard and unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/blastoise.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the combination of the value for all the attributes that make the cards’ uniqueness. Hence, a card describing a fire type Pokémon with 150HP is not a Charizard — it is merely a card with 2 attributes equal to those of Charizard, out of 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pokémon cards are useful because they make most of the concept of non-fungibility easy to grasp. &lt;strong&gt;NFTs are a category of tokens that share common attributes&lt;/strong&gt;. But each token has a set of unique values for these attributes which make the token itself unique.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you were too young for Pokémon cards, or too old, it’s precisely the same principle for other card games: Magic, Yu-Gi-Oh !, World of Warcraft (the card game) and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fungibility-applied-to-cryptocurrencies&#34;&gt;Fungibility applied to cryptocurrencies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the cryptocurrencies you already know such as Bitcoin or Ethereum can be considered fungible (see below ⬇️). One BTC is worth another and two BTC can be exchanged with one another. It’s the same for all cryptocurrencies you could find on Coinmarketcap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Since the history of transactions of most cryptocurrencies can be checked on block explorers, some tokens involved in illicit activity are flagged and blocked on exchanges. Therefore, cryptocurrencies with public transaction histories are not truly fungible. Full fungibility is currently achieved by privacy-focused coins such as Monero, because the transaction history is not publicly disclosed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We won’t address these today, as we focus on non-fungible tokens. There were several attempts, as early as 2013 to create NFTs, but they were mostly unsuccessful. What made a difference was a new Ethereum standard, the ERC-721 which greatly facilitated the creation of “cryptocollectibles.” They are unique goods which share common attributes — the blockchain equivalent of Pokémon cards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-humble-beginnings-powered-by-theerc-721&#34;&gt;The humble beginnings powered by the ERC-721
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cryptokitties.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cryptokitties&lt;/a&gt; is what made NFTs known to the general audience — they are virtual kittens which were the precursors of the ERC-721.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/cryptokitties.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project went live in October and took a couple month to reach its peak of virality last December. Cryptokitties were such as success than the whole Ethereum network was clogged for several days by the flood of transactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/ck-price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specific kittens, the most desirable of the bunch, reached prices in the 5 digits ($) and changed hands several times in a few days early December. Considering the success of the CryptoKitties, the ERC-721 went through the due diligence to get approved and finalized last June.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;non-fungible-tokens-in-the-everydaylife&#34;&gt;Non-fungible tokens in the everyday life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to pushing and improving new technologies, you’ll often find porn and video games sharing the front line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, collectible and video games are at the forefront of the innovation. Indeed, when it comes to pushing and improving new technologies, you’ll often find porn and video games sharing the front line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the real-world applications of NFTs are very diverse, numerous, and much closer than we think. Thanks to their characteristics, NFTs can be an excellent support for the tokenization of real-life goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokenize means creating a token representing a good. The token by itself has no value; it draws its value from the good it represents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenize-everything&#34;&gt;Tokenize everything!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tokenization allows to handle goods like tokens which open a wide range of possibilities: exchange, P2P transferring, fractional ownership (0.x), etc. Besides, other features can be added depending on the tokenized goods: list of the previous owners, history of the value of the good, exhaustive list of the goods’ characteristics, limitations of ownership…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the benefits of tokenization are understood, we realize that tokenizing real goods will let us &lt;strong&gt;spare ourselves the need for greedy intermediaries while getting many exciting new features&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of real estate =&amp;gt; who need notaries?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of pieces of art =&amp;gt; auctioneers and several other jobs would see their utility and even their existence challenged.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tokenization of official documents (IDs for instance) =&amp;gt; a substantial cleanup in the actors and institutions currently involved in their emission, as well as those in charge of detecting and preventing frauds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the three scenarios detailed above, checking the authenticity of these goods as well as making sure their owner is indeed the real owner of the good would be much easier than now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-benefits-of-disintermediation-thanks-to-tokenization&#34;&gt;The benefits of disintermediation thanks to tokenization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tokenization is much bigger than creating a token to represent a real-world good. Let’s come back to the definition of NFTs we proposed: “unique goods which share common attributes.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So tokenization would work as well for certificates. IDs, passports, report cards or even software license could be tokenized. Not only would it greatly facilitate the process of emitting and sharing them; it would also provide traceability, unlike anything we’ve ever known so far. Which in turns would make a 99.9% fraud detection and prevention goal a realistic one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we keep pushing the logic further, we could go back to the digital world and envision NFTs to store our digital identity. Our social network profiles could be open-source and easily exportable from one network to the others. Besides, it would give full control and ownership over our own data and prevent malicious third parties from stealing them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get there, we need to &lt;strong&gt;overcome the current limitations of both the Ethereum network and non-fungible tokens&lt;/strong&gt;: as stated before, the CryptoKitties were enough to clog the whole Ethereum network for several days. The current state of the tech (or December’s state at least) is apparently insufficient for a large scale usage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ercsthe-new-standards-of-the-ethereumnetwork&#34;&gt;ERCs — The new standards of the Ethereum network
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the Ethereum network, several teams are already working on the technical optimization of the network. Among them, we could mention Omisego/Plasma or the upcoming Ethereum update (Casper). Check the sources at the end of the article for resources on these matters; today we’re talking about NFTs so let’s get back to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-721 was a good start yet it faces many problems while going at scale. Before we get here, let’s zoom in on ERCs. An ERC (Ethereum Request for Comment) is a proposal submitted by an Ethereum developer. It introduces methods, behaviors, innovations or research that could be used to used to improve the network functionality. Once accepted, an ERC can become a standard — it’s quite a long process. Once again an example makes the concept much clearer: the most famous standard for Ethereum is the ERC-20. It described a fungible and straightforward token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The primary interest of ERCs is that they allow integrating the tokens within the ecosystem smoothly&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need to know the specifics of each token since they follow a set of methods shared with others (defined by the ERC). This is why a wallet which supports ERC-20 tokens support all of them without requiring particular development for each new one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;erc-1155-the-future-of-non-fungible-tokens&#34;&gt;ERC-1155, the future of non-fungible tokens?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 is a new standard for NFTs proposed by Witek Radomski, the founder of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://enjincoin.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EnjinCoin&lt;/a&gt;, a platform made to facilitate the development of games with tokenized goods on the Ethereum network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 fixes many issues raised when trying to use NFTs based on the ERC-721 at scale, and also brings many new features. Regarding the technical optimization, the ERC-1155 allows sharing a given piece of code between several different tokens or collections of non-fungible tokens. It will enable to support a much higher volume of transactions for the same load on the Ethereum network (compared to the ERC-721).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/erc1155.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A transaction involving several fungible and non-fungible goods thanks to ERC-1155&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A transaction involving several fungible and non-fungible goods thanks to ERC-1155&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using ERC-1155, it’s also possible to exchange several items in one single transaction. With ERC-721, if Bob wants to exchange its cryptokitties #1, #2, #3 and #4 for Alice’s Cryptokitty #5, it would require 5 different transactions while one would be enough using ERC-1155.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ERC-1155 also supports fungibles goods which are plenty in online games: think about all the coins, potions, arrows and other consumables. Using only one standard, the ERC-1155, versus a mix of them (ERC-721 for non-fungible goods and ERC-20 for fungible goods) makes it much easier for developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, ERC-1155 could treat NFTs in a group, allowing them to retain some fungibility. It would allow players to differentiation the different iteration of a same common object, and the first owner of it could prove he was indeed the first to own it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Non-fungible goods are taking off, and Ethereum is a the forefront of the innovation. To better understand the ramifications of this concept, it’s best to go check its current usages. Let’s have a look at some games being developed/already available in pre-release versions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/godsunchained.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Gods Unchained&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Gods Unchained&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://godsunchained.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gods Unchained&lt;/a&gt;: We used card games to introduce the concept, it’s only logical to find one here. Gods Unchained is among the most well-known one and uses the ERC-721 standard. The benefits compared to regular card games (such as Hearthstone) are numerous: immutability of the cards after the release (no more surprise nerfs), full transparency of the rarity of each type of cards, traceability of the previous owners of a given card… The team is focusing on eSports, and the first world championship will take place early 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://decentraland.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Decentraland&lt;/a&gt;: Take Minecraft, in virtual reality with blockchain-based mechanisms to handle ownerships: Welcome in today’s Tomorrowland! Once they own a piece of virtual land, users can create/develop the experience of their choosing (thanks to the SDK); they will then be able to control the access to their land and make other users pay for it if they want. Decentraland is a human and social experiment at world scale. It will be seriously insightful!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/nft/augmentors.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A creature of Augmentors&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A creature of Augmentors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.augmentorsgame.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Augmentors&lt;/a&gt;: Since we were talking Pokémon earlier, what about Pokémon GO? Augmentors combined Augmented Reality with blockchain to offer a game where NFTs allow each user to truly own their augmented reality creatures and trade them as they want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dismissing NFTs could be tempting as for now it could appear like something for kids and nerds. Yet, it’s precisely the opposite: as the CryptoKitties have demonstrated it, NFTs are one of the best Trojan horses to drive the mainstream adoption of cryptocurrencies and decentralization-based mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With new technologies, the technical development is only the warming up phase. &lt;strong&gt;The real challenge lies with the social and legal acceptance of the tech: on that front, CryptoKitties and other collectibles are precursors.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr/vulgarisation/tokens-non-fongibles-expliques-par-tortank-et-dracaufeu/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;an original (French) EcoCrypto.fr story.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources--deepdive&#34;&gt;Sources / Deep Dive
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/point-nine-news/mapping-the-emerging-non-fungible-token-landscape-ee56f0d1079f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Mapping the Emerging Non-Fungible Token Landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Pawel Chudzinski on Medium, 06/15/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/0xcert/erc-721-ethereum-standard-confirmed-and-finalized-73b78f7ea315&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;ERC-721 Ethereum standard confirmed and finalized!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — 0xcert on Medium, 06/24/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/porn-drives-technological-innovation-again-this_us_59f8085de4b094db8e76f834&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;_Porn Drives Tech Innovation Again, This Time In VR _&lt;/a&gt;— Jarone Ashkenazi on the HuffPost, 10/31/2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@argongroup/ethereum-plasma-explained-608720d3c60e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Explained: Ethereum Plasma&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;— Lukas Schor on Medium/ArgonGroup, 05/28/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jonchoi/ethereum-casper-101-7a851a4f1eb0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethereum Casper 101&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Jon Choi on Medium, le 10/22/2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/a-proposal-to-shake-up-ethereum-a-new-standard-on-the-horizon-d2dfa88507a6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;A Proposal To Shake Up Ethereum — A New Standard On The Horizon? Mapping the Emerging Non-Fungible Token Landscape&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Ermos Kyriakides on HackerNoon, 06/27/2018.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Respecting Users Privacy - The oddity that must become a standard</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/respecting-users-privacy-the-oddity-that-must-become-a-standard/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 10:54:13 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/respecting-users-privacy-the-oddity-that-must-become-a-standard/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Respecting Users Privacy - The oddity that must become a standard" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2018, respecting your users’ privacy should be easy, right? After the revelations made by Snowden about the NSA practices and all other that followed, web hosting providers and other services changed their practices, right? That’s what we thought — and the illusion didn’t last for long. Today we take you on a little data tour: who’s collecting them, how, and for what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;setting-up-thecontext&#34;&gt;SETTING UP THE CONTEXT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You might know it; else we recommend you to read the manifesto — we recently launched a publication, EcoCrypto, that respects its users and their attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding their attention, that’s our issue. However, when it comes to respecting our users’ privacy, it’s much bigger than us: we must double check each third party service we use to ensure they’re not abusing our (and your) trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we published the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr/manifeste/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, we realized &lt;strong&gt;how little people knew about the systematized data harvest that happens online&lt;/strong&gt;. We decided to write an article to provide a comprehensive overview of the main tracking solution currently enforced pretty much everywhere on the web. At the end of the article, we propose two sets of recommendations. The first one is for everyone: the very basics on how to protect your privacy online. The second one is specific to webmasters: how to respect your users’ privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-trackermania&#34;&gt;THE TRACKER MANIA
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each additional tracker is one more guest at the feast held on our privacy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with the basics: what’s a tracker? Essentially, it’s a small script one can place on his/her website — it allows the different services used to collect data on the visitors, therefore enabling new services for the webmaster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tracker is like a snitch for a third party — &lt;strong&gt;each additional tracker is one more guest at the feast held on our privacy.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-small-dozen-of-trackers-theminimum&#34;&gt;A SMALL DOZEN OF TRACKERS, THE MINIMUM?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: To stay true to the original article (written in French for a French public), we kept French websites as examples. The situation is similar all around the globe, even worse in some countries .&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any media website is using at the very least a dozen trackers. No need to trust us, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ghostery.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check by yourself using Ghostery&lt;/a&gt;: it lets easily you visualized all the trackers present on a website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a little tracker-tour of a selection of the most visited websites in France:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leMonde.fr \[France’s #2 (audience) daily national newspaper\] — &lt;strong&gt;32&lt;/strong&gt; different trackers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leFigaro.fr \[#1 Daily national newspaper\] —** 35**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mediapart \[Online only publication\] — &lt;strong&gt;21&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;l’Express \[Weekly magazine\] — &lt;strong&gt;49&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tf1.fr \[#1 Private TV channel\] —** 35**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;France2.fr \[#1 Public TV channel\] — &lt;strong&gt;18&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agence France Presse (AFP — French news agency) — &lt;strong&gt;12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the cleanest of the bunch, l’Humanité, still has &lt;strong&gt;10 different trackers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The measure was made on July the 18th, on the Homepage of every website. Remember to disable any adblocker or script blocker to see all the trackers on a given website.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/trackers.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Elle.fr \[Weekly women magazine\] — 53 trackers; Liberation.fr \[Daily newspaper\] — 40 trackers&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Elle.fr &lt;/p&gt;
\[Weekly women magazine\]
&lt;p&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;53 trackers&lt;/strong&gt;; Liberation.fr &lt;/p&gt;
\[Daily newspaper\]
&lt;p&gt; — &lt;strong&gt;40 trackers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite often, the people working on/for these websites don’t even know about the trackers. We reached out to French crypto publications to let them know about their privacy-intrusive practices. All said they were “surprised” to discover how extensive the net was. Some might say they were laughing at our face — you are the judges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this little visit to the horror gallery we can conclude two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The owners/webmasters of 99% of internet websites are apparently not even thinking about respecting their user privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The users of these websites don’t know about the tracking and its consequences. Therefore, they don’t ask/push for practices that would be both cleaner and more respectful of their privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is any change coming up, it will come from the users: we need to be demanding and uncompromising. To do so, one must know what one is fighting against — let’s start a quick tour of some of the shadiest practices taking place in the online tracking world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-typology-of-thetrackers&#34;&gt;A TYPOLOGY OF THE TRACKERS
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are several different types of trackers, here’s an overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advertising trackers&lt;/strong&gt;: These trackers allow webmasters (and advertising services) to collect additional data when a user goes on a website — this data is then used to increase the effectiveness of the ads. The most common are Double Click and Facebook Ads. We’ll give more details on a subsection of the advertising trackers — the pixels — a little below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statistics services trackers&lt;/strong&gt;: the most famous is Google Analytics, but there are many others. They’ll have their section.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social networks trackers:&lt;/strong&gt; they allow for a direct integration of social media on a website, such as liking a Facebook page from a media website. It means that the user is identified (through his/her Facebook/Twitter/X profile). One last thing: no need to interact with the buttons to be recognized — that’s the whole beauty of the mechanism. Smile! You’re being spied on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;visitor-stats-and-an-extremely-detailedprofile&#34;&gt;VISITOR STATS… AND AN EXTREMELY DETAILED PROFILE
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each webmaster has the same issue: he/she needs stats to know the most visited pages or articles, where his/her users are coming from, how many are they… To do so, the go-to is to implement Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value proposition of Google Analytics is pretty straightforward: Google is an expert on data collection and processing, you’re probably not. Implement this little script and Google will do most of the work for you: collecting the data, processing it, or presenting it in comprehensive dashboards. It’s convenient, and most (if not all) websites now use it. The issue? All the data is going through Google, putting it another way: &lt;strong&gt;Google is now collecting data on 99% of any websites users, straight at the source (on the website).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If each website were a bar, the Google Analytics situation would be similar to having a Google Home with the mic always on at the very center of the room. It’s already annoying and problematic when it’s just a few bars/websites. However, now, since almost all websites use this mechanism, it became the web all-seeing eye / all-hearing ear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who handled a website with Google Analytics implement knows what we’re talking about: the amount of data available on any user is staggering. It’s hard to give a precise number because each implementation of Google Analytics is different. Google itself boasts about its &lt;strong&gt;400 different “metrics and dimensions&lt;/strong&gt;” — &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/reporting/core/dimsmets#mode=web&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here is the list.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Webmaster rejoice! We suggest an alternative at the end of the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-advertising-and-user-privacy-strictly-irreconcilable&#34;&gt;ONLINE ADVERTISING AND USER PRIVACY: STRICTLY IRRECONCILABLE
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we talked about advertising trackers, it was a rapid overview. Allow us to zoom in a little here. First, some basics about online advertising:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s paid by action: cost per click, per thousand views, per specific action (register, download an app…)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All actions are not equal — a click can come from someone completely outside your main target or on the contrary from the potentially perfect customer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online advertising campaigns can be adjusted in real time and at any time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the basics are clearly stated, it’s easy to understand that there is a choice to be made between privacy and online advertising. To optimize the online ads, one must collect more and more data to improve his/her targeting and avoid unnecessary expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/privacy.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Online media and social networks often get quite lyrical about their “fight to protect users’ privacy” — don’t let yourself be fooled. &lt;strong&gt;All the most visited websites are big users of online advertising services and use many trackers: in short, they have no respect for their users’ privacy. Even worse: they are making money out of its violation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-spy-pixel&#34;&gt;THE SPY-PIXEL
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still unconvinced? You think that “ethical advertising” is a thing? Let us zoom on a specific kind of trackers: the advertising “Pixels,” such as the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/business/learn/facebook-ads-pixel&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook Pixel&lt;/a&gt;. Once again, it’s a little script that works a bit like Google Analytics. The webmaster implements the pixel on his/her website and gain access to extra (advertising-related) statistics and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On of the main interest for webmasters is that all the data collected will be available straight in Facebook Ads — it makes it much easier to optimize the ads: it’s a mandatory tracker for anybody who is dedicating a significant budget to the platform. Thanks to the pixel, the website owner can make the connection between the ads on Facebook and actions undertook on his website: signups, purchases, downloads, and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the problems with the Facebook’s pixel is the same as Google Analytics: since the pixel is now everywhere, Facebook is collecting data right at the source on most of the most visited websites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/pixel.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;An example of a retargeting scenario using Facebook (source: Lyfe Marketing)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
An example of a retargeting scenario using Facebook (source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.lyfemarketing.com/spa-owners-facebook-customers/facebook-retargeting-example/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lyfe Marketing&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, the pixel allows a specific kind of advertising campaigns called “retargeting”: the term refers to any ad where the targeting is made using the previous behavior of the prospects. A typical retargeting flow using Facebook (Pixel and Ads service) looks like that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You go to a given website, let’s say a lawnmower shop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smile, someone’s is spying on you! Thanks to the pixel, you’re immediately recognized, your “Facebook ID” (unique identifier of your Facebook profile) is added to a retargeting list.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You go on Facebook and discover incredible sales of lawnmower straight in your newsfeed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-little-gifts-discovered-by-theway&#34;&gt;THE LITTLE GIFTS DISCOVERED BY THE WAY
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we delve into our recommendations, let us examine a concrete example that tells a lot about the challenge it became to respect the privacy of your website users online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever heard of WordPress? It’s a framework (~engine) allowing you to create blogs and websites easily — this is what we use on EcoCrypto… for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A default WordPress installation uses a service called Gravatar: thanks to it, each user (=anybody who write articles or comment on one) can have his/her very own profile picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even better, users can go on gravatar.com, create their account and set their profile picture once — Tada! Your picture is now on every WordPress using Gravatar without having you to set it up again. Nice, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except that the reality behind the gimmick is quite ugly. Gravatar uses the email to match its user with his/her profile picture. It means that &lt;strong&gt;by default, anyone commenting on a Wordpress sees his/her email getting a free round-trip to Gravatar’s servers.&lt;/strong&gt; With the round trip, Gravatar can build a list of the users of every WordPress installation — still looking for that sweet custom profile pic?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many alternatives exist, and they can be set up in a few clicks, but since Gravatar is enabled on all installations, it’s still widely used. &lt;strong&gt;The default installation, combined with the widespread ignorance of the practice allows Auttomatic (Gravatar’s developers) to stuff itself with the emails of its users unknowingly collected over the years.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;To go further, here’s&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://meta.stackexchange.com/questions/44717/is-gravatar-a-privacy-risk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;an interesting read on Gravatar’s privacy issues.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of scenario repeats itself over and over again when it comes to privacy. Everyone agrees with and supports the concept, yet only a few really look into it. On the business side, the “respecting your users’ privacy” theme is nothing else than a potential communication topic: it’s rarely enforced at the software level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-can-wedo&#34;&gt;SO, WHAT CAN WE DO?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We tried to stay concise and not delve too much into the technical details — we’ve omitted many practices, this article is not exhaustive at all. Dozens, probably hundreds of different tricks and mechanisms exist to track and spy on users online. Some are much more insidious and harder to counter than others, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://panopticlick.eff.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;fingerprinting.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What inspired this article is the surprisingly hard journey to set up a simple blog that respects its readers’ privacy. &lt;strong&gt;We’ve left this topic to the experts, and because of that we are reaching a situation where violating the privacy is now the norm — and those who want to respect it struggle.&lt;/strong&gt; All of this happening while Apple, Google, Facebook and others are painting themselves as “privacy champion” in front of the general audience, while they are the first to systemize the very end of the idea of privacy. We should fight back, or maybe we should have ten years ago already? It’s never too late!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;toolbox-the-bare-minimum-to-protect-yourprivacy&#34;&gt;TOOLBOX: THE BARE MINIMUM TO PROTECT YOUR PRIVACY
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The good news (there is one!) is that protecting your privacy necessitates that you block all the ads — as well as the script that detects if you have an adblocker or not. Stealth has a bright side!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What follows is the bare minimum setup, you must go much further to be really covered, if ever possible:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-block-theads&#34;&gt;1. BLOCK THE ADS
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;For Chrome users, we recommend the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nano-adblocker/gabbbocakeomblphkmmnoamkioajlkfo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nano Adblocker&lt;/a&gt; + &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nano-defender/ggolfgbegefeeoocgjbmkembbncoadlb?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nano Defender&lt;/a&gt; (anti ad-block defuser) combo: it’s easy to set up and works well. Firefox users can use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/ublock-origin/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;uBlock Origin&lt;/a&gt; for similar results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Whatever adblocker you chose, don’t forget to enable the EasyList corresponding to your country. Here’s a demo GIF for the French list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/adblock-fr.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can try your setup by visiting any media website with the adblocker enabled; you’ll see a lot of free space! Insidious ads such as sponsored posts (“native advertising” as professionals call them) are not blocked — beware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-list-and-block-thetrackers&#34;&gt;2. LIST AND BLOCK THE TRACKERS
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ads are only the start. Now we need to tackle the trackers. The good news is that there are very extensions to take care of this for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/user-privacy/privacy-badger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy Badger is developed by &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/about&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the EFF — the Electronic Frontier Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, a nonprofit that has been defending civil liberties in the digital word for years — it’s not enough to blindly trust them, but it does provide reassurance. You don’t need any specific setting, but you might want to have a look at the trackers list (by clicking on the extension icon) and disable those you don’t need. At the beginning of the article, we mentioned &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ghostery.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ghostery&lt;/a&gt; — it also works quite well, and might be easier to use for some.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-use-https-everywhere&#34;&gt;3. USE HTTPS, EVERYWHERE
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you visit a website that uses HTTPS, the exchanges between your browser and the website are encrypted. HTTPS is now widespread, but its implementation on certain websites is quite messy: they’ll make you switch back and force between the secured and regular HTTP. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/https-everywhere&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HTTPS Everywhere&lt;/a&gt;, another browser extension from the EFF solves the issue: it forces websites to use HTTPS whenever it’s available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-notes-on-privacytools&#34;&gt;ADDITIONAL NOTES ON PRIVACY TOOLS
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to be even safer, use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/fr/firefox/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; instead of &lt;strong&gt;Google&lt;/strong&gt; Chrome. If you’re looking for sensitive stuff online, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/projects/torbrowser.html.en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;use TOR at least, it’s super easy to set up&lt;/a&gt;. Finally, if you want to be a little safer, look for more sensitive stuff, or leak critical information please check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tails.boum.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TAILS — an operating system (Linux based) made for privacy&lt;/a&gt;. Before going to the dark side of the web, READ and document yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep the article short-ish, we limited ourselves to three tools. &lt;strong&gt;To really cover your digital steps, you’ll have to go much further.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We could have easily listed a hundred of different &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/tools&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tools&lt;/a&gt; relevant for different situations — it would be pointless. You need to be able to pick the most suitable tools for your usage by yourself. To do so, there is no other way than lifting the hood to delve into the technical stuff. &lt;strong&gt;Privacy is not given nowadays; you must fight for it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All around the globe, nonprofits are doing their part with their means. The EFF edits a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Surveillance Self Defense guide&lt;/a&gt; which could be an excellent place to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;respecting-users-privacy-as-a-webmaster&#34;&gt;RESPECTING USERS PRIVACY AS A WEBMASTER
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are handling a website, the most critical action you could start with is breaking free from Google Analytics. We have chosen &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://matomo.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Matomo&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source and &lt;strong&gt;self-hosted&lt;/strong&gt; analytics solution. The self-hosted part means that the data stays on our servers: it’s essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your hosting provider, setting up Matomo might be more or less accessible. If your hosting provides supports &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.softaculous.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Softaculous&lt;/a&gt;, the installation will be done in a few clicks. Else, you might need to learn a thing or two on server management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other actions you can undertake will depend on the services and framework you use. Rather than a list of tools, let us suggest a methodology:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party services minimization&lt;/strong&gt;: reduce to the very minimum the number of third-party services you use. Each new service is a potential risk both for your website &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/security&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;security&lt;/a&gt; and for your users’ privacy. Even a decent, honest service can go rogue in a flash, and it won’t warn you about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigate any third-party service you do implement&lt;/strong&gt;: despite 1/, you’ll have to use some third-party services. Look into the developers of these services, their other products, the reviews. There might even be other people who audited their code and talked about it. Use open-source services whenever it’s possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forget about online advertising&lt;/strong&gt; on the main services (Social media, Google…) — you can’t reach cost-efficiency on these services without violating your users’ privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask for help!&lt;/strong&gt; More and more people are getting “privacy-fluent” and would be &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;happy to help&lt;/a&gt; a well-intentioned webmaster to establish a decent setup.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of an original (French) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EcoCrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Money 101 - Discarding the myth of bartering to understand Bitcoin better</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/money-101-discarding-the-myth-of-bartering-to-understand-bitcoin-better/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 12:13:32 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/money-101-discarding-the-myth-of-bartering-to-understand-bitcoin-better/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Money 101 - Discarding the myth of bartering to understand Bitcoin better" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Money is a critical element of our modern societies: a slight change in its mechanisms can have a much broader impact than simply affecting the economy. Therefore, a better comprehension of these mechanisms will give you a better grasp on various topics ranging from Political Economy to cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money is a complex subject, even more lately if we consider all the &lt;strong&gt;convoluted systems and protocols&lt;/strong&gt; that were progressively built on top of it: monetary creation, central banks, inflation… With this piece, we’ll go back to the basics and eventually down to cryptocurrencies: What defines a currency? Why do we need them? What types of currencies do exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buckle up for a quite an adventure in which we discard old but still prevalent tales and propose necessary new ones to make complex mechanisms crystal clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tale-of-the-origins-ofmoney&#34;&gt;The Tale of the Origins of Money
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you hear about currencies, you often get a tale that is easy to understand and compelling; yet it’s just a tale. It goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning, we were barterers, the my chicken for your corn kind of deal. Then, since bartering wasn’t efficient, we needed a more standardised mean of exchange: a good that could pass as a store of value. Precious metals were the perfect candidates — they became coins, a form of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, later on, those coins evolved once again and became paper money — still a currency, but the origin of their value shifted: while a coin gets its value from its very material (the precious metal it’s made of), the paper money needs an institution to emit it and guarantee its value one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in the digital era, money evolved one more time. It’s now all “digital” — just bits, 0 and 1 located somewhere in a server and transiting almost instantly in the fiber network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must take our time to methodically deconstruct the tale in order to dismiss it, we’ll learn quite a few things along the way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;money-is-not-a-store-ofvalue&#34;&gt;Money is not a store of value
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Money is not a store of value, it’s a claim upon value.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;lets-burn-some-cash-to-understand-moneybetter&#34;&gt;Let’s burn some cash to understand money better
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s study together the example that made the distinction between the two very clear to me: let’s say I burn a $20 bill — will any value be destroyed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/joker.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Thanks to the Joker for helping with the experiment&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Thanks to the Joker for helping with the experiment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well… Simply no! What has been destroyed is my ability to claim the aforementioned value: I can’t exchange the ashes of my bill for a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;make-itrain&#34;&gt;Make it rain!
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding the difference between a store of value and a claim upon value allows us to also understand &lt;strong&gt;the obsession with circulating currency&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, money is not wealth by itself: as long as the money is not claimed (spent for goods or services), it has no contribution whatsoever to the wealth of the given country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/fly.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to our previous cash burning experiment to dig deeper: when I burnt my $20 bill, it had no impact on the GDP (Gross Domestic Product) of the USA. Yet, if I start to burn millions of dollars, we might start to see &lt;strong&gt;secondary consequences&lt;/strong&gt; affecting the GDP: since there will be less money circulating, there might be less people using it to claim value (a beer, clothes…) and therefore an impact on the real economy of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those secondary consequences will &lt;strong&gt;only happen if the cash I burnt was meant to be spent&lt;/strong&gt; — if burning the bills prevented me from claiming the value they carried. Hence, if I’m a multi billionaire (so let’s assume: incapable of spending all of my money), I can burn millions of dollar without having any impact on the economy: those millions would have never flowed back into the economy anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting a stop to the flow of money which would have changed hands without that stop is like preventing others to work to provide value; this value would have been exchanged for currency if the money was circulating freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;counterfeit-money-realvalue&#34;&gt;Counterfeit money, real value?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To get over with the myth of money as a store of value, let’s consider a third and last scenario. Let’s say I print a very **well done stash of counterfeit money **— everybody take it for the real one. Now I give out those bills to normal American citizens, and for the sake of the simplicity of this example, the FED doesn’t notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/print.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that scenario, the happy citizens who got free real-like yet counterfeit bills will start spending them for goods and services — they will claim what is rightfully theirs because of their ownership of the bills, hence increasing the GDP of the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, all of this is a scam, no value was actually created: I only printed and handed out fake bills that people think legit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money barely is the key to the gold chest. When money itself, its physical medium, still had value (such as gold or silver coins), the content of the chest was still tied to the amount written on the key. Now, we are in a system where keys are changing endlessly changing hands without ever returning to open the chest. &lt;strong&gt;Our trust in our currencies is so high that the amount written on the key is sufficient and even authoritative&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-myth-of-bartering-and-its-inefficiency&#34;&gt;The myth of bartering and its inefficiency
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s go back to the first tale about the origin of money presented in the beginning of this article: was bartering really as prevalent as the story make it seems?&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to place some context to answer this question. We’re talking about a world where money doesn’t exist yet; hell, the very notion of “property” is even clear yet. &lt;strong&gt;Of course there were exchanges, but the “exchange protocol” was very different that what we picture behind the idea of bartering&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/swap.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premodern agricultural societies were largely self-sufficient: exchanges between the member of a given community followed informal systems based on relationships: the “economy” was powered by gifting and reciprocity.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practical terms, rather than the &lt;code&gt;my goat for your corn&lt;/code&gt; kind of deal, it was more like &lt;code&gt;I will help you build this house because I know how to do it. Later on, you&#39;ll help me furnish this other house since you&#39;re a skilled woodworker. If you don&#39;t, it can put an end to 1/our relationship, 2/your very place in the community&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Considering the system depicted above was informal, the “if you don’t…” part didn’t need to be stated, it was understood.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the premodern agricultural societies depicted above, barter also existed but wasn’t the main mean of exchange: it was useful to be able to exchange with people who didn’t share the kind of relationship we depicted — for exchanges between communities for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-distortion-of-the-historians-lens&#34;&gt;The distortion of the Historian’s lens
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;There could be another reason to explain why the tale of the evolution from bartering to currency is still prevalent. &lt;strong&gt;To reconstruct the past, historians use remains found in modern times&lt;/strong&gt;. Coins stand the test of time. On the opposite, informal gift/counter-gift dynamics barely leave any traces behind them.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/helixism.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Helixism was born when Reddit started to play Pokemon, together (Twitch Plays Pokemon) — The Origin of Ancient Helixism&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Helixism was born when Reddit started to play Pokemon, together (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Twitch_Plays_Pok%C3%A9mon&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Twitch Plays Pokemon&lt;/a&gt;) — &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/twitchplayspokemon/comments/20cz6i/the_origin_of_ancient_helixism/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Origin of Ancient Helixism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the example frequently chosen to illustrate the bartering system are doubtful. We’re talking about &lt;code&gt;goat vs corn&lt;/code&gt; deals, but is it realistic in the context of a premodern agricultural society? Since they were mostly auto sufficient, bartering was for goods that weren&amp;rsquo;t required for the community&amp;rsquo;s survival, since these were already produced within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;downplaying-the-role-ofbanks&#34;&gt;DOWNPLAYING THE ROLE OF BANKS
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the tale of the origins of money, banks look like mere intermediary. They provide more or less practical systems allowing the money to flow: it used to be ledgers, and it’s still is but now we have a clunky web interface to write/edit stuff in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, this skip &lt;strong&gt;the crucial role played by banks in our current monetary systems: monetary creation&lt;/strong&gt;. For the sake of the easy-of-comprehension of this article, I won’t dive into the depths of it in here, a quick presentation of it will have to suffice. This mechanism is called the fractional-reserve banking.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/fractional-reserve.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;fractional-reserve&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a short and (too) quick explanation — a central bank emit a monetary base allowing commercial banks to issue currency by themselves through loans. When Bob comes to Bank of America for a $10,000 loan, BA is not pulling money from its reserve to credit Bob’s account. No, what happens instead is this: the amount written in Bank of America’s ledger next to Bob’s name is increased by 10,000, and that’s pretty much it. The confidence is the banking system is preserved through mandatory reserve, corresponding to a fraction (~10%) of the loaned amount.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Which leads us to our next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-myth-of-bits-a-digital-ledger-is-still-a-good-oldledger&#34;&gt;The myth of bits: a digital ledger is still a good old ledger
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we are clear on monetary creation — made by bank and nothing more that an input on a ledger — let’s tackle the last myth surrounding money, the one that states that money became 0 and 1, bits stored somewhere on a server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/1000xcut.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In real life, the nature of money hasn’t changed&lt;/strong&gt;: the good old bank ledger is still authoritative. Its authority comes from the fact that it doesn’t exist in a vacuum: it draws its authority from the whole &lt;strong&gt;political, societal and judiciary system that surround it&lt;/strong&gt;. The way we interact with the ledger (analog or digital) doesn’t reshuffle the decks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With credit cards, ATMs, online banking and all the others “innovations”, it might seem like our monetary system evolved. In reality, we’re still very close to our first monetary systems and our modern currencies follow pretty much the same rules as the old ones. &lt;strong&gt;Innovations and changes happened mostly at the interface level: how we interact with the ledger.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/coins.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the changes happened at the monetary creation level, it used to be much simpler and a state matter but the rest didn’t budge much. Our modern currencies share more with the Gold Franc&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; - pardon my Frenchness - that we imagine. Disruption has yet to happen on currencies, what we had so far is barely a parade of facelifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-sneak-peak-into-the-real-monetary-innovations&#34;&gt;A sneak peak into the real monetary innovations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We needed to lay out the groundwork in order to finally reach this point, the most interesting part: how does real monetary innovation looks like? The answer is not as simple as “Bitcoin”, it can take many forms:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;change-the-ledgers-governance-mechanism&#34;&gt;Change the ledgers’ governance mechanism
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quick reminder: the current trust placed in our ledgers is due to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The reputation of the institutions who handle the monetary systems, be it central banks, private banks or other institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The political, legal and societal framework built around banks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The general public ignorance of the mechanisms governing currencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think it’s not much to hold the whole monetary system afloat; don’t worry, you’re not the only one. Critics have been numerous and early; in the 80s the cypherpunk movement were already looking into alternative currencies to break free from the fiat ones.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiat currencies are intrinsically useless objects that serves a medium of exchanges. They only have value because a government maintain and guarantee it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cypherpunk experimented with digital currencies and eventually lead us to the Bitcoin introduced by Satoshi. With Bitcoin, &lt;strong&gt;the trust in the monetary institutions is no longer required&lt;/strong&gt; (“trustless”). Indeed, in short the idea is as follows: instead of trusting the banks and other institutions to maintain the ledger, why not make that ledger public (=blockchain) and rely on our peers instead? This system also requires the use of cryptography and mechanisms to reach a consensus on the public ledger (so there is only one), but that will be covered in another article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;alter-the-innate-propriety-ofmoney&#34;&gt;Alter the innate propriety of money
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;What about a currency that depreciates if not used? It would help to keep it circulating. The idea is not new, it was theorised in 1916 already by Silvio Gesell and is called demurrage.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of a currency depreciating over time might seem scary at first as it contradict our intuitive comprehension of money (“&lt;em&gt;how can it be a store of value if its value shrink over time?”&lt;/em&gt;). We already have already established that this intuitive comprehension of money was far from the truth of the practical world. This kind of money has an evident interest for recessionary phases, as it promotes spending the money quickly and “punishes” hoarding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;limit-what-kind-of-items-money-can-claim-be-claimedupon&#34;&gt;Limit what kind of items money can claim be claimed upon
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without even altering the innate proprieties of money, we can change what it can be exchanged for. Local currencies are a good example of this. If they are designed carefully, this kind of currencies can help revitalize the local economy and independent businesses. Local currencies are plentiful; the Brixton Pound (B£) is one of the most well known. The team behinds it does a pretty good job to explain their thought process.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article will provide you with a better understanding of money but most importantly that it sparked an interest and it makes you want to learn more about it! The actual monetary innovation has yet to happen. The good news is &lt;strong&gt;now that we have cryptocurrencies, it’s much easier to create new ones&lt;/strong&gt; — pretty much anybody can do it and it’s an excellent news!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It means that all the mechanisms we talked about and many more will be implemented and tested at scale. They already are: there are more than 1500 traded cryptocurrencies and easily another 10 thousands local, confidential or developed for learning purposes. You would like to mint your own coins too? Here’s a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.ethereum.org/2015/12/03/how-to-build-your-own-cryptocurrency/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;guide to get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/money101/bricedollar.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Soon in your wallets: the Brice paper e-Dollar coin pegged on sand&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Soon in your wallets: the Brice paper e-Dollar coin pegged on sand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond what blockchain can offer, maybe here lies the most valuable contribution of Satoshi. &lt;strong&gt;By creating Bitcoin, he paved the way and reminded the whole world that minting money isn’t reserved to states&lt;/strong&gt; — it’s the business of regular people too: you, me, us, and even your computer illiterate grandma should have a say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like all changes, it sounds scary but if you think twice about it, it makes so much sense: &lt;strong&gt;who better than the future users themselves could design the currency the most fitted to their needs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of an original (French) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EcoCrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sources-to-digdeeper&#34;&gt;SOURCES: TO DIG DEEPER
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would like to give a special acknowledgement to Brett Scott who tremendously helped me to understand what money is and the different mechanisms tied to it. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://suitpossum.blogspot.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Go check his blog, it’s worth the read!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://suitpossum.blogspot.com/2016/03/money-is-not-store-of-value.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Money is not a store of value. It is a claim upon value&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Brett Scott for The Hectic’s Guide to Global Finance, on March the 10th 2016&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://neweconomicperspectives.org/2013/09/money-created-overcome-barter.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Was money created to overcome barte r?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Reynold F. Nesiba for New Economic Perspective, on September the 23rd 2013&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03071028008567469&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;The ties that bind: Culture and agriculture, property and propriety in the Newfoundland village fishery&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;— Gerald M.Slider for Social History on May the 30th 2008&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://howwegettonext.com/the-future-of-money-depends-on-busting-the-fairy-tales-you-believe-about-its-past-30cbd90619e0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;The Future of Money Depends on Busting Fairy Tales About Its Past&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Brett Scott for Medium — How We Get to Next?, on March the 30th 2016&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fractional-reserve_banking&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Fractional-reserve Banking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Wikipedia&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1057521914001070&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Can banks individually create money out of nothing? — The theories and the empirical evidence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Richard A. Werner for the International Review of Financial Analysis, in December 2014&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gold_franc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gold Franc&lt;/a&gt;, Wikipedia.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cypherpunk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Cypherpunk&lt;/a&gt;, Wikipedia&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Demurrage_%28currency%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Demurrage (Currency)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Wikipedia&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://brixtonpound.org/what&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;What is the Brixton Pound?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; — Official website of the Britxton Pound&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Nation as a Service and its fractional citizenship- a good idea?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-nation-as-a-service-and-its-fractional-citizenship-a-good-idea/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 11:54:20 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-nation-as-a-service-and-its-fractional-citizenship-a-good-idea/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/naas/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Nation as a Service and its fractional citizenship- a good idea?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;While nationalists movements seem to be thriving, an equally interesting counter trend is shaping itself quietly. Despite nationalists’ wish to provide the services of the nation only to the purest of their kind, others countries are turning to the opposite direction: they are starting to provide services to non-citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Estonia is one of the pioneers reshaping role of the nation and what being a “citizen” even means. Since the launch of the e-residency program, close than 30 000 world citizens applied. Yet e-Estonia is only beginning: the country is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/happy-3rd-birthday-to-our-global-e-resident-community-7143adc73994&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;aiming to reach 10 millions e-resident by 2025&lt;/a&gt;, for a country counting 1.35 million “physical” citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we explore what a Nation as a Service entails, you’ll remark that all of its features already existing in regular nations. The NaaS simply take it so much farther than the nation itself become something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-birth-of-the-nation-as-aservice&#34;&gt;The Birth of the Nation as a Service
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I first introduced the concept in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/the-demise-of-nation-states-introducing-the-nation-as-a-service-naas/&#34; &gt;a very raw article&lt;/a&gt; that went from my head to Medium in 90 minutes. It started with a tale to introduce the concept that scared some readers and hurt the political sensibility of others. While passion could be nice, I wanted to offer a more formal take on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first introduced the concept, I depicted the “4 cornerstones of the Nation as a Service” as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of nation state, as we use to know it, becomes obsolete. Regular nations are decomposing or powerless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the void, “digital nations” emerge. They might be tied to real nations (like Estonia), entirely virtual, or even raise money (ICO?) to purchase a land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These digital nations will offer the same services offered by our current nations, on a narrower scope: they will focus mostly on business regulations. Then, the most advanced ones might expand their scope: finance, currency, healthcare, education…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, citizens won’t be tied to a nation by birth anymore. Citizens will compare the offers from different nations and choose their fit. They might have to pay for the service (Estionian e-residency is 100€ one time cost). Nations will compete with one another to attract citizens, and extreme concentration is possible (winner-takes-all market): there are no limits anymore to contain the amount of citizens a nation can have. We’ll observe the birth of “Citizenship portability” — changing nationality will be easier than changing of internet service provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still stand by them, but allow me to dive deeper today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-formal-definition-of-the-nation-as-a-servicenaas&#34;&gt;A formal definition of the Nation as a Service (NaaS)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s go straight to the point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Nation as a Service (NaaS) provides a digital fractional citizenship under a subscription model.&lt;/strong&gt; The definition might be short but it’s quite dense, let’s unfold it methodically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-is-digital-native&#34;&gt;The NaaS is digital-native
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The concept of NaaS emerged over the last few years. The first full-fledged NaaS is e-Estonia which opened up its e-residency 3 years ago. Since these new nations were born in a digital world from start, we observe a drastic paradigm shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It translates into the incorporation of digital concepts in the very nature of the state:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital first&lt;/strong&gt;: all public services are available online and remotely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Open data&lt;/strong&gt;: making public data accessible to all through APIs. This allow for the creation of third-party services for public infrastructure: the easiest example to grasp would be the app that gives the departure time of trains/metros/bus already available in most big cities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data portability between public services&lt;/strong&gt;: there is no need to resubmit information to every public service anymore. One submission to the relevant service is enough since the access is shared to other public services that might need it (with the citizens’ consent of course).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These concepts might be hard to envision in practice, so let me take you to Estonia thanks to Kaspar Korjus (the managing director of the e-residency program). He depicts what it means in the real world while he talks about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/e-residency-blog/what-is-a-nation-children-born-today-will-grow-up-with-a-radically-different-answer-b31f14403c3c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the birth of his son Ruufus&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This information &lt;/p&gt;
\[The name, sex, date of birth and parents of the children, registered by the doctor at the hospital\]
&lt;p&gt; is really useful straight away because various parts of government would need it to better serve us as new parents, such as by scheduling health checks, supporting with child care and allocating our parental leave allowance. This would generate added hassle for new parents in most countries, but in Estonia the information begins flowing automatically between departments and agencies along our secure, decentralised information network known as the ‘X-road’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear in mind that e-Estonia is a digital nation built on top of a regular one. Now imagine what kind of efficiency a digital nation from start could achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-offers-fractional-citizenship&#34;&gt;The NaaS offers fractional citizenship
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The citizenship offered by a NaaS is not a full-fledged citizenship. So far Estonian e-residents can open up an Estonian bank account and own a business, but they can’t settle in Estonia or vote. The choice was made for practical reasons: it’s much easier to start small.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next years, we will see new features added to the service provided by NaaS. Since the idea of single citizenship status for all citizens is already shattered in pieces, the logic will be pushed even further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be different tiers of citizens who have access to different services. The most bare bone tier being the only made only of the identity verification protocols while the most advanced one will eventually offer something similar to our current citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-naas-is-available-under-a-subscription-model&#34;&gt;The NaaS is available under a subscription model
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The subscription model is the direct consequence of the fractional citizenship. Since the citizenship is now made of different parts citizens can choose to subscribe to or not, we can envision the establishment of a subscription model for the NaaS, with several different options ranging from a pure business citizenship to a full-fledged citizenship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, in e-Estonia it’s a single 100€ fee to submit a candidacy. In the future, it might take the form a yearly/monthly subscription with different features. Here’s what I see, from the most basic to the most advanced one. The first two are already available in the Estonian e-residency in its current form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identity citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: provide a digital ID card allowing the holder to prove its identity to public or private services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: provide the ability to open a bank account and set up a business in the country.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;: allows the benefactor to vote and participate in local (city/region) elections and create NGOs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political citizenship:&lt;/strong&gt; allows the benefactor to vote at national elections and other public consultations such as referendums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription to the &lt;strong&gt;national Healthcare service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subscription to the &lt;strong&gt;national pension plan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to the &lt;strong&gt;full-fledged citizenship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: All these different features will probably be gated behind conditions, such as being an e-citizen for X years, and an additional fee.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;citizenship-portability&#34;&gt;Citizenship portability
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another direct consequence of all three characteristic of the NaaS depicted below is the notion of citizenship portability. Since citizenships become subscription based, what used to be an edge case — changing nationality — will become commonplace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, with more and more fractional citizenships available under a subscription model, “prospects” might start to compare the offers essentially putting citizenships in competition with one another. Some might even stack or mix and match different citizenship offers. E-Nations will have to account for this new trend and provide services to facilitate the switch from one NaaS to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;CONCLUSION
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This article was written to be nothing more than an analysis giving you a framework to read the current shift happening on the very definition of a nation. I tried my best to avoid any judgement one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I think the ongoing shift I described in this article will have tremendous consequences, many of which are not yet envisioned. I still can’t really figure how to feel about this, I jump from curiosity to anger, or from fascination to despair. What about you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of an original (French) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EcoCrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to Crypto Bullshit: How to spot a shitcoin?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-crypto-bullshit-how-to-spot-a-shitcoin/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 10:36:25 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-hitchhikers-guide-to-crypto-bullshit-how-to-spot-a-shitcoin/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The Hitchhiker&#39;s Guide to Crypto Bullshit: How to spot a shitcoin?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking to invest in an ICO, or get your hands on some already traded coins? Awesome, welcome aboard! Before you jump in, let me give you some clues to spot shaky projects with examples taken from actual ones. These tips come from my experience (and failures) as well the discussion I had both with friends and the cryptocurrency community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-whitepaper-is-always-the-most-insightful-resource&#34;&gt;The Whitepaper is ALWAYS the most insightful resource
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whitepapers (WP for the rest of this article) can be scary. While some manage to keep it short (~10 pages), others can reach the hundreds yet it’s the best place to gauge the seriousness of a project. &lt;strong&gt;It’s still the first thing I check once I’m seriously considering a coin&lt;/strong&gt;. So what should you be watching closely in a WP?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-englishlanguage&#34;&gt;The English Language
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Surprising? Not so much if you put it this way: &lt;strong&gt;how to trust an organization unable to put out a flawless WP with a decentralized cryptocurrency project?&lt;/strong&gt; It might seem small or even petty, but if you find a low-quality English or repeated typos in the WP, you better start running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;big-promises-with-technical-vagueness&#34;&gt;Big Promises with technical vagueness
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most common, as most people won’t read the technical parts of the whitepaper. Even if you don’t fully get the technical details, the difference between a WP trying to cover its lies and a transparent one are quite apparent. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.sficoin.co/white-paper/white-paper.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SFIcoin is the perfect example of this — DONT INVEST: SCAM&lt;/a&gt;, the full recipe is here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big promises that don’t mean anything&lt;/strong&gt;: “The Next Global Paying System”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unbacked claims&lt;/strong&gt;: their WP that details the vision, the roadmap, the use cases but doesn’t address AT all the tech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not the least, the SFICOIN is just going to be the first leading peer to peer cryptocurrency to manage the high-value instant payments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“We will be the first to X”&lt;/strong&gt;: massive red flag. There are no certainties in cryptocurrencies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A WP made by marketers for marketers&lt;/strong&gt; lot of visuals, a lot of work on design but overall it’s empty of real meaning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s ok for a WP to get quite technical (here is Stellar’s — XLM), but it’s not OK to cover an absence of technical solution with jargon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/stellar-wp.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;stellar-wp&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-darwin-awards-of-whitepapers&#34;&gt;The Darwin Awards of Whitepapers
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wanna see how does a terrible WP looks like? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://narbonne.io/Narbonne.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Check Narbonne’s&lt;/a&gt;, it’s been 7 months and I can’t find any worse. Out of the 22 pages, ~18 are spitting copy pasta about the future. Most of the paper is very generic, and so many things in it are so off. I had to pick one so here we go, the comparison between Narbonne, Ether&lt;strong&gt;i&lt;/strong&gt;um and Wa&lt;strong&gt;w&lt;/strong&gt;es. Yes, you read it right, they can’t even spell Ethereum and Waves properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/narbonne-wp.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;narbonne-wp&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many things need to be debunked in this table, it’s actually a good exercise. Here are a few you do the rest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Bookkeeping at the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/blockchain&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt;”: I’m not even sure what it means, but I think a project like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://request.network/#/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Request (REQ)&lt;/a&gt; covers this for Ethereum.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Mobile Banking”: Hello &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://omisego.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OmiseGo&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“AI, chatbot, voice control”: strictly no use for the project (an infrastructure for banks) but buzzwords so they had to be here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;how-does-a-proper-wp-looklike&#34;&gt;How does a proper WP look like?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;A WP is a &lt;strong&gt;technical document&lt;/strong&gt; usually presenting at least:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The vision for the project / what problem the team is trying to crack,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of the technical solutions proposed to the problem and why they were chosen,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The details of the technical implementation of the chosen solutions,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A credible roadmap for the delivery,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical information about the token: token type, total amount, token mechanisms…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifications for the ICO, if any.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To hone your skills, there is nothing better than the OG! I invite you to read the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;original Bitcoin’s whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; written by Satoshi. You can also check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ethereum/wiki/wiki/White-Paper&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ethereum’s WP&lt;/a&gt; to remind you that &lt;strong&gt;the design doesn’t have to be fancy&lt;/strong&gt; (it’s a GitHub wiki) if the fundamentals are sound.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cardano’s WPs: split between a “&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cardano.org/en/philosophy/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;philosophical WP&lt;/a&gt;” and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cardano.org/en/academic-papers/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;academic papers&lt;/a&gt;, I think the team does an outstanding job to make their project intelligible to those interested.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-transactions-per-secondmyth&#34;&gt;The Transactions per second myth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve got the whitepapers covered, let me address another big chunk of today’s article: the myth of the transactions per second (TPS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;transaction-per-second-a-convenient-lie&#34;&gt;Transaction per second: A convenient lie
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TPS doesn’t mean anything at all.&lt;/strong&gt; So why is it so popular? Well, it’s a bit like the GHz for processors: it used to be the only thing advertised. It makes sense in a way, &lt;strong&gt;it gives the impression&lt;/strong&gt; that you have a standard allowing you to compare different processors that are actually not comparable: higher is always better right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, no. You can have a 32 bit 1 core processor operating at 3.5 GHz and a 64 bits 8 cores processor operating at 2 GHz. Guess which one delivers the most computing power? It’s the second one without a doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s exactly the same for the tokens, except it’s not only the power that matters here. Let me pull &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/coinmonks/why-decentralization-matters-a-12-min-overview-for-the-layman-6ec572d35af6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a quick reminder from my previous article if you missed it&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The choice to make a system more decentralized isn’t made for performance; it’s made for the advantages provided by decentralization. It allows creating new kind of services offering guarantees that weren’t possible before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the TPS is meaningless, it’s almost expected now. Newcomer investors will put significant trust in this very misleading indicator, and most projects advertise a given TPS. Good! It gives you a good sign of how honest they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;using-tps-to-cut-through-thecrap&#34;&gt;Using TPS to cut through the crap
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consider coin A, advertising 1M TPS and coin B advertising 10 TPS. What about the features they support? What about decentralization? What about the team vision? Community support? Simply by looking at the number, I know now that Coin A is bullshit and coin B could be OK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/nano.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;nano&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The current state of the art of tech allows for a maximum of ~10 000 TPS (already huge) without excessive centralization.&lt;/strong&gt; Any coin promising something higher than this is either:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Making compromise on decentralization.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@CryptoPeterG/eos-centralization-problem-bd7a392eeed2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The prime example of this EOS&lt;/a&gt; and its 21 block producers that have tremendous power over the network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lab scenario&lt;/strong&gt;: you can see some coins advertising crazy TPS, some will even show a test network supporting their claim. The thing to look for is the setup of the test network: usually, it’s just a few nodes. It’s easy to reach a high TPS on a three nodes &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/network&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;network&lt;/a&gt;, but it gets harder and harder as the nodes multiply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Banking on novel and previously untested technological solutions.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nano.org/en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NANO&lt;/a&gt; uses a new kind of ledger called block-lattice and supports up to 7 000 TPS in ideal conditions. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.iota.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IOTA&lt;/a&gt; which uses another radically new solution (the Tangle) currently supports ~800 TPS, but it will scale with user adoption. Those two are the most radical “ledger innovations” there are and the most promising. They are the current state of the art: to me any project advertising TPS over this without an equally radically new technical solution is instantly suspicious.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Including &lt;strong&gt;off-chain scaling&lt;/strong&gt; solutions in their computation of TPS, which leads back to point one: excessive centralization.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Including new mechanisms such as sharding&lt;/strong&gt; in their computation. Ethereum which has arguably one of the most robust dev community there is, is still 1 to 2 years away from a live implementation of sharding. How could a bunch of newcomers pull this in 6 months?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulling this number out of their hat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: A cryptocurrency development project often starts quite centralized. What matters is that the team have a plan to open up the network progressively. For instance, NEO is quite centralized for now, but now that the infrastructure is sound&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://neo.org/blog/details/4089&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;the team is making moves towards decentralizing more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we conclude, let us dive into the crazy world of ICOs, it’s such a wild west that it deserves another section by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;icos-red-flags-to-lookfor&#34;&gt;ICOs red flags to look for
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;huge-discounts-for-earlybirds&#34;&gt;Huge discounts for early birds
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you see an ICO offering huge discounts (&amp;gt;30%) on the first phases of the sale that’s usually a recipe for disaster. Indeed, it means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since the early birds get such a large discount, they have a &lt;strong&gt;strong incentive to dump at ICO price or even a little below&lt;/strong&gt; once the token hit the market: it’s guaranteed free money if they sell fast enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why should the team need such a strong incentive to drive the sale? I see this pattern a lot for &lt;strong&gt;tokens with close to no utility&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even the two situations above don’t unfold, one is guaranteed: huge discounts push towards a concentration of the tokens in the hand of a few: it attracts whales. Massive discounts are a recipe for &lt;strong&gt;political centralization and governance problems&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;no-product-demo-orcode&#34;&gt;No product, demo or code
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The big risk with ICOs is that you’re essentially investing on a promise or a vision. Yet some ask for money once they already have a working alpha while some others run straight to the ICO as soon as the WP is ready. The latter is much riskier. If there is an alpha or a demo version available, please do check it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you’re not a dev, &lt;strong&gt;it’s always insightful to check the GitHub repository of the project.&lt;/strong&gt; GitHub makes it easy to see how active the repository is, even without looking at the code. This method is far from perfect are there are ways to make it look like a repo is active even if it’s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-team-doesntmatch&#34;&gt;The team doesn’t match
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are seriously considering investing in an ICO, I urge you to google the most prominent team members. Look at their LinkedIn, their Twitter, their previous companies, etc. If you find inactive profiles, it’s usually a pretty bad sign. You might also find skeletons in the closest, such as one team member who participated in another crypto project that turned out to be a failure or a scam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/team.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Screenshot for Banano, a NANO fork that doesn’t take itself too seriously&#34;
	
	
&gt;)
Screenshot for &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://banano.co.in/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Banano, a NANO fork&lt;/a&gt; that doesn’t take itself too seriously&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A low quality or frequency social media presence is also a bright orange flag. These guys will have to market their project, acquire users and partners. If they can’t market themselves, it’s already a shaky start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s also very common for ICO scams to advertise a prestigious advisor… that has nothing to do with the project&lt;/strong&gt;. Double check any high profile figure to make sure they are actually involved in the project. If you see Satoshi as advisor, RUN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;inappropriate-token-distribution&#34;&gt;Inappropriate token distribution
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The token distribution chart is usually present in every WP. If it’s not, it’s essentially like “give us your money, and we won’t tell you what we’ll do with it”… RUN!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It usually looks like a pie chart. The most transparent projects have two: one for the distribution of the tokens, and one covering how the funds will be spent by team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/hitchhikerguide/distribution.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Storm token distribution is pretty good (source)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Storm token distribution is pretty good (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.stormtoken.com/token-structure-and-ceo-update-bd055860251e&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;source&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s ok, even good that the team reserves a share of the token for the development of the project. You have to watch the share allocated to the team: it can range from 10% to 30% for the reasonable projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other extreme of the spectrum, you have coins like Ripple (XRP) for which the team owns ~60% of the total supply. It is a significant risk for token holders: first, it’s an enormous vector of centralization. Besides, it means that &lt;strong&gt;the team can heavily manipulate the price of its coin&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: A few months ago, facing a backlash against this very centralized distribution, the team put an escrow system in place using a smart contract.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ripple.com/dev-blog/explanation-ripples-xrp-escrow/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;55 billions tokens are now placed in escrow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;and released at the pace of 1 billion per month. It doesn’t change anything to the underlying centralization issue and makes me wonder which kind of team would need $500 million (current price of XRP ~ $0.5) each month for its development/partnership/other. Besides,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;since these tokens are now locked they are not counted in the circulating supply (~39B)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;, which might reassure investors but is purely misleading. The actual supply is 100B tokens. Personal view: the whole move feels like a marketing stunt.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote this article to provide you with some clues to help you spot unreliable crypto projects. Overall, I hope that you understand by now that &lt;strong&gt;the more you read before investing, the lower the risk will be&lt;/strong&gt;. I advise you NOT TO INVEST IMPULSIVELY. Even if it’s the best project in the world, you can sleep on it, read some more and decide a couple of days later with a fresh outlook if you want in or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finish, let me give you more tricks I use to get a quick idea of the seriousness of the project:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google search &lt;code&gt;site:reddit.com &amp;quot;token name (+scam/shitcoin/issues...)&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;: this method allows you to search Reddit for a specific token. If there is a massive red flag on the project, it&amp;rsquo;s usually documented somewhere on Reddit. &lt;em&gt;Additional note: Reddit is getting quite tribal now. The best place to find reliable information on a given token is certainly not the token subreddit. Don&amp;rsquo;t go to /r/Ripple/ if you want an objective perspective on XRP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t trust one single source, always cross them!&lt;/strong&gt; Greedy people are promoting shaky projects all around the internet, never blindly trust just one guy even if he seems to be honest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Several services exist to organize the community due diligence on ICOs. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://icocheck.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ICOCheck&lt;/a&gt; is a pretty reliable one, but do your own due diligence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last but not least: &lt;strong&gt;I strongly recommend you to not invest in ICOs for at least the first year you’ve been invested in cryptos&lt;/strong&gt;. A lot of them fail dramatically. You are much better off limiting yourself to the top 25/100/200 tokens depending on the risk you’re willing to take. Even among those, there are many doubtful projects: beware and happy investing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: You have some tricks to spot an unreliable project you haven’t seen in this piece? Feel free to share them below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me know if you liked this article and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/Ahirice/BCC/wiki&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check out my wiki for more content like this.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Don’t forget to clap it&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;to help it spread:&lt;/strong&gt; you can keep pressing  👏up to 50 claps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is the translation of an original (French) &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EcoCrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; story.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why decentralization matters? A 12 min overview for the layman</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/why-decentralization-matters-a-12-min-overview-for-the-layman/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 08:31:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/why-decentralization-matters-a-12-min-overview-for-the-layman/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Why decentralization matters? A 12 min overview for the layman" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the general public is hearing more and more about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/blockchain&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; and cryptocurrencies, the philosophical and political underlying of decentralization are still kept mostly within the community. &lt;strong&gt;Decentralization is bringing a paradigm shift that deserves more coverage than price action in my book&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few months ago, I realized that I didn’t really understood decentralization. I got the high-level concept, but I failed to connect all the dots and &lt;strong&gt;understand the social and political ramifications of it.&lt;/strong&gt; Since then, I’ve done my homework and now it’s time to give back my humble understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;doomsayer-gets-the-spotlight&#34;&gt;DOOMSAYER GETS THE SPOTLIGHT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/homer.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Simpsons: Season 16, Episode 19 — Thank God it’s Doomsday&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The Simpsons: Season 16, Episode 19 — Thank God it’s Doomsday&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralization is not an easy change to apprehend. Imagine yourself in the internet early days, let’s say 1995. Could you have thought about all the potential use cases for this new tech and how they were going to unfold? Back then, you even had prominent actors from the tech industry &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.newstatesman.com/science-tech/internet/2016/08/25-years-here-are-worst-ever-predictions-about-internet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;predicting the uselessness or failure of the internet&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robert Metcalfe, in InfoWorld, 1995:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I predict the Internet will soon go spectacularly supernova and in 1996 catastrophically collapse.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waring Partridge, in Wired, 1995:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Most things that succeed don’t require retraining 250 million people.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s easy to laugh at them now, but ask yourself this question: Aren’t you doing exactly the same thing with decentralized services?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first audience for this article are people who read two articles from mainstream medias before concluding that decentralization is stupid. &lt;strong&gt;Let me be the third and the charm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mainstream medias are here to promote emotional content that makes you react, so you get your dopamine shot and come back. They are not here to help you learn and grow. They caused their own demise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, for one am simply a 26 years old French dude with a knack for writing and time on his hand. &lt;strong&gt;I have nothing to sell to you, but simply one goal: help people to realize what’s happening, so they can be part of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve tested the draft on people aged anything from 20y old to 60+. &lt;strong&gt;It’s foolproof, as long as your willing to lend me 12 minutes of your attention&lt;/strong&gt;. You’ll gain a framework allowing you to see decentralization for what it is: the premise of a new world order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is hard, scary and confusing. It destroys your previous references and leaves you in a world where you have to re-think everything again. It’s a lot of work to adapt, but the earlier your start, the easiest it is, just like it happened for Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to share this piece with your decentralization-sceptic and decentralization-enthusiast friends alike!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralization-is-multidimensional-spectrum&#34;&gt;Decentralization is multidimensional spectrum
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It might seem obvious to some, but it’s an important fact: &lt;strong&gt;Decentralization is a spectrum, not a state&lt;/strong&gt;. It goes from the most centralized systems possible, such as our current fiat monetary systems (&lt;strong&gt;“Central”&lt;/strong&gt; Banks decide pretty much everything) to the most decentralized systems, such as the English language (more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive in, here is an interesting infographic giving you an overview of the centralization of major industries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/industry-landscape.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Thanks to Lillian Wei, Source&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Thanks to Lillian Wei, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/blockchain-governance-how-decentralized-do-we-need-to-be-799a7988ce84&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you get the spectrum of decentralization, the second thing to understand is the &lt;strong&gt;different dimensions of decentralization.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hard part is than in absolute, they aren’t any typology of the different dimensions of decentralization. To make things easier, I’m gonna use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cgStgMyR9sY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the one proposed by Vitalik Buterin&lt;/a&gt; (Co-Founder of Ethereum, one of the leading decentralization projects) that features three main dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-architectural-dimension&#34;&gt;1. The Architectural Dimension
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This dimension is easy to grasp because about the physical things&lt;/strong&gt;: the devices, the servers, the stuff! The architectural dimension address &lt;strong&gt;the base units of the network&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maximize architectural decentralization, you’ll need to multiply the devices powering your &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/network&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;network&lt;/a&gt;, and spread them around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/tangle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Graphical representation of the transactions happening on the IOTA Network (Tangle). Visualizer: Tangle.glumb.be&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Graphical representation of the transactions happening on the IOTA Network (Tangle). &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://tangle.glumb.de/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Visualizer: Tangle.glumb.be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To know how architecturally decentralized a system is, you can ask these questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many underlying devices are powering the network?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they geographically spread or concentrated in one area?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-the-political-dimension&#34;&gt;2. The Political Dimension
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Politics is about power. This dimension address the &lt;strong&gt;decision making process of the system&lt;/strong&gt;. The most politically centralized protocol is one where a sole decision maker makes all the shots. At the other end of the spectrum, you’ll have many actors and evenly distributed responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/politics.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the most politically decentralized systems, the spread between the least influential node and the most influential node is kept to a minimum. The perfectly politically decentralized network would offer the same influence to any node.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some good questions to determine how politically decentralized a system is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many people/groups are involved in the decision making process?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the power repartition looks like? What kind of criteria is used to weight each participant influence?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are they any recourse / appeal mechanisms built in the system?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-the-logical-dimension&#34;&gt;3. The Logical Dimension
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The logical dimension is by far the hardest of the three to understand. Don’t give up if you don’t get it from the first read! In Vitalik’s terms, it reads like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does your system look like one thing single thing like a singleton or does it look more like an amorphous swarm?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Essentially, this dimension is about the differences between each nodes that compose the network. To maximize logical decentralization, you want them to diverse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t let some fancy words scare you, it’s actually not so hard. Looking at examples really helped me understand this one, so here they are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A direct democracy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The architecture of a direct democracy is quite centralized&lt;/strong&gt;: there are a few places (parliament, chambers, police, military…) that are the nodes of the protocol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Despite the architectural centralization, the decision power is spread in a direct democracy so &lt;strong&gt;the protocol is politically decentralized.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It’s logically centralized&lt;/strong&gt; — aka it’s one main “body”. There is only one government enforcing one set of laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nation vs Federation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both are architecturally centralized,&lt;/strong&gt; for the same reason than the direct democracy: there are only a few locations/institutions where the action happens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both are also politically centralized&lt;/strong&gt;: the president/assembly/other elected or not officials hold most of the power, without any public oversight. You can’t swap president two years in, you have to wait the full term, even if the president lie, collude with foreign powers, mishandle public money… Hi to the elephant in the room! The federation might be a little less politically centralized than the nation, but it’s quite similar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The logical dimension is where things get interesting. While &lt;strong&gt;a nation is one unique main “body”, aka logically centralized&lt;/strong&gt;, a federation is made of distinct “parts” that acknowledge and preserve their difference while working towards a common goal. Hence the federation is a good example of logically decentralized system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/decentralisation-quadrant.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Logical centralization overview for common protocols (Source: Vitalik Buterin)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Logical centralization overview for common protocols (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cgStgMyR9sY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Source: Vitalik Buterin&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The English Language&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The architecture is very decentralized.&lt;/strong&gt; Considering the English language as a protocol, a node would be any English speaking person. The good news is they are plenty, they are diverse, and spread all around the world!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The political dimension of it is also quite decentralized.&lt;/strong&gt; There is no single governing body deciding what English is and is not. Yes, there are official institutions publishing English Grammars for instance, but the grammar is not law: you can choose to follow it or not. The actual English, the one linguists study, is not the one depicted in a grammar, it’s the one spoken by all English speaking individuals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;it’s also very logically decentralized&lt;/strong&gt;. Two English speakers coming from different countries might speak an English that is very different from one another, because of the vocabulary, the emphasis, or even the sentence structure. You have many different kind of English spoken all around the globe: American English, UK English, my beloved Frenglish…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-three-dimensional-decentralization-spectrum&#34;&gt;Using the three dimensional decentralization spectrum
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each dimension is mostly independent from one another. &lt;strong&gt;You can have a service at one end of the spectrum for one dimension, and the other end on another&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study-web-hostingservices&#34;&gt;Case Study: Web Hosting Services
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Web hosting services such as AWS (Amazon Web Services) are the perfect example of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From an architectural perspective, they want their network to be as decentralized as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. As a hosting provider, AWS need to be reliable. To do so, they have many servers so that the redundancy builds resilience. Moreover, &lt;strong&gt;both for performance and security reasons, they have their servers spread all around the world&lt;/strong&gt;. It reduces latency and further increase resilience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/aws.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Overview of the main AWS datacenters location. Source: AWS.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Overview of the main AWS datacenters location. Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/global-infrastructure/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AWS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet, from a political perspective, Amazon has absolute control over the network. They can refuse to serve you, delete your content (if it’s illegal for instance) and the AWS user community no say on their decisions. &lt;strong&gt;Hence, on the political dimension, AWS is close the most centralized end of the spectrum.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, on the logical dimension AWS is centralized, it’s a pretty monolithic company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-significant-hassle-than-can-be-worth-thetrouble&#34;&gt;A significant hassle than can be worth the trouble
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’re clear on the decentralization spectrum, you might wonder why going through the hassle? Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;decentralized systems tend to be more complex and harder to manage that centralized ones&lt;/strong&gt;: they have many different components, a decision power spread between several parties and an accountability imperative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-decentralized-systems-efficient-for-computations&#34;&gt;Are decentralized systems efficient for computations?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;All those requirements weight on the system and slow it down, right? So why go through the hassle?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out it’s even more than that! It can be hard to find a relevant comparison between centralized and decentralized systems, but the price of computing power is probably the easiest to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right now, the ratio between the cost of the computing power on the Ethereum Word Computer vs a traditional one (ex Amazon EC2) is between roughly one million&lt;/strong&gt;. Scary ratio, right? (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a-xHiI-G_CQ&amp;amp;t=251s&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Don’t trust me, go here to check&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well… yes and no. First, you have to consider how cheap computing power got over the last couple decades. We’re reaching a point where even just $1 spent on AWS represents a tremendous amount of computing power. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.visualcapitalist.com/visualizing-trillion-fold-increase-computing-power/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This page&lt;/a&gt; presents the evolution of computing over the last 25 years with neat infographics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/decentralisation-layman/storage.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Hard Disks dramatically increased in capacity while becoming more compact. Source&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Hard Disks dramatically increased in capacity while becoming more compact. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.visualcapitalist.com/visualizing-trillion-fold-increase-computing-power/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Source&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And well, we’ve got to ask ourselves: does the comparison even makes sense? It can be useful to understand the current state of our tech, but does it tell us anything else?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The choice to make a system more decentralized isn’t made for performance; it’s made for the advantages provided by decentralization&lt;/strong&gt;. It allows creating new kind of services offering guarantees that weren’t possible before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralizations-benefits-the-edge-of-thecrowd&#34;&gt;Decentralization’s benefits: The Edge of the Crowd
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To put it simply, decentralized systems offer a set of unique advantages opening a wide range of use cases. Let’s go through the main advantages one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;efficiency&#34;&gt;EFFICIENCY
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In some cases, making a system decentralized is simply the best way to answer your needs&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, the physical distribution of post offices is decentralized. It wouldn’t be efficient to have all the post offices in the same city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another notion that can play a large role for the efficiency of a system: &lt;strong&gt;spare capacity&lt;/strong&gt;. Consider people who already own a resource (let’s say a house or car), but only use it 10% of the time. Instead of having to build a whole new infrastructure for your service, you can use instead the spare capacity that is already available: hello Uber or Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fault-tolerance&#34;&gt;FAULT TOLERANCE
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since a decentralized system is redundant (there are no elements that exist only once, all have many “copies”), &lt;strong&gt;the risk of the whole system failing accidentally is much more limited than a centralized system.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s precisely why web hosting services have to be architecturally decentralized. But many systems benefit from fault tolerance: consider the energy production/distribution network for instance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is another notion quite useful to understand why decentralized system are resilient, it’s the &lt;strong&gt;SPOF. Single Point of Failure&lt;/strong&gt; is a term used in network infrastructure to describe an element than is not redundant: it exists only once. &lt;strong&gt;If this element was to fail, it would bring the whole system down, hence the name.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re still following, you should be able to connect the dots: since everything is redundant in a an architecturally decentralized system, there are no SPOF. If there is a SPOF, it means that there is a single/central element somewhere (that could break), hence it’s not a decentralized system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;attack-resistance&#34;&gt;ATTACK RESISTANCE
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attack resistance is essentially a matter of cost/benefit. &lt;strong&gt;Unattackable systems don’t exist, what do exist are systems that are simply to costly to attack considering the potential reward.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also consider malicious actors that would be looking to damage the protocol not for direct financial benefit, but for something else. Maybe it’s a competitor trying to bring you down? Even in that scenario, the attacker would need to dedicate a lot of resource to have a chance to bring a decentralized system down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting fact to consider is also that information is spread over many devices. &lt;strong&gt;If an attacker manage to get control over one device, he only gets access to a fragment of the whole dataset.&lt;/strong&gt; It makes the system more resilient to hacks, as the data is less exposed. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.google.fr/search?q=ashley&amp;#43;madison&amp;#43;hack&amp;amp;rlz=1C1CHBF_enFR792FR792&amp;amp;oq=ASHLEY&amp;#43;MADISON&amp;#43;HACK&amp;amp;aqs=chrome.0.0l6.3446j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Too bad Ashley Madison wasn’t architecturally decentralized.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;collusion-resistance&#34;&gt;COLLUSION RESISTANCE
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The idea behind collusion resistance is to make it hard for one subgroup of the system to come together and act only for their own best interest, to the detriment of the whole system. The extreme example of collusion would be a monopoly — it lets actor gain an unfair advantage over the whole market and impose its bidding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For instance, in our modern democracies, collusion resistance is extremely low&lt;/strong&gt;: the common interest of the system (the betterment of the country) is frequently, some would even say systematically hijacked by specific subgroups (such as businesses) for their own benefits (profits).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decentralization is a high level concept that is essential to understand blockchain and other decentralized ledgers. If you want to explore further, you can look at videos of founders of the major project explaining their vision to get a better idea of what a decentralized system enable:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0lJDy5wvwaU&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Here is Vitalik Buterin explaining what ETH is for the layman. \[03:51\]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_BnBmBZPvS8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles Hoskinson explaining the Cardano team approach and what Cardano is trying to achieve. \[1:02:49\]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gA5X69YY3yY&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NEO explained by its founder Da HongFei. \[16:04\]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might have missed the internet revolution, but you’re in luck for this one: it’s barely beginning! &lt;strong&gt;Now is the time to get knowledgeable about it so you can recognize and harness opportunities as they emerge&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you get a better understanding of the paradigm shift offered by the newfound ability to develop decentralized protocols at scale, thanks to blockchain. and other decentralized protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>EcoCrypto&#39;s Manifesto</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/ecocryptos-manifesto/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 10:36:03 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/ecocryptos-manifesto/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome on Ecocrypto, the incorruptible French publication soon to become a reference. EcoCrypto was created to provide an answer the lack of honest and qualitative content in the French crypto ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The manifesto establishes the rules we will abide by to ensure EcoCrypto starts and stays majestic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecocrypto-brings-a-slow-approach-to-news&#34;&gt;EcoCrypto brings a slow approach to news
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We take our time to produce high-quality content. We don’t just write a commentary or a reaction to the latest news. We follow our own pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have but one agenda: broaden the crypto world. We want to include as many people as possible in the discussion currently taking place in the cryptosphere. We think the crypto community would benefit from ALL perspectives, and especially the perspectives of those who are presently left out such as people who are unfamiliar with new technologies, or those who don’t speak English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We write content to make you think, to help you learn, and to challenge your views to broaden your perspective on the world as a whole. If a given piece of content cannot fit any other these three goals, it will not be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralization and cryptocurrencies are our focus, but they don’t happen in a vacuum: they will affect the whole world. Hence, we won’t restrict ourselves, and we will bring insights from politics, sociology, philosophy and any other relevant field when appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;are-you-schizophrenic-brice-whats-up-with--we-&#34;&gt;Are you schizophrenic Brice? What’s up with « we »?
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe EcoCrypto will grow bigger than myself. Yet, I’m not afraid to carry this project alone as long as necessary. Anyone who recognizes oneself in this manifesto is welcome to join the adventure. The adherence to the manifesto and the quality of the content are the two only required criteria to be able to publish on EcoCrypto.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ecocrypto-is-part-of-the-new-world-and-held-to-its-standards&#34;&gt;EcoCrypto is part of the new world and held to its standards
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Youngsters and oldsters alike from all around the world finally have the chance to step up and do their part in a new genesis. We will hold ourselves to the highest standards to ensure we are not steering this blank state back to its greedy roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will enforce the following policies from day one:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;centralized-and-proprietary-services-minimization&#34;&gt;Centralized and Proprietary Services Minimization
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will avoid using proprietary and centralized services as much as possible. Ultimately, our goal is using none. We won’t be using Google Analytics for obvious reasons. We won’t implement that freakin’ Facebook pixel or any other tracking pixel. To still have exploitable stats on our website, we implemented &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://matomo.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Matomo (ex Piwit)&lt;/a&gt;, the self-hosted open analytics solution. We will always prefer an open-source solution if available. The blog is currently powered by WordPress and hosted on SiteGround for its first year. Feel free to reach out if you can figure a more privacy-conscious solution covering our needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;no-sympathy-for-the-devils&#34;&gt;No sympathy for the devils
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While EcoCrypto will need awareness at first, we don’t want compromise with our principles. We will allow ourselves one year of presence on centralized social networks to help develop the initial awareness around Ecocrypto. After that date, it will be time for a cleanup. Since EcoCrypto was officially launched today (07/08/2018), all of our social accounts on centralized services will be deleted on the 8th of July 2019. Hell, we’ll make it a party!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;writers-privacy&#34;&gt;Writers Privacy
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosing your identity is not a requirement to become a writer. Simply send us an email at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:redaction@ecocrypto.fr&#34; &gt;redaction@ecocrypto.fr&lt;/a&gt; from a disposable email address. As long as the content is sound and follows the principles stated in this document, we really don’t give a fuck about your name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;manifestos-accountability&#34;&gt;Manifesto’s Accountability
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If any change is made to this document, the previous versions will be kept online and accessible. You will be able to find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ecocrypto.fr/manifeste/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;all the editions of the manifesto here&lt;/a&gt;, as well as a changelog detailing the main changes and their motivations. Feel free to suggest any solution that could allow us to prove the untempering of the manifesto and that wouldn’t require you to trust us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;our-articles-are-meant-to-spread&#34;&gt;Our articles are meant to spread
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;All articles published on EcoCrypto will be translated into English to maximize their availability. If you enjoyed a particular article and would like to translate it into your native language (excluding French, as we cover that already), feel free to do so. Our only condition is that you keep us informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;we-value-your-attention&#34;&gt;We VALUE your attention
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;You, readers of EcoCrypto are entrusting us with a highly sensitive material: the time and the attention you give to our articles. We are fully aware of the responsibility it entails. We will be transparent, honest and incorruptible to prove ourselves worthy of your time. We will not mislead you to make you click on our articles. Each story will have to provide a real contribution for it to be published. If you think a given piece of content is not paying its due respect to your attention, please let us know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-decentralization-of-ecocrypto&#34;&gt;The Decentralization of EcoCrypto
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the initiator of the project, I, TokenBrice, will have a significant influence over it in its early days. I am fully aware of the centralization vector I represent. EcoCrypto will eventually grow into a decentralized project, but I must first ensure its development and maintain its quality. I will communicate directly on EcoCrypto regarding the steps taken for its decentralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
