<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stable Assets on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/stable-assets/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stable Assets on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/stable-assets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is this a Lending Protocol Renaissance?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/lending-protocol-renaissance/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/lending-protocol-renaissance/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2024/lending-protocol-renaissance/0-lending-protocol-renaissance-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Is this a Lending Protocol Renaissance?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we’ve seen a flurry of novel and exciting lending protocols come to market, such as Morpho, DYAD, Fluid, or Tapioca; even more are expected in the coming months, such as Liquity V2 (Bold) or Euler V2. All are innovative, in the arena, trying things to the point that I wonder if we’re not experiencing a lending protocol renaissance after a few years of rehashing the same concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, in this article, I’d like to give you a tour of the interesting ideas I’ve seen being explored — we’ll go through some of the protocols mentioned above and, for each, focus on understanding their main innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collateralized-debt-position-cdp-protocols-vs-money-market&#34;&gt;Collateralized Debt Position (CDP) protocols vs Money Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive in, starting with a primer on the differences between CDP protocols (e.g., Maker or Liquity) and money markets (e.g., Aave or Morpho). It will come in handy as we will discuss both in this article and even finish with a project merging the two models into one protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;CDP (ex: Liquity)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Money Market (ex: Aave)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Borrower Interest Rate&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Predictable, can even be fixed or initiation fee only&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Volatile, entirely dependent on pool usage&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collateral accepted&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usually limited options, cannot mix collateral&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Various collateral: a given position can mix several collaterals at once&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Assets that can be borrowed&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only the protocol stablecoin (DAI on Marker, LUSD on Liquity)&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Diverse – any asset enabled as a borrowable asset&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collateral re-hypothecation&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collateral are deposited in a pool and thus potentially re-lent to other users&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protocol core challenge&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stabilizing the stablecoin outputted &amp; securing enough liquidity on it&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Attracting sufficient borrowable assets (USDC, ETH) to fulfill borrowing demand&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Protocol main risk&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oracle failure ⇒ collateral value not accurately evaluated ⇒ some users can borrow more than their collateral worth ⇒ stablecoin death spiral&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Oracle failure ⇒ collateral value not accurately evaluated ⇒ some users can borrow more than their collateral worth ⇒ all borrowable assets are drained&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDP protocols stand out for their ability to facilitate cheaper borrowing costs, thereby stimulating more borrowing-side demand, a challenging feat to achieve. This is due to the unique feature of CDPs, where the user directly contracts debt against the protocol, eliminating the need to source and pay an external stablecoin depositor demanding a competitive interest rate, as is the case with a money market like Aave. The primary challenge with CDPs lies in the stability and liquidity of the stablecoin that is produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, money markets tend to be more flexible. Thanks to their structure, they allow users to mix and match collateral and can quickly onboard new ones. Yet, they tend to require more maintenance, as collateral parameters must be constantly adjusted to reflect the realities of the market. This creates quite the load for governance, as seen on Aave, where &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://boardroom.io/aave/overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;over a thousand proposals&lt;/a&gt; were already processed in four and a half years: approximately 22 per month. It works, but it seems overengineered; surely there must be a better way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dyad-flirting-with-the-endogenous-collateral-taboo&#34;&gt;DYAD: Flirting with the endogenous collateral taboo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dyad is a CDP protocol that implements several novel ideas, such as delivering free borrowing to its users, who must own an NFT to partake (Note). It also serves as the protocol&amp;rsquo;s base coordination layer. I invite you to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dyad.gitbook.io/dyad-docs-v2/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read the documentation&lt;/a&gt; to become more familiar with it. Let’s zoom in on Dyad’s novel approach to handling a key topic for CDP protocols: overcollateralization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For stablecoins, we talk about endogenous vs exogenous collateral. To quickly tell, ask yourself this question: if the stablecoin fails, does the collateral also fail? If yes, your collateral is endogenous (ex: my beloved &amp;amp; defunct &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;seigniorage-based stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;); if not, it’s exogenous (ex: ETH for Liquity).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins harnessing endogenous or no collateral can scale quickly, as seen with ESD, Basis Cash, or Terra/UST. However, they can and usually do explode even faster. For this reason, harnessing endogenous collateral is considered a risky practice – worthy of an instant Red Flag / F on the stablecoin rating agency &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bluechip.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bluechip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/lending-protocol-renaissance/1-endogenous-collateral-bluechip.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;1-endogenous-collateral-bluechip&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I would like to focus on today regarding Dyad is its utility token, KEROSENE, which is a mechanism for allocating the right to mint against existing surplus collateral in the system. By default, the system&amp;rsquo;s minimal collateralization ratio is 150%. However, KEROSENE holders can deposit it into their Notes to reduce their exogenous collateral ratio to 100%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, KEROSENE is not technically an endogenous collateral but a mechanism to price and enable users to harness the protocol&amp;rsquo;s exogenous over-collateralization. KEROSENE’s utility gives it a “deterministic value” corresponding to its utility while deposited into a Note. Since KEROSENE is mostly farmed by supplying liquidity on DYAD, it could entertain an interesting flywheel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/lending-protocol-renaissance/2-dyad-defillama.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;2-dyad-defillama&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched at the end of the year, the protocol has seen gentle and steady growth, although still limited. The rollout is progressive: the base functionalities are live (Note, DYAD minting, LP incentives, KEROSENE utility), yet much more is coming: sDYAD, momentum (a mechanism to better align protocol participants), a lending market, etc. It’s worth following for any stablecoin enjoyer such as myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;liquity-v2--the-base-rate-of-defi&#34;&gt;Liquity v2 – The base rate of DeFi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquity’s LUSD remains one of the most successful genuinely decentralized stablecoins on the mainnet, so when v2 was announced, it gathered a lot of attention. After researching a novel approach harnessing a reserve model, the team pivoted back to a CDP protocol, growing from learning the first iteration. V2 is expected to be released by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to focus on one, in particular, on interest rate management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interest-rate management is crucial for all lending protocols, even CDP protocols. The rate can be easily defined based on the market utilization rate in money markets. For CDP protocols, replicating a similar approach is impossible, and other venues must be explored; several were:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Governance-defined (ex: Maker / DAI): while this approach provides flexibility, it generates uncertainty for borrowers and challenges in governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithmic (ex: Liquity / LUSD): no governance is always better, when possible; however, it doesn’t come without shortcomings either. In the case of Liquity, the set initiation fee proved inflexible, which led to the protocol adjusting to a higher interest rate environment with redemptions and, thus, through a lowering of the overall LUSD supply.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With v2, the protocol switches to an interest rate model (no more initiation fee), which should already provide more agility. What’s more interesting is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/liquity-v2-why-user-set-interest-rates&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;how this interest rate is decided: directly by the users&lt;/a&gt;. The team introduces another protocol-level game with straightforward parameters: redemptions will be processed based on the interest rate paid by the user, from lowest to highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, users who choose a very low interest will put themselves first in line for redemptions, while those who pick the highest interest will be maximally protected. To make it easy for any user to partake, interest rate delegation will be possible, with various delegates delivering different mandates expected at launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will allow the protocol to rapidly adjust to all kinds of market environments, from low interest rates to high, avoiding the long redemption phases as seen in v1 while remaining immutable and delivering greater predictability to borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/lending-protocol-renaissance/3-bold-stability.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3-bold-stability&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the protocol gains adoption, the average interest rate observed could even inform beyond Liquity v2 itself, as it will correspond to a base rate borrowers are willing to pay on a risk-minimized and immutable protocol. Riskier protocols will have to offer a lower interest rate to attract borrowers. The v2 packs many more interesting innovations. To get up to speed, I recommend checking out &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://x.com/bjnpck/status/1772227278606389496&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bojan’s thread of threads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tapioca--cdp-x-money-market-convergence&#34;&gt;Tapioca – CDP x Money Market Convergence
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tapioca was launched just a few weeks ago and is still being progressively released, as some protocol components still need to be made live. In today’s highlight, I’d like to focus on two main items:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convergence of the CDP and Money Market model with Tapioca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The innovative token lock model harnessed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s dive right in. For more context about Tapioca, as often, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.tapioca.xyz/tapioca&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the official documentation&lt;/a&gt; is a great source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;convergence-of-cdp-and-money-market&#34;&gt;Convergence of CDP and Money Market
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CDP protocols face a challenge: they must deliver competitive yield on the stablecoin they output to drive demand. Liquity v2 will redirect most of the fees collected, thanks to the interest rate, to BOLD stakers, Maker has the DSR / sDAI, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, another way to ensure stablecoin minters can access competitive yields is to build a money market on top of the stablecoin: that’s precisely what Tapioca is doing. Indeed, Tapioca is essentially a double protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there is the CDP—branded “Big Bang,” where users can mint USDO against selected collateral: gas tokens and LSDs. The collateral selection is purposely restrictive, as tokens accepted here directly affect USDO backing. Borrowers pay an interest rate and, depending on USDO’s peg situation, potentially an initiation fee of up to 1% (if underpeg). It enables users to loop-leverage their ETH / LSD exposure or simply harness their ETH / LSD as collateral to borrow some USDO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, there is the money market — branded “Singularity,” which provides isolated markets where users can supply various types of collateral to borrow USDO, supplied by borrowers on the CDP side. This creates a native yield for USDO holders that is decorrelated from the CDP side, as well as offering an elegant approach to handle all types of collateral:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Censorship resistant majors ⇒ CDP collateral =backing USDO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Derivatives / more risky tokens ⇒ Singularity = yield to USDO holders without compromising USDO’s backing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dual structure allows Tapioca to host various collateral, with appropriate risk-mitigation measures for each. Since singularity harnesses isolated markets, the risk for each collateral onboarded there is isolated, and it can be further managed with its parametrization (LTV, interest rate, and liquidation bonus) and limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;twaml-an-innovative-token-locking-model&#34;&gt;twAML: an innovative token-locking model
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After following and commenting on the DEX evolutions, starting with veCRV and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-vs-velo/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the improvements we observed with Velodrome (veNFT)&lt;/a&gt;, I anticipated seeing token lock models harnessed on lending protocols too. It has been, but only in a primitive manner, with gauge-based emissions &amp;amp; governance token locking to allocate them, such as seen on Prisma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapioca finally delivers with an exciting approach harnessing a new type of token locking (twAML), both for their governance token TAP and for the suppliers of the money market, to secure the supply side and thus drive more borrowing demand. Hence, after Velodrome improved the veCRV model and delivered the first credible improvement over veCRV, we might see its third iteration come to fruition. Here are the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td colspan=&#34;4&#34; &gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Main Locking Model Overview&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Name&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;veCRV&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;veNFT (ex: veVELO)&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;twAML (ex: twTAP)&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meaning&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vote Escrowed&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vote Escrowed NFT&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Time Weighted Average Magnitude Lock&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locked Position Represented by&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;None&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;NFT&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;NFT&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Locked Position Transferable&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;No&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;TKN &amp;lt;&gt; veTKN ratio&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Solely dependent on time duration, one veTKN per TKN if 4-year lock&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;same as veCRV&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Depends on twAML – the average lock duration of other lockers: if equal/above, then one veTKN per TKN&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;veTKN &amp;lt;&gt; TKN Decay&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, linear over time (ex, after 2 years of lock, only 0.5 veTKN per TKN)&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;same as veCRV&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;No Decay&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revenues for lockers&lt;/em&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pro-rata share of the fees collected on Curve&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential bribes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;LP boost revenue&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weekly rebase added to veNFT&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fees from pool voted on&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Potential bribes&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;USDO Interest Accrued &lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Liquidation Profit Shares&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;USDO Creation Fees&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flash Mint Fee&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main innovation lies in the flexibility and additional game theory layer this model implements. Instead of a linear veTKN to TKN correspondence, depending on the time locked and maxing at four years, like with veCRV and veAERO, twAML looks at other lockers&amp;rsquo; average lock time (magnitude weighted). In practice, achieving a 1:1 TKN&amp;lt;-&amp;gt;veTKN correspondence no longer requires a four-year lock but simply to lock for as much / longer than the existing locks. Thus, the lock time will rapidly increase during the first epoch, ramping up from the 4-week maximum initially set up until it finds an equilibrium point and potentially starts to decay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2024/lending-protocol-renaissance/4-twTAP.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;4-twTAP&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released for the first time with dynamic adjusting, the twAML was met with excessive degeneracy and quickly ramped up over four years. Thus, the team has returned to work and switched the adjustment to epoch-based. The new iteration is expected in the coming weeks, another development worth monitoring for stablecoin and lock tokens enjoyers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tapioca is quite the beefy protocol, two years in the work. I’ve barely scratched the surface there, as there are many other components worthy of commentary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s natively omnichain harnessing Layer 0&amp;rsquo;s omnichain fungible token standard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tapioca, like Liquity, will be one of the few CDP protocols redirecting fees generated from stablecoin minting to its token holders through the twTAP model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewards for USDO lockers are distributed in oTAP, an option token connected to the twAML logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The protocol is keen on accruing Protocol-Owned Liquidity, both for TAP and USDO, which will enable it to lower its liquidity maintenance costs and potentially turn it into a profitable endeavor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to cover more protocols, but this article is already beefy, so I’ll keep it there for today. There are many exciting developments for lending protocols worth discussing, such as the growth of isolated markets with protocols like Morpho or Silo. All of this and more leads me to believe that after years of Aave &amp;amp; Maker dominating the lending protocol landscape, we might see some challengers rising to a similar size, if not overtaking them in the coming years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll be watching, and so should you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to Gray for the cover image.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Maurauder&#39;s Map of Decentralized Stablecoins</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/stablecoin-marauder-map/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Sep 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/stablecoin-marauder-map/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/stablecoin-marauder-map-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post The Maurauder&#39;s Map of Decentralized Stablecoins" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wild new stablecoins are constantly appearing, and with the multiplication of chains, layers, and viable stablecoin models the trend is not stopping anytime soon. &lt;strong&gt;Navigating the stablecoin landscape is turning into a critical skill for DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While centralized stablecoin models are easier to evaluate, decentralized stablecoins harness various complex mechanisms, making it harder to compare their data face to face. Yet, dozens of relevant new decentralized stablecoins are appearing yearly, and I don’t expect the trend to stop anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, this article intends to provide a marauder map to help navigate the landscape of decentralized stablecoin designs. Before combing through the innovations for decentralized stablecoins, allow one more minute to the context: why do we care so much about (decentralized) stablecoins in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;size-matters&#34;&gt;Size matters
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;stablecoins are cryptocurrency’s top product-market fit by a wide margin&lt;/strong&gt;. DeFi is cool, right? We love it on this blog. Yet size-wise, there are about 3 times more value locked in stablecoins than in DeFi protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the total TVL in DeFi is around $38B for $124B of stablecoins circulating, serviced mainly by centralized options: USDT makes 66% of the total, and USDC is another 20%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember that there is a lot of redundancy between the two metrics as stablecoins are widely used across DeFi, so the effective spread is even higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let’s dive in! As we consider the various designs harnessed to deliver decentralized stablecoins, I’ll illustrate the mechanisms discussed using examples from live projects: picture this article as recipe book meets marauder map on the topic of decentralized stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-build-a-decentralized-stablecoin&#34;&gt;HOW TO BUILD A DECENTRALIZED STABLECOIN
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is a virtually infinite range of designs that can be harnessed to output decentralized stablecoins; however, they all rely on two essential core needs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stablecoin Price Stabilization&lt;/strong&gt; | Finding an effective way to stabilize the stablecoin price without too much compromise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stablecoin Liquidity&lt;/strong&gt; | The active management of the liquidity on the stablecoin to maximize its effectiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While both themes address the same need: ensuring that the stablecoin can be traded at peg whatever the circumstances, they operate on different time frames. Stabilization mechanisms are built so that stablecoins tend to their peg over the mid/long time-frames. Liquidity strategies are here to ensure even sizable amounts of the stablecoin can be bought/sold as close as possible to the peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are two prerequisites for a stablecoin design to be relevant and have a chance at gathering traction. Faults on those two dimensions jeopardize the whole design, so let’s look at the leading price stabilization mechanisms harnessed and their consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;price-stabilization-mechanisms&#34;&gt;PRICE STABILIZATION MECHANISMS
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When faced with sizable demand, decentralized stablecoins can depeg - that is, divert from the peg, usually $1, either upwards or downwards. While similar, the two depegs stem from vastly different design challenges. Let’s start with the most common, the depeg when a $ stable is worth less than $1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;underpegging-illustrated-with-gho&#34;&gt;Underpegging illustrated with GHO
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It usually happens when the stablecoin is mainly used for leverage and lacks significant direct use cases – &lt;strong&gt;a current prime example is Aave’s GHO, trading around $0.97&lt;/strong&gt;. GHO is one of the cheapest stablecoins to borrow (1.5% max APY), creating a lot of initial demand for it. Yet, there is not much to do with GHO directly apart from providing liquidity. Thus, many borrowers swap their GHO for something else, for instance, DAI, to harness the 5% yield from the DSR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides, the AaveDAO has been slow to take action to support GHO. Despite the stablecoin being live since mid-July, there are still very few incentives directed to growing GHO’s liquidity, and they are poorly allocated as most of them focus on stableswap pools where GHO is overweight because of its price. Since these pools are 80% composed of GHO, they provide little adequate liquidity at the current price:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/gho-balancer-pool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;gho-balancer-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, the only pressure for GHO to repeg comes from the existing borrowers who could consider repaying their debt with a ~3% discount if they could borrow and swap GHO around $1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GHO will need attractive earning options directly available in GHO to approach the peg again, such as liquidity-providing options. Still, a GHO-based staking module with revenue sharing would fit the task nicely. Overall, we need more GHO-sinks: mechanisms resulting in GHO being minted and held as such for long periods. Right now, it seems like governance is pushing forward increased support for GHO’s liquidity incentives and a potential GHO PSM (Peg Stability Module): more on this design is below while we address Maker/DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it was launched a few weeks ago, most of GHO’s current challenges come from its young age, coupled with a lack of preparation for the launch on the DAO side. The DAO is improving in that regard, with many propositions pushed forward to address the situation, including establishing &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/arfc-treasury-management-gho-liquidity-strategy-update/14801&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a liquidity committee for GHO&lt;/a&gt; I should contribute to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;overpegging-illustrated-with-lusd&#34;&gt;Overpegging illustrated with LUSD
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; utilizes a unique mechanism called Redemptions to maintain its price stability. In Liquity, users deposit their ETH as collateral to borrow and mint stablecoins (LUSD). The key innovation lies in the redemption mechanism, which enables users to redeem LUSD for the underlying collateral (ETH) at a fixed ratio, even if the market price of ETH drops significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This mechanism incentivizes users to stabilize the price of LUSD by redeeming it when ETH prices are low, thereby reducing the circulating supply of LUSD and supporting its peg to the USD. It provides &lt;strong&gt;immediate and immutable access to LUSD’s collateral to LUSD holders&lt;/strong&gt; without the need for liquidity on a decentralized exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redemptions provide an additional layer of guarantee to LUSD holders but add complexity on the borrowing side, pushing borrowers to monitor and adjust their LTV against other protocol users and market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collateral redemptions provide the most direct access to the underlying backing of a stablecoin. Centralized stablecoins like USDC or USDT use a similar, although permissioned, mechanism to enable redeemability to USD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LUSD traded at a premium for most of its existence, even though the situation has improved recently. Indeed, several factors contributed to enhancing the liquidity and the peg pressure: the success of the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chickenbonds.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chicken Bonds&lt;/a&gt;, advanced liquidity strategies on novel DEXes like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mav.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maverick&lt;/a&gt;, or the accumulation of LUSD by DAOs and treasuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The why of the premium still needs to be pinpointed precisely. One of the likely main factors is that &lt;strong&gt;LUSD is servicing a unique niche&lt;/strong&gt;, the resilience-maximized stablecoin, where there is usually more demand (people wanting to hold LUSD) than offer (ETH holders borrowing LUSD and selling it). &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/the-premium-of-resiliency#:~:text=LUSD%20is%20a%20stablecoin%20fully,also%20comes%20with%20scalability%20challenges.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This topic was covered in depth last year on Liquity’s blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While underpegging is usually more concerning, overpegging can have real consequences, too, as it can make effective borrowing costs less predictable for the users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LUSD’s overpeg stems from mostly psychological mechanisms: the worst case of sustained overpegging was observed during movements of market panic, especially when a prominent centralized stablecoin is perceived at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, thanks to its resilience, LUSD is seen as a &lt;strong&gt;safe haven stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. A remarkable feat, but it comes with a price: crowds rush to LUSD when other stablecoins are at fault, such as when USDC depegged 10% following the bank run on Silicon Valley Bank. LUSD saw an incredible trading volume that day, with sizeable purchases above $1.03, $1.04, and $1.05 as the market panicked. Amid the panic, some users are willing to pay a high price to fly to safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dai-and-the-psm-solving-overpegging-for-a-price&#34;&gt;DAI and the PSM: solving overpegging, for a price
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In its early days, before the Mutli Collateral Dai update, DAI had similar challenges to LUSD: it tended to overpeg. With the update, Maker introduced the Peg Stability Module (PSM) to manage the price stability of its stablecoin DAI. The PSM acts as a buffer between the market and the DAI ecosystem. It allows users to swap stable assets like USDC for DAI at a fixed exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By adjusting the exchange rate in response to market dynamics, MakerDAO can influence the supply of DAI in the market and keep its price close to the USD peg. It helped MakerDAO resolve the DAI problem over pegging, observed before the PSM. Still, it came with a cost: an accumulation of USDC and other centralized stablecoins as DAI’s collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/maker-psm.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;maker-psm&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fraxs-amo-algorithmic-market-operations-scale-liquidity-and-risk-to-infinity&#34;&gt;FRAX&amp;rsquo;s AMO (Algorithmic Market Operations): scale liquidity and risk to infinity
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;FRAX is a decentralized stablecoin that utilizes Algorithmic Market Operations to maintain its peg. FRAX employs an adaptive mechanism that adjusts its collateralization ratio based on market conditions. When the FRAX price trades above its peg, the system mints new FRAX and buys back collateral, increasing the stability of the peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conversely, when the FRAX price falls below the peg, it reduces the collateralization ratio to encourage users to mint FRAX, which helps restore the peg. AMOs come with additional risks, mainly depending on the usage of the assets minted without collateral: the riskier their exposure, the bigger the threat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The principal risks of such a design manifest when an issue with one of the services harnessed (usually money markets or DEX) arises. Say 10M FRAX are minted by the AMO and deposited into a money market to be borrowed by users. Now, the money market suffers an issue with one of its collateral and gets drained: there are now 10M more FRAX in open circulation with 0 collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitigating this requires very active management of the AMOs - by humans, through a multisig, which is not ideal from a security perspective, as AMOs can mint FRAX at will with no backing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;crvusd-pegkeeper-a-better-psm&#34;&gt;crvUSD pegKeeper: a better PSM?
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To ensure the peg-stability of crvUSD, Curve explored a path similar to the PSM, but slightly improved. Indeed, here, the need for users’ input is removed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Maker PSM, it’s still user-driven: when overpeg, users supply USDC as collateral to Maker PSM and mint DAI, helping to push its price back. If DAI was to underpeg, users could similarly buy DAI (below $1) to redeem it for 1 USDC, helping to restore its price to peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;crvUSD works similarly at a high level (if crvUSD&amp;gt;$1 =&amp;gt; mint, if crvusd&amp;lt;$1 =&amp;gt; burn) but does not require any input: the system stabilizes itself thanks to its pegKeepers contract. These special contracts can mint non-collateralized crvUSD under certain conditions and for specific use cases only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 4 pegKeepers, each plugged into a different pool of crvUSD paired against a redeemable centralized stablecoin: USDC. USDT, USDP &amp;amp; TUSD. When crvUSD is overpeg, they can mint crvUSD to trade into the associated pool, helping to push crvUSD price back to $1. When crvUSD is underpeg, the pegKeeper can repurchase crvUSD on their associated pool (using centralized stable balances accumulated during overpeg) and burn it to push crvUSD’s price back to peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, pegKeepers accumulate a crvUSD debt to the protocol when the stablecoin is overpegged, to be ideally resorbed once crvUSD is underpeg. The key here lies in the balance, ensuring that the spread between the supply of crvUSD (incl. Pegkeeper debt) and the borrowed supply does not grow too big.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/pegkeeper.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pegkeeper&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While pegKeepers still pose a decent threat to the protocol, just like the FRAX’s AMO or Maker’s PSM, the risk seems more mitigated there. Yet, crvUSD is still quite a young stablecoin, and only time will tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-management&#34;&gt;LIQUIDITY MANAGEMENT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquidity management, even just for a stablecoin, could be a good topic for a thesis. It’s one of the most misunderstood topics across the space. I wanted you, dear reader, to be aware of its importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;liquidity-management-as-a-non-topic&#34;&gt;Liquidity management as a non-topic
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you read this blog, you’ve likely already internalized that &lt;strong&gt;liquidity strategies are the heart of the storm of the stablecoin wars.&lt;/strong&gt; Yet, many teams have yet to attain this realization. They picture it as something of low criticality that the DAO will handle later, which is incredibly dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, DAOs are not the best structure to manage liquidity, they tend to harness suboptimal solutions, overpay, and simply need more velocity to match the fast pace of the liquidity games. No surprise here; we’ve already established ages ago that &lt;strong&gt;DAOs/governance are a good fit for strategical (long-term) orientations but inapt at mid/short term (tactics) management,&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to the example of MakerDAO (where, despite the absurdity of it, MKR holders are still voting on the vault’s interest rate, a purely operational parameter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obvious solution would be for the DAO to &lt;strong&gt;appoint a liquidity committee&lt;/strong&gt; - a small team of liquidity specialists provided with a budget they can mobilize autonomously. The committee could be hired for a set term, while the DAO retains the right not to renew the committee or even revoke it similarly to other service providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I invite you to look at the main stablecoin projects run by DAOs and see which one has a committee yet. As far as I know, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/temp-check-treasury-management-create-and-fund-gho-liquidity-committee/14800&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;only Aave is finally considering it for GHO&lt;/a&gt;. Besides the increased agility and operational capacity provided by the committee, it also enables the DAO to be more structured and forward-planning in its liquidity approach, allowing it to explore partnerships and collaboration with more relevant actors, such as supporting an innovative DEX from day one at launch, instead of the many months required to explain the relevancy of the innovation to the DAO’s stakeholders and have a budget being voted and implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;competence-is-scarce&#34;&gt;Competence is scarce
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The hard truth about liquidity management is that competence is extremely scarce. This could explain why the topic needs to be better understood and rarely prioritized at the project&amp;rsquo;s design stage or later in the governance discussions. An apt liquidity manager must have an accurate understanding of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Base liquidity structure model, x*y=k&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Custom liquidity structures like stableswap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic concentrated liquidity, UNIv3 style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uniswap liquidity management layer (Bunni, Merkl, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CL liquidity manager model (Gamma, Arrakis, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;veCRV tokenomics &amp;amp; ecosystem // veBAL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote marketplaces and bribe culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advanced concentrated liquidity, Maverick style&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick incentives model (Boosted Pool)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maverick tokenomics (veMAV)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DEX Aggregator landscape and pathing logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The scope of tools, services, and protocols used for liquidity management is increasing exponentially, and very few actors are following closely&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s frequent to observe absurd spreads between the liquidity spending of two similar projects, with sometimes spreads of several orders of magnitude of difference in terms of $ invested / results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-attract-piles-of-ethlsds-onchain&#34;&gt;How to attract piles of ETH&amp;amp;LSDs onchain?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we focused on stablecoins harnessing the CDP (Collateralized Debt Position) model, such as Maker, Liquity, or Reflexer, where users must deposit collateral to contract debt directly against the protocol (every borrower on a CDP protocol mints their “own” debt). It’s an elegant design that enables the protocol to implement various devices to absorb the volatility of the collateral, thus maximizing the price inertia of the stablecoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-limits-of-cdp-based-stablecoin&#34;&gt;The limits of CDP-based stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, CDP-based stablecoins come with one main downside: the over-collateralization requirement.&lt;/strong&gt; Indeed, it’s difficult, if not impossible, to dampen the volatility of collateral such as ETH without any margin of error. For instance, on Liquity, the minimum collateralization ratio tolerated is 110%, yet the average ratio observed on the protocol is 226.3%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overcollateralization is the central limit of the CDP model, and is hard to overcome. Indeed, lowering the collateralization requirement could attract more borrowers, increasing the risk scope of the stablecoin outputted. Thus, scaling a CDP-based stablecoin is a tough job. There are other relevant ideas to attract more borrowers, such as diversifying the collateral offering, as shown below. But here again, it comes with increased risks on the stablecoin, as seen with DAI, which observed a sizeable collateral degradation over the last years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, many projects are exploring approaches that could result in a stablecoin with fewer compromises than DAI while achieving a similar scale. Let’s consider a few directions currently explored to scale decentralized stablecoin further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;expand-the-collateral--chain-offering-liquity-forks&#34;&gt;Expand the collateral &amp;amp; chain offering: Liquity forks
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;2023 is the year of the Liquity fork: many protocols were launched this year, harnessing a model more or less similar to Liquity, with some twists. These include Gravita, Prisma, Lybra, and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;gravita&#34;&gt;Gravita
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.gravitaprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Gravita&lt;/a&gt;, probably the closest to the base Liquity model. Here, the focus is put on making the protocol more attractive to borrowers, with several welcome additions, including the possibility of borrowing using liquid staked ETH like stETH or rETH as collateral or the protocol being made available on L2 like Arbitrum. Of course, it’s a game of balance here, as the rule specified above still applies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conditions enforced on the borrowers dictate the guarantees provided to stablecoin holders&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;prisma-finance&#34;&gt;Prisma Finance
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://prismafinance.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Prisma Finance&lt;/a&gt; is also exploring a similar approach, another Liquity fork enabling the usage of ETH-LSD as collateral, built by a team close to the Curve/Llama ecosystem. Components of the veTokenomics are also envisioned on the fee-sharing/governance token PRISMA, but they still need to be made live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;lybra-finance&#34;&gt;Lybra Finance
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another team, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lybra.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lybra&lt;/a&gt;, experimented with a lock/escrow model on their governance token LBR. While it seems to have initially worked nicely to attract a sizeable amount of capital, the challenge with such tactics is to sustain them over time…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;dyad&#34;&gt;DYAD
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dyadstable.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DYAD&lt;/a&gt;. This one is technically not a Liquity-fork per se, but more of a Liquity-inspired protocol, especially regarding the price stabilization mechanism of their stablecoin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main challenge they are trying to solve is onboarding new collateral on a live CDP protocol without expanding the risk scope of the base protocol more than it needs to. To do so, DYAD introduces a &amp;ldquo;Social Licensing Layer,&amp;rdquo; essentially the governance layer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, it looks like none of the governance we&amp;rsquo;re used to: here, there is no governance token, so that it won&amp;rsquo;t be your usual plutocracy. Instead, governance power lies directly within the dNFT needed to use the protocol:  each dNFT gets to control a single &amp;ldquo;switch&amp;rdquo; for each proposed collateral type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can change the position of this switch at any time from off to on or on to off and back again, as often as they want. A given collateral can comprise part of DYAD&amp;rsquo;s collateral basket if it maintains a 2/3 supermajority of &amp;ldquo;on&amp;rdquo; switches. The only way to increase your governance power is to control more dNFTs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DYAD also gets bonus points for preserving immutability as much as possible. While the protocol can be changed since it can onboard new collateral, the whole governance layer is immutable. DYAD is not fully live yet, only dNFTs are, but I&amp;rsquo;m eager to see how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m keeping with the majors here: LSDfi was all the rage a few months ago, and we’ve seen many protocols providing options to leverage ETH-LSD launching lately. While this sub-market is likely already crowded, there’s room for a CDP-based model delivering a stablecoin slightly less resilient than LUSD but with additional features. The question is which?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;be-gentle-with-your-borrowers-llamacrvusd&#34;&gt;Be gentle with your borrowers: LLAMA/crvUSD
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way to create a sink for ETH/ETH-LSD: make the conditions more attractive to borrowers / soften the liquidation penalties. Indeed, one of the main innovations behind crvUSD lies with the liquidation model that differs vastly from other services providing leverage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LLAMA (Lending Liquidating AMM Algorithm) replaces the usual liquidations with “soft liquidations”, where underwater borrowers are rebalanced across “bands,” each representing a different price segment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides a sizeable protection against liquidations stemming from brutal but unsustained market movements. Instead of the sudden liquidations we’ve been used to, LLAMA&amp;rsquo;s soft liquidations are more gradual, as the collateral is progressively adjusted in proportion to its market price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;make-it-rain-dai-saving-rate--variants&#34;&gt;Make it rain: Dai Saving Rate &amp;amp; variants
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Why even bother improving your design when there are more direct paths forward? MakerDAO pioneered this idea of offering a “risk-free” yield to stablecoin holders to drive the demand: the DAI Saving Rate, currently at 5%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sustaining it proves very costly for the DAO, which is increasingly pushed towards riskier but more lucrative collateral to keep afloat. A sizeable share of the collateral are now real-world assets (RWA) managed by custodians, some of which are slow or even fail to meet their yield or reporting obligations or simply sub-optimal (MakerDAO is currently earning 3% on its USDC while &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cryptoslate.com/coinbase-raises-usdc-interest-rate-to-5/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;retail can score 5% with Circle&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, surprise, surprise: incentives work, at least at first. Thus, this brutal, low effort, and poorly efficient design over the long term is now spreading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mirror.xyz/0xa486d3a7679D56D545dd5d357469Dd5ed4259340/1qSAAQtVdNCW_xn9cObEjwrQzFpwEshNrm0sjX0nkG8&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Raft launched a similar concept at 6%.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frax is also working on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.frax.finance/t/fip-2xx-sfrax-governance-proposal/2585&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;sFRAX / Frax Saving Rate targeting 5%&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/maker-dsr-impact.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;maker-dsr-impact&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, time will tell for the impact of such design over the long run. The way I see it, these protocols are &lt;strong&gt;depleting most of their revenues to pay for acquisition on an ongoing basis&lt;/strong&gt; — they will lose most of the users acquired with DSR the minute they stop. They would have burned a massive amount of money to sustain the charade, money that could have been spent on strategic assets providing life-long incentives to the liquidity providers of their stablecoin, for instance. &lt;strong&gt;This design is a great tactic but one of the most short-sighted strategies I have ever seen&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-shift-to-reserve-backed-stablecoin&#34;&gt;A shift to reserve-backed stablecoin?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A shift is brewing! While CDP-based models, such as Maker, Liquity, or Reflexer, are flourishing, &lt;strong&gt;reserve-backed stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; are also getting increasingly considered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, as we highlighted above, there is an inherent tension in purely borrow–based / CDP stablecoins. To put it simply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scaling a decentralized lending-based stablecoin requires attracting and retraining a sizeable amount of ETH / ETH-LSDs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But the more permissive the protocol is to borrowers, the less desirable the stablecoin its output will become.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state of a CDP-based stablecoin depends entirely on its users&amp;rsquo; actions. Under the reserve model, the protocol directly manages the reserve and minting of stablecoins instead of individual positions. Thus, reserve-based models seem to offer a credible answer to CDP-based stable shortcomings, enabling the stablecoin supply to potentially scale more thanks to the native protocol reserve providing increased price inertia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s summarize this article by examining two prime examples of implementing a reserve-backed stablecoin model. I’ll keep it short and digestible and add resources for diving further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fx-leverage-with-no-fundind-costs--90-volatility-dampened-eth&#34;&gt;f(x): leverage with no fundind costs &amp;amp; 90% volatility dampened ETH
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;F(x) is a fascinating protocol freshly released! It’s a dual product, enabling stETH depositors to expose themselves to two types of assets in the proportion they desire:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;xETH: a “high-volatility leveraged ETH”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fETH: a “low-volatility floating stablecoin”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly to a CDP protocol, users deposit ETH (or stETH) to mint fETH or xETH. However, unlike Liquity/Maker/Other CDP, the user does not manage its position (a Trove). Instead, the protocol directly manages the stETH reserve. A redemption feature enables holders of fETH or xETH to reclaim the underlying stETH. However, how much they redeem depends on the system&amp;rsquo;s state, most notably its Net Asset Value: the overall value of stETH in reserve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2023/stablecoin-marauder-map/protocolfx.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;protocolfx&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Launched just a few weeks ago, the protocol is still in its early stages with about 1300 ETH of TVL, and the liquidity on fETH is still being worked on. A third token, FXN, the governance token of the protocol, is also planned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The value proposition of both xETH and fETH is relevant to me and should be met with demand once the protocol is more mature. In my view, along with crvUSD, it’s one of the most exciting releases we got stablecoin-wise this year: I’m just waiting for the right time to experiment-ape into xETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquity-v2-protected-lsd-leveraging&#34;&gt;Liquity v2: protected LSD leveraging
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Liquity v2” (codename) is not live yet but has been &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Zps__IMxtTs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;introduced by Robert Lauko at the last Stable Summit in June&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like fETH, v2 will offer non-liquidatable leverage on ETH-LSD with no funding fee and even add downside protection. The novel, reserve-backed stablecoin the protocol will output is optimized for scaling. Its liquidity needs are also minimized since the protocol acts as a primary AMM for the stablecoin: users can mint and redeem the stablecoin for $1 of staked ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;V2 is being built in public: if you’d like to learn more about it or even get involved, make sure to come by the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/RCRp2CJR2S&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity’s Discord dedicated v2 channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn-more-on-aladindaos-fx--liquity-v2&#34;&gt;Learn more on AladinDAO’s F(x) &amp;amp; Liquity V2
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I kept it short on the reserve-backed stablecoins, as I will likely publish several articles focusing on this topic over the coming months. Meanwhile, feel free to get your alpha directly from the builder’s mouth — here’s a selection of articles &amp;amp; interviews to learn more about both protocols:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/aladdindao/status/1684141750900736000?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;A recent community call, when Robert and I joined the AladinDAO/Protocol F(x) team to discuss decentralized stablecoins more broadly [60min]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_xA6AFufGoQ&amp;amp;t=3871s&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Community Call - Deep Dive into f(x) [30min]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Nzy7xO09SFw&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;f(x) protocol with Kmets and Crouger from AladinDAO (Leviathan News) [28min]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/introducing-liquity-v2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Introducing Liquity v2 — Liquity Blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KOnGCPE5gaU&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity v2 with Colin Platt (Leviathan News)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;KEY TAKEAWAYS
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquidity management is the nerve of the stablecoin wars: observe &amp;amp; analyze the strategies deployed by the projects you monitor – their effectiveness is one of the main drivers of the success of the underlying protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👉️ TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Follow the event surrounding GHO’s liquidity management on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave Governance Forum&lt;/a&gt; and try to articulate your thesis. If you can anticipate the repeg accurately, you get 3% of free profit waiting for your (GHO ~$0.97 to $1.00).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👉️ BONUS-TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; GRAI, another stablecoin (Liquity fork), is currently trading at ~$0.985 with its redemption ceiling increasing over the next few weeks; a similar play can be considered there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LSD-FI (protocols to leverage LSD) has been overcrowded over the last few months. Most protocols in the vertical are losing traction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👉️ TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Look at the incentive structure of protocols like Gravita, Raft, or Lybra, and confront it with their growth metrics — try to evaluate the incentive structure that seems persistent versus the ones losing steam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After ~4 years of going autistic with the CDP-based model, it seems like the most savvy teams started to look another way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;👉️ TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Prepare for the future! Thanks to the resources shared above, deep-dive the reserve-based stablecoin models by getting familiar with protocols like f(x) or v2.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Chicken Bonds: an NFT-powered hatching factory to beat DeFi’s liquidity chicken and egg problem</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/lusd-chicken-bonds/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/lusd-chicken-bonds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-chicken-bonds-cover-tokenbrice.png" alt="Featured image of post Chicken Bonds: an NFT-powered hatching factory to beat DeFi’s liquidity chicken and egg problem" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liquity recently released the LUSD Chicken Bonds, a &lt;strong&gt;game-theory experiment merging DeFi and NFT elements to grow LUSD’s liquidity and reduce its price premium&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although Chicken Bonds are building on top of existing protocols, such as Yearn, b.protocol, or Curve, it also instigates novel mechanisms, the two leading ones being:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No maturity principal-protected bonding&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicken Bonds use a new type of bonding offering strong guarantees to the depositor, including the possibility to recoup the entire initially supplied capital at no cost (Chicken Out).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate to Earn dynamic NFT&lt;/strong&gt;: While interacting with the LUSD Chicken Bonds protocol, users obtain a &lt;strong&gt;dynamic NFT&lt;/strong&gt; that evolves depending on their choices and previous onchain interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds tackle one of the core challenges of DeFi, the sustainable growth of liquidity pools, first for the LUSD token only. Still, eventually, the model will be made available in a generalizable permissionless version for any protocol in need of liquidity to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post explores how &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chickenbonds.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LUSD Chicken Bonds&lt;/a&gt; work and what they achieve. However, before answering these questions, additional context is needed on LUSD: let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-context-lusd-price-premium&#34;&gt;The context: LUSD price premium
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the most misunderstood dimensions of Liquity’s model is &lt;strong&gt;LUSD pegging mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, while LUSD has strong guarantees (hard peg) than LUSD&amp;gt;$1.00 (redemption) and &amp;lt;$1.10 (110% minimal collateralization ratio), in between the equilibrium is more based on a &lt;strong&gt;game of incentives (soft peg)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.chainalysis.com/reports/tornado-cash-sanctions-challenges/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OFAC’s crackdown on Tornado Cash&lt;/a&gt; back in August, there has been an &lt;strong&gt;increased demand&lt;/strong&gt; for censorship-resistant stablecoins. Yet, the &lt;strong&gt;appetite for leverage is low&lt;/strong&gt; because of the deteriorated market conditions. Thus, will the demand for LUSD is high, a significant share of its adopters purchase it at a premium on the markets instead of minting it by leveraging their ETH.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both factors have converged over the last few months, leading to a &lt;strong&gt;sustained price premium&lt;/strong&gt; for LUSD, often trading in the $1.02 to $1.04 range. I won’t expand too deeply into this topic here, as it has already been covered on Liquity’s blog: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/the-premium-of-resiliency&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Premium of Resiliency&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. However, let’s discuss &lt;strong&gt;the impact of the premium on Liquity users&lt;/strong&gt; since it has real consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-peg-incentives.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-peg-incentives&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-of-the-lusd-premium&#34;&gt;Impact of the LUSD premium
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impact of a price premium on borrowers &lt;strong&gt;can be positive or negative&lt;/strong&gt;, depending on their timing and actions. Borrowers worried about LUSD price volatility can use Chicken Bonds, or b.protocol to preserve a pure LUSD exposure while earning yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that borrowers who preserve a 100% LUSD exposure do not suffer any consequence from its price fluctuations since they do not need to buy it back when repaying their debt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, having LUSD fluctuates can also benefit informed users that can arbitrage the discrepancies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Profit margin&lt;/strong&gt; | The more LUSD goes over $1, the more profitable it is to take an arbitrage trade on its peg: at $1.01, shorting the peg returns $0.01 per LUSD if successful. At $1.09, the profits jump to $0.09 per LUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Likelihood of profits being realized&lt;/strong&gt; | The farther away LUSD strands from $1.00, and the closer it gets to $1.10, the more likely it is for peg arbitrageurs to outweigh LUSD buyers and thus push the price downward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus arbitraging LUSD is a game of balance between maximizing profits (1) and their odds of realizing (2). To put it simply: past a certain price point, the arbitrage trade becomes &lt;strong&gt;too profitable and too likely to realize for arbitrageurs to ignore&lt;/strong&gt;. It has helped to ensure that LUSD stayed in the lower bond of its soft peg, the $1.00-$1.05 range, even during phases of peak demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For users who do not monitor the situation continuously, though, it can translate into a loss of capital — for instance, if one borrows LUSD while the price is at $1.02, invest it into something else, and then weeks later try to buy back LUSD to repay its debt, only to find the price at $1.04.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, LUSD’s fluctuations in the $1.00-1.10 range add &lt;strong&gt;an additional layer of uncertainty for borrowers&lt;/strong&gt;. Growing the liquidity of LUSD and stabilizing its peg will help restore the borrowers’ confidence and streamline interactions with the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;enter-lusd-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;Enter LUSD Chicken Bonds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/chicken-bonds.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-chicken-bonds&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve LUSD’s liquidity challenge, the Liquity team worked on a &lt;strong&gt;brand new protocol&lt;/strong&gt;, first tried out with LUSD: Chicken Bonds. If successful, the model will be generalized with an LQTY instance. As a final step, the generalized model could be made ready to be harnessed by any DAO with the Chicken Bond Factory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Tuesday, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/chicken-bonds-is-live&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the LUSD Chicken Bonds were released&lt;/a&gt;, offering &lt;strong&gt;a novel proposition merging DeFi and NFTs&amp;rsquo; elements providing optimized yield-producing opportunities to LUSD holders&lt;/strong&gt;. It will also fuel the growth of LUSD’s liquidity on the LUSD/3CRV Curve pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two protagonists interacting with Chicken Bonds:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The depositors (users)&lt;/strong&gt; enjoy a gamified experience delivering &lt;strong&gt;amplified and auto-compounded yields on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The deployer (protocol)&lt;/strong&gt; sets up an &lt;strong&gt;engine enabling the sustained growth and capture of liquidity on its token&lt;/strong&gt; while actively engaging its holders.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-what-exactly-are-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;So, what exactly are Chicken Bonds?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a consequence, Chicken Bonds fulfill the function of different types of products depending on the perspective. &lt;strong&gt;For users, Chicken Bonds act like an NFT-enhanced yield optimizer&lt;/strong&gt;. Bonding enables them to maximize their returns on LUSD by optimizing the compounding frequency and amplifying the existing yields. From their perspective, they could compare the utility of Chicken Bonds to the one already delivered by a protocol like Yearn, lacking the NFT element. It maximizes and streamlines yield-producing activities on LUSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the deployer (protocol) perspective, Chicken Bonds are a &lt;strong&gt;cost-effective solution to develop the available liquidity on their token&lt;/strong&gt;. Alternative solutions to achieve a similar goal would include liquidity mining, POL-capture solution like Olympus Pro, acquiring liquidity-driver tokens (CRV, BAL, VELO, etc.)&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, or bribing liquidity-driver token owner votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/chicken-egg.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;chicken-egg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While each existing solution has its own tradeoffs, they all share a similar profile: they &lt;strong&gt;require recurring expenses to grow and sustain liquidity&lt;/strong&gt;. Only the acquisition of liquidity-driver tokens can provide continuous incentives to support liquidity, but it’s also the most costly approach as it requires significant investments from projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, Chicken Bonds have no cost as they harness existing yield sources: &lt;strong&gt;all it needs to capture and grow liquidity is time&lt;/strong&gt;. They harness a novel form of &lt;strong&gt;no-maturity principal-protected bonding&lt;/strong&gt;, offering amplified yields and strong protections for the depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To explain the model of LUSD Chicken Bonds, let’s jump to the depositor perspective by looking at the lifecycle of a bond and its impact on the associated NFT.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-story-of-a-bond-through-its-nft&#34;&gt;The story of a bond through its NFT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3chickens-static.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3chickens&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To create a bond, a user deposits LUSD. In exchange, he receives an 🥚 Egg NFT representing his deposit&lt;/strong&gt;. The NFT contains the claim on the underlying bonded LUSD and can be sold or transferred. From thereon, the user has two mutually exclusive options that will transform his NFT too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐔 Chicken In&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or 🐣 Chicken Out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Egg NFTs have four attributes: a card, egg, and background colors rolled randomly, and an egg-size scaling with the deposited LUSD amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When an egg is created, it starts progressively accruing bLUSD. As the bond matures, it becomes profitable for the users to claim it, forgoing their LUSD to obtain the bLUSD accumulated — It’s the “&lt;strong&gt;Chicken In&lt;/strong&gt;” option and makes the visual of the NFT evolve accordingly: the Egg turns into a 🐔 &lt;strong&gt;Proud Chicken&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user can recover the full invested amount at any time during the process. Still, he will renounce the bLUSD accumulated so far — it’s the “&lt;strong&gt;Chicken Out&lt;/strong&gt;” option and also leads to an evolution of the NFT from the Egg to a 🐣 &lt;strong&gt;Scared Chick&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3chickens.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3chickens&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;going-deeper-into-the-chicken-bonds-nft&#34;&gt;Going deeper into the Chicken Bonds NFT
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Chickening In, the NFT gains additional attributes rolled at random (comb, tail, beak, and wings) and special attributes depending on the wallet onchain activities. Wallets engaged in the following activities are eligible for special attributes or boosted chances at rolling rarer ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning a Liquity Trove with ongoing debt,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owning LQTY, or staking it either directly or with Pickle,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Voting for the LUSD/3CRV gauge (veCRV holders).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NFT collection also harnesses interesting mechanisms, such as the &lt;strong&gt;affinity&lt;/strong&gt; to generate the coolest chickens possible; read the dedicated article on Liquity’s blog for more information on the topic:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/egg-variants-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;egg-variants-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All NFTs are part of the same collection and can be traded on the usual venues, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://looksrare.org/collections/0xa8384862219188a8f03c144953Cf21fc124029Ee/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LooksRare&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://x2y2.io/collection/lusd-chicken-bonds-nfts/items&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;X2Y2&lt;/a&gt;. Chicken Bonds is a generative NFT collection as much as a DeFi protocol: both are intrinsically tied together. The art and initial generation script were made by the NFT artist &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://luchadores.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Luchador&lt;/a&gt;, creator of the eponym game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For an explainer of all the attributes and modifiers taken into account, read the article dedicated to the NFTs on the Chicken Bonds blog:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/nft-x-defi-deep-dive-into-lusd-chicken-bonds-dynamic-nft&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NFT x DeFi: Deep dive into LUSD Chicken Bonds&amp;rsquo; Dynamic NFT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;boostedlusd-blusd-a-yield-enhanced-auto-compounded-lusd&#34;&gt;boostedLUSD (bLUSD): a yield-enhanced auto-compounded LUSD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By bonding and eventually Chickening In, depositors can accumulate bLUSD, but you might wonder at this point why this token can be desirable: let’s dive into the beefy DeFi side of Chicken Bonds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/blusd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;blusd&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short story is that &lt;strong&gt;owning bLUSD provides access to auto-compounded and amplified yields on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. bLUSD is a standard ERC-20 token backed by LUSD thanks to the redemption mechanism, with a rising price floor thanks to the yield amplification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/user-flow-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;user-flow-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;base-yield-source&#34;&gt;Base yield source
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a protocol, Chicken Bonds collect LUSD and deploy them into two potential yield sources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquity Stability Pool&lt;/strong&gt;, where LUSD can be deposited to earn LQTY as well as variable ETH liquidation premiums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Curve LUSD/3CRV&lt;/strong&gt;, where LUSD can be supplied against USDC/USDT/DAI to earn trading fees as well as CRV tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are not familiar with how Liquity works yet, you can get up to date with this dedicated article: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖️ Liquity: an unstoppable, efficient and innovative borrowing service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;auto-compounded&#34;&gt;Auto compounded
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of plugging into the yield sources directly, middleware solutions are used to provide various benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposits into the Liquity Stability Pool are managed using the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bprotocol.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;B.Protocol vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which handles the frequent harvesting and compounding of ETH and LQTY obtained into LUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For the Curve Pool, the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yearn.finance/#/vault/0x5fA5B62c8AF877CB37031e0a3B2f34A78e3C56A6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Yearn vault&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is used to optimize the yields obtained by harnessing Convex.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, so good: streamlined solutions to simple problems. Yet, the yield amplification, one of the biggest feats of the Chicken Bonds, is a bit trickier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;yield-amplification&#34;&gt;Yield Amplification
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand how it can achieve this, we must start peeling the onion that is the internal accounting tool of the protocol: the Buckets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three buckets enabling the Chicken bonds to guarantee the three core features of the protocol: the option to Chicken Out (Pending), the yield amplification (Reserve), and the growth of liquidity (Permanent).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/3buckets.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3buckets&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Pending Bucket&lt;/strong&gt; has a simple job: it must be able to repay investors fully if they were to Chicken Out. To ensure it’s always possible, the Pending Bucket harnesses a yield source free of impermanent loss: the Stability Pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When users Chicken In a bond, the corresponding LUSD balances are split between the Reserve and Permanent Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reserve Bucket backs bLUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. With redemptions, bLUSD holders can burn their tokens to obtain a pro-rata share of the LUSD contained in the Reserve Bucket —  securing a price floor for bLUSD. Funds in reserve are also producing a yield harnessing the Stability Pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finally, the Permanent Bucket grows the liquidity of LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to its shifting function, triggerable by anyone when LUSD is overpeg, the Permanent Bucket can pull its liquidity out of the b.protocol vault to single supply the Curve LUSD/3CRV pool instead. It helps reduce the LUSD price and secures a favorable entry point in the pool since the deposit rebalances it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;yield produced by the Pending and Permanent buckets is redirected to the Reserve Bucket&lt;/strong&gt;, which creates the yield amplification and rising price floor of bLUSD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-cb-user-timeline.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-cb-user-timeline&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bootstrap-period--next-steps&#34;&gt;Bootstrap period &amp;amp; next steps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LUSD Chicken Bonds have been live since Tuesday, October 4, 2022. During the first two weeks of the system, until Oct 19, it’s still in the &lt;strong&gt;bootstrap period&lt;/strong&gt;: Chicken Ins are not possible, which means the supply of bLUSD is still 0. It means that all the LUSD are in the Pending Bucket, except the yield already produced that is being redirected to the Reserve Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the bootstrap period is over, the Chicken In option will be available, enabling depositors to start accessing bLUSD. To facilitate getting in and out of bLUSD, a &lt;strong&gt;bLUSD liquidity pool will be incentivized on Curve Finance, using a 3% fee paid while Chickening In&lt;/strong&gt;. It will enable the liquidity to develop progressively as the first batch of bonds reaches their break-even point (~Oct 19) and optimal rebond time (~Nov 4).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next section will discuss the chosen liquidity structure and its impact.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chicken-bonds-impact-on-lusds-price-and-liquidity&#34;&gt;Chicken Bonds’ impact on LUSD’s price and liquidity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you read me up to this point, you are now in the know regarding LUSD’s price premium and the model introduced by the Chicken Bonds. Let’s connect the dots then and consider how the LUSD Chicken Bonds will &lt;strong&gt;contribute to LUSD’s overall liquidity and help to contain its premium&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds have two impacts on LUSD liquidity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With the growth of the Permanent Bucket, the liquidity supplied to the LUSD/3CRV will grow as long as the LUSD price still has a premium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The liquidity pool structure was chosen for bLUSD to help further grow liquidity on the LUSD/3CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a short time frame, the release of LUSD Chicken Bonds lead to more demand for LUSD and an increase in its price. However, LUSD deposited into the Chicken Bonds proves beneficial to LUSD’s liquidity in the long run, as we highlight in this section.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-engine-to-capture-liquity-over-time&#34;&gt;An engine to capture liquity over time
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As deposits into the LUSD Chicken Bonds accrue, the potential impact on the LUSD peg grows. Indeed, when a user Chickens In, the underlying LUSD are distributed between the Reserve and the Permanent Bucket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, all three buckets produce yield by deploying the LUSD into the b.protocol vault. However, the Permanent Bucket also features a &lt;strong&gt;shifting function&lt;/strong&gt; triggerable by anyone as long as LUSD trades at a premium. It shifts the LUSD of the Permanent Bucket to &lt;strong&gt;provide liquidity on Curve&lt;/strong&gt; (single asset supply), helping to progressively rebalance the pool while also growing its liquidity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The share of the total amount of LUSD deposited into Chicken Bonds allocated to the Permanent Bucket is hard to predict, as it depends on users&amp;rsquo; behaviors. Here are some napkin maths using a conservative estimate of 10% of the total assets in the Permanent Bucket, with the 5M LUSD currently available in the LUSD/3CRV to estimate the Chicken Bonds impact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Chicken Bonds TVL&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Directly Added Liquity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;Added Liquity (%)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;7M (Current)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;700K LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;14.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;10M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;1M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;20.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;20M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;2M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;40.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;50M&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;5M LUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:left&#34;&gt;100.00%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The added liquidity percentage could be a good proxy indicator of how much of the price premium can be reduced. Keep in mind that it remains approximative, as it only considers the LUSD/3CRV main pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, with $10M TVL into the Chicken Bonds by the end of the first cycle, the impact could already be palpable with an increase of ~20% of the LUSD amount available in the Curve pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shifting function is disabled for the first 45 days of the system, i.e. until November 19. After this date, anyone will be able to move the Permanent Bucket liquidity from Curve &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; B.Protocol if &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://liquity.gitbook.io/chicken-bonds/faq/lusd-peg-stability#_vowf7444yzdt&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;conditions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; are met.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;growing-blusd-liquidity-hands-in-hand-with-lusd&#34;&gt;Growing bLUSD liquidity hands in hand with LUSD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is another indirect beneficial effect of the Chicken Bonds, stemming from the chosen structure for bLUSD liquidity, incentivized by the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, a &lt;strong&gt;3% Chicken In fee is collected and redirected to incentivize liquidity providers of the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool&lt;/strong&gt;. This pool is a meta pool made of bLUSD paired with the LP token of the existing LUSD/3CRV. At perfect equilibrium, the asset exposure would be: 50% bLUSD / 25% LUSD + 25% 3pool (8.33% USDC / 8.33% USDT / 8.33% DAI).&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This liquidity structure ensures that &lt;strong&gt;50% of the deposits made into the bLUSD LP pool directly contribute to growing the liquidity of the main LUSD/3CRV&lt;/strong&gt;. Moreover, because this pool has its own incentive budget (Chicken In fee), it will provide an attractive LUSD yield to stakers on top of the base yield generated by swaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the Chicken Bonds mature, the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool could get its own gauge, securing additional CRV (and potentially CVX) rewards on top of the existing ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model was chosen over a bLUSD/LUSD pool which would have required a sizeable amount of LUSD without contributing to LUSD’s liquidity against other stablecoins. The main downside of the chosen model is that it makes the deposit and withdrawal interactions more complex for liquidity providers. However, this concern will be lifted with &lt;strong&gt;zaps enabling the supply and withdrawal from LUSD and bLUSD directly&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV pool equilibrium, supplying it single-sided with either LUSD or bLUSD can result in a premium:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is too much LUSD-3CRV in the pool, providing bLUSD rebalances the pool and results in a premium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is too much bLUSD in the pool, then supplying it with LUSD will result in a &lt;strong&gt;double premium&lt;/strong&gt; as both the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV and LUSD/3CRV pools are rebalanced in the process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV in the dedicated article on the Chicken Bonds blog &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog-posts/game-of-chickens-the-end-of-the-bootstrap-period-and-what-it-means-for-blusd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game of Chickens!&lt;/strong&gt; The end of the bootstrap period and what it means for bLUSD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;additional-solutions-to-grow-lusds-liquidity&#34;&gt;Additional solutions to grow LUSD’s liquidity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chicken Bonds are the main ongoing initiatives attempting to grow LUSD’s liquidity, yet, other projects and solutions are being explored too. Here’s an overview.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vecrv-position-and-bribes&#34;&gt;veCRV position and bribes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liquity treasury entered the Curve Wars months ago, acquiring and locking CRV tokens to support the bLUSD/LUSD-3CRV gauge. To maximize the impact of the LUSD Chicken Bonds, &lt;strong&gt;a bribing campaign&lt;/strong&gt; is also synchronized with the release to increase the CRV APY of LUSD/3CRV pool depositors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Warden Quest, LQTY tokens are awarded to veCRV and vlCVX voters on the LUSD/3CRV CRV gauge. The bribing campaign secured &lt;strong&gt;5M veCRV votes (~1% of total votes)&lt;/strong&gt;, which led to a sharp increase in the APY, bringing it to parity with a basic Stability Pool deposit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you out of the loop with the Curve Wars? Start here: &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV wars: the race to accumulate the ability to influence the Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;powerpools-lucy-interest-bearing-lusd-lp-position&#34;&gt;PowerPool’s LUCY: interest-bearing LUSD LP position
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PowerPool team has been working on an interesting &lt;strong&gt;novel type of Balancer pool&lt;/strong&gt; suited for LUSD, and it’s now close to being released: the LUSD-a-bb-USD pool, also known under the sweet name of &lt;strong&gt;LUCY&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like the Chicken Bonds, this pool &lt;strong&gt;harnesses b.protocol to provide an auto-compounded earning opportunity on LUSD&lt;/strong&gt;. Indeed, the main innovation of this pool is to involve interest-bearing assets and constantly &lt;strong&gt;rebalances between yield-bearing and liquidity-providing activities&lt;/strong&gt;. The pool is made of two wrapper tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-balancer-boosted-aave-usd&#34;&gt;1/ Balancer Boosted Aave USD
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;This pool is essentially the &lt;strong&gt;Balancer’s equivalent of Curve’s 3 pool&lt;/strong&gt;, the main stablecoin pool of the decentralized exchange. The key difference here is that the pool involves &lt;strong&gt;interest-bearing wrappers&lt;/strong&gt; of each stablecoin. Depending on the pool’s liquidity needs, each stablecoin rebalances between liquidity-providing or yield-bearing through Aave:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/bbaUSD-pool-composition.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;bbaUSD-pool-composition&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-lusd--bprotocol&#34;&gt;2/ LUSD + b.protocol
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bb-a-USD tokens are paired against LUSD, which also &lt;strong&gt;rebalances yield-bearing (Stability Pool with b.protocol) and liquidity-providing&lt;/strong&gt; depending on the needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, the LUCY pool should be interesting to grow LUSD’s available liquidity, as it could provide an interest yield-stacking option for liquity providers, earning:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;swap fees APR&lt;/strong&gt;, collected on exchanges involving the pool’s tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;base yield&lt;/strong&gt; on each pool token (Aave’s yield for USDC/USDT/DAI, Stability Pool’s yields for LUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[If a BAL gauge is obtained] the &lt;strong&gt;LP token BAL staking APY&lt;/strong&gt;, which can be further increased with gauge votes and bribing campaigns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This novel pool will mark the arrival of LUSD on Balancer, diversifying its liquidity source further, as the main venues to trade LUSD are currently Curve, Uniswap, and Velodrome on Optimism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lusd-integrations-into-other-lending-protocols&#34;&gt;LUSD integrations into other lending protocols
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, LUSD has been increasingly integrated across various DeFi protocols, providing &lt;strong&gt;additional options to LUSD holders and arbitrageurs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.aave.com/reserve-overview/?underlyingAsset=0x5f98805a4e8be255a32880fdec7f6728c6568ba0&amp;amp;marketName=proto_mainnet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;addition of LUSD as a borrowable asset on Aave&lt;/a&gt; marked the first time the stablecoin could be borrowed using collateral other than ETH to secure the position. As the liquidity available on the market grows, it opens LUSD arbitrage to non-ETH holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-aave-market.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-aave-market&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, &lt;strong&gt;LUSD was also added as collateral on two €-based lending protocols&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://angle.money/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Angle Money&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mimo.capital/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mimo&lt;/a&gt;. Both enable LUSD holders to enter a short position on €, using their LUSD as collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gearbox.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;GearBox&lt;/a&gt; is gearing up to release its V2 shortly, enabling users to get leverage according to a pre-determined and smart-contract-enforced set of rules. Amongst the options available at release, &lt;strong&gt;liquidity providers of the LUSD/3CRV will be able to leverage their position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing the lending market of LUSD beyond Liquity grows the stablecoin utility while enabling more various types of users to arbitrage its price fluctuations. Paired with the ongoing efforts to grow LUSD’s liquidity on DEX, it will help stabilize its price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lusd-on-optimism-velodrome-and-stargate&#34;&gt;LUSD on Optimism: Velodrome and Stargate
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;LUSD also &lt;strong&gt;has a strong presence on Optimism&lt;/strong&gt;, thanks to Liquity being one of the protocols involved in the Velodrome races. With a respectable veVELO position, Liquity has been able to grow several LUSD-related pools to sizeable TVL. Moreover, pools on Velodrome tend to be more balanced than the mainnet pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/lusd-chicken-bonds/lusd-velodrome.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;lusd-velodrome&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, bridging LUSD to Optimism is currently a bit of a one-way trip. Bridging LUSD to Optimism is easy and only takes 5-10 min using the official bridge. However bridging back to the mainnet takes 7 days with the official bridge, and no alternative options with decent liquidity are available yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The situation is about to change, enabling LUSD’s strong liquidity on Optimism to positively impact the mainnet situation: Stargate, the omnichain liquidity transport protocol, recently voted to &lt;strong&gt;add support for LUSD&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://snapshot.org/#/stgdao.eth/proposal/0xe6fef4aa9c8e9d162f694ab764b11c06918b9f199aafe43e0d85b12d8271011c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SIP#16&lt;/a&gt;), which will enable its fast bridging from and to Optimism once implemented. If Stargate can provide a reliable solution to fast bridge LUSD from Optimism to mainnet, it could positively impact mainnet’s LUSD liquidity pools balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;learn-more-about-chicken-bonds&#34;&gt;Learn more about Chicken Bonds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article piqued your curiosity about Chicken Bonds and LUSD. If that’s the case, many resources are available for you to explore the model further; here are some recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chicken Bonds website&lt;/a&gt; is a great starting point — you’ll find &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/lusd-bonds#front-ends&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the list of the front ends&lt;/a&gt; you can use to interact with LUSD Chicken Bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To go deeper, feel free to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.chickenbonds.org/blog&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check the blog&lt;/a&gt; available on the website: it features several articles deep diving into critical dimensions of the Chicken Bonds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, the most comprehensive resource about Chicken Bonds is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://liquity.gitbook.io/chicken-bonds/faq/table-of-content&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the user documentation&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to check it if some of your questions are left unanswered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep track of what is happening with the Chicken Bonds, you&amp;rsquo;ll find stats in the UI of the front-end you use. Else, a community member has made a neat &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dune.com/nemoventures/chicken-bonds&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chicken Bonds Dune Analytics&lt;/a&gt; that will be helpful. For further discussion, you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/WQMEcgHBpc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;join the Liquity Discord&lt;/a&gt;, where a brand new section is dedicated to Chicken Bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, Liquity is the only &amp;ldquo;deployer.&amp;rdquo; This concept will gain relevance with the Generalized version of the Chicken Bonds, where other protocols can harness the model to benefit their tokens.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquidity driver tokens enable direct incentives to selected liquidity or lending pairs, usually through a locking system. They allow projects which lock them to direct emissions to pools of their choosing to attract liquidity.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, this is the first time this kind of bribery has been attempted on Curve voters (or any other DeFi token holders): NFT-attribute-based bribes; here we come!&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pool is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/factory-crypto/134&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;already live&lt;/a&gt; but cannot be supplied before the end of the bootstrap period.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Can Aave&#39;s GHO stablecoin help the protocol further grow and overtake MakerDAO and DAI?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/aave-gho-stablecoin/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/aave-gho-stablecoin/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/aave-gho-stablecoin/aave-gho-stablecoin-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Can Aave&#39;s GHO stablecoin help the protocol further grow and overtake MakerDAO and DAI?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, the concept for the GHO stablecoin was introduced on the Aave Governance Forum and triggered a wave of excitement across DeFi. Indeed, the idea of a decentralized, collateral-backed stablecoin, pegged to USD and native to the Aave DAO makes a lot of sense as a next step for the protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll examine the design introduced before considering how the Aave DAO and team could bring it to market and turn it into a stablecoin potentially as significant as DAI. Of course, the information is still scarce, so the second part of the article will be primarily extrapolations stemming from my DeFi experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-gho-aaves-native-stablecoin&#34;&gt;Introduction to GHO, Aave&amp;rsquo;s native stablecoin
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since its early days, one of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s main challenges has been attracting sufficient stablecoin deposits since it&amp;rsquo;s a preferred choice for most borrowers. Thus, creating a stablecoin native to the DAO is a natural next step and should also allow lowering costs for borrowers. Since this stablecoin is minted, there is no need to pay the APR of the depositors on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the main characteristics of GHO as presented on the governance forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-overcollateralized-usd-pegged-stablecoin&#34;&gt;An overcollateralized USD-pegged stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GHO will be an overcollateralized stablecoin, minted using aTokens as collateral. So in a sense, it&amp;rsquo;s similar to MakerDAO but slightly more efficient since all collateral will be productive assets generating some interest (aTokens) – depending on their borrowing demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the naming, it&amp;rsquo;s also interesting to see Aave not including &amp;ldquo;USD&amp;rdquo; in the name. Considering how aggressive the US regulators can be, it&amp;rsquo;s probably a net benefit from a legal perspective. Still, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be the only driver of the decision, as Aave&amp;rsquo;s founder Stani hinted at a potential peg swap further down the line:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference to a currency has limitations over long term, potentially you might want to swap the peg from one underlying asset to another (for various reasons) or track something else and being bound to a USD in the ticker would be a limiting factor. On top of that everyone is doing that already which makes it a bit repetitive and restrictive from the messaging perspective. DAI follows the same path actually and has been helpful to build a narrative over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stani on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/introducing-gho/8730/27&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s GHO introduction post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interest-model-and-stkaave-discount&#34;&gt;Interest model and stkAAVE discount
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The interest rate model for GHO is currently its most underwhelming component, as the initial post envisioned an interest rate directly determined by the Aave DAO, just like how it works on Maker. However, that would be inefficient and add unnecessary bloat to the governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The community feedback will dictate where it goes. Still, I genuinely hope for Aave that the final call lands on a model where the interest rate is algorithmically determined by market conditions, just like with other tokens on Aave where the supply/demand on the pool dictates the interest rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the Aave community feels like it is a necessity to involve the DAO in determining the interest rate — an absurdity in my book since a DAO is absolutely unfit to manage the operational parameters of a system — then a hybrid model could be envisioned with a fixed base rate voted on by the DAO, and modulated within a range depending on the market condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, having the interest rate evolve dynamically can help protect GHO&amp;rsquo;s peg by deterring against massive minting events, just like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.liquity.org/faq/lusd-redemptions#how-is-the-baserate-calculated&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;how the baseRate works on Liquity&lt;/a&gt; to protect LUSD from de-pegging downward. Initially, at 0.5%, the fee rises when demand surges to progressively decays back to 0.5% as the demand stabilizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post also mentions a discount for GHO borrowers staking AAVE tokens, creating further synergies. Finally, 100% of the interest rates paid by depositors will go to the Aave DAO (vs. a Reserve Factor in the ~10% range for most other tokens), meaning that if GHO grows to a significant market cap, it could turn into a goldmine for the DAO. &lt;strong&gt;With a market cap similar&amp;rsquo;s to DAI, and an average interest rate of 3.5% (high-end), AaveDAO would earn close to $150K daily from GHO&amp;rsquo;s interest rate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some quick napkin maths with different GHO market cap and interest rate assumptions to give you an idea:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;GHO Marketcap&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;Avg. Interest Rate&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;DAO Yearly Earning&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;DAO Daily Earning&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$1.5B (FRAX market cap)&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
1%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$15,000,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$41,095.89&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$6.6B (DAI market cap) &lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
1%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$66,000,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$180,821.92&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$52B (USDC market cap)&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
1%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$520,000,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$1,424,657.53&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$1.5B&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
3.50%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$52,500,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$143,835.62&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$6.6B&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
3.50%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$231,000,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$632,876.71&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$52B&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
3.50%&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$1,820,000,000.00&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;p style=&#34;text-align: center&#34;&gt;
$4,986,301.37&lt;/p&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Table references:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GHO Marketcap: 1.5B = FRAX&amp;rsquo;s current supply, 6.6B is DAI&amp;rsquo;s, and 52B is USDC — one can dream.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GHO Average Interest Rate: 1% would be highly competitive, 3.5% in the higher-end of the usual rates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;facilitators-and-rwa&#34;&gt;Facilitators and RWA
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GHO&amp;rsquo;s design envisions &amp;ldquo;Facilitators,&amp;rdquo; onboarded by Aave&amp;rsquo;s governance, that would be able to mint GHO. The first facilitator would be the Aave protocol itself, but others will follow suit, be they protocols or entities. This part is exciting, as it widely opens up GHO&amp;rsquo;s design space. Following the release, we could see other protocols applying to become facilitators and building on top of Aave and GHO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/aave-gho-stablecoin/gho-facilitators.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;gho-facilitators&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also explicit mentions of undercollateralized positions based on credentials such as a credit score. Each facilitator will have a maximal GHO minting capacity determined by the DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralization-and-absence-of-censorship-resistance&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Decentralization&amp;rdquo; and absence of censorship resistance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;GHO is presented as a decentralized stablecoin by the Aave team, with even some mentions of censorship resistance. However, it&amp;rsquo;s never directly associated with GHO:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The usage of stablecoins will only continue to grow as cryptoassets become further integrated with a user base that is less crypto-native. Decentralized stablecoins provide censorship-resistant fiat-denominated currency on the blockchain. Introducing, GHO, a decentralized multi-collateral stablecoin that is fully backed and native to the Aave Protocol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless I&amp;rsquo;ve misunderstood the design, GHO will be &lt;strong&gt;as &amp;ldquo;decentralized&amp;rdquo; as DAI and have weak censorship resistance&lt;/strong&gt; because of its collateral composition. Indeed, assuming that all aTokens that can be currently used as collateral to borrow on Aave will also be used to borrow GHO, GHO&amp;rsquo;s collateral composition will be mostly made of censorable tokens such as USDC:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/aave-gho-stablecoin/aave-collateral.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;aave-collateral&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defillama.com/protocol/aave-v2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiLlama&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed excluding stETH used as collateral to leverage the ETH staking yield (borrowing ETH), USDC is the top collateral used on Aave, with another trusted token (wBTC) not far behind. &lt;strong&gt;Still, the collateral composition would be much better than DAI,&lt;/strong&gt; which is &amp;gt;50% backed by pure USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/aave-gho-stablecoin/dai-collateral.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;dai-collateral&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another ~25% of the backing comes from other trust-required collateral or reflexive liquity providing positions (such as DAI/USDC LP used as collateral to mint DAI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information on the envisioned design for GHO, feel free to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/introducing-gho/8730&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the governance forum post&lt;/a&gt; and the replies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gho-to-market-what-could-aave-with-gho-look-like&#34;&gt;GHO to market: What could Aave with GHO look like?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that the stage is set regarding GHO, we can move into a more speculative territory and consider how the GHO release could unfold in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the interaction between the Aave protocol and GHO is quite exciting to consider: while the initial post mention Aave x GHO, as well as the enablement of the eMode (enabling significant leverage on selected pairs such as USDC/DAI) on GHO, it quite scarce in details, so let me share instead how I envision it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;aGHO would be fascinating collateral on Aave, but it could also create significant reflexive risks if allowed to borrow GHO. Thus, &lt;strong&gt;I expect aGHO to be blocked from minting GHO&lt;/strong&gt; to prevent reflexive backing like we&amp;rsquo;re currently seeing on DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it would allow for exciting stablecoin arbitrage loops, such as aUSDC &amp;gt; Mint GHO &amp;gt; aGHO &amp;gt; Borrow another stablecoin. With the eMode, this would make Aave &amp;amp; GHO a very effective protocol for stablecoin arbitrage. Besides, the GHO interest rate would become a kind of &amp;ldquo;base stablecoin interest rate&amp;rdquo; and maybe help keep the interest rate of other stablecoins like USDC in check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ghos-liquidity-strategy&#34;&gt;GHO&amp;rsquo;s Liquidity Strategy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another critical and essential part of any stablecoin&amp;rsquo;s design is its liquidity strategy. Since CRV, CVX, and BAL are accepted as collateral on Aave, there could be exciting things done with the CRV, CVX, and BAL accumulated by the treasury, thanks to the Reserve Factor. Locking them into their native protocols would enable the Aave DAO to direct incentives to GHO-related pools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/aave-gho-stablecoin/aaveDAO-treasury.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;aaveDAO-treasury&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Source: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/aave-treasury-report/5575/37&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave’s Treasury Report&lt;/a&gt; (July 2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Frax is currently pivoting away from USDT and DAI and trying to establish the Frax Basepool (FRAX/USDC) as a pairing currency on Curve for other stablecoins, we could envision a similar move from Aave. Moreover, many projects currently exposed to USDC and DAI are looking to diversify their liquidity away from them. GHO might arrive with perfect timing to enable DeFi to be less reliant on USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, while Frax controls sizeable governance and gauge-voting power in the Curve Wars, this is not the case for the Aave DAO. Current treasury CRV/CVX balances will clearly be insufficient to incentivize pools to grow into the billion dollar range, so it could drive the AaveDAO to look into acquiring more liquidity-incentive-driver tokens. With the significant revenues that the DAO will collect from GHO&amp;rsquo;s interest rate, it should have sufficient means to support appropriate liquidity, whatever GHO&amp;rsquo;s market cap ends up being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, Aave has been historically close to Balancer, with the 80% AAVE / 20% wETH Balancer Pool used in the Safety Module since the transition to the AAVE token. The treasury currently owns 200k BAL and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/arc-strategic-partnership-with-balancer-part-2/7813&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;another acquisition is planned&lt;/a&gt;. Thus we could expect an exciting play for GHO on Balancer. Yet when it comes to stablecoin, Curve remains both the king and king-maker: I don&amp;rsquo;t see how Aave could sufficiently grow GHO&amp;rsquo;s liquidity without getting involved one way or another in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md%22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the CRV wars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the base protocol incentives (such as the dynamic or DAO-governed borrowing interest rate) and liquidation mechanism, the liquidity strategy is probably one of the most crucial element for a stablecoin since it also has an impact on how well the peg is held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parting-words&#34;&gt;Parting Words
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope this article helped you better understand what is at stake in the stablecoin wars. The end of the year will be interesting, with the GHO release approaching and Curve&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, also overcollateralized, which was hinted to release before the end of this year. The multiplication of stablecoin is a natural next step for DeFi, as most established protocols see their design converge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frax started as a stablecoin only, now has FraxSwap and soon FraxLend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave started as a money market, soon with its own native stablecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve started as a DEX, but the addition of its own stablecoin soon could enable efficient borrowing for liquidity providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, as shown with my napkin maths earlier, the main reason for a protocol to create its stablecoin is quite apparent: it&amp;rsquo;s where there is the most money to be made, as well as massive demand and product/market fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;artist&amp;rdquo; of the cover image for this article is an impressive (and slightly scary) AI called &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.midjourney.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Midjourney&lt;/a&gt;. It was given the following prompt: &lt;code&gt;a cute and friendly glowing ghost minting the coins of his own currency in a cyberpunk environement, 4k,cartoon,fully details,high contracts,unreal engine. --ar 19:10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Behind the scene of the decentralization theater: a study of the inalterability of DeFi protocols</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/unstoppable-defi/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/unstoppable-defi/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/unstoppable-defi-tokenbrice-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Behind the scene of the decentralization theater: a study of the inalterability of DeFi protocols" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Decentralized finance has allowed the emergence of autonomous protocols whose functionalities are ensured by smart contracts that are sometimes immutable. It enables individuals from all over the world to use financial services that are at the same time sovereign, accessible, and more efficient and resilient than those available in traditional finance. It&amp;rsquo;s the lovely story that newcomers are told to lull them to sleep: the reality is much more nuanced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;a handful of protocols fit this reality,&lt;/strong&gt; but most are far from being up to par. When the bulls are out, interest in the resilience of the protocols is generally shallow: the only thing that matters is price appreciation. But the bears have made a comeback, and thankfully it means a renewed interest in these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent implosion of the Luna ecosystem and its associated stablecoin, UST, will hopefully serve as a wake-up call for some. It was, unfortunately, a &lt;strong&gt;perfectly avoidable&lt;/strong&gt; disaster. The model used for this stablecoin and its flaws were already known, with many previous instances covered on this blog: BAC, MIC, ESD, DSD, etc. (at the application level on Ethereum rather than the protocol level, but with the same fundamental problems). They all had the same end: an endless spiral that brought them closer to absolute 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of this event, many investors have become aware that not all stablecoins are created equal and seek to learn more about the resilience of the many stablecoins available on the market and the robustness of different DeFi protocols in general. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;m seizing this exceptional moment to discuss this essential topic for the sustainability of DeFi; it has been a passion of mine for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, last year I already proposed to you an exhaustive analysis of the risks incurred on the borrowing services in DeFi and how to evaluate them. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is still relevant and a highly recommended read for any informed investor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enough with the introduction. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to the point and define the term &amp;ldquo;unstoppable&amp;rdquo; and what it implies in concrete terms at a protocol level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-unstoppable-defi-protocol&#34;&gt;What is an unstoppable DeFi protocol?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the most basic level, we can call &lt;strong&gt;a DeFi protocol unstoppable &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; when its essential functions are provided by smart contracts that are not modifiable, and it does not require external intervention to subsist.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To this relatively straightforward definition, I must add many notes and clarifications to cover the diversity of DeFi protocols and their use cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-third-party-protocol-dependencies&#34;&gt;⚠️ Third-party protocol dependencies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In DeFi, it is infrequent that a protocol does everything by itself. More often than not, a given protocol relies on various third-party protocols. Of course, the most common and well-known case is the oracle - the source of prices for assets - a critical component for borrowing services in particular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dependence-on-oracles-like-chainlink&#34;&gt;Dependence on oracles like ChainLink
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this regard, the most widely used oracle is &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/chainlink-oracles/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ChainLink&lt;/a&gt;. Although technically robust, the industry recently got a reminder, thanks to Chris Blec and a few other actors concerned about the resilience of the service: ChainLink&amp;rsquo;s oracles are susceptible to manipulation or censorship. The riskiest attack vector seems to be &lt;strong&gt;the 3/20 multisig&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows the price source for a given asset to be changed immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concretely, if three people synchronize among these 20, they could change the ETH/USD oracle, for example, for an in-house oracle that returns a price of $1, and almost all DeFi loans would be liquidated in the process. However, it seems rather unlikely that people on or close to the ChainLink team would carry out such an attack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most significant risk seems to be an &lt;strong&gt;attack by an external actor&lt;/strong&gt; who would like to harm the whole of DeFi. Indeed, with such a permissive multisig, it would be &amp;ldquo;enough&amp;rdquo; to identify three or more members of this multisig, kidnap them and threaten them to change a price source of ChainLink. It is the famous &amp;ldquo;🔧 wrench attack.&amp;rdquo; No matter how secure the smart contracts are, if they are administered by a multisig, they are vulnerable to this type of attack that goes through the people behind the protocols rather than the code directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main problem here is not the existence of this multisig, which is necessary to update and improve the services that ChainLink provides, but its setting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3/20 is extraordinarily permissive&lt;/strong&gt; and riskier from a 🔧 wrench attack point of view than 3/6, for example (which would have fewer potential targets to perform the attack). A more reasonable number aligned with what is usually done for 20 signers in total would be something between 8 and 12 signers required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No timelock&lt;/strong&gt;: so changes are immediate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⚠️ Update - May 27&lt;/strong&gt;: On May 23rd (5 days after the publication of this article), the Multisig setup has been updated to a 4/9, which makes a 🔧 wrench attack harder to perform; there is still no timelock&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dependence-on-other-protocols-that-are-less-resilient-than-the-base-protocol&#34;&gt;Dependence on other protocols that are less resilient than the base protocol
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the fascinating elements in DeFi is &lt;strong&gt;composability&lt;/strong&gt;: protocols integrate and use each other. While this allows for the emergence of synergies and innovative use cases, it also comes with additional risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without going into too much detail, as we will come back to it later, we will take as an example PoolTogether, one of the most resilient protocols of the DeFi and quasi-unstoppable. The quasi comes from its external dependencies and, more precisely, the sources of yields used: Compound or Aave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the smart contracts of PoolTogether are immutable except for the part that manages the price allocation (v4). Still, the funds are deployed in protocols powered by smart contracts that can be altered (such as adding a new collateral, a necessary feature but also a potential attack vector&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The general rule is that a protocol is as resilient as the weakest link in its composability chain&lt;/strong&gt;. This rule is not absolute, as it is still possible to mitigate or contain the exposure taken with integrations, for example, by implementing redundancy, as we will see below in the detailed assesments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-access-to-protocols-the-question-of-websites-front-end&#34;&gt;⚠️ Access to protocols: the question of websites (front-end)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On this topic, there are two key questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the access point to the protocol (= the website/front-end) resilient / can it be censored, for example, by a state actor?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the site secure? Can a malicious actor attack it?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-of-censorship-of-the-front-end&#34;&gt;Risk of censorship of the front-end
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, I must start by reminding you of a fundamental point: a DeFi service exists thanks to a set of smart contracts. It is &lt;strong&gt;entirely possible to interact with any DeFi service by going directly through the contracts&lt;/strong&gt; - and thus, even if their site were to be inaccessible. Of course, not all DeFi users have the technical skills required to interact with smart contracts directly, which is why &lt;strong&gt;the front-end issue remains essential&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, protocols that maximize their resilience need to think about it. Two main approaches are possible and can be combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a protocol can have &lt;strong&gt;multiple access points&lt;/strong&gt; that allow access to its service: if one of them were inaccessible, others would remain online, thus causing only minor inconvenience to the service users. For example, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/aave/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt; can be used through the main app.aave.com site, but also through tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://instadapp.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;InstaDapp&lt;/a&gt; and many others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, most of these sites are still hosted by &lt;strong&gt;centralized services&lt;/strong&gt; that could all be censored simultaneously: it&amp;rsquo;s more work, but it&amp;rsquo;s technically possible. To overcome this limitation, another option is available: having one or more &lt;strong&gt;sites hosted via a decentralized solution like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, in terms of front-end resilience, the most original, elegant, and efficient approach deployed to date is probably the one of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; protocol. Indeed, Liquity does not have an official website for its application deployed and managed directly by the team. Instead, the team provides &lt;strong&gt;a kit to deploy a front-end&lt;/strong&gt; of Liquity, usable by all. Because of this approach, the project now has &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/frontend&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a myriad of different sites to use its service&lt;/a&gt;, some of which are hosted on IPFS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/liquity-frontend.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;some-liquity-frontends&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;security-risks-of-front-end&#34;&gt;Security risks of front-end
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, one should not forget that a front-end remains a website. Even if it is not censored, &lt;strong&gt;it may be susceptible to attacks&lt;/strong&gt; of varying degrees of severity: the websites of the decentralized exchange SpiritSwap and QuickSwap, for example, have recently &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/QuickswapDEX/status/1525306033400188928?s=20&amp;amp;t=UKpcM2Gu6nZ9Kgl65kmp3w&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;suffered from such a scenario&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The attack vector is linked to the service&amp;rsquo;s domain name manager (GoDaddy). Other types of attacks are possible: for example, code injections through a third-party service that the site integrates, as we recently saw on EtherScan, as an advertising tracker they use was compromised (CoinZilla).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ℹ-limitations-of-unstoppable-protocols&#34;&gt;ℹ️ Limitations of unstoppable protocols
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unstoppable protocols cannot cover all use cases. Indeed, depending on the complexity of a protocol, it is sometimes impossible to avoid any dependency on another protocol that is itself at least partially censurable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, one must keep in mind the counterpart that comes with the immutability of the smart contracts of unstoppable protocols: &lt;strong&gt;an update of these is technically impossible&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, when an unstoppable protocol needs to evolve, there is only one possible path: deploy a new version of the protocol (with its new set of immutable contracts) and encourage the &lt;strong&gt;migration&lt;/strong&gt; of its users to it. This is, for example, what Uniswap has done twice, with the migration to version 2 in May 2020 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and then again one year later with the release of Uniswap v3 in May 2021 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/UNIv2-migration-tool.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;UNIv2-migration-tool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on the differences between the versions, the protocol may also offer a tool to facilitate migration, as was the case for UNIv1⇒UNIv2. However, it was impossible for UNIv2⇒UNIv3 mainly because of the introduction of liquidity concentration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be exhaustive on the cost/benefit analysis of immutable contracts, don&amp;rsquo;t forget that they make 🔧 wrench attacks impossible and may also be of interest from a legal perspective.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-spectrum-of-resilience&#34;&gt;The Spectrum of Resilience
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve established the definition of &amp;ldquo;unstoppable&amp;rdquo; with all the necessary precisions, I propose to move directly to the analysis. Before digging into the relevant protocols, let me offer you a spectrum that highlights different levels of resilience:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/resilience-spectrum-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-spectrum-resilience-tokenbrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailing centralized or &amp;ldquo;DINO&amp;rdquo; (Decentralized in Name Only) protocols, decentralized in name only, is not very insightful, so I will let you dig for yourself. Instead, let&amp;rsquo;s look at protocols on the more exciting end of the spectrum: to the right of MakerDAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;analysis-of-the-most-resilient-dex&#34;&gt;Analysis of the most resilient DEX
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we get to the resilience of Uniswap and Curve, we need to recall a few crucial things about decentralized exchanges. Specifically, they have two types of users who assume pretty different levels of risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users who exchange tokens through the DEX. These users bear the risks linked to the DEX smart contracts for the time of the swap only (as well as those related to unlimited &amp;ldquo;approve&amp;rdquo; if the DEX contract is compromised and is not immutable)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity providers are exposed as long as their position is maintained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Uniswap as on Curve, &lt;strong&gt;the contracts relating to the two situations are immutable&lt;/strong&gt;. It is technically impossible to envisage a &amp;ldquo;rug&amp;rdquo; of the liquidity providers, which is not the case for all DEXs: such an attack was possible on SushiSwap once because of their migration function. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that DEXs relying on an Automated Market Maker such as Uniswap or Curve do &lt;strong&gt;not need an oracle to work&lt;/strong&gt;, which significantly reduces their dependency on potentially censorable third-party services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, even if the contracts are immutable, the risk is not zero for the liquidity providers who assume all the risks related to the tokens involved in the pair. The general rule here is similar to that of the composability chain: &lt;strong&gt;a given LP position is as risky as its most dangerous token&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The front-end issue for DEX is less critical since many access points exist. The most competent users go through a decentralized exchange aggregator, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;uniswap&#34;&gt;Uniswap
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The contracts core functions are completely immutable on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap&lt;/a&gt; v1, v2 and v3. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/uniswap-v2/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2&lt;/a&gt; release markededthe introduction of an administrative fee the governance can decided to turn on&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (= to the protocol), as already seen on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the case is straightforward. If there is indeed a governance, the good news (less for UNI holders) is that what it can do is very limited. &lt;strong&gt;No seizure or migration of funds is possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Apart from the fee, it manages matters such as deploying Uniswap on a new chain, adding a new tier of fees (1bps for stablecoins), or using the protocol&amp;rsquo;s treasury &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, for example, to fund liquidity mining campaigns or to distribute UNI to friendly people who ask for it, without any limit or accounting &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;curve-finance&#34;&gt;Curve Finance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve Finance&lt;/a&gt; is another example of resilient DEX with an equally exciting approach. Again, the essential functions are provided by immutable contracts. Nevertheless, Curve also has an &amp;ldquo;Emergency DAO&amp;rdquo; whose members are elected by the governance. This Emergency DAO can &amp;ldquo;kill&amp;rdquo; a pool (only if pools that are younger than 2 months old and not factory pools): all functions except withdrawal are disabled. It prevents further loss of funds if a problem emerges with Curve&amp;rsquo;s contracts. The Emergency DAO can also kill a gauge - that is the reward contract handling CRV (and potentially other token) rewards. Killed gauges can then be resurrected by the main DAO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Uniswap, Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance is centered around the management of CRV token issuance and management. However, the model is much more refined here; I invite you to read my previous articles on the subject to better understand it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/crv-wars.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ CRV War: Understanding the race to accumulate the ability to influence the Curve Finance protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2022/crv-wars-l2.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚔ Advanced CRV Wars: Analysis of Protocols Built on Curve and Convex &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike Uniswap, participation in Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance requires locking CRV tokens ( ⇒veCRV) for up to four years for those who want to maximize their influence. Thus, it protects the governance from different types of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, the governance also manages a whitelist of smart contracts authorized to interact with the veCRV contract &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;: such decisions are consequential for liquidity providers on Curve and CRV owners in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Curve&amp;rsquo;s governance is one of the most fascinating to follow in DeFi. To help it make more informed decisions, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://substack.com/profile/66151946-crypto-risk-assessments&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a newsletter offering risk assesments of the various protocols that require a gauge&lt;/a&gt; has been set up. I highly recommend reading it; it&amp;rsquo;s an excellent source for perfecting one&amp;rsquo;s understanding of risk in DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-depth-analysis-of-other-notable-protocols&#34;&gt;In-depth analysis of other notable protocols
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to decentralized exchanges, other types of protocols get as close as possible to the most resilient end of the spectrum. Nevertheless, the use cases of the protocols we will detail now are more complex and cannot be served, to my knowledge, without dependencies on other more or less censorable services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquity&#34;&gt;Liquity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; is a dogged project that aims to create the most resilient borrowing system and stablecoin while maintaining an economically efficient system for borrowers. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into too much detail about this protocol here, I invite you to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read the dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s focus on the points relevant to our topic of the day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquity&amp;rsquo;s code is entirely immutable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquity has no governance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nevertheless, like any borrowing service, Liquity depends on an oracle (ETH price in USD). Here, ChainLink is used, but a backup system is also in place. Calculations are made to determine if the data provided by ChainLink is deemed reliable. If it is not, the system automatically switches to a secondary price source as long as it is needed: the Tellor oracle. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, as I mentioned above, Liquity also has an interesting approach to maximizing front-end decentralization.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:12&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to this approach, Liquity is the most resilient borrowing protocol available on Ethereum, allowing LUSD to sweep the title of the most robust and decentralized stablecoin.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:13&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;pooltogether&#34;&gt;PoolTogether
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is a fascinating protocol that explores a new concept: &amp;ldquo;no-loss&amp;rdquo;. Concretely, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/pool-together-v5/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is a prize-linked savings account where the player takes no financial risk on his principal: the game relies entirely on the yield produced by the principal. It redistributes it to the different players according to their luck at the draw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/pooltogether.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pooltogether&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about this protocol, I invite you once again to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/pool-together.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;read the dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the resilience of the protocol. Here, the main issue is &lt;strong&gt;the initial source of yield, which is external&lt;/strong&gt;: it comes from services like Aave or Compound, which are not unstoppable. Thus, a PoolTogether player assumes this risk on his entire deposit: the principal and the yield generated (before it is collected and redirected).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this third-party dependency, the PoolTogetger protocol is remarkably resilient. Indeed, on the PoolTogether side, &lt;strong&gt;contracts are as immutable as possible&lt;/strong&gt;. Specifically, they are all immutable (so a given pool cannot change its source of yield), except for the prize distribution part, which only affects the yields generated. Indeed, the prize distribution model can change following a governance vote (mainnet) or a multisig operation (Avalanche/Polygon), which is necessary because cross-chain governance is not yet available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This point is fascinating and unique in DeFi: PoolTogether is a no-loss prize-linked savings account. This (financial) design principle also manifests itself in smart contracts. A player cannot lose his principal, excluding a problem with Aave/Compound or a critical bug in the PoolTogether contracts. The code itself guarantees this; only the return is potentially at risk. Even if the entire PoolTogether team suffers a 🔧 wrench attack or PoolTogether&amp;rsquo;s governance turns hostile. So &lt;strong&gt;the promise of no loss is upheld at the smart-contract level&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also nuances and differences between V3 and V4 of the protocol as far as risks are concerned. The best thing is to carefully read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.pooltogether.com/security/risks&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trustlessfi-&#34;&gt;TrustlessFi 🏗️
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trustless.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trustless&lt;/a&gt; is a protocol that I&amp;rsquo;ve been fascinated with lately. It&amp;rsquo;s not live yet, but I think the approach has a lot of merits. To describe it very simply, &lt;strong&gt;TrustlessFi is like Liquity and Reflexer having a child together on zkSync&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the goal is, as with Liquity, to create a protocol that will eventually be as unstoppable as possible, and the associated stablecoin (HUE) will inherit this property. Other mechanisms are similar to Liquity, such as ETH as the only collateral, immediate liquidations, or decentralization of the front-end (with a community validation mechanism this time).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the governance side, we have here an approach similar to the Reflexer/RAI de-governance plan but more engaging: 4 phases are envisaged, and at each stage, the control of the Foundation and the community decreases making the protocol more and more immutable. These &lt;strong&gt;phases will be implemented in the code of the contracts themselves&lt;/strong&gt;: it is possible to delay the transition to a new phase by 45 days up to three times if necessary, but it is impossible to cancel this transition altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mechanism similar to Maker-MCD&amp;rsquo;s Dai Saving Rate allows participation in the system without necessarily needing to generate debt. HUE owners will be able to stake it to get a return from the interest rates paid by the borrowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are also some fascinating new features, such as that Troves/CDPs will be tokenized as NFTs, allowing their transfer. Another example is the deployment of HUE liquidity in Uniswap v3 (HUE/ETH), managed by the protocol. At the oracle level, we would also have an unstoppable price source using Uniswap v3, but this undoubtedly comes with increased manipulation risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the approach is going in the right direction. Still, there are many new concepts in this protocol, so it is not easy to anticipate the result once it is available in production for the time being &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:14&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;14&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-and-last-clarifications&#34;&gt;Conclusion and last clarifications
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope that this definite article can serve as a reference for all those who have essential questions about the resilience of DeFi protocols. As usual, rather than delivering assesments as is, I have tried to detail as much as possible the methodology and reasoning so that you can study for yourself the resilience of any protocol not mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To go deeper, I warmly invite you to read an article I published last year, which perfectly complements this one, focused on money markets. It proposes a method of analysis to evaluate the different potential risks they imply:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Assessing risk in decentralized finance: a handbook for money markets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I imagine that such a precise analysis of such a critical subject could arouse more or less positive emotions. Please know that, as always, my intention is only &lt;strong&gt;to inform as many DeFians as possible on matters that I consider essential for DeFi in general.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My educational and pedagogical actions in DeFi have no other purpose than maximizing the resilience and relevance of decentralized finance over the long term. I hope that developers or promoters of protocols to the left of my suggested resilience spectrum will also understand and recognize this mandate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 A huge thank you to all the proofreaders and contributors who participated in the development of this article:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Proofreading and clarity of expression: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Technical and factual proofreading: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.radjaidjah.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Taz&lt;/a&gt; from DeFi France, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MTorgin&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MTorgin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;Footnotes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mention throughout this article the unstoppability of some DeFi protocols: we&amp;rsquo;re talking about the immutability of smart contract code here. The order of transactions on Ethereum can still be manipulated (⇒ MEV), and miners keep an essential role (until the transition to PoS). The contractual unstoppability discussed in this article thus has infrastructural limits.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChainLink provided more info &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.chain.link/docs/using-chainlink-reference-contracts/#updates-to-proxy-and-aggregator-contracts&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;in their documentation&lt;/a&gt; and the multisig contract can be checked &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/0x21f73d42eb58ba49ddb685dc29d3bf5c0f0373ca#readProxyContract&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;directly on EtherScan here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/unstoppable-defi/chainlink-multisig-updated.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;chainlink-multisig-updated&#34;
	
	
&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://governance.aave.com/t/analysis-of-xsushis-incident/6335&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Analysis of the incident&lt;/a&gt; on Aave&amp;rsquo;s governance forum.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/blog/launch-uniswap-v2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Uniswap V2 launch announcement&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://uniswap.org/blog/uniswap-v3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Announcement of the launch of Uniswap V3&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infamous migrator function, also present in many SushiSwap fork. More information on this dreaded feature in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rugdoc.io/education/migrator/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this dedicated Rugdoc article&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.uniswap.org/t/i-think-it-is-necessary-for-uniswap-concurrently-to-turn-on-the-fee-switch-and-liquidity-mining-incentive/15645&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the latest discussions on the subject&lt;/a&gt; on the Uniswap governance forum.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entirely in UNI token, this treasury is quite volatile. Nevertheless, more than 227M UNI is still available today, or about $1.1B. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://openorgs.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OpenOrgs&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the infamous 005 &amp;ldquo;DeFi Education Fund&amp;rdquo; vote; read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.uniswap.org/t/governance-proposal-005-defi-education-fund/12963&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the related topic on the governance forum&lt;/a&gt; for more context.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are three at present: Yearn Finance (yveCRV), Convex (cvxCRV) and StakeDAO (sdCRV).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article provides &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/price-oracles-in-liquity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a clear introduction to the oracle management system on Liquity&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:12&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.liquity.org/blog/liquity-runs-on-decentralized-frontends&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;on the technical and incentive model for Liquity front-end operators&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:12&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:13&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably already seen, I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to have &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2022/tokenbrice-liquity.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;joined the Liquity team very recently&lt;/a&gt;. I mention Liquity in this article because it is a relevant and instructive example of resilient protocol, independent of my professional commitments.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:13&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:14&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, the alpha is for those who dig in and read footnotes carefully as well as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trustlessfi.notion.site/Trustless-4be753d947b040a89a46998eca90b2c9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:14&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/defi-vs-inflation-tokenbrice-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation is more than ever at the center of discussions and concerns: no one understands much about it, no economist has really anticipated it, but we all have an opinion about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we leave economics and politics aside to focus on what matters for your wallet: in decentralized finance, all kinds of protocols are developed, and a good part of them &lt;strong&gt;provide credible and innovative tools to preserve and develop the purchasing power of a portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;, even when the macroeconomic context is most uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to evaluate strategies involving different assets and protocols, all with the same goal: to preserve and develop the effective purchasing power of a given portfolio. Nevertheless, we have to start with the basics, level 0: what is inflation and why should we, DeFians, care about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover image was made by a generous anonymous contributor and features the majestic &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/valkyre/created&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Valkyr-E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;α-tutorial-understanding-the-impact-of-inflation-on-a-crypto-portfolio&#34;&gt;α/ Tutorial: Understanding the impact of inflation on a crypto portfolio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t venture into the details of inflation for fiat currencies here, but the basic concept is known to anyone familiar with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the term: here is how the INSEE (Institut National de la Statistique et des Études Économiques) defines inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation is the loss of purchasing power of money that results in a general and lasting increase in prices. It must be distinguished from the increase in the cost of living. The loss of value of money is a phenomenon that hits the national economy as a whole (households, businesses, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just remember that, &lt;strong&gt;just like in DeFi where each token is associated with a protocol and potentially even an ecosystem, each fiat currency is also based on an economy as well as a set of rules&lt;/strong&gt; (legal system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-macro-point-of-view-scale--country&#34;&gt;Inflation, macro point of view (scale = country)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation corresponds to the production of new money, the important thing is not so much the quantity of money created, but more &lt;strong&gt;what is done with&lt;/strong&gt;. We all understand this rather well with two caricatural examples at each extreme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country A issues a large amount of money in order to invest massively in its transport infrastructure and its energy supply (= long-term investments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here, inflation can be controlled because the new money issued is used to finance investments that develop the country&amp;rsquo;s economic potential in the long run (-&amp;gt; compensation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country B issues a large amount of money to finance an emergency plan to compensate for the foreseeable consequences of previous pseudo-sanitary measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second scenario, the new money is used to cover a &amp;ldquo;current expense&amp;rdquo; of the government. The personal equivalent would be to go into debt every day to pay for lunch. This is obviously unsustainable in the long run. In this scenario, inflation can only be massive as a large amount of new money is issued, while the economic potential of the country in question stagnates or deteriorates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluating-future-inflation&#34;&gt;Evaluating future inflation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough about the macro, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our scale, with things we know well. Here is the evolution of the M1 money supply on the dollar, this allows us to visualize its &amp;ldquo;marketcap&amp;rdquo; in a way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/USD-m1-supply.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;USD M1 Supply&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we only look at M1 for simplicity but the trend is similar on M2 and M3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested here in the dollar which, although challenged, remains the fiduciary currency that sets the tone. As you can see, the curve has been going vertical since the beginning of the Covid crisis. The curve is now much scarier than the worst shitcoins I have ever seen. Doubt it? Consider the same information, presented in this light:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dollar has been around since 1914. 20% of all dollars in circulation were created in 2020. At the current rate, the total amount of dollars in circulation doubles about every 4-5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare with crypto, many are concerned about inflation / new token issuance on Curve Finance (CRV). The 4 year issuance curve looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/crv-release-schedule.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-release-schedule&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no economist, but I know my shitcoins. The official US inflation figure we are given is 7.5% per year. Like unemployment figures, it&amp;rsquo;s a highly political metric that&amp;rsquo;s hard to really appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7.5% figure may seem high, but it is still low when compared to the unprecedented money creation to deal with Covid. So I expect to see this inflation rise further, or else to be sustained over an extended period of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So inflation is here, at 7.5% minimum for several years at least. Enough with boomers&amp;rsquo; macro, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the range of tools that the DeFi offers us to face it and overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-beating-inflation-with-classic-stablecoin-returns&#34;&gt;I/ Beating inflation with &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; stablecoin returns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first approach is as always the simplest, &lt;strong&gt;the brute force method&lt;/strong&gt;: an inflation of 7.5% means that USD left as is will lose 7.5% of their value over the year. The point here is to find a source of return higher than inflation: the difference between the two is the effective return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inflation at 7.5% on the USD, I think it is prudent to make sure to &lt;strong&gt;reach at least 1.5x this figure in yield&lt;/strong&gt; to really consider yourself inflation-proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the game is simple and the rules fairly easy to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with a position in a given stablecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to make it productive, without assuming IL risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a return that exceeds the inflation figure, once the gas costs have been amortized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-stablecoin-deposit&#34;&gt;Simple stablecoin deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we would aim for &lt;strong&gt;a 10.875% annual return on stablecoin $ at the very least&lt;/strong&gt;. With recent declines and yield compression this is increasingly difficult, but still findable even with a single stablecoin deposit without IL risk. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coindix.com/?kind=stable&amp;amp;sort=-apy&amp;amp;chain=ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Coindix&lt;/a&gt; can help you find the vault of your dreams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/coindix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coindix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, &lt;strong&gt;not all vaults are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;! For example, we see nice returns on Bancor on the screenshot: don&amp;rsquo;t forget to consider the volatility of these returns as well as the fees in gas to deploy the position (a Bancor LP is notoriously more expensive than a Yearn deposit for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention it here only to forget it just as quickly afterwards: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.anchorprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Anchor protocol&lt;/a&gt; also offers you a &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; return close to 20% on UST stablecoin. Such a guaranteed rate does not come, of course, without serious compromises that raise real questions about the sustainability of this whole ecosystem (Terra/Luna).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;provision-of-liquidity--time-commitment&#34;&gt;Provision of liquidity + time commitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still in dollars, but a bit riskier, we can consider different types of commitments, with very controlled / no IL risks. For example, a liquidity provision between FRAX and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/DAI LP opportunities on Frax&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax Finance&lt;/a&gt;, the prime rate (x1) is just our minimum target, but it is possible to reach up to x5 with two types of commitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X3 by locking LP tokens for 3 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X2 by using your veFXS (much harder to reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective return on a position locked in for three years corresponds to about 3 times our minimum target, thus offering a credible protection against the loss of value due to the consequences of inflation, but you still have to be able to assume the three-year commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is taken here on DAI, but the situation is similar on the other major stablecoins; for example, here are the FRAX/USDC pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/USDC LP opportunities&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex for Frax is coming (optimizing Frax LP farming via Convex), if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own veFXS, it&amp;rsquo;s probably pertinent to wait until the service is released to make a decision with all the cards in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenizing-and-speculating-on-future-yields&#34;&gt;Tokenizing and speculating on future yields
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To beat that famous 10% return on the dollar, there are still many other options. I present you one last one here to help you consider the other possible strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, we rely on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol that allows the tokenization of future yields on productive assets. The principle is both simple and complex: depositing an asset on APWine allows to separate its future yield (FYT: Future Yield Token) from the underlying principal (PT: Principal Token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, different strategies are possible, such as immediately selling the future yield (FYT) in order to increase the quantity of the productive principal. Such a tool enables better risk management considering the volatily of yields observed in DeFi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and still well above the 10% requirement: let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on the aUSDT vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apwine-USDT-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine aUSDT vault&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automatically exclude the PT/FYT pool which is more complex to understand and has much higher risks than the PT/Underlying offering a 44% return in APW anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the strategy is simple, but you have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the important gas costs linked to the use of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;. To implement the strategy using USDT in the wallet, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit a part of them on Aave (I&amp;rsquo;d recommend 55% of the total maximum for this specific strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit the aUSDT obtained in 1 on APWine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow (x2) + Deposit the PT and Underlying (USDT) tokens as liquidity providing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Stake of the LPs PT/Underlying tokens to obtain the return in APW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget also the gas fees related to the APW claims + unwinding of the position at the end of the period (or before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore better to wait for a day when the transactions clear under 30 gwei so as not to suffer too much from the gas costs on such a strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage here, compared to Frax for example, is that &lt;strong&gt;the position is much more liquid&lt;/strong&gt;. APWine works with an epoch logic that lasts 90 days. Thus, to more easily amortize the costs in gas it is preferable to deploy the strategy at the beginning of the epoch: this is also when the returns are generally the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third winelisting (where the next tokens supported on APWine are decided) has just ended, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apw-winelisting3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine - Winelisting 3&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APWine is still a young protocol, but the governance is dynamic. The next step is approaching: as on Curve, it will soon be the veAPW holders (locked APW) that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.apwine.fi/t/apgp-2-enable-gauges-for-apw-rewards/171&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;will decide on emissions&lt;/a&gt; for each given vault. A redistribution of the cards is to be expected, plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-hedged-productive-positions-with-various-alternative-stablecoins&#34;&gt;II/ Hedged productive positions with various &amp;ldquo;alternative&amp;rdquo; stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have stayed for now on the dollar, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to begin with. Although dollar stablecoins are still largely dominant, there are now &lt;strong&gt;many stablecoins based on other fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt; such as EUR, JPY (Japanese Yen), CHF (Swiss Franc), KRW (Korean Won) or even CAD (Canadian Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the few centralized stablecoins (EURS or EURT), this market is mostly covered by protocols that offer to create synthetic stablecoins backed by other stablecoins. This is the case for example with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jarvis Network&lt;/a&gt;, which uses USDC to collateralize different types of stablecoins: jEUR, jCHF, jKRW, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-deposit&#34;&gt;Single deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yield opportunities with no/low IL for such stablecoins are still quite rare, and usually found on Curve: providing liquidity against other stablecoins based on the same fiat currency, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/curve-chf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CHF pool on Curve Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few stablecoins have lucrative single deposit options jEUR, jCHF, jJPY. They are based on the corresponding Curve pools, with additional incentives offered by Jarvis and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via Jarvis (also available farmed by Harvest), it is also possible to generate a return without IL on jCAD and jJPY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiatafiatb-liquidity-providing&#34;&gt;FiatA/FiatB Liquidity Providing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a slightly different approach, more risky, but also potentially more protective against inflation: providing liquidity on two stablecoins representing two different fiat currencies, for example EURT/3pool (USD) still on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, especially for smaller portfolios, many alternative stablecoins are available on Polygon or Avalanche, with a fairly dense ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarvis offers jCHF-USDC, jEUR-USDC or jCAD-USDC pools with returns above 20%. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beefy.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Beefy.Finance&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to automatically compose the returns obtained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/harvest-jarvis-2-stables.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Network Jarvis jFIAT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: depending on your base asset (e.g. USDC), exposure to EUR (or other currencies) can be lucrative or costly - depending on the evolution of the USDC/EUR exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the more adventurous among you, you should know that APWine is also available on Polygon and already supports several Jarvis tokens, such as the MooJarvis_4eur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity contribution on Curve (4eur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed by Beefy Finance (moo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which compounds return that Jarvis offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the addition of tokens voted during winelisting 3 will open new doors with the upcoming arrival on APWine/Polygon of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooKyber_USDC-jEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooMai_USDC-MAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forex-borrowing&#34;&gt;Forex Borrowing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if liquidations don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, know that a Fuse pool on Polygon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://polygon.market.xyz/pool/7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool7 - Jarvis Forex Market&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to use different jFiat as collateral as well as to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/fuse-pool7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Fuse pool 7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a service, almost anything is possible, here are some examples to inspire you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long USD + short EUR = MAI in collateral, borrow jEUR then sell jEUR and potentially loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short GBP via CHF = jCHF in collateral, borrow jGBP then sell and potential loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also note that the productive stablecoins m2CAD and m2JPY are available as collateral while keeping their yield: they can be interesting for more traditional leverage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding your balance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than just one magic position, what I like about Jarvis stablecoins is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;diversify easily into different types of fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to the low transaction fees on Polygon, it is quite possible to mix several different currencies and positions to make a coherent whole and well protected against its local inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a European (= spending €):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in stable productive € without IL, for example MooJarvis_4eur (+APWine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in jEUR/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% in stable productive dollar (e.g. aUSDT APWine strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Diversification: 15% jCHF/USDC + 15% jGBP/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject of &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; stablecoins, you should know that there are also a few that track gold or silver - they can be relevant from this perspective too. For example XAUT (with Pool Curve XAUT/3crv). Gold and silver remain &lt;del&gt;barbaric&lt;/del&gt; boomers&amp;rsquo; relics, personally I see very little interest in them for a competent DeFian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-inflation-resistant-stablecoins&#34;&gt;III/ Inflation resistant stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beating inflation is nice. Hedging it? Even better. But &lt;strong&gt;why not just abstract it&lt;/strong&gt;, using products that are naturally resistant to it? There are still very few stablecoins that are not tracking fiat currencies, but the supply is growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-the-first-dollar-free-stablecoin&#34;&gt;RAI, the first dollar-free stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast, the very first &amp;ldquo;unpegged stablecoin.&amp;rdquo; Launched at a value of Pi in USD (3.14) in 2021, it has been moving between 3.02 and 3.06 almost since its launch. Given its recent arrival (just over a year), it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how RAI will perform in a period of prolonged inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, diversifying a portion of your stablecoins into RAI may be an attractive option. In addition, there are different return options available on RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple deposit without IL risk: Idle Finance deposits your RAI in Fuse/Aave to optimize the native return + incentives in FLX from Reflexer + incentives in IDLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle-0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Additional FLX incentives for RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By assuming IL risk via liquidity provision on Curve vs. 3pool, a better return is possible. The crvRAI can then be staked directly on Curve or via Convex or Yearn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is based on a mechanism inspired by Maker MCD but with many modifications to make it possible. To understand how it works, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Signals that the mentioned protocol is still under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-inflation-resistant-stablecoin-the-frax-fpi&#34;&gt;🚧 An inflation-resistant stablecoin? The FRAX FPI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Frax Price Index is a new protocol that should arrive soon within the Frax ecosystem. The goal is to offer a new stablecoin, which would follow the CPI (Consumer Price Index) to protect against inflation. Just like Frax, &lt;strong&gt;the system is based on two tokens&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stable - Frax Price Index (FPI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the governance token - Frax Price Index Share (FPIS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/frax-price-index/inflation-hedge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax documentation&lt;/a&gt; offers some information about the upcoming token. &lt;strong&gt;An airdrop of FPIS is planned&lt;/strong&gt; for veFXS or cvxFXS holders. Thus, the protocol will be independent of FRAX/FXS, although a value capture mechanism to FXS is planned beyond the initial airdrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to project solely on a mere design, but it is clear that a stablecoin that would maintain its value despite inflation is a very desirable product. &lt;strong&gt;There are several questions as to whether the peg on FPI can be maintained&lt;/strong&gt;: to keep its equilibrium, people will have to take the opposite trade to FPI, i.e. &amp;ldquo;short inflation&amp;rdquo;. However, in the current context of galloping inflation, it is hard to imagine who could assume such a position and massive incentives might be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the arrival of the FPI is imminent. Traces of the token &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/token/0xdb68c6264e9d0f8a6df1fa5a89f205da38698d15&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FPIS on EtherScan&lt;/a&gt; can be found as early as early March. I look forward to seeing the Frax team&amp;rsquo;s proposed design to address these consequential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-inflation-resistance--degen--volt&#34;&gt;🚧 Inflation resistance + degen = VOLT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI, there is another project I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely, waiting for a long time and holding high hopes for. The high-level concept is very simple: an Abracadabra-like product that would not be a walking security loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Abracadabra allows borrowing from various productive collaterals, which makes the service desirable. Nevertheless, the infrastructure is close to a hack and the actions of the team members make Abracadabra a second or third grade money market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here, with Volt, is to cover the same vertical using a proven infrastructure: the base offered by Reflexer (RAI). Three main changes are expected on this model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Reflexer, which only accepts ETH as collateral, Volt will diversify the available options, notably with productive collateral such as wstETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of VOLT, the system&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, will be indexed to Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI. The Reflexer infrastructure will be reused (PID controller adapted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Volt team is also working in collaboration with Fuse and Olympus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow Volt, as always, the alpha lives on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dGhvDmCNGr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I describe here the initial design of Volt Protocol, which has since evolved. The vision of creating a borrowing service with an inflation-proof stablecoin remains, but the technical choices have evolved. Read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/volt-protocol/whitepaper/blob/main/volt.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper available here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-beating-inflation-with-returns-on-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;IV/ Beating inflation with returns on volatile assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a world where nothing holds and value leaks, what&amp;rsquo;s left? How about good, proven DeFi assets backed by protocols with massive, recurring revenues shared directly with their holders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few of them, very few. We will detail them one by one, as well as the different options available on them to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-the-origin-and-the-end&#34;&gt;ETH: the origin and the end
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is of course ETH, which has many different sources of return - just like stablecoins, there is nothing to stop you from diversifying your ETH exposure with several sources of return, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH staked with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lido.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lido Finance &lt;/a&gt;(low yield, but a priori the safest) [~5%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rocketpool.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rETH&lt;/a&gt; on Curve (more innovative, more lucrative, more risky) [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vault covered call options on ETH via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stakedao&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ribbon.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ribbon Finance&lt;/a&gt; [~25%, risks!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-chain liquidity on a Bridge, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cbridge.celer.network/#/liquidity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celer&lt;/a&gt; [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A position balanced in this way tracks/exceeds inflation slightly with the returns obtained on ETH. The profitability of the position over the long term depends of course mainly on the average entry price on ETH and its evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crv-cvx-and-fxs-the-three-fates-of-the-defi&#34;&gt;CRV, CVX, and FXS: The three Fates of the DeFi?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Romans, the Fates are three goddesses who govern the lives of humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clotho weaves the thread of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lachesis unwinds it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atropos cuts it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi also knows these Fates: three protocols that play a critical role in the survival and growth of potentially any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in addition to ETH, there are several DeFi projects that have already proven themselves, control substantial revenue streams, and offer a truly relevant service in a macro context of prolonged inflation; I see three essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve Finance - CRV&lt;/strong&gt;: the mother of all yields in DeFi + peg machine and liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convex Finance - CVX&lt;/strong&gt;: an option on CRV, which controls almost 50% of all locked CRVs and adds real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frax Finance - FXS&lt;/strong&gt;: innovative stable project, native DeFi, very productive via AMOs + arrival of FPI + Frax has a big position on CVX &amp;amp; some other protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being tokens backed by key protocols in DeFi, there is no shortage of return options on these three tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV -&amp;gt; Deposit on Convex in CvxCRV then stake or LP cvxCRV/CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVX -&amp;gt; Locked vote on Convex in vlCVX -&amp;gt; Return in cvxCRV + bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FXS -&amp;gt; Direct deposit on Frax (veFXS) or management via Convex (cvxFXS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-promising-tokens&#34;&gt;Other promising tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still other projects that have not yet reached the profitability of Curve or Convex but represent credible bets. In a world where inflation is here to stay, the tools that will allow us to protect ourselves from it can become very popular: I propose you some other theses related to what has been already mentioned in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apwinefi-apw-betting-on-the-advanced-defi-infrastructure&#34;&gt;APWine.fi (APW): betting on the advanced DeFi infrastructure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When inflation goes up, everyone is looking for yield. Let them run behind the %, and instead target the pick sellers in this gold rush. This is the main thesis behind a bet on APW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the article already, APWine offers interesting products to bet on the evolution of yields or even realize a future yield immediately. As DeFi develops, the demand for a product like APWine will keep growing. Will it be APWine, or another one? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the APWine Wars coming up, it&amp;rsquo;s not a stretch to envision bribes similar to what we see on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflexer-flx-a-bet-on-degovernance&#34;&gt;Reflexer (FLX): a bet on degovernance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the very interesting technical approach, Reflexer also innovates on another level. Indeed, since the launch of the protocol, the team has presented a &amp;ldquo;De-governance Plan&amp;rdquo; aiming at progressively minimizing the team&amp;rsquo;s control over the protocol through two main means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of everything that can be automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management by FLX holders for situations still requiring manual analysis/decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;Reflexer now exceeds RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The Money God League is a set of projects building using the Reflexer infrastructure, with the support of the team. So it seems quite natural to consider an airdrop of the governance token of these new projects, including VOLT, to FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last tip: the stakers of the FLX/ETH LP in the Reflexer Safety Module are the last resort to guarantee the solvency of the protocol. If I were to consider an airdrop to thank the Reflexer community, I would probably target them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looksrare-looks-bet-on-nfts&#34;&gt;LooksRare (LOOKS): bet on NFTs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of LOOKS as an option on the NFT market. In fact, LooksRare is the first NFT marketplace that shares revenue. This translates into &lt;strong&gt;an ETH yield for stakers on LOOKS that reached 3 digits sustained during the first few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/looks-eth-farm.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ETH yields on LOOKS staking&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, trading volume has dropped and the ETH yield with it, but &lt;strong&gt;the staking LOOKS is still one of the biggest ETH yields out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with these three suggestions, but of course there are other options - you be the judge. For example, the QI Wars have started and the protocol has good traction. Be careful, however, not to fall into the trap of thinking that all protocols that adopt the ve + bribes model will be as successful as Curve and Convex. ve tokenomics will multiply: it&amp;rsquo;s about making the right choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-and-happy-harvesting-&#34;&gt;Good luck and happy harvesting 🚜
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be tempted to apologize for the length of this article, but I remain confident that it&amp;rsquo;s worth a read and will be informative even for the most knowledgeable DeFians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have considered other useful strategies or protocols for protecting against inflation, please feel free to suggest them to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further reading, here are some recommended related articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-wars/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Curve Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Reflexer RAI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, for the practice, which remains ESSENTIAL, your best bet to warm up is to try with small amounts on inexpensive sidechains/L2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The APWine protocol on Polygon to familiarize yourself with these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting jFIAT / Liquidity contribution on Curve + farming to discover Jarvis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long/short on Forex with jFiats + Fuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: I have invested in APWine pre-sale and I am a big user of the protocol. I am a user and frequent holder of almost all the protocols mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice, I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing my research to help you do yours!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt; for their careful proofreading and their suggestions to help improve this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
