<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Adoption on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/adoption/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Adoption on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 14:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/adoption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A cold look at decentralized finance mass adoption: introducing the Great DeFi Filter</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/a-cold-look-at-decentralized-finance-mass-adoption-introducing-the-great-defi-filter/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/a-cold-look-at-decentralized-finance-mass-adoption-introducing-the-great-defi-filter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/great-defi-filter/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post A cold look at decentralized finance mass adoption: introducing the Great DeFi Filter" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the industry the question of adoption is so recurring it now almost triggers an automatic answer leading to a boilerplate response: &amp;ldquo;something about UX, something scalability&amp;rdquo; &amp;amp; if you&amp;rsquo;re lucky, &amp;ldquo;something about privacy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, as my usual, I&amp;rsquo;d like to bring to your attention a different perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-great-defi-filter&#34;&gt;The Great DeFi Filter
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It might be a bit hard to hear for the bulls amongst us, but &lt;strong&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think DeFi is ready for mass audiences just yet&lt;/strong&gt;. From an outsider perspective, onboarding an Ethereum DApp is an exhausting adventure involving learnings in several disciplines and at least a basic understanding of the network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, the numbers of steps and their complexity are reducing by day — the products are becoming more comfortable to use. However, &lt;strong&gt;usage is not the north star metric here: understanding is.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is still quite a steep learning curve before being able to use DeFi the smart way. &lt;strong&gt;This research and documentation phase is often too much work for most — this is the first layer of the filter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this were an economic model, we would probably throw a &amp;ldquo;rational assumption&amp;rdquo; here and conclude that all users going past this point documented themselves and understand what they are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this is the real world, so let me give you a peek of mundanity: through my daily interactions, I run into some users interacting with services they do not understand. Most of the times, they haven&amp;rsquo;t committed too much, and their situation is salvageable, but sometimes the stakes are real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;great-filter-or-great-safety-net&#34;&gt;Great Filter or Great Safety Net?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To understand the filter better, we need to look at what&amp;rsquo;s happening in legacy finance. In the good old banking and finance industry, the learning curve is much less steep. Indeed, you usually have &lt;strong&gt;several intermediaries offering neatly packaged and easy to use products&lt;/strong&gt;: they abstract things for the user while the user of DeFi services is still doing a lot of the nitty-gritty work himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;these intermediaries also play their own game&lt;/strong&gt; - their goals can easily conflict with their users&amp;rsquo; best interest. For instance, if a banking service has its own saving-account product, it can become a form of incentive for them to mislead their users and push them towards it (instead of potential better options @competitors).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we look at different options to lift the filter, I&amp;rsquo;ll close the loop with decentralised finance. The Great Filter I&amp;rsquo;m cornering is also a form of great safety net: everything is transparent and happening on-chain. After a bit of learning, anybody can read the same base data, process it, and be informed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that the &lt;em&gt;Great Filter&lt;/em&gt; will only be lifted with a concerted effort from both sides: users of DeFi services and their builders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lift-the-filter-by-championing-your-favourite-projects&#34;&gt;Lift the filter by championing your favourite projects
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We need more effort from the community - that&amp;rsquo;s you - to explain what is happening with all the different DeFi services. The amount of complexity involved is still massive, and we need more than ever content of the highest quality — videos, infographics, articles, you name it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, a &lt;strong&gt;high-quality DeFi post goes beyond just explaining: it sparks its readers&amp;rsquo; curiosity and leave them hungry for more&lt;/strong&gt;. If you want some help to get involved on this front,&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tokenbrice&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt; please reach out&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;d be more than happy to give you some pointers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m at it, let me address another recurring myth: &lt;strong&gt;you don&amp;rsquo;t need to code to contribute to decentralized finance projects&lt;/strong&gt;. You can be delivering as much value, if not more, doing any of the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding family &amp;amp; friends: that&amp;rsquo;s quite obvious, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve found value in DeFi services, why could they not?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you speak another language? Feel free to reach out to your favourite projects to help them translate their interface, support &amp;amp; other written content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can draw, on paper or digitally? Make a neat infographic of a system you like.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re the king of the opps? Get involved with your local meetups and help them organize!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Got video or audio editing skills? You&amp;rsquo;re going to have many friends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;builders-using-new-devices-to-solve-an-unprecedented-ux-challenge&#34;&gt;Builders: using new devices to solve an unprecedented UX challenge
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before I wrap this up, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about the second side, the builders. UX of the Dapps is obviously a significant challenge - but why is that so?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that as an industry, we&amp;rsquo;re still quite user-shy. We see again and again projects being developed in an Ivory Tower, and then unleashed to the crowds by their creators, full of hope &amp;amp; dreams - ready to be crushed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you thought the tech by itself was enough - insider tip: it&amp;rsquo;s not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now accounting for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fact that we are building &lt;strong&gt;services operating in a manner never seen before&lt;/strong&gt;: transparent, interoperable, and more or less trustless thanks to decentralized or distributed networks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not only their operations are novel — these services are already delivering &lt;strong&gt;use cases that previously did not exist anywhere else&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are at the avant-garde and must try our best to make sure decentralized finance lives to our ideals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I think we should consider radically novel ways of approaching DeFi services design&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need to bring all kind of perspectives, try weird and new stuff again and again until we crack the nut and figure out the tools most fitted to our needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tkb-x-tkb-using-linguistics-to-improve-dapp-ux&#34;&gt;TkB x TkB: Using linguistics to improve dApp UX
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, at my level, I went back to my first loves: literature and linguistics and thought about how to use them to better the UX of a DeFi wallet. I did a quick trial run on the onboarding of the Monolith wallet — the results are insightful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find them here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/TokenBrice/blog/blob/master/static/others/monolith-semantic-analysis.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📔 Monolith App Semantic Analysis v0.1 - Initial Draft | 04/05/2020&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out if this UX writing angle is an approach you&amp;rsquo;d like to explore or implement in your dApp design process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ♥ love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TokenBrice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PS: The use of the term&lt;code&gt;Great Filter&lt;/code&gt; is a direct reference to the Fermi Paradox. To learn more about it, check out this &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UjtOGPJ0URM&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;intro video from Kurzgesagt&lt;/a&gt; (Also the base image used for the cover of this article, thanks 🙏)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
