<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Liquidity Providing on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/liquidity-providing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Liquidity Providing on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/liquidity-providing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>BadgerDAO&#39;s story: an intro through DIGG</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/badger-digg/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/badger-digg/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/cover.png/" alt="Featured image of post BadgerDAO&#39;s story: an intro through DIGG" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite launching barely a few weeks ago, BadgerDAO quickly grew into a DeFi powerhouse now &lt;strong&gt;hosting &amp;gt; $1.2B of assets farming&lt;/strong&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;ve quickly touched on Badger in previous articles or shows, I think it&amp;rsquo;s about time for a dedicated piece focusing on DIGG but not forgetting about its context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-quick-intro-to-badger-dao&#34;&gt;A quick intro to Badger DAO
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;BadgetDAO is a community-driven project with a clear value proposition: to help &lt;strong&gt;build the infrastructure needed to relay BTC into DeFi&lt;/strong&gt;. This core vision manifests through all their products, all centered around representations of Bitcoin on Ethereum like wBTC or sBTC and the native tokens - BADGER and now DIGG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clear-value-proposition-btc-on-ethereum-optimizer&#34;&gt;Clear value proposition: BTC on Ethereum optimizer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first layer of this onion is pretty straightforward: Badger offers a Yearn-like service for BTCs on Ethereum: users can deposit tokens representing a position in a Curve BTC pool to earn BADGER &amp;amp; DIGG on top of the native APY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-stats.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-sett-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also vaults (called &amp;ldquo;setts&amp;rdquo;) available for BADGER and DIGG themselves, as well as their respective LP tokens on both Uniswap and SushiSwap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setts function like the Yearn vaults, inspired by the aTokens design on Aave: initially when the vault is launched, the correspondence between the base asset and the vault token is 1:1. As the vault accrues additional tokens through its harvests, the vault token increasingly represents more and more of the underlying asset.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This value proposition by itself is nothing new and could have been delivered by Yearn directly. What makes Badger special is &lt;strong&gt;how the team approaches building the product and the whole underlying vision behind it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;community-focus&#34;&gt;Community-focus
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the start, the community has been put at the center with Badger. It&amp;rsquo;s clearly visible simply by looking at the token distributions&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-breakdown.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-distribution-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/digg-breakdown.png/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;digg-distribution-overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the two largest shares of the supply of both tokens were allocated to the liquidity mining program - rewarding active users of the protocol as well as the DAO&amp;rsquo;s treasury tasked with structuring the long-term operations of the protocol and its growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The airdrops, along with the vaults created a very attractive loop for the receivers: unlike the UNI airdrop where most people choice was to sell or hold, with BADGER &amp;amp; DIGG, people &lt;strong&gt;optimistic about the protocol from the get-go had the chance to compound their airdrop with the vaults&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial BADGER airdrop recognized key actions tied to Bitcoin on Ethereum, as well as gitcoin donors. The second airdrop (DIGG) rewarded interactions with the Badger ecosystem itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the momentum created by the launch and initial distribution, the community was able to sustain it thanks to a blossoming spirit of meming: a distribution of NFT was organized on Meme&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, available to the depositors in the bBADGER sett or wBTC/BADGER Uniswap sett.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of 6 different NFTs were available and the fist one to collect them was able to claim a neat BADGER bounty. Being a holder or farmer of these NFTs was acknowledged in the initial DIGG distribution &amp;amp; their inclusion to Badger as yield multiplier is being discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/badger-nft-satoshi.gif/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;badger-meme-satoshi-nft&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are very bullish on a token price short-term wise, it&amp;rsquo;s usually a bad idea to enter a 50/50 liquidity providing position on it. You&amp;rsquo;ll be much better off simply holding your stack and selling it. If you are worried about this scenario unfolding with Badger or DIGG, you can deposit to the BADGER or DIGG only vaults (no risk of impermanent loss).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;are-you-digging-it-yet&#34;&gt;Are you DIGGing it yet?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG is the second major step of Badger&amp;rsquo;s DAO project: a new type of representation of BTC living on the Ethereum blockchain. Unlike wBTC or renBTC, DIGG is not backed by a fixed supply of BTCs. Instead, it uses the rebase mechanism initiated by Ampleforth to attempt to eventually deliver an asset keeping track of BTC&amp;rsquo;s price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into how DIGG works, let&amp;rsquo;s quickly discuss the pre and post-launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wen-digg&#34;&gt;Wen DIGG?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG&amp;rsquo;s launch was a highly anticipated event. While from the outside it looks like it took longer than what was expected, what happened internally was fascinating: the &lt;strong&gt;initial community gathered around Badger was actively involved in the key decisions surrounding DIGG.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After discussion within the community, it was decided to go with a relatively low starting supply (4000) allowing for a &lt;strong&gt;stress test from the start of the rebase mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;. The rebases also started from the very beginning - 24h after the launch of the token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/badger-digg/wen-digg.jpeg/&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;wen-digg&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Badger being Badger, the hype machine was of course on point with a &amp;ldquo;Wen DIGG?&amp;rdquo; meme contest to make sure everyone was aware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into the meat of it: the rebases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rebases&#34;&gt;Rebases
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGG is what is called an &amp;ldquo;elastic currency&amp;rdquo;, as initiated by Ampleforth. What it means is that the total supply of DIGG is not set, but fluctuates daily based on the time-weighted average price of DIGG against its peg - BTC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more DIGG is &amp;ldquo;off from his peg&amp;rdquo;, meaning its price is superior to the price of BTC, the more the DIGG supply is diluted, with the additional DIGG produced distributed proportionately to all the holders. The mechanism works exactly the same the other way around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like with AMPL, with DIGG all holders (liquidity pool tokens included) are impacted by the rebase, be it positive or negative. However with DIGG, just like with the seigniorage tokens, there is a mechanism to abstract it to allow for a better composability within DeFi: that&amp;rsquo;s bDIGG, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss it right after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebases happen at a set time, for DIGG it&amp;rsquo;s 3pm EST, that&amp;rsquo;s 9 pm for my dear French readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rebase tokens harness mechanisms similar to the ones involved in algorithmic stablecoins / seigniorage tokens, so feel free to read my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/seigniorage-basis-vs-esd.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;previous post on the topic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, after the first day, the genesis rebase was positive and triggered a production and redistribution of about 12% of the initial supply. Several positive rebases followed and DIGG is still trading above peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now the rebase mechanism is quite straightforward but it might be better aligned with the setts incentives in the future to help DIGG maintain its peg.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-step-for-the-setts&#34;&gt;Next step for the setts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With DIGG launched, the next big step for Badger as the protocol is to start increasing its capital efficiency: to put it in simple words - to allow its users to borrow from their setts positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make it clearer (while extrapolating quite a bit): picture the current Badger, with an additional function allowing you to mint DAI from your setts like you do with your vaults on Maker. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, setts would make for quite desirable collateral, considering they accrue in value against the base asset. So BTC setts for instance could be potentially as safe as their underlying assets, accounting for the additional layers of risks involved by the fact that the underlying asset is a Curve LP token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, before we see a native lending market on Badger, I expect to see different &lt;strong&gt;Badger-related tokens and setts accepted as collateral&lt;/strong&gt; on other lending platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this front, I&amp;rsquo;d like to draw your attention to bDIGG in particular. While it represents a position made a 100% of DIGG which rebases, &lt;strong&gt;bDIGG itself does not rebase&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s like a layer of abstraction built on top of DIGG, a rebase-buffer amongst other things. It makes it easier to integrate it into other protocols, and I expect to eventually see a wide range of support for bDIGG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-endgame-for-badgerdao--defi-in-general&#34;&gt;The endgame for BadgerDAO &amp;amp; DeFi in general
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The endgame for Badger would be like what I described before along with a full ecosystem around the CLAW or whatever his name is.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; It would increasingly turn Badger into a more of a Synthetix-like service where holders are given different options of more or less active involvement in the ecosystem, with the appropriate rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As services like Badger integrate money-market components such as borrowing, they &lt;strong&gt;increase the capital efficiency for their users&lt;/strong&gt;. What used to be a representation of BTC producing 20% APY is now the same + you can borrow a share of its value in stablecoin to further increase the yield, if that suits your risk appetite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This logic is bigger than Badger, as it&amp;rsquo;s observed elsewhere too, we could call it the &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;platformization of Defi&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;. Yearn is implementing a similar approach with the Iron Bank where some services will be able to borrow under-collateralized, generating a capital-efficiency moat for the eligible lucky ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, to go back to Badger, moving towards a model like this could mean native &amp;amp; sustained revenue feeds to potentially tie back to Badger. Considering that most of the yields currently come from liquidity mining incentives, that would be quite synergistic to grow out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/dex-value-capture.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;success of the Curve &amp;amp; CRV model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, it makes sense to see more and more protocol adopting elements of it: the gist being giving your holders the options to commit their tokens to participate in governance, tap into the platform revenue streams &amp;amp; boost their own returns obtained by the usage of the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The graphs are coming from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://badgerdao.medium.com/badger-dao-liquidity-mining-launch-b2415301bd31#:~:text=Tokens%20distributed%3A%20%24BADGER%20and%20%24,2nd%20product%20of%20the%20DAO.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Badger&amp;rsquo;s DAO liquidity mining launch announcement&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dontbuymeme.com/collections/badger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Meme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is a distribution mechanism for NFT where users stake a given token (bBADGER in our case) to earn points - pineapples. They can them redeem the pineapples for the NFT of their choice.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not purerly speculative as BadgerDAO is already exploring how it could &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/spadaboom1/status/1354826775801561091?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;harness synergies with UMA and SushiSwap&lt;/a&gt; to achieve a similar end.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-yield-farmer-tier-list/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post 💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;DeFi is like a layered yield cake. When you first walk through the door, making a deposit on Aave and seeing your balance grow puts you in awe. Shortly thereafter, through your own research or discussions with the community, you realize there is more to it &lt;strong&gt;- there could be icing on the cake too!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many ways you could find several streams of yields on a given capital utilizing Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. &lt;strong&gt;Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll exclude out of the box any strategy involving leverage&lt;/strong&gt; - the easiest way to achieve such a feat. There are still a lot of high-quality crops to plant, even without leverage!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, capital efficiency is increasing at a rapid pace in DeFi thanks to novel financial primitives like Compound, Balancer or Curve. It&amp;rsquo;s now possible to &lt;strong&gt;achieve up to 3 layers of returns&lt;/strong&gt;, and there are pools for any risk appetite, from pure stablecoins ones to 100% ERC-20 tokens exposure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Liquidity Wars are merely beginning.&lt;/strong&gt; Follow the governance of the protocol you&amp;rsquo;re invested in closely, it&amp;rsquo;s even more critical now. Meanwhile, since DeFi feels more and more like gaming, allow me to import a concept inherited from there: tier list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In video games, tier lists are useful to navigate the different types of characters or builds. They establish both a typology and a ranking. Today, we&amp;rsquo;ll bring this concept back to DeFi to arrange the most attractive liquidity pools into coherent groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;before-we-start&#34;&gt;BEFORE WE START
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ℹ Please note - This content assumes a basic understanding of the world of Ethereum&amp;rsquo;s decentralized finance. Refer to my earlier articles if that&amp;rsquo;s the first time you&amp;rsquo;ve heard of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This piece will not cover basic DeFi investment strategies, detailed in the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 DeFinancial Services Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information regarding the tools you can use to implement and manage these strategies, please check &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not investment advice and reading this document as anything more than a structured list of incentivised liquidity pools would be a misrepresentation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;suggest-yours&#34;&gt;Suggest yours!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This post can be a living document. Feel free to suggest incentivised pools I&amp;rsquo;ve missed. If you are familiar with Github, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/TokenBrice/blog/blob/master/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;you can do a pull request&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If not, just reach out and share documentation about the pool and its incentive program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, allow me to make the distinction between:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Mining&lt;/strong&gt;: a base action of the platform (such as supply liquidity) is rewarded with the platform native token (ex: BAL on Balancer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Incentive Programs&lt;/strong&gt;: a specific liquidity pool is eligible for extra rewards, through staking of the pool token or weekly distributions (ex: Wednesday for JRT Balancer pools).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news is: you can stack both! Let&amp;rsquo;s see how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/yield-farmer-tier-list.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;TokenBrice-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List-DeFi&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-1-defi-yield-trifecta&#34;&gt;Tier 1: DeFi Yield Trifecta
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I walk you through the main earning-staking opportunities I&amp;rsquo;ve found, I will also share broader considerations about providing liquidity on AMMs, such as thoughts on the pool weighting to help you make informed decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we chase our wildest dream, the highly-thought-after yield trifecta, let&amp;rsquo;s take a minute to consider what it looks like. When it comes to yields, the cream of the crop is usually an incentivised &amp;amp; balanced Balancer pool with low fees, meaning it&amp;rsquo;s eligible for the maximum amount of BAL liquidity mining rewards, on top of the liquidity incentive program (&amp;amp; the commissions on swaps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is exactly one Balancer pool matching these criteria with 2 stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; to my knowledge, so this is where we start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-50-musd--50-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;The 50% mUSD / 50% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;mstable&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a meta-stablecoin. You can go on their app to lock your USDT, USDC, DAI &amp;amp; TUSD to mint mUSD. Once you own mUSD, several earning opportunities are available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most direct one is the &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; feature on the mStable app. It will lock your mStable tokens and generate a return through lending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/mstable.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that&amp;rsquo;s a simple yield and won&amp;rsquo;t deserve a feature here by itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s the perfect introduction to the Balancer mUSD/USDC pool, our first trifecta of the day. What&amp;rsquo;s a trifecta you ask? Pretty simple: 3 layers of yields:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commissions on swaps&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s a liquidity pool facilitating trades and earning a fee.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BAL liquidity mining&lt;/strong&gt;- this is a balanced 50/50 pool with low fee (5 bps) earning the maximum amount of BAL possible (mining factor = 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/mstable/introducing-meta-mta-mstables-protocol-token-6e1032291ccf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MTA liquidity incentives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; program on this pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% USDC&lt;br/&gt;50 %mUSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;MTA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 26 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;?? BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 000 MTA/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Native rewards = earned in the same token as the exposure (usually a commission fee taken on trades facilitated)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note: The respective ratios of four stablecoins backing the mUSD (half of the exposure) can vary, go to the m stable app&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to view it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/musd.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;mstable-asset-distribution&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is particularly attractive because the exposure is 100% stablecoin-based, despite a very solid yield thanks to the max BAL mining ratio + the incentive program paid in the highly anticipated MTA token.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note/Warning: 💬 Discussions are ongoing in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.com/invite/ARJWaeF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Balancer Discord&lt;/a&gt; governance channel to lower the BAL mining ratio on this pool. It was lowered to 0.1 for tokens tracking the same asset.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9010-incentivised-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;90/10 Incentivised Balancer Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;90-snx--10-usdc-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;90% SNX / 10% USDC Balancer Pool
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feel like you missed out on SNX rise? For medium capitals (&amp;lt; 5000 SNX) it makes little sense to stake if you account for the gas costs. This pool is a great alternative for a bullish SNX exposure with great yield potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% SNX&lt;br/&gt;10% USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5 Jun 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;DONE&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, since the pool is heavily skewed towards SNX, the BAL mining is not maximized. Remember the factor of 1 for the BAL mining on the mUSD pool? Here it&amp;rsquo;s 0.36: you get about a third of the amount of BAL you would mine in a 50/50 &amp;amp; low-fee pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, 90/10 pools are great to heavily minimize impermanent losses risk if you believe the token has a lot of upside potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/balancer-snx-usdc-liquidity-trial/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;incentive program on this pool is now over&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s back to being a regular twofecta pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;jrt-balancer-pools&#34;&gt;JRT Balancer Pools
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jarvis Network offers an incentive program over three pools, all 90 % JRT + 10% DAI, ETH or USDC. The reward model is similar to the previous pool:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;90% JRT&lt;br/&gt;10% ETH, DAI or USDC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;JRT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Jun 17 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;23 % for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;70 000 JRT/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/jarvis-network/liquidity-program-with-balancer-db23aa0ce10&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: JRT price&amp;rsquo;s action has been quite explosive lately. DYOR.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⚡ Update (&lt;em&gt;July 08&lt;/em&gt;): JRT rewards are now distributed to ANY Balancer pool (whitelisted):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ampl-geyser&#34;&gt;AMPL Geyser
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;AMPL is a beast of its own, so I invite you to read more on it &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; before you dive into this one. Here, the exposure is 50 % ETH and 50 % AMPL. On top of your commissions, you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for extra AMPL &amp;amp; as well as the AMPL rebalances (on your AMPL = 50% of the exposure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50 % ETH&lt;br/&gt;50 % AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;AMPL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;April 21st 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable - AMPL Rebalances&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;36 911 AMPL/month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ampltalk.org/app/forum/ampl-geyser-19/topic/about-the-geyser-21/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖 AMPL Geyser Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rebalances compounded impact can be hard to calculate. This spreadsheet recently emerged to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.publish0x.com/canuhodl/ampleforth-dollar-ampl-calculator-spreadsheet-for-investors-xmdjxvy&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧮 help AMPL investors calculate the impact of the rebalances.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ampleforth-geyser&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geyser code is audited&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; and insured on Nexus Mutual&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The reward calculation here takes into account the time staked - so this pool is best utilised over the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-2-how-many-fecta-can-there-be&#34;&gt;Tier 2: How many fecta can there be?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;synthetix-incentivised-pools&#34;&gt;Synthetix Incentivised Pools
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Synthetix has been pioneering liquidity incentive programs with the early Uniswap sETH/ETH pool (+SNX incentives). Synthetic pools are still highly attractive, we&amp;rsquo;ll consider the two main ones of interest for yield stakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note the Curve&amp;rsquo;s token (CRV), one of the liquidity mining rewards of both pools presented below, is not live yet. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/curvefi/curve-dao-contracts/blob/master/doc/readme.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CRV currently documented mechanisms&lt;/a&gt; can change before the launch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-og-curve-susd-pool&#34;&gt;The OG: Curve sUSD Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just like the mUSD/USDC pool, this pool exposure is 100% in stablecoins, yet the rewards are paid in SNX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;31.58 % USDT&lt;br/&gt;30.67% USDC&lt;br/&gt;24.62% suSD&lt;br/&gt;13.13% DAI&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Aprill 22 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;CRV (not live yet)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;48 000 SNX / week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/new-curve-pool-launch/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pool is one of the earliest liquidity mining programs there is yet still quite competitive. If you&amp;rsquo;ve read my previous guides, you know about this already&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-btc-og-variant-curve-renbtcsbtcwbtc&#34;&gt;The BTC-OG Variant: Curve renBTC/sBTC/wBTC
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/curve-btc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;curve-synthetix-balancer-ren-btc-pool&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is similar to the first one, with different tokens. Here, your price exposure is 100% in BTC, while your liquidity mining rewards are made of four hot DeFi tokens: BAL, SNX, REN &amp;amp; CRV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;44.54% renBTC&lt;br/&gt;32.21% wBTC&lt;br/&gt;23.26% sBTC&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;SNX, REN, BAL &amp;amp; CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June 19 2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~5 %&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;BAL&lt;br/&gt;CRV&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;10 000 SNX/week&lt;br/&gt;25 000 REN/week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.synthetix.io/btc-yield-farming-pool/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📖Incentive Program Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because these two Curve pools have full exposure in a stable (USD) or relatively stable assets (BTC), they are a great resource to &amp;ldquo;park&amp;rdquo; profits realised on more risky ERC-20 based pools. You still &lt;strong&gt;maintain a decent APR on the base asset (~3-5%) while having a nice upside potential on the liquidity mining rewards&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tier-3-twofecta-are-nice-too&#34;&gt;Tier 3: Twofecta are nice too!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-favorite-erc-20-balancer-pool&#34;&gt;Your Favorite ERC-20 Balancer Pool
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Balancer exchange comes with built-in BAL mining incentives. They apply to any pool involving whitelisted tokens. Therefore, any Balancer pool is already a twofecta: you&amp;rsquo;re eligible for commissions on the swaps facilitated + the BAL mining rewards. Please keep in mind that the pool weighting (ideally balanced) and fees (ideally low) affect the BAL mining ratio. The table below assume a ratio of 1, observed for instance on 50/50 pairs with 5 bps fees (0.05%).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the return profile generic Balancer pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;50% wETH&lt;br/&gt;50% ERC20&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;~60% for a $10 BAL&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond Balancer, Liquidity incentives programs are getting into fashion, expect more to be revealed, as well as liquidity mining programs. You can &lt;strong&gt;use a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://pools.fyi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool FYI&lt;/a&gt; which now has an &amp;ldquo;Incentivised&amp;rdquo; tag to check for the best opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;. For Balancer, use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/balancer/%5B%5D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; to explore the pools and check their BAL mining factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compound-deposit&#34;&gt;Compound Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of COMP, a Compound deposit could also be considered a twofecta. Indeed, on top of the base APR the deposit is earning, users are also now eligible for COMP rewards. You can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/compound/None&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;calculate them here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;EXPOSURE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;REWARDS IN&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;AVAILABLE SINCE&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L1 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L2 APY&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;L3 APY / INCENTIVE BUDGET&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Depends&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Native&lt;br/&gt;COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;June&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Variable in COMP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-risk-breakdown---read-this&#34;&gt;⚠ RISK BREAKDOWN - READ THIS
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each pool comes with its own sets of risk, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview to help you account for them. When you invest in a liquidity pool, you&amp;rsquo;re assuming the following risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ The base Ethereum network risk (51% attack, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ You&amp;rsquo;re also assuming the risk carried by the token contracts of any token involved in the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ As well as the risk involved to the exchange&amp;rsquo;s contracts, which can be hacked or faulty to begin with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/ALWAYS/ An economic risk, the impermanent losses (loss vs raw holding) - that will be heavily affected by your token choices &amp;amp; the pool weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;/WHILE ENTERING &amp;amp; EXITING/ The risks associated with any service you use, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;, for the time of the transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will walk you through the risk profile of one of the pools to help you model it: the mUSD/USDC pool. Just like the returns, the risk profile is a cake with many layers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t develop on the Ethereum network risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we have two tokens in the pool: mUSD &amp;amp; USDC. To compute the risk, we need to look at what&amp;rsquo;s backing mUSD - unwrapping, we&amp;rsquo;re exposed to: USDC, USDT, TUSD. Each of these tokens carry their own risks, since for instance &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://support.usdc.circle.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001314526-Circle-USDC-Risk-Factors&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Circle can freeze USDC balances of any account&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here, we&amp;rsquo;re using Balancer. Their contracts were audited by Trail of Bits recently&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Still, the protocol is quite recent. We&amp;rsquo;re also relying on mStable contracts for the mUSD.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re lucky on the impermanent losses - considering the pool involves two stablecoins, the risk is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It all depends on the tools you&amp;rsquo;re using here. Bear in mind that you&amp;rsquo;re also assuming a risk associated with mUSD/Mstable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/gregoireljda&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Grégoire&lt;/a&gt; for his help proofreading this article.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/otherbright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; for his careful review of the FR translation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mstable.org&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable&lt;/a&gt; is a &amp;ldquo;meta stablecoin&amp;rdquo; aggregating several stablecoins together (USDC, USDT, TUSD &amp;amp; DAI) under the mUSD token, while the underlying supply is mobilised similarly to Curve (lending and liquidity providing).&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the current mUSD underlying distribution on the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.mstable.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;mStable app&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://ampleforth.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ampleforth (AMPL)&lt;/a&gt; is &amp;ldquo;adaptive money built on sound economics&amp;rdquo;. It intends to provide a new type of asset which price movement is uncorrelated from any other.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ampleforth/ampleforth-audits/blob/master/token-geyser/v1.0.0/CertiK_Verification_Report.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Certik - Audit Report 28 Feb 2020&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently 51 643 NXM staked on the AMPL Geyser Contract &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/address/0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;code&gt;0xd36132e0c1141b26e62733e018f12eb38a7b7678&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list/ampl-geyser-insurance.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;cover-Yield-Farmer-Tier-List&#34;
	
	
&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Curve sUSD pool was already mentioned as part of a DeFi investment strategy built on an SNX stake in the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/#5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFinancial Service Guide&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-definancial-farming-toolbox/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-definancial-farming-toolbox/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post 🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Howdy farmer,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you made it here, we will assume a shared basic understanding of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethereumprice.org/guides/article/yield-farming/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;what yield farming is&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might even have tried it by yourself, or heard the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiweekly.substack.com/p/tales-from-a-yield-farmer&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tales from a yield farmer&lt;/a&gt;: amazing! Today, it’s my turn to share key concepts &amp;amp; a curated list of tools to help you make the most out of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If by any chance you landed here without any idea of what &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethhub.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is, please click these links. This is not a guide, I keep it short &amp;amp; sweet with pointers only - Let’s get started!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;organic-defarming&#34;&gt;Organic DeFarming
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Farming used to be simple: you planted some seeds and hopefully collected yields. Nowadays, we have some &lt;strong&gt;super crops&lt;/strong&gt;, landing extra yields on top of usual commissions on the swaps facilitated or fees collected on lending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How? Essentially because &lt;strong&gt;some DeFi platforms like Compound or Balancer are now incentivising users to perform actions critical to the service;&lt;/strong&gt; such as supplying liquidity and borrowing for Compound. Their users are rewarded with their native governance token (COMP in this case). Pricing such token is a hard task the markets are currently crunching on. Price stability of these token may take time as they are currently in price discovery mode&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So before we go any further, it’s time to hear a tale from Stani, an organic farmer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is needed is sustainable farming. In essence, farmers should farm quality crops by bringing quality liquidity for long term and keeping the seeds of these crops to expand their farms to new lands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stani Kulechov, Aave&amp;rsquo;s CEO &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/StaniKulechov/status/1276093091624226816?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll dive deeper into this later, but the overall &lt;strong&gt;high average gas prices are incentivising you to pick solid crops and stick with them&lt;/strong&gt; instead of foraging all around. For more context on liquidity mining, I’d also recommend reading this piece about the SAFG framework:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally the SAFG shifts us from a world of “buying to own” to one of “participating to govern,” which can ultimately result in more successful protocols and healthier communities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/ideo-colab/meet-the-safg-defis-emergent-framework-for-participatory-investing-and-protocol-development-62286a576fb5&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Intro - SAFG Framework&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;liquidity-mining-sources&#34;&gt;Liquidity Mining Sources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here are the main liquidity mining sources, ordered by the share of tokens available through liquidity mining:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balancer Labs - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/balancer-protocol/proposing-balancer-liquidity-mining-cab4503972fa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL&lt;/a&gt; - 100M total supply, 75M distributed through liquidity mining (75%), since June 1 - includes some externally incentivized pools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curve Finance - CRV ??? - there is currently little to no public information available.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compound Finance - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/compound-finance/expanding-compound-governance-ce13fcd4fe36&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;COMP&lt;/a&gt; - 10M total supply, ~4.2M through liquidity mining (42%), since June 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Universal Market Access - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defirate.com/safg/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;UMA&lt;/a&gt; ~ 35% of the supply through mining (details TBD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthetix &amp;amp; other incentives program (like JRT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jarvis x Aave &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sponsoring.jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Onramp Sponsoring Program&lt;/a&gt;: redirect interest earned form your stablecoins on Aave to earn JRT tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/synthetix-liquidity-mining.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;synthetix liquidity mining programs&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;adapting-the-strategy-to-your-budget&#34;&gt;Adapting the strategy to your budget
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we see how to get in and out of such positions, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a quick discussion on gas prices. They have been pretty high lately in a 25-35 gwei/fast range. Here&amp;rsquo;s roughly what it means for common operations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Compound ($2-3 gas)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Liquidity Pools @Zapper, an all-in-one tool to handle your liquidity providing positions, more on this below ($3-5 + swap fees)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deposit @Liquidity Pools &amp;ldquo;manually&amp;rdquo; ($0.3 (approve) + $2-3 as many times as tokens as in the pool)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exiting also has a cost, as well as any token swap required (like selling your COMP while exiting your position) $1-3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-cold-hard-look-at-gas-cost-impact-on-medium-capitals--2000&#34;&gt;A cold hard look at gas cost impact on medium capitals ($ 2000)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the returns over time of a 2 000 USDT Deposit @Compound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep this simple, we assume the current parameters will stay as such for the next year. &lt;strong&gt;This is obviously unrealistic - take this as a thought experiment.&lt;/strong&gt; Here were the parameters at the time of writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4% APY on USDT on Compound = $80 for a year on the capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.66 COMP/year =~$150 produced by our capital&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the table below, the &amp;ldquo;Actual Profits&amp;rdquo; column corresponds to a total exit of the position (back to USDT), which means effectively 3 transactions overall for the operation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supplying on Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Withdrawing on Compound&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling the COMP tokens&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if we look at this position with these assumptions over several time frames, here is what we get:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Timeframe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Total Return ($)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Actual Profits ($)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;Effective % return over the timeframe&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 day&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$0.63&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-$8.37&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-0.42%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 week&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$4.42&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-$4.58&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;-0.23%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;1 month&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$23.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$14.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;0.70%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;3 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$57.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$48.50&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;2.43%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;6 months&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$115.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$106.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;5.30%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;A year&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$230.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;$221.00&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td style=&#34;text-align:center&#34;&gt;11.05%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please note: This simplistic scenario ignores the opportunity cost on ETH price. $5 of gas (=ETH) paid today might be worth $10 a year from now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The learning here I wanted to share is that &lt;strong&gt;for such capitals, considering the current gas costs, it will probably be better to stick to a position for months instead of trying to chase the best currently available yield&lt;/strong&gt;. Decent profits (~0.81 % /month) starts around the 3-months timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, remember Stani the farmer? You need to pick your crops wisely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;whales-playground---10-000&#34;&gt;Whale&amp;rsquo;s Playground (&amp;gt; $ 10 000)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now if you have more skin in the game and are willing to take more exposure, gas costs become less prohibitive and there are more options available to you. I won&amp;rsquo;t expand on these, some pointers will be enough:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, you can leverage your Compound exposure to maximize your effective COMP mining (through supply/borrow). It obviously comes with a risk of liquidation. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dsa.instadapp.io/compound&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;InstaDapp&lt;/a&gt; helps you maximize COMP returns by folding your position up to 4x.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a previous article, I&amp;rsquo;ve detailed a strategy built on the Synthetix platform which included another form of small leverage. It observed impressive returns (~200% effectively) since &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/posts/2020/definancial-services-guide/#5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;introduced 5 weeks ago&lt;/a&gt; - mostly due to a significant appreciation of the price of SNX, the largest exposure in this strategy and the very high level of activity on the Curve sUSD pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/yieldburger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Synthetix-Yieldbuger-TokenBrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alright, enough prep - you are now an advised farmer - congrats! Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the tools used to plant your seed, secure your crops and harvest your yields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-in-and-out-of-positions&#34;&gt;Getting in and out of positions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can get into liquidity pools “manually”, that is directly on each platform. It will require several transactions and a proportionate amount of a least two tokens, to begin with. If not, you will also have to swap accordingly beforehand, using a service like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. ParaSwap also helps you get into tokens like cDAI (interest-bearing DAI from Compound) from any other ERC20 with gas and price-efficient paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Balancer just add the option to enter a liquidity pool from &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jbrukh/status/1276958110024896514?s=20&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;just one token&lt;/a&gt; (-&amp;gt; getting up to 8 tokens from 1, watch for slippage!).&lt;/em&gt; 🔥&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not the most familiar with Ethereum yet, the easiest way for you to partake in this feast would be to use tools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/zapper-fi.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zapper.Fi-zap-in-liquidity-pools&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting in and out of pools&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;: in the Invest tab, Zapper lets you conveniently get into/out of pools on Balancer, Curve, and Uniswap, from ETH, DAI and a few other tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying ETH &amp;amp; using DeFi services&lt;/strong&gt; like Aave (gas free on Aave for now!) - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spending ETH &amp;amp; stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith&lt;/a&gt;. Now with ParaSwap built-in for swaps and soon an on-ramp to buy ETH/ERC-20 from your bank account!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/monolith.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;monolith&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we’re at it, here’s a quick tip because I see this way too much.
&lt;strong&gt;You should never claim on Compound.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s costly and your COMP tokens are automatically claimed every time you adjust your position by depositing or withdrawing assets (minimal amount of COMP claimable required).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-definancial-farmers-essential-toolbox&#34;&gt;The DeFinancial Farmer&amp;rsquo;s Essential Toolbox
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that we’ve explained  the basics dear organic farmers, it’s time to finally have a look at that promised toolbox. You&amp;rsquo;ll find below tools that help you track your positions and the markets &amp;amp; analyse the potential returns of strategies you think about applying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of helping you zap in/out of pools, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zapper.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.fi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an amazing all-in-one DeFi position tracker. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zapper.fi/synthetix?address=0x4E60bE84870FE6AE350B563A121042396Abe1eaF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Zapper of the wallet&lt;/a&gt; of the legendary farmer &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/DegenSpartan&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DegenSpartan&lt;/a&gt; - seems like he took a bite into that juicy yieldburger:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/degen.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Zapper.fi - DegenSpartan&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you need to look at a wallet from a historical perspective, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zerion.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zerion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a more holistic market view, you can check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://defimarketcap.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiMarketCap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see the main DeFi tokens and the prices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://defipulse.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DefiPulse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to see the main platforms ranked by total assets locked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.tokenterminal.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Token Terminal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; for an overview of the earnings and P/E ratio of DeFi protocols&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://explore.duneanalytics.com/public/dashboards/c87JEtVi2GlyIZHQOR02NsfyJV48eaKEQSiKplJ7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;This &lt;strong&gt;Dune Analytics&lt;/strong&gt; dashboard&lt;/a&gt; giving you an overview of the volume on DEXes:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox/DEX.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DEX volumes overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;⛽ You can also use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/HAL_team&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HAL&lt;/a&gt; to create notifications on different situations, like &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@mattiascaricato/get-notified-when-gas-price-is-cheap-%EF%B8%8F-2a157a3d18b9&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;when gas prices are below a certain threshold&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;platform-specific-resources&#34;&gt;Platform-specific resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Synthetix / Yearn&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are so many pools and opportunities, it can be hard to keep track! Luckily, some really neat yield farmer tools are being developped. For Synthetix and Yearn.Finance especially, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yieldfarming.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;yieldfarming.info&lt;/a&gt; is a neat ressource&lt;/strong&gt; to keep track of both platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll find an &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://explore.duneanalytics.com/public/dashboards/JMB9bYfVUtMAPHM5moj7aIjLaDwos2k9JjJTtk64&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;overview of the COMP tokens mining &amp;amp; claims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; here. Use this tool to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/compound/None&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;calculate the expected COMP returns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; obtained by supplying or borrowing tokens on Compound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balancer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Compound, you can estimate your BAL mining: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.predictions.exchange/balancer/%5B%5D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL Distribution Calculator&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you intend to use Balancer, I&amp;rsquo;d also recommend brushing up on the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygwei.substack.com/p/striking-a-balancer-the-daily-gwei&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BAL token distribution early shenanigans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RealT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liquidity mining returns are quite variable, so on the side you might want to consider tokenised real estate for more predictable returns with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt;. Here are two main helpful resources: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt-dashboard.co/portfolio/0x51a7ead10340af963c3124b026b86dd2807c2b1c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;see owners &amp;amp; earnings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; + &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.sigri44.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Amazing Google Sheets to help you track your profits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - both are made by the community so feel free to thank their creators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Various&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aavewatch.now.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;follow Aave&amp;rsquo;s market using AaveWatch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. If you are a TokenSet user, &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://tokenviz.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenViz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; will help you make sense of the sets&amp;rsquo; performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;keeping-track-with-the-defi-news&#34;&gt;Keeping track with the DeFi news
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To learn more on DeFi, here are a few resources I&amp;rsquo;d recommend:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bankless.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bankless Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, Podcast, Livestream, discussions: all of it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://thedailygwei.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Daily Gwei&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - a short and sweet daily read on a key event/release
-&amp;amp; you can find me discussing DeFi every week with my friend Abel here: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://abelsabstracts.substack.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abel Abstracts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parting-words&#34;&gt;Parting Words
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s Gitcoin grant season so please indulge this closure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been in the space for a bit, hopefully even making some profits? How about sharing a small share back, let&amp;rsquo;s say 2 %, to critical infrastructure projects and to support your favourite DeFi services or content producers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your contributions are immensely appreciated and can have a great impact, even for just 1 DAI thanks to the CLR matching. So if you liked this piece or my contributions to the DeFi space overall, feel free to have a look at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/811/tokenbrice-shining-light-on-ethereums-defi-en-fr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my Gitcoin grant&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will help me fund more initiatives for the French community &amp;amp; help to go on with content production efforts like this one. Every contribution makes a difference, even 1 DAI (currently matched +5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you are on Gitcoin with a grant in your basket, why not add more? Feel free to look around and support critical initiatives, from vulgarisation efforts to core research. Remember the gas struggles? You can &lt;strong&gt;donate to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gitcoin.co/grants/946/project-title-eip-1559-community-fund&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;EIP 1559 Community Fund&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to help on that front too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading &amp;amp; happy farming!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;thanks&#34;&gt;Thanks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; who helped make sure this article is as clear as it can be.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/OtherBright&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jon&lt;/a&gt; for his help proofreading this article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; To &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AntoineMouran?s=09&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Antoine&lt;/a&gt; for his various suggestions to improve this content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>📖 How to make DeFinancial products work for you</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-definancial-products-work-for-you/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 10:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/how-to-make-definancial-products-work-for-you/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post 📖 How to make DeFinancial products work for you" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new economic paradigm!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you landed here, you probably already have heard about Ethereum and even decentralised finance (DeFi). That&amp;rsquo;s great - today we take it to the next step: how to use DeFi to better your personal finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article walks you through 6 base strategies and their variants that harness the most relevant DeFinancial services. We start with the &amp;ldquo;set and forget&amp;rdquo; strategies and progressively move down the stack towards the more complex but also lucrative ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into the strategies, I URGE you to read attentively the primer on gas below &amp;amp; as well as the disclaimers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This article is not investment advice. I am not an accredited investor or asset manager. I am just a 27 year old dude using DeFinancial services abundantly and highly active in the space.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU ARE THE ONLY ONE RESPONSIBLE FOR YOUR INVESTMENT DECISIONS.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-primer-on-gas&#34;&gt;A primer on gas
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ℹ If you know what gas is, feel free to ignore, else - please read this:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All strategies described here are enabled thanks to decentralised finance services and executed on the Ethereum network. &lt;strong&gt;To interact with DeFi services, you&amp;rsquo;ll have to pay for the commons of the Ethereum network - and that&amp;rsquo;s what gas costs are.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas costs are paid in gwei, a subunit of ETH (1 gwei =  0.000000001 ETH). Most Ethereum wallets will suggest a default gas price. That&amp;rsquo;s usually enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as you dive deeper into the arcane of DeFi, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself coming back to gas to understand it better and optimise your transaction costs. Indeed, depending on the gas cost you pick (vs network observed one), your transaction will clear quickly, slowly, or not at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/gas-station.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;eth-gas-station&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ethgasstation.info/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;check recommended gas prices on ⛽ EthGasStation&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.ethhub.io/using-ethereum/transactions/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;📑 EthHub Docs on Ethereum Transactions&lt;/a&gt; to learn more about gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Some strategies listed below (1, 3 &amp;amp; 4) are applicable without having to worry about gas, using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re almost ready to go in! I just have some necessary disclaimers to share with you to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re on the same level &amp;amp; you understand the content presented below for what it is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;necessary-reminders---please-read&#34;&gt;Necessary reminders - PLEASE READ
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All returns discussed in the articles are yearly APR (Annual Percentage Rate)&lt;/strong&gt; - to realise these APR (assuming the estimation is accurate), you need to hold your position for a year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There are no objective measurements of complexity or risk&lt;/strong&gt; - the parameters I present you with while introducing a strategy are here for understanding only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;risk&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; represent? A chance of losing your assets due to market events or your own shortcomings (usually stemming from a lack of understanding)  &lt;br&gt;
The &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;complexity&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; score gives you an idea of how technical and hard the risk is to understand and estimate.
&lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Please note: the risk of a failure at the Ethereum network-level is not equal to 0. I do not mention this risk again below - it&amp;rsquo;s implied as a base-level of risk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are no free lunches: be sensible with your decisions, here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;quick rule of  thumb &amp;ldquo;the higher the APR, the higher the risk&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When markets go wild (either way), some products are affected more than others. While a sudden ETH price variation doesn&amp;rsquo;t impact RealT&amp;rsquo;s APR (2) - it can translate into significant losses for users of TokenSets or liquidity providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, keep in mind that most of the APR mentioned below change quite often. Don&amp;rsquo;t take them as such, especially if you read this piece weeks after its release: double check by yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering committing capital to a given project, &lt;strong&gt;I URGE YOU&lt;/strong&gt; to check the following ressources to learn more on their risk model &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.defiscore.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiScore&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defiwatch.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiWatch&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/defiscore.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;defi-score&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;passive-definancial-services&#34;&gt;PASSIVE DEFINANCIAL SERVICES
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Products 1-4 are &amp;ldquo;set and forget&amp;rdquo; (please monitor your positions still). What&amp;rsquo;s meant is that entry is usually done through a simple purchase/swap - and so is the exit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Meanwhile, in between the two, you have nothing to do to earn your yield - it&amp;rsquo;s paid to you without requiring any intervention (claim or other).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;with-stable-assets&#34;&gt;With Stable Assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some passive investment products involve only stablecoins - these are tokens tracking the price of a stable currency, usually the dollar. Considering the minimal amount of work required to use them, and the lower overall risk (mostly technical failure) these products are the best to get you started with decentralised finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-stablecoins-yield&#34;&gt;1/ Stablecoins Yield
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own an Ethereum-based asset tracking the price of the dollar (ex: DAI). You find a way for this asset to earn interest: lending (ex: aDAI) or liquidity providing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1 = lowest, 5 = highest)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/1-stablecoin-yield.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;1-stablecoin-yield&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yield-bearing stablecoins are the gateway drug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They can provide decent returns (up to 8-9% APR), are convenient to use and also not too complex so they are a good start to understand some fundamentals about DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in and out is as easy as swapping a token. So, if while considering this approach, you only have three things to keep in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk: base stablecoin risk (on DAI) + any service on top of it (ex: Aave for aDAI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return: there are some neat ressources to keep track with the yields, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://loanscan.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;LoanScan&lt;/a&gt; for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gas costs to get in &amp;amp; out (especially &lt;strong&gt;if you invest small amounts, or while the network is busy&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement this first strategy, you have several options: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://compound.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Compound&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt;, etc. You can acquire their corresponding tokens (cDAI, aDAI, iDAI) using a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://paraswap.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt;. In terms of APR, historically, aDAI has been consistently topping the charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to expand on top of the base concept, you have several options offering better returns (meaning more risk):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-a-implementing-a-basic-stablecoin-yield-based-strategy&#34;&gt;1-A/ Implementing a basic stablecoin-yield based strategy
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RECAP: You own an Ethereum-based asset dynamically rebalancing between several stablecoins providing yields to optimise your return.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As said above, there are several services offering stablecoins providing returns thanks to lending pools. You can manually chase the best rate yourself, but will require you to monitor the rates and do the rebalances yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead, why not use an Ethereum native service to do that for you in full transparency? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://idle.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Idle Finance&lt;/a&gt; is the leading solution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/idle-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;idle-dai&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-b-stablecoins-liquidity-providing-curve-pools&#34;&gt;1-B/ Stablecoins Liquidity Providing: Curve Pools
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own several Ethereum-based stablecoins and help facilitate trades on Curve (= liquidity provider). You earn a commission on each trade corresponding to the prorata of your share of the pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will have a dedicated section about liquidity pools below but I had to mention the Curve Pools here. In a gist, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://curve.fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Curve&lt;/a&gt; is a service made to optimize stablecoin swaps. Providing liquidity on Curve can be quite attractive since the base assets are all stablecoins &amp;amp; the returns provided by the commissions collected on the swaps (&amp;amp; lending) are decent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;1-c--no-loss-lottery-pool-together&#34;&gt;1-C / No loss lottery: Pool Together
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You lock a stablecoin (DAI or USDC) for a week or a month. They are pooled with other users&amp;rsquo; to generate interest (-&amp;gt;Compound). At the end of the week/month, the winner gets all the interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love this one because it&amp;rsquo;s both surprising to see it here and amazing. So first, let me clear the air: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether&lt;/a&gt; is not a financial product per-se - their vision is more pedagogic: PoolTogether is a money game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept is quite simple, as described in the recap. Since all the profits of the winner are generated on the interests of all players, nobody loses any money with PoolTogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However please rest assured, the addition of PoolTogether in this list is not ideological: **average returns are superior to Compound. &lt;strong&gt;The reason why is quite simple: PoolTogether uses Compound to generate its return (= same APR) + each pool has some &amp;ldquo;sponsored&amp;rdquo; ticket - tickets contributing to the interest accrual, but without winning chances.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/pt-sponsored.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;pool-together-sponsored-balances&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, with the average APR is higher, please bear in mind that PoolTogether is much less regular - most of the time you&amp;rsquo;ll get nothing, but if you win you get the equivalent of years of interest on your capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PoolTogether essentially provides a new flavor of interest distribution on top of Compound&amp;rsquo;s return: PT&amp;rsquo;s returns are much more random but also potentially massive (if lucky).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/pooltogether/winning-more-prizes-185bad7f6d63&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PoolTogether released the pods&lt;/a&gt; - a new option for users to play as a group. Users can now share their odds and their gains - which makes the wins less significant but much more frequent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.pooltogether.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;You can play the PoolTogether lottery directly from their website.&lt;/a&gt; You&amp;rsquo;ll need some DAI or USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;2-tokenized-real-estate---realt&#34;&gt;2/ Tokenized Real Estate - RealT
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own shares of tokenized properties (securities). You earn your share of the rent daily (currently in USDC) + extra earning opportunities (liquidity providing, incentive programs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/2-tokenised-real-estate.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;2-realt-tokenised-real-estate&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://realt.co&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;RealT&lt;/a&gt; is a totally different beast from anything else in that list, at several levels&lt;/strong&gt;. Since RealT tokens represents real estate in the real world, the risk profile is also totally different (~~&amp;gt;  less Ethereum risk, more real-word risk).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into what makes RealT tokens so interesting, let&amp;rsquo;s make sure we are clear. &lt;strong&gt;RealT tokens are securities - you have to go through a KYC process to be able to purchase them&lt;/strong&gt; (whitelist + lease agreement).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/realt.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RealT-tokenised-real-estate&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit more work than for interest-bearing stablecoins, but you have several benefits to gain here compared to strategy 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Returns&lt;/strong&gt;: depending on the property, APR ranges from 8% to 12.5%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daily payment of returns&lt;/strong&gt;: once you have some RealT tokens in your wallet, you will receive your corresponding** share of the rent, daily, in USDC**.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hedging&lt;/strong&gt;: you have a yield based on real estate - AKA less correlated to the rest of the crypto markets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additional opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;: you can add more to this strategy to increase the return. To do so, consider providing liquidity on Uniswap - generating some returns. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/realtplatform/announcing-the-uniswap-incentive-program-f82f721cf63a&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Providing liquidity on RealT tokens is currently incentivised&lt;/a&gt; - landing even more returns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;with-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;With Volatile Assets
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;3-automated-trading-strategies---tokensets&#34;&gt;3/ Automated Trading Strategies - TokenSets
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You own a &amp;ldquo;set&amp;rdquo; representing a stake in an automated trading strategy based on a technical indicator or another trader (social sets) a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;Holding on autopilot&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/3-tokensets.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;3-tokensets-automated-strategies&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.tokensets.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenSets&lt;/a&gt; are the holders&amp;rsquo; best friend&lt;/strong&gt;. While the service is definitely not the easiest to understand or the less risky, it currently provides significant utility. Indeed, if you are a long term holder of ETH for instance, TokenSets is one of your best options to grow your ETH stash (against ETH).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sets are automated trading strategies represented by a token. Each set trades a given pair (ex: ETH/cUSDC) following a pre-set of rebalancing rules triggered by the cross with the set technical indicator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/tokenviz.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Tokensets performance visualised with TokenViz&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Wondering which set to pick? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenviz.io&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TokenViz&lt;/a&gt; provides a neat dashboard to help you chose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So as a user who is not willing to look at charts all day, TokenSets is an excellent option. Indeed, most people trying to trade tend to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;With the sets, the emotions are out &amp;amp; machines rule.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of the regular sets following a technical indicator (such as ETH 20 Days Moving Average), there are now social sets. It&amp;rsquo;s the same mechanism, but your set will follow another&amp;rsquo;s trader strategy instead of simple technical indicators: aka &amp;ldquo;copy-trader&amp;rdquo; feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;4-simple-yields-to-chase-on-erc20-tokens&#34;&gt;4/ Simple yields to chase on ERC20 tokens
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially the ERC-20 version of strategy 1: you own an ERC-20 (non-stable) token producing some form of returns, usually through lending or liquidity providing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/4-erc20-yields.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;4-erc20-yields&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we explore the more active approaches, allow me to introduce one more passive approach, this time based on ERC20 tokens (not stablecoins.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Aave offers aTokens on up to 15 different ERC-20 tokens, it might be worth for you to keep an eye on them - with a tool like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aavewatch.now.sh/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AaveWatch&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/aavewatch.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;AaveWatch - overview of lending opportunities offered on Aave&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among them, I think the following are the most interesting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aSNX: base rate around 7%, can spike quite high for a bit - keep a very close eye to this one on Wednesdays, especially if prices of ETH/SNX crashed during the week: we observe SNX borrowing surges during certain claim periods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;asUSD: can spikes quite hard too, especially lately (~12% APR over the last month)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aZRX: rates can spike, read more about ZRX to know when&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;aMANA: same here - decentish rate (1-2%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;active-definancial-services&#34;&gt;ACTIVE DEFINANCIAL SERVICES
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Doing nothing is amazing - and when it comes to investing it’s a strategy that can be surprisingly effective&lt;/strong&gt;. Being able to stand still and do nothing, even in the middle of a marketstorm is truly an art you would gain to master. However, and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t come as a surprise for you: the best yield will require effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/nothing.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Doing nothing - the best strategy of them all?&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice how I didn&amp;rsquo;t say work? Sometimes, the &amp;ldquo;efforts&amp;rdquo; can simply be that you accept to stomach a risk others wouldn&amp;rsquo;t, and get paid nicely for it &amp;mdash; &lt;strong&gt;the investor equivalent of a stunt double.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next strategies will require a more precise understanding of what you are doing. Indeed, at their core, all strategies would benefit immensely from your market acumen. So before we explore such strategies, allow me some reminders:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information is power.&lt;/strong&gt; More specifically for DeFi investing: the information you have &amp;amp; understand is the main thing driving the alpha (returns) you&amp;rsquo;re extracting from the markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take it slow, be safe, it&amp;rsquo;s not a race&lt;/strong&gt;. Despite writing this article (with many people advising), I have yet to use strategy 6 with serious amounts of capital for instance. It&amp;rsquo;s wise to double-check your understanding of a given platform every time you increase your stake.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Want to quickstart the process? Go in with $50.&lt;/strong&gt; Small amounts are amazing to help you understand a protocol and be involved without taking too many risks and stressing about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-pointers-on-passive-vs-active-styles&#34;&gt;Some pointers on passive vs active styles
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s impossible to give an accurate representation of the potential earning spread between an average DeFi passive investor and an active one. However, a combination of services reproduces a similar situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synthetix: SNX staking model to collateralise synthetic assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aave + Synthetix = aSNX Passive (type 4) investment asset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;table align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;
&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Actions Required&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Expected Yearly Return &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Passive Style (aSNX)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;None (once you own aSNX)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;~10%&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt; &lt;b&gt;Active Style (SNX stake managed through mintr)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;Weekly claim of reward (1y escrowed) + sUSD + synths management strategy (trading, liquidity+staking)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
   &lt;td&gt;&lt;div align = &#34;center&#34;&gt;~80% &amp; more (up to you)&lt;/div&gt;
   &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-synthetix&#34;&gt;5/ Synthetix
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You start with a stake of SNX (Synthetix token). You stake (lock) them which already generates a neat SNX return but vested for a year (+weekly sUSD non-vested). Thanks to your stake, you can then mint synthetic tokens - that expose yourself for up to 1/8 of the initial SNX value &amp;amp; offer additional earning opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/5-synthetix.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;5-synthetix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before anything else: what I say below is NOT ENOUGH to understand Synthetix+SNX if you are just discovering it. &lt;strong&gt;Do not rush it!&lt;/strong&gt; Synthetix is definitely a next step in terms of complexity, here&amp;rsquo;s an overview of all the new things you will have to do:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a secured wallet - &lt;strong&gt;will you be able to access your wallet in a year?&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;br&gt;
SNX rewards are escrowed a year: you claim them today, but you can only move them out of Mintr (Synthetix platform) a year after the claim date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claim reward weekly&lt;/strong&gt; (SNX vested for a year + sUSD)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor&lt;/strong&gt; your collateralization ratio and adjust when need to be able to claim&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decide&lt;/strong&gt; which Synth you&amp;rsquo;re exposing yourself to and when&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Synthetix is really flexible, allow me to stick to a strategy I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully implemented. Other approaches are possible, and my choice is suggestive. However, I think this strategy does a good job at highlighting the different synergies available with Synthetix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;5-a-the-synthetixcurve-yieldstack-aka-the-4-steaks-yieldburger&#34;&gt;5-A/ The Synthetix/Curve YieldStack (a.k.a. &amp;ldquo;the 4-steaks yieldburger&amp;rdquo;)
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use Synthetix (+SNX) to mint sUSD, a stablecoin, and supply this stablecoin to an incentivised liquidity pool for extra returns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s not beat around the bush: this is much harder, much more work than 1-4, but the returns are an order of magnitude higher if done right. Your position is also more complex to monitor since you are exposed to several types of assets, getting returns in several kinds of assets too, and the timeline of the returns are not the same either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/yieldburger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The Synthetix-Yieldbuger-TokenBrice&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Stake? Steak? Does it matter as long as there is meat on the bone?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s have a look at the base of the yield stack:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Staking SNX + SNX reward&lt;/strong&gt; ~ 50% APR, in SNX, paid weekly (claim required) &amp;amp; vested for a year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sUSD Staking reward&lt;/strong&gt; - variable sUSD reward (based on exchanges volume), paid weekly, claim required, no vesting period.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity Provider Curve sUSD pool&lt;/strong&gt; - 3 to 5% APR, earned while exiting the pool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Incentive Program&lt;/strong&gt; for that pool (accessed by staking the pool token)-  25% APR, in SNX, paid weekly (claim required), no vesting period&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: The Curve sUSD pool ran into some issues, and the current live version is not the most optimised one for returns. A new version of the sUSD pool is coming up, harnessing Aave to optimize it even farther. This strategy might get even more compelling as soon as this ships!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Curious ? Here is a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://synthetix.community/docs/intro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;comprehensive overview to get started with Synthetix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-liquidity-provider-not-on-stablecoins&#34;&gt;6/ Liquidity Provider (not on stablecoins)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You use a capital equally split into to tokens (ex 50% ETH 50% DAI) to supply a liquidity pool, which generates commissions on the trade you help facilitate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/definancial-services-guide/subh/6-liquidity-provider.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;6-liquidity-provider&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially a riskier variant of the strategy 1-B. In this scenario, you are still providing liquidity but this time you move to another kind of pair - the ETH based ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;While you provide liquidity on a decentralised exchange, the main risk you face (on top of the usual) is what we call &amp;ldquo;impermanent losses&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;. (confusing name, they are very permanent)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t explain the full concept here, but here&amp;rsquo;s a quick recap: &lt;strong&gt;impermanent losses usually stem from a sudden variation between the relative prices of the two assets you&amp;rsquo;re providing liquidity to&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So if the two assets are tracking the same price (ex ETH/sETH), the impermanent loss risk is minimized&lt;/strong&gt;. So, from the lower level of risk, to greater, you have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on stablecoins: both assets prices are relatively stable, and they track the same price =&amp;gt; the impermanent losses risk is minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on assets that are not stable but tracking the same price, such as ETH/sETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on an ETH/stable pair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Providing liquidity on a ETH/ERC20 (both non stable &amp;amp; not tracking the same price) - this is where the risk is greater, since both assets can move - if both assets price were to suddenly move in opposite directions you can suffer significant impermanent losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering providing liquidity on AMMs, please read more on the topic: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.bancor.network/beginners-guide-to-getting-rekt-by-impermanent-loss-7c9510cb2f22&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Risk/Reward of liquidity provision in AMMs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edit (07/16)&lt;/em&gt; - If you are curious about liquidity providing, here is another guide covering the main incentivised opportunities: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think this is a good place to call it a run and keep this guide digestible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re ready to jump-in, here are some solutions that will make it easier for you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://argent.xyz/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Argent Wallet&lt;/a&gt; Secure wallet offering one tap access to Aave tokens, PoolTogether &amp;amp; TokenSets presented in this article.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://monolith.xyz&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monolith Visa Debit Card&lt;/a&gt; You&amp;rsquo;ve made some profits in DeFi you&amp;rsquo;d like to cash out in the real world? This is the only no-compromise solution allowing you to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering what could be your next steps, here is are some of your potential ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opening vaults on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt; or using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&lt;/a&gt; to get leverage (⚠ liquidation risk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using options like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://opyn.co/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Opyn&lt;/a&gt; or insurance service such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://nexusmutual.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nexus Mutual&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://aave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Aave&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Flash loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope this was an insightful read and you&amp;rsquo;ve figured a few ways to make DeFinancial services work for you. If you have any questions, feel free to reach out to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://t.me/de_fi&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFi community on Telegram&lt;/a&gt;, or their variants in your native language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article was made possible thanks to a tremendous amount of support from people in the community who shared their suggestions, insights and proofread it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these amazing people:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy Ragosa - follow him on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, his meme game is woke 👌&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lemiscate&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Marc Zeller&lt;/a&gt; - dev advocate @Aave, do I need to say anything more?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marouane - he&amp;rsquo;s coming after your risks, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/UnslashedF&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;watch out!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;mailto:victor@function.media&#34; &gt;Viktor&lt;/a&gt; who worked on the graphics of this article and indulged my terrifying napkin diagrams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as people who did not contribute directly to this specific article but were key in helping me understand DeFinancial services better - allowing me to be in a position to write this guide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/pscltllrd&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pascal Tallarida&lt;/a&gt;: founder of Jarvis Netowrk, proeminent onboarder and vulgariser in the French community. He&amp;rsquo;s the one who helped me (and MANY others) grasp their heard around synthetic assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mounibec&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Mounir&lt;/a&gt;: founder of Paraswap.io, the OG-est of DEX aggregator and still the only one that can fetch a price &amp;lt;1-2s without melting your laptop. Mounir is a one-man-army and an incredibly helpful actor in the French &amp;amp; international communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/AbelsAbstracts&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Abel&lt;/a&gt;: this guy keeps up with everything and he&amp;rsquo;s my go-to person to discuss new releases and see through the marketing. Check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/show/6NO8M2R4u9YSgAdz5TA4ZA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;his amazing podcast&lt;/a&gt; - we do a DeFi catchup every week together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
