<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Advertising Model on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/advertising-model/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Advertising Model on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 15:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/advertising-model/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The attention economy: from engagement to dollars</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-attention-economy-from-engagement-to-dollars/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 15:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-attention-economy-from-engagement-to-dollars/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2019/attention-economy/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post The attention economy: from engagement to dollars" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;The attention economy is the idea that we’re switching to or already exploring a new economic paradigm where the individuals’ attention is the limiting factor. Goods and content became more accessible and cheaper to produce, but they are now facing a demand wall: attention is a scarce resource — a person has only so much of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Our mental capabilities are limited and therefore so is the receptiveness of information.&lt;/strong&gt; With the multiplication and the diversification of content (books, videos, blog posts, social media, etc.), we observe a paradigm shift. &lt;strong&gt;The limiting factor switched&lt;/strong&gt;: we’re running out of captivated eyeballs for all the content that gets produced daily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/attention-economy/60s.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Attention became the new scarce limiting factor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This topic is very dense, as it recoups pretty much the whole digital marketing industry. We will start with some considerations on attention itself before exploring the impact of the attention economy on the format and content of the media we consume. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at the other side of the mirror and see how marketing professionals are addressing this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;attention-the-unit-of-the-neweconomy&#34;&gt;Attention, the unit of the new economy?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attention is a complex phenomenon. We all have a basic understanding of it when we crave for it or get it. However, we often fail to realize how the attention dynamics drive us in our behavior online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-mechanics-of-attention&#34;&gt;The mechanics of attention
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attention is &lt;strong&gt;a resource that can lead us to action&lt;/strong&gt;. Once we have it, we can also pass it to someone else, and put her/him under the spotlight. To understand how attention works in our modern world, considering its relationship with money is vital. We tend to think that money can buy attention yet we fail to recognize that this feat cannot be achieved consistently. &lt;strong&gt;Money cannot reliably buy attention.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money came with a paradigm of value: with its price units, it made it easy to put a price on everything. &lt;strong&gt;Attention is a wholly different beast. It does not come in precise, indistinguishable units&lt;/strong&gt;. The listeners’ identity matter, and so do their level of attention since there’s no absolute. Therefore, within the attention economy, exchanges are more complex than their streamlined monetary counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, just like wealth, attention can build up. Every time you draw attention to you, you somehow build or deplete a stock. If you provide something of interest to your audience, it will grow with each session. With that in mind, we can consider attention like &lt;strong&gt;a kind of enduring wealth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-roots-of-the-attention-economy&#34;&gt;The roots of the Attention Economy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the general public has just recently started to be aware of the attention economy, it’s been theorized a while ago already. To dive deeper into the nature of attention, I recommend to read the transcript of this fascinating conference: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://firstmonday.org/article/view/519/440&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Attention Economy and the Net (1997)&lt;/a&gt;. While Michael H. Goldhaber did not coined the term “attention economy,” his conference helps to understand better where it’s coming from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He draws a metaphor of the switch from the monetary economy to the attention economy using the last major transition as a referral point: the end of the feudal period and the transition to the capitalist economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At the end of the feudal period, the pomp and display of the nobility reached a level never before attained; the most gorgeous armor, the most magnificent tournaments of knights, the most elaborate ceremonies between rival nobles, the most brilliant marriages, the greatest interest in noble lineage. But by then it had lost all real function or importance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So today, when the stock market goes up and up, when money wealth itself seems a source of fame more than ever, when being number one on Forbes 400 list seems the height of perfection, when every basketball superstar wants a contract that is at least a million more than the last record one, we seem to be more dazzled by money than ever, just as we seem to be more intrigued by material goods than ever.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But these interests are superficial and faddish. They are signs of decadence not of a glorious future for the money economy. Even in themselves they speak to the growing desire for attention, the need for it as well. Money is now little more numbers, one number among many, and as a source of lasting attention it can fade in an instant. The attention economy is already here, and more completely so every day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://firstmonday.org/article/view/519/440&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;The Attention Economy and the Net (1997)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;_ — Michael H. Goldhaber_&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-face-of-the-attention-economy-a-brief-history-of-onlinemedia&#34;&gt;The face of the attention economy: a brief history of online media
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The attention economy manifests itself everywhere on the internet nowadays. However, some trends or activity make its realities more palpable than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk consider content farms for a minute. Content farms are low-efforts website made to maximize the audience using a different kind of strategies. Filled with ads, their goal is to develop their audience as much as possible to increase their advertising income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, the strategy was simple: Google was still somehow easy to game. Publications such as Demand Media amassed a large audience with low-value pieces of content optimized for a specific topic. Back then, the actual time spent on the site after a search was not a profoundly impacting factor of a given website ranking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/attention-economy/google-updates.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Two famous updates to Google&amp;rsquo;s ranking algorithm&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Two famous updates to Google&amp;rsquo;s ranking algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2011, Google released an update to its ranking algorithm that impacted content farms: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moz.com/learn/seo/google-panda&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Panda&lt;/a&gt;. Its goal was to reduce the prominence of content farms in the search results. It penalized websites based on different triggers such as thin, low quality and duplicate content, or the overall space occupied by ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-content-farms-to-clickbaits&#34;&gt;From content farms to clickbaits
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Content farms were deeply impacted, as their traffic plummeted. Soon, the activity became unprofitable. However, in the wake of content farms disappearance, the development of social media offered new opportunities for content tricksters. &lt;strong&gt;Content farms imploded, and clickbait and linkbait content quickly took their spot.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of gaming Google, these new media were able to &lt;strong&gt;lure millions of people to junk content using social media&lt;/strong&gt;, and particularly Facebook. They used catchy cover images and mastered the art of producing nonsensical yet attractive headlines. The headlines play on emotions to induce a click:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A school girl gave her lunch to a homeless man. What he did next will leave you in tears!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;15 hilarious tweets of stupid people that makes you think ‘Do these people even exist?’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Supermodels apply these three simple tricks to look young. Click to know what they are&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ashuta Bhattarai provides a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/zerone-magazine/you-wont-believe-how-these-9-shocking-clickbaits-work-number-8-is-a-killer-4cb2ceded8b6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;well-written and highly ironic overview&lt;/a&gt; of the main techniques used to drive clicks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Listicle&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Listicles&lt;/a&gt; (article listing tops) became a recurrent pattern of low-effort yet high-impact articles. While the exhaustive formula of virality is not solved yet, we have a good idea of the different elements that make it. &lt;strong&gt;Emotions, be them positive or negative play are good drivers of shares.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To learn more about t&lt;strong&gt;he impacts the attention economy has on the format of the content published&lt;/strong&gt;, you can read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.frankrose.com/the-attention-economy.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;this fascinating article written by Frank Rose&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This affects all form of content: blog posts of course, but even videos and pictures. Allow to dive into one weird, disturbing and yet very telling example to show what the end-results can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-weird-world-of-kidsyoutube&#34;&gt;The weird world of Kids’ Youtube
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Content optimized to maximize the attention-grabbing and virality potential are plenty and diverse. So far, we talked about articles, yet as seen in the infographics at the beginning of the article, the volume of video content posted and shared is ever increasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/attention-economy/youtube-kid.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A weird, potentially computer-generated kid video on Youtube&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A weird, potentially computer-generated kid video on Youtube&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is currently plagued with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@jamesbridle/something-is-wrong-on-the-internet-c39c471271d2&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;weird kids videos that depict graphical, shocking and stressful content.&lt;/a&gt; Because of the suggestions and the autoplay, kids using YouTube can stumble upon one of such starting their visit from a innocent cartoon video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some YouTubers produce disturbing knock-off videos based on characters kids love, such as Peppa Pig. Then, &lt;strong&gt;they game the algorithm with stuffed titles and descriptions to emerge&lt;/strong&gt;. The goal is ultimately to handle channels with a large following and views so that they can, once again, maximize ads revenues. &lt;strong&gt;Attention drives monetization.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;attention-economy-and-gamification&#34;&gt;Attention Economy and Gamification
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Different forms of incentives are tested to have highly engaged users that frequent check back their feeds**, the biggest one being gamification. It is the import of gaming reward mechanisms on non-game mediums, such as apps**.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@BBerdah/dark-patterns-submission-by-design-6f61b04e1c92&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;They fall into Dark patterns&lt;/a&gt;, a design trend we discussed in another article. They are used to nudge users to do or accept things they wouldn’t have if the information were presented to them. By adding points, achievements, unique rewards, power-ups and random reward schedule, apps and websites developers can ease the adoption of their service and increase engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Since the content we consume gets more and more engaging, we become more demanding&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;and less attentive&lt;/strong&gt;. We need stories and compelling content to stay engaged. We crave bite-sized videos and short articles. At the same time, the gamification of apps is becoming a standard. It is now expected, and maybe soon necessary to create apps people understand and use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-other-side-of-themirror&#34;&gt;The other side of the mirror
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the marketing world, the attention economy is qualified as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.trendone.com/en/trend-universe/mega-trends/mega-trend-detail/attention-economy.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;a “mega-trend”&lt;/a&gt;; a shift that manifests itself with many different macro-trends. Since &lt;strong&gt;paying for attention is no longer sufficient not reliable,&lt;/strong&gt; different trends are shaping the future of advertising and digital marketing to acknowledge this reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;medium-agnostic-trends&#34;&gt;Medium-agnostic trends
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advertising as a service:&lt;/strong&gt; the value proposition by itself is not cutting it anymore. To increase their reach, brands aim to convince potential customers with deeds rather than words. This includes surprises, entertainment and unexpected help at the right time — in real and digital places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Native Advertising:&lt;/strong&gt; regular advertisements don’t get as many eyeballs as they used to be. To reach a wider audience, the frontiers between media and advertisement are blurred. Native advertisements match the look, feel and function of the media format in which they appear. They are often found in social media feeds or as recommended content on web pages. Deception sells.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storytelling:&lt;/strong&gt; brands are telling stories, and making them more compelling than ever. Using data, stories can be fine-tuned to match an audience expectation (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cio.com/article/3207670/big-data/how-netflix-built-a-house-of-cards-with-big-data.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;House of Cards&lt;/a&gt;). Stories are turning into games, and becoming increasingly more personalized and interactive. Some stories are pure myths, like Apple&amp;rsquo;s focus on privacy, yet they are widely spread and believed. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;/I know iPhones are sexy, but please look into&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apple.stackexchange.com/questions/46396/is-it-possible-to-hide-my-devices-udid-from-ios-apps/46398#46398&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;Apple Advertising ID policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;if you believe Apple really care about your privacy./&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;expanding-the-marketing-world&#34;&gt;Expanding the marketing world
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Influencer Marketing:&lt;/strong&gt; audience can be kickstarted by renting someone else’s. The influencer marketing offers quickly diversified and increased over the last years. There are now thousands of influencers and “micro-influencers” (niche specific) ready to place products in their content and co-create with brands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proximity Marketing:&lt;/strong&gt; thanks to a dramatic increase in the precision of location-tracking devices over the last years, a new form of marketing is emerging. Beacons, relying on Bluetooth or Wi-Fi are increasingly used to deliver the messages about local deals to passerby. Apple paved the way establishing the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.beaconstac.com/2018/02/how-to-run-a-powerful-proximity-marketing-campaign-on-ios/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IBeacon&lt;/a&gt; protocol and Samsung quickly followed suit. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.computerworld.com/article/3321932/social-media/google-maps-is-the-new-social-network.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Maps is also turning into a social network&lt;/a&gt; / advertising platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensation Marketing:&lt;/strong&gt; brands are now able to harness the power of sensations and emotions better than ever before. New forms of advertising are used, such as stunts. Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Guerrilla_marketing&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;guerilla marketing&lt;/a&gt;, new spaces are also exploited like building facades or streetlights. Finally, with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensory_branding&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;sensory branding&lt;/a&gt;, our senses are being used to promote new messages. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.shopify.com/retail/the-science-of-smell-how-retailers-can-use-scent-marketing-to-make-more-sales&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Scent marketing&lt;/a&gt; is highly effective at modulating our experiences and attract bystanders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For marketers, the attention economy is the underpinning of novel approaches to finding more intrusive and effective forms of advertising and explore new channels&lt;/strong&gt;. It seems like the plethora of content that is causing the attention shortage is not going anywhere and will keep increasing. Where does this leave us with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-problem-with-the-internet-businessmodel&#34;&gt;A problem with the Internet business model?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The challenges of the attention economy lie with the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/facebook-x-cambridge-analytica-the-hidden-cost-of-free-services-3f5724e80baf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;dominance of the advertising model&lt;/a&gt;. Advertisement is now considered as the only way to offer free services and content at scale. It doesn’t have to be this way. It was a deliberate choice, promoted by a few actors including the GAFA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertisements show no signs of slow down, and millions of content pieces are published every day. The demographics are simply not there to support this much content. However, marketers and content producers are surprisingly optimistic. Indeed, bots might save us: their eyeballs multiply.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dark patterns: submission by design?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/dark-patterns-submission-by-design/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 09:02:04 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/dark-patterns-submission-by-design/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2019/dark-patterns/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Dark patterns: submission by design?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever scrolled through Facebook for hours despite having other things to do? Or went through a sign up process, clicking “Next”, “Ok”, “Get Started” buttons without reading anything else? Or maybe you’ve been using an app every day for years without knowing anything about its privacy policy? Don’t worry, there is a whole science created to make sure you don’t feel bad or even question this, it bears a name and it’s discussed publicly: dark patterns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dark design practices are very diverse in nature, but they all share a common attribute: &lt;strong&gt;nudging the users to accept, do, or share something they wouldn’t have if the information were presented to them in a non-ambiguous fashion&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s essentially deception and dishonesty by design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From deceptive wordings (such as “Don’t opt out” check-boxes) to shiny, colorful buttons opposed to boring legalese grayscale text on white background, the artifices are plenty. They involve an understanding of human psychology, such as harnessing FOMO to pressure us into making an impulsive decision or playing with timing and time pressure (the e-commerce’s beloved “Limited offer”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-kind-ofmagic&#34;&gt;A kind of magic?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Magicians use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Misdirection_%28magic%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;misdirection&lt;/a&gt; to draw their audience attention in order to screen from detection certain details for which secrecy is required. They attract the attention to one thing to distract it from another. Dark design patterns are used to achieve the same effect. Except that this time the goal of the trick is not to entertain you, but to harvest your data, manipulate your thinking processes or your votes, make you an app-addict, or just to make you buy things you do not need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magicians face their audience when they perform the deception; they have no trouble sleeping at night. They use their art to enchant. &lt;strong&gt;If they used it to steal, it would no longer be called magic but pickpocketing.&lt;/strong&gt; Part of what allowed dark design patterns to spread is the disconnection with the audience: &lt;strong&gt;such practices are developed by UX designers who don’t have to look at their audience in the eyes&lt;/strong&gt;. They merely see the conversion metrics grow and keep the grin to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-dark-patterntypology&#34;&gt;A dark pattern typology
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dark patterns are nothing new. The UX designer Harry Brignull coined it eight years ago already and registered the website &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://darkpatterns.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;darkpatterns.org&lt;/a&gt; to call out the practice as unethical and help users recognize it as such. What’s new is the scale it reached, as we can now find dark patterns used in pretty much every major website or app. Harry Brignull even established a typology of dark patterns, all who are documented by countless examples. Here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-app-darkpatterns&#34;&gt;In-app dark patterns
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confirmshaming:&lt;/strong&gt; guilting the user into opting into something. The decline option is usually worded so that the user is shamed into compliance: who wants to click a &lt;code&gt;I am a bad person&lt;/code&gt; action link?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/dark-patterns/adblocker-guilt-trip.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden costs&lt;/strong&gt;: hiding additional costs (such as delivery) until the very last step of the purchase process. By then, the user has committed quite time to the process, and probably already inputted his credit card info. The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Confirmation_bias&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;confirmation bias&lt;/a&gt; might give him the nudge he needs to finish his purchase despite the surprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trick questions&lt;/strong&gt;: framing questions to mislead the users. While reading quickly, the user might think he’s opting-out while he’s actually opting-in. It works even better when used in series alternating opt-in and opt-out like on the example below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/dark-patterns/trick-q.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;service-level-darkpatterns&#34;&gt;Service-level dark patterns
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The playbook is quite extensive yet not exhaustive; you can check out the other ones &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://darkpatterns.org/types-of-dark-pattern&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Besides the software and the apps themselves, dark patterns are found all thorough products and services, from the sign up to the account deletion process. Privacy policies and terms and conditions are the dark patterns magnets. Different methods are used to make them easy to accept, hard if not impossible to truly understand and even harder (if even possible) to refuse:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Privacy-intrusive options enabled by default&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Obscuring the more privacy-friendly settings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threats of loss of functionality or deletion of the user account if specific settings are not chosen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pop-ups compelling users to make certain choices, while essential information is omitted or downplayed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inability to use the app or register if the privacy policy is refused (“take it or leave it” approach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dark-patterns-beyond-theapps&#34;&gt;Dark patterns, beyond the apps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While dark patterns thrived and prospered on the Internet, they’re not bound to the digital world. Many subscriptions service adopt a “signing up is easy, canceling is hard” model. Once again, different tricks are used to make it as hard as possible for the user to unsubscribe, such as the threat of a high cancellation fee or making the unsubscribe process tedious. Some services even force the user to send a letter or call a given number while he registered by filling a form online. Those who work up the courage to call might face absurd business hours or agents that simply hang up on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gym clubs are among the worst when it comes to canceling subscriptions. On boards and forums online, you can find countless stories of people going through the hassle of the cancellation process. This story from a redditor is particularly insightful: it took him &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://np.reddit.com/r/AMA/comments/9duble/i_successfully_canceled_an_la_fitness_membership/e5k7o9b/?st=jltqrwml&amp;amp;sh=040d8d01&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;4 hours and 26 phone calls to cancel his gym membership&lt;/a&gt;, and the use of several different phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-did-we-getthere&#34;&gt;How did we get there?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering the frustration and even anger they generate, one might wonder how dark patterns can be so prevalent? After all, stories like the one told above are detrimental to the brand. The deceived user will not fail to share his disappointment with his friends and online once he freed himself from the trickery. Well, the short answer is that superficially, dark patterns work. If you A/B test an honest, non-deceptive form versus a dark pattern filled one, the second one will certainly land more conversions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/dark-patterns/abtesting.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A basic form of A/B Testing&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A basic form of A/B Testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When only the perimeter of their implementation (sign up form, purchase process…) is considered, dark patterns inevitably land more results than an honest approach. The harmful consequences they can unleash are delayed and at the brand level. They only come later on when people are denouncing their practices online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-whats-the-actual-hidden-cost-of-dark-patterns&#34;&gt;So, what’s the actual hidden cost of dark patterns?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Outside of a simple risk/benefit analysis at the scale of the brand, dark patterns behind widespread are now one of the main contributing factors of massive issues, at a societal level:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Users are being hooked to apps&lt;/strong&gt;: the dark patterns are engineered to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nirandfar.com/2012/03/want-to-hook-your-users-drive-them-crazy.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;encourage users to form addictive habits&lt;/a&gt; to the apps they interact with. These apps use diverse techniques such as abusive notifications (“We haven’t seen you in a while!”), or feeds implementing a variable schedule of rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal data are collected at an unprecedented pace and scale&lt;/strong&gt;, and privacy is getting harder and harder to achieve. Free apps and social network harvest data and share them with a vast network of data brokers who profit from trading people’s personal information. In 2015, data brokering was already a $200 billion industry. This activity is lawful, but the users are mostly unaware of it or its extent thanks to misleading interfaces — this pattern bears the name of Facebook’s founder: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://darkpatterns.org/types-of-dark-pattern/privacy-zuckering&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Privacy Zuckering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The data collected makes it possible to target ads and communication so precisely that we reach a point where &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/facebook-x-cambridge-analytica-the-hidden-cost-of-free-services-3f5724e80baf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;free will is put back into question&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The consequences of dark design and other privacy-intrusive practices are already there, and their effect will be felt for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-reclaim-our-digitallives&#34;&gt;How to reclaim our digital lives?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Individuals concerned about privacy are forced to work at well, an individual level so far. They look into the software they use and prefer open-source whenever it’s possible. They double check every piece of hardware they get and quite often have to disable several features (Wifi, Bluetooth…) to not compromise their privacy. To learn more about how to protect your privacy online, you can check the resources from the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.eff.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Electronic Frontier Foundation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alas, at a societal level the answers are lackluster if not inexistent. The laws are still very lax, and many of the patterns described before are still lawful. There were many talks about GDPR this year, but despite being more restrictive than previous regulations, it has &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://researchsupport.admin.ox.ac.uk/policy/data/exemptions&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;many exemptions&lt;/a&gt; and is overall insufficient to protect individual consumers against privacy-intrusive companies like Google or Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what are we left with? In situations where privacy is an absolute necessity, some tools are available, yet they have a steep learning curve as they do not share the friendly UX of their privacy-intrusive counterpart. Individuals who are unfamiliar with such solutions have no other option than going analog if they are not willing to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ssd.eff.org/en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;train themselves&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;can-tech-fight-techsabuses&#34;&gt;Can tech fight tech’s abuses?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the laws won’t suffice to ensure individuals’ protection, some people are looking for solutions to trigger an ethical revolution in the tech space itself. It means that we’ll need not only new tools but a complete overall of the internet business models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding privacy and traceability of the data we share, the decentralized ledgers such as blockchain-based systems might provide a credible solution. They offer interesting features to regain control over our digital lives, such as censorship and attack resistance, or fault tolerance. Different projects are emerging to solve the several problems we currently face:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethical advertising and privacy protection: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://brave.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brave&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reliable and decentralized identity management: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.civic.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Civic&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.uport.me/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;uPort&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial privacy: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.getmonero.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Monero&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/dark-patterns/bat.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such systems are still under development and far from mainstream adoptions. In the meanwhile, the way we design digital interfaces needs to change: can there be such a thing as bright design? We can at least see how it would look like: transparent, honest, and empowering the users instead of deceiving them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Growing beyond the advertising model to achieve democracy’s true potential</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/growing-beyond-the-advertising-model-to-achieve-democracys-true-potential/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 14:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/growing-beyond-the-advertising-model-to-achieve-democracys-true-potential/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/ad-model/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Growing beyond the advertising model to achieve democracy’s true potential" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@BBerdah/facebook-x-cambridge-analytica-the-hidden-cost-of-free-services-3f5724e80baf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, we raised many issues about the advertising model and free online services in general. &lt;strong&gt;They all fall within the spectrum of hidden cost, something society, we, eventually pay for.&lt;/strong&gt; From recurring annoyances to a loss of political power, the range of consequences of data concentration for political and social influence is wide. &lt;strong&gt;Behind all of these “free” offers, compromises are made&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many issues with the ad model, all falling under the spectrum of hidden cost. Indeed, behind FB’s “free” offer, a lot of compromises are made, here is a quick overview:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advertisement-overload&#34;&gt;ADVERTISEMENT OVERLOAD
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering the online services business model, the (infinite) multiplication of ads inevitable. Indeed, it’s the main way for the actor to maximize their revenues. &lt;strong&gt;They are essentially caught in a profitable and vicious circle&lt;/strong&gt;: More ads -&amp;gt; More views, more views -&amp;gt; more sales, more sales -&amp;gt; more money -&amp;gt; more ads.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since ads are profitable, more and more media space is used to that end. New forms of advertising-content hybrids appeared over the past years, like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://techscience.org/a/2015121503/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Native Advertising&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;as advertisers are looking for new territory to conquer where the consumer resistance is lower.&lt;/strong&gt; The frontier between a media outlet and a brand outlet is progressively fading out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the online side of the industry, the sheer size of the actor should be a cause for concern. &lt;strong&gt;Facebook now as 2bn+ users. That’s more than any government, even China or India can’t compete&lt;/strong&gt;. With this level of mainstream adoption, the reach is virtually unlimited and nobody is out of scope. &lt;strong&gt;To continue to personalize its ads further, Facebook amasses detailed profiles for most individuals, that can then be used to influence them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Facebook is the most influential medium for political and social causes. Concentrating so much power in one space is obviously dangerous, as it makes the social discourse more prone to manipulation and coercion. Yet &lt;strong&gt;data is meant to be shared&lt;/strong&gt;, and advertisers are quite generous when it comes to user data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;collected-data-areleaking&#34;&gt;COLLECTED DATA ARE LEAKING
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, the frequent exchanges between actors in the industry make the data issue widespread and hardly revocable. Whatever the collect point is, the data gathered will eventually be sold to “independent measurement and data company” like Nielsen or Axciom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The consumer not only lose control over its data, he also has no knowledge of the usage made of it and who currently owns it&lt;/strong&gt;. Given enough money and resources, anyone could potentially acquire a very detailed file on anybody, including relatives of course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The profile is often &lt;strong&gt;qualitative enough to let the advertisers and their clients influence opinions, behaviors and ultimately votes.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;welcome-in-the-state-of-surveillance&#34;&gt;WELCOME IN THE STATE OF SURVEILLANCE
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The data is not only used for business purposes. Since the beginning of the war on terror, &lt;strong&gt;many western governments got rid of railings limiting the actions of intelligence agencies and surveillance services&lt;/strong&gt;. As monitoring of online services become commonplaces, the novelty now rely on using the data for live facial recognition on surveillance video camera streams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/toolbox&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;toolbox&lt;/a&gt; for crowd and individual control is here. &lt;strong&gt;Even if we ignore what the data gathered allow advertisers and governments to do, this simple act of collection is deeply problematic.&lt;/strong&gt; As the society gain knowledge over this practice, our behavior “normalize”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simple awareness of knowing oneself observed will push individuals to modify their behavior in response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20140209-being-watched-why-thats-good&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;People under scrutiny change their behavior and their choice without even realizing.&lt;/a&gt; Because we know we’re watched, we monitor and censor our own behavior. It doesn’t even have to be a conscious process; we’ll simply tend to match the ideals of the watcher — this is called the observer effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phenomenon is present in every academic discipline, sometimes with a different name (Hawthorne Effect).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/ad-model/panopticon.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;panopticon&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This observation was used by the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeremy_Bentham&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;philosopher Jeremy Bentham&lt;/a&gt; to envision an institutional building designed for maximum efficiency, the panopticon. Since the watchtower is placed in the center, with prisoners all around, any prisoner can potentially be watched at all times with only one guard. Worse, the prisoners can’t know if they’re being watched or not. He described it himself as &lt;strong&gt;“a new mode of obtaining power of mind over mind”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ads-affect-the-very-content-of-the-media-that-hostthem&#34;&gt;ADS AFFECT THE VERY CONTENT OF THE MEDIA THAT HOST THEM
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advertisements also affect the media that host them. Some of the effects are quite obvious — such as finding the space for ads (ads break, banner…) but &lt;strong&gt;the most damaging effects are also the less prominent ones.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, because the content is tied to the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/advertisement&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;advertisement&lt;/a&gt;, the content creator must follow a &lt;strong&gt;“advertiser-friendly” guideline&lt;/strong&gt;. Media are now competing with one another to host ads, and innovate to attract them: product placement, reality shows… (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?time_continue=162&amp;amp;v=hr99HzCa0Kg&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Publicitarisation — French&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;strong&gt;Everything is becoming a media&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Cv5WLF6UdZc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Depublicitarisation&lt;/a&gt;). Millions of people are voluntarily following brand accounts on social networks to receive a healthy daily dose of promotion (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8ZNOCKl-0Mc&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hyperpublicitarisation&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, the free supported by ads model is costly. Advertisers are getting close to the media, restricting what can or cannot be said, topics, and schedules. &lt;strong&gt;Because of ads, diversity and quality of the media are reduced.&lt;/strong&gt; But there is more to it. Once ads are running, &lt;strong&gt;there is a strong incentive to stay compliant with dominant, advertiser-friendly framework&lt;/strong&gt; in order to retain and increase revenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;meant-to-bebig&#34;&gt;MEANT TO BE BIG
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we have seen already, Facebook’s and others main profit driver is &lt;strong&gt;how addicted to their service, to maximize the time spent on it&lt;/strong&gt;. It can’t be balanced, &lt;strong&gt;it’s a design flaw&lt;/strong&gt;. When Zuckerberg speaks about Facebook’s ideals, and how he wishes to make it more honest and transparent, it’s no more than marketing and PR.On a market where two actors (Facebook and Google) hold more than half of the revenue of the whole industry, what can you do if your ad costs explode? Essentially, you have no alternative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/ad-model/revenues.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Net digital advertising revenue share of major ad-selling online companies worldwide from 2016 to 2019&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.statista.com/statistics/290629/digital-ad-revenue-share-of-major-ad-selling-companies-worldwide/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Net digital advertising revenue share of major ad-selling online companies worldwide from 2016 to 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-edge-ofscale&#34;&gt;THE EDGE OF SCALE
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not pleading for breaking down Facebook or Google. The result would eventually be the same a few years down the road. Indeed, &lt;strong&gt;because of their business model, the GAFA are meant to be giants&lt;/strong&gt;. Behind the “big data” or whatever name they give to it are basically two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building a robust system to collect data on consumers, organize it, tag it, and clean it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling the data after a form a processing (building audience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Both those activities benefit hugely from scale&lt;/strong&gt;. For data collection, the bigger you are, the more present you will be which in the end multiply the opportunity to collect new data points. The ideal scenario here would a quasi-monopolistic situation where people can hardly avoid using your service (Hello Zuckie).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it comes to reselling data, once again size does matter, a lot! &lt;strong&gt;Datasets scale twofold, both in terms of quantity and quality&lt;/strong&gt;. The bigger the dataset, the more people they cover, allowing the data reseller to reach new markets. Simultaneously, each new data point collected on a given individual allows the reseller to charge more, because of the precise targeting and personalization it allows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, as the dataset covers more and more people, new correlations can be found, which in turn increase the amount of information available in any given person present in the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What it means, in an economic sense, is that &lt;strong&gt;each time Facebook register a new user, it benefits twice from it&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, it will increase its total amount of (active) user, which is the base multiplier of FB’s revenues.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secondly, because a bigger dataset allows drawing more insightful analysis, &lt;strong&gt;FB is able to increase its revenue per user (ARPU)&lt;/strong&gt; more for each data point it already has on one.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/ad-model/arpu.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Facebook’s ARPU, 2015–2017&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.statista.com/statistics/251328/facebooks-average-revenue-per-user-by-region/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook’s ARPU, 2015–2017&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ARPU (Average Revenue per User) is an interesting metric to look at. It gives you an idea of &lt;strong&gt;how much money Facebook is actually able to extract from your data.&lt;/strong&gt; The ARPU is also strongly correlated on how detailed the database is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A high ARPU could then indicate that Facebook has a very detailed file. With an ARPU of $26+ for the US and “up to 5,000 data points on 220 million Americans”, it seems to match. &lt;strong&gt;Ultimately, the ARPU is an indicator of the extent in which Facebook can be used to influence a population.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we look at the growth of Facebook’s ARPU, it has been on exponential growth over the last four years. Once again, the real word seems to confirm the observation, as the role played by Facebook keep getting more important with each new ballot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/ad-model/arpu-growth.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Facebook’s average revenue per user as of 4th quarter 2017, by region (in U.S. dollars)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.statista.com/statistics/251328/facebooks-average-revenue-per-user-by-region/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook’s average revenue per user as of 4th quarter 2017, by region (in U.S. dollars)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GAFAs are now so big that each of their decisions has huge impacts&lt;/strong&gt;. Google and Facebook together are the biggest source of traffic for most websites. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.legrandsoir.info/un-nouvel-algorithme-de-google-limite-l-acces-aux-sites-web-progressistes-et-de-gauche.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;When Google slashes incoming traffic by 70% to a 20 years old left-leaning website — French&lt;/a&gt;, the World Socialist Web Site, &lt;strong&gt;it is a political action with real consequences on the political life of the country&lt;/strong&gt;. GAFAs are now the gatekeepers of the information online and make calls about what we see or not. Because of their size, their decisions have tremendous impacts on society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we know about Facebook and other online services data collection practices, it’s time call the shots:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do we keep sacrificing our political power on the altar of convenience, or should we build our own decentralized social network services framework to prevent control and manipulation from hostile parties?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain opened a range of new options to build decentralized institutions we can trust. Some solutions are already working. We’ll see radical alternatives emerge over the upcoming years, &lt;strong&gt;it’s up to us to make the best of it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Facebook X Cambridge Analytica : the hidden cost of free services</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/facebook-x-cambridge-analytica-the-hidden-cost-of-free-services/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 14:23:08 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/facebook-x-cambridge-analytica-the-hidden-cost-of-free-services/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2018/free-services/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Facebook X Cambridge Analytica : the hidden cost of free services" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last month was a strange one. We saw mainstream media questioning &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/facebook&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and Cambridge Analytica practices after recent concerns over the US election. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2018/mar/24/facebook-week-of-shame-data-breach-observer-revelations-zuckerberg-silence&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Guardian&lt;/a&gt; sums it up in one frightening sentence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had manipulated the voters of democracies across the globe, notably in the US, with unsourced propaganda that was not necessarily true; and boasting of sting operations and honey traps&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cambridge Analytica took part in the yes for the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://hackernoon.com/tagged/brexit&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brexit&lt;/a&gt; campaign, the election of Donald Trump, Ted Cruz’s campaign, and in &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/politics/cruz-campaign-paid-750000-to-psychographic-profiling-company/2015/10/19/6c83e508-743f-11e5-9cbb-790369643cf9_story.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;dozens of local election&lt;/a&gt; (44 apparently in 2014, just for the US). They are now a massive &lt;strong&gt;political force, engaged all across the globe with a strong&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.politico.com/story/2015/07/ted-cruz-donor-for-data-119813&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;preference for conservative candidates.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Cambridge Analytica was already &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=c_SlD7D_xug&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;advertising its services on Youtube since August 2015&lt;/a&gt;, they weren’t very secretive about their intent; here’s what they boast about in their promotional videos:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the American market, they claim to have &lt;strong&gt;“up to 5,000 data points on 220 million Americans”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“We go beyond big data, we add an extra layer of personality data to &lt;strong&gt;get down to an individual level”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The activity of Cambridge Analytica and its impact over elections have been well covered, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/news/series/cambridge-analytica-files&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;such as in The Guardian’s Cambridge Analytica files&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2017/03/06/us/politics/cambridge-analytica.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NY Times&lt;/a&gt;. Now, even Google will tell you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/free-services/google.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s less discussed is how could we even get to this point? Considering the company’s goals and practices, abuses should have been expected and prevented. Let’s broaden the discussion and address the tradeoff made with “free” services instead and the &lt;strong&gt;consequences of this data theft: a loss of political and personal power.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-advertising-model-the-necessary-pain&#34;&gt;THE ADVERTISING MODEL: THE NECESSARY PAIN?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s actually a quote from Mark Zuckerberg that got me started on this article. In the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/2018/4/2/17185052/mark-zuckerberg-facebook-interview-fake-news-bots-cambridge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ezra Klein Show&lt;/a&gt; when asked about the &lt;strong&gt;limits of Facebook’s current business model&lt;/strong&gt;, he didn’t exactly answer the question yet provided a fascinating response:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, I find that argument, that if you’re not paying that somehow we can’t care about you, to be extremely glib and not at all aligned with the truth. The reality here is that if you want to build a service that helps connect everyone in the world, then there are a lot of people who can’t afford to pay. And therefore, as with a lot of media, having an advertising-supported model is the &lt;strong&gt;only rational model that can support building this service to reach people&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He presents the advertising-supported model &lt;strong&gt;as the only rational one able to bring free services to the world&lt;/strong&gt;. I would argue instead &lt;strong&gt;it’s only the easiest way&lt;/strong&gt;. Essentially, advertising allows generating revenue out of each/most users of the service. Because of the monetary incentive tied to ads, the provider tends to focus on collecting more data and increasing the user base even further instead of actual development of the service. It can’t be sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As they restlessly harness data, &lt;strong&gt;online services gain actual power and influence on individuals and societies&lt;/strong&gt;. Facebook is now the kingmaker, or is it already the king? If Facebook is king, it’s a sneaky one: he’s being secretive about its regal nature. They didn’t come public about the Cambridge Analytica scandal, they waited for the public to notice and patiently prepared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2017/feb/16/mark-zuckerberg-new-facebook-manifesto-letter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;In a manifesto written in 2017 about the future of Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, he develops a grandiose and frightening vision for the social network, as &lt;strong&gt;“the social infrastructure for the global community”.&lt;/strong&gt; What we’re seeing today is only stage 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, Facebook isn’t a lone wolf. There is a whole industry built on similar concepts: online advertising. While Cambridge Analytica and Facebook are probably at fault, many other companies such as Google, Yahoo, or Baidu have similar practices. A whole industry is at fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-crookedindustry&#34;&gt;A CROOKED INDUSTRY
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The advertising industry has always been ripe for abuse and scams, but &lt;strong&gt;digital advertising brought it to another level&lt;/strong&gt;. Abuses are common, both for advertisers and other actors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a closer look at the industry, you uncover several battles being lead all at once. First, &lt;strong&gt;shady practices are rampant in the industry&lt;/strong&gt;. On the advertiser side, botting and click-fraud are massive. To top this all up, users, annoyed by the evermore intrusive ads, are now fighting back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;abuses-and-shady-practices&#34;&gt;ABUSES AND SHADY PRACTICES
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abuses and misleading tactics are spread all around the industry on all kind of ads and devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On mobile, apps and games may have &lt;strong&gt;aggressive data collection practices&lt;/strong&gt;, requiring unnecessary permissions (contacts, pictures, files…), which allow them to collect unnecessary data. Unsurprisingly, the Facebook app is among one of the most demanding in terms of permissions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On desktop, there are intrusive banner ads and pop-ups all around deteriorating the browsing experience on the web. Worst, there are also much more intrusive practices such as &lt;strong&gt;spywares&lt;/strong&gt; (your beloved grandma’s toolbar) &lt;strong&gt;bundled with free softwares&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2018/free-services/toolbars.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A glimpse in toolbars’ hell&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A glimpse in toolbars’ hell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If scammy tactics are common for advertisers, brands pay the price for it as automated clicks are hard to distinguish for real ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;practically-in-a-civilwar&#34;&gt;PRACTICALLY IN A CIVIL WAR
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bots or automated activity is indeed massive in the online advertising world. It’s hard for brands to recognize these practices, and it allows the ad seller to increase their profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AKA, why are they so many bots on Twitter? About 20% of all accounts are bots (fully automated), and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.pewinternet.org/2018/04/09/bots-in-the-twittersphere/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;at least 20% others use automated methods&lt;/a&gt;. So, if Twitter was to take actual measure against automated activity, it would risk losing up to 40% of the impressions it sells to advertisers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry itself is well aware of the issue, the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/fb66c818-49a4-11e6-b387-64ab0a67014c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;World Federation of Advertiser&lt;/a&gt; estimates that &lt;strong&gt;between 10 to 30% of the slots are never seen by consumers because of fraud&lt;/strong&gt;. The total loss is estimated at $50bn a year, roughly a third of the current online advertising industry yearly revenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;users-are-fighting-backtoo&#34;&gt;USERS ARE FIGHTING BACK TOO
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of the click fraud, you must add another stream of lost revenues for advertisers: users using an ad blocker. To protect themselves, surfers took matters in their own hand and developed Ad-Blockers extension, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/nano-adblocker/gabbbocakeomblphkmmnoamkioajlkfo?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;NanoBlock&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/ublock-origin/cjpalhdlnbpafiamejdnhcphjbkeiagm?hl=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;uBlock origin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering how intrusive and annoying ads have become, it was bound to happen. &lt;strong&gt;While adblockers minimize annoyance on the user side, it doesn’t solve the problem at all at the industry level.&lt;/strong&gt; Because less users now see the ads they host, media advertising revenues dwindle putting their very subsistence at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one side, installing a Firefox/Chrome extension come easy for some, many don’t know about them or even about ad blockers. &lt;strong&gt;Only the most tech-savvy users tend to use ad blockers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;the ad industry is fighting back&lt;/strong&gt;, some websites are now blocking access to users with an ad blocker enabled. Luckily, blockers currently have the final world with anti-ad blocker defusers like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jspenguin2017.github.io/uBlockProtector/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Nano Defender&lt;/a&gt;. It’s an ongoing back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advertising industry is mined by vicious circles of abuse that lead users to fight back. Since it lowers their revenues, media and advertisers are pushed towards even more intrusive advertising and data collection practices to try to break even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The whole advertising model is unsustainable. &lt;strong&gt;The actual consequences of the development of free services spread all the way down to the individual level. The tributes we pay is already massive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These include the abuses within the industry, the ongoing war with the users but most importantly &lt;strong&gt;the political clout claimed by online service which now makes them able to coerce public opinion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not only about Cambridge Analytica, it’s much bigger than this. I share &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/club-max/zuckerberg-in-dc-exposes-how-little-our-governments-understand-where-humanity-is-heading-b568607ab216&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Max Evans views&lt;/a&gt; on Zuckberg’s hearing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Words will be said, apologies noted, laws passed, but the problems will grow. Companies will not moderate their behaviour totally because they only have to accede to individual nations”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the state is unfit to deal with this, &lt;strong&gt;we have but one option left: do something about it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advertising model is not only tendentious but perverse. Is it really the only option Zuck, or just the one that happened to be proposed first and quietly established as a standard? &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@BBerdah/growing-beyond-the-advertising-model-to-achieve-democracys-true-potential-5990de48a86f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Other models that allow a fairer distribution of the values between all the actors of the ecosystem exist.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
