<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Content on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/content/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Content on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 09:44:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/content/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Static web - back to the roots?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/static-web-back-to-the-roots/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 09:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/static-web-back-to-the-roots/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;This article goes back to the early years of the web to understand why dynamic websites are so prevalent today. Then, we consider what static websites bring in terms of performance, editing speed, and organic results.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, the web was static.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early days Internet was a place for tinkerers. Despite the frequent comparisons between MySpace and Facebook, the two services are fundamentally different. They are also a &lt;strong&gt;good representation of the &amp;ldquo;Internet Paradigm&amp;rdquo; of their respective time of fame&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both are social networks, yet creating a page on MySpace required a basic understanding of HTML and CSS. The service was launched in 2003 after all. On the other hand, Facebook&amp;rsquo;s easy to use interface contributed to its success and helped it reach 2+ billion users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Behind the MySpace/Facebook antagonism lies on the most critical point of tension on the internet - &lt;strong&gt;how to interact with the content we edit?&lt;/strong&gt; There are mostly two ways to look at this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WYSIWYG (What You See Is What You Get)&lt;/strong&gt; — As the name suggests, in this paradigm the goal is to have an editor as close as the final rendering. WordPress was one of the most visible early proponent of WYSIWYG, but others joined. The Medium editor (featured below), built using &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TinyMCE&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;TinyMCE&lt;/a&gt;, is now regarded as one of the best WYSIWYG experience available online.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency First&lt;/strong&gt; — WYSIWYG editors are easy to get started with but tend to be either clunky or limited. Ultimately, introducing some form of syntax adds complexity, but it also allows more control over the final rendering of the content. Moreover, since the formatting is enforced with syntax (HTML, CSS, Markdown…), it&amp;rsquo;s no longer dependent on the editor used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/staticweb/mediumeditor.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Medium Editor&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dawn-of-wordpress&#34;&gt;The Dawn of WordPress
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;WordPress quickly took over the web: it currently holds about 60% of the CMS market share. WordPress is so commonplace that we can even look at it from a venture point encompassing the whole web: &lt;strong&gt;about a third of all websites use WordPress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success does not mean relevance. Indeed, power users are leaving WordPress in drove for various reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Editing&lt;/strong&gt;: The WP Editor, even the new Guttenberg, is a pain. It&amp;rsquo;s slow, clunky, and comes with a convoluted block logic. Using it to format and edit content results in a pure waste of time considering the alternative options. Besides, it does not support any &amp;ldquo;smart feature&amp;rdquo; by default such as footnotes or tables of content. They require an absurdly complex workflow or yet another plugin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt;: Because of its success, WordPress is a prime target for hackers. Any large WP-based website will have to implement additional measures (plugins?) to handle different types of attacks. Moreover, WordPress supports all version of PHP ranging from 5.2.4 (released 12 years ago) to 7.2. Cross this with all the potential plugins and themes, and you get an endless list of attack vectors. Here is an &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kinsta.com/blog/is-wordpress-secure/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;overview of the most common ones&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance&lt;/strong&gt;: Out of the box, WordPress performance is atrocious. With some plugins (cache, CDN…) and other settings you can speed it up - but is it your job? &lt;strong&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t the point of a web framework to minimize the optimization effort?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin Bloat&lt;/strong&gt;: Because of all the plugins WordPress requires, it ends up slowing down the website and hindering security. &lt;strong&gt;A fresh WP install needs 5-10 plugins to be usable and 10-15 to be &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;make-it-static&#34;&gt;Make It Static!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Back when WordPress was released in 2003, the competition was unconvincing. However, this was 15 years ago. In the meanwhile, we saw exciting &lt;strong&gt;tools and frameworks emerge both to format written content and to host and render it for the end-user.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s the development of both, hand in hand, that paved the way for the static web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with editing, focusing on Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rise-of-markdown&#34;&gt;The Rise of Markdown
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;While WordPress was getting fatter and fatter, alternatives developed both to host website and format content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the content, new lightweight markup languages like Markdown offer a credible alternative even for a non-technical profile. Markdown&amp;rsquo;s promise is simple: take an hour to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;master the cheatsheet&lt;/a&gt; to cut down formatting time to virtually 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Markdown is reasonably straightforward, quick to master yet incredibly potent. A writer using a markdown editor and some shortcuts can write and format its content at the same time. On top of that, Markdown offers many exporting options (HTML, PDF, LaTex, Doc…) and ensures that your formatting stays consistent whatever the end format is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it might seem, but it&amp;rsquo;s not given: with markdown you can handle text-related features (footnotes, tagging, linking to a section, table of contents, diagrams and charts) at the document-level instead of having to interact with yet another layer. &lt;strong&gt;It dramatically improves the maintainability and portability of your content.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/staticweb/jamstack.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;JAMStack&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;version-control-is-not-just-about-code-writers-love-it-too&#34;&gt;Version control is not just about code: writers love it too!
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Version control and git-based development rapidly developed in the software world for solid reasons. It makes the whole development process more reliable and safe. Furthermore, the user permission management system, the branch logic and the access to the full file history as well as the ability to compare files between to versions are incredibly useful to avoid breaking changes or fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the developers got all these fancy new tools, us writers were still editing our articles in Word to copy paste it in the WordPress WYSIWYG editor and then start our formatting struggle. Why not share the goodies?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, as paradoxical as it can seem, a Github repo makes for a very compelling CMS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy User/Access Management&lt;/strong&gt;. The branch logic fits the editing process. For instance, if there is a need to keep a tight grip over the content published, the merging power on the master branch can be granted only to the chief editor to ensure consistency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Branch Logic&lt;/strong&gt;: while using a repo as a CMS, branches can serve various purposes. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to use one branch as a staging environment so that the writers can see the final rendering of their content on their machine.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File History&lt;/strong&gt;: with GitHub repos, you can access the whole history of a file and easily compare two versions. It is handy, especially if your blog has a lot of different contributors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No setup&lt;/strong&gt;: the repository can be opened in a click. From here, another click with a service like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.netlify.com/docs/deploy-button/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Netlify&lt;/a&gt; is enough to have a blog up and running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;beyond-the-lack-of-performance-lies-exclusion&#34;&gt;Beyond the lack of performance lies exclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So far, we stayed very pragmatic as we addressed static websites&amp;rsquo; benefits in terms of performance or increased efficiency. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a step back and consider the big picture for a minute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average website size is now well over 3 MB&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; (as 2017). &lt;strong&gt;More the size itself, the macro-level issue lies in the trend&lt;/strong&gt;. Here is the evolution of the average website page since 2011 for reference&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/staticweb/pagebloat.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Web performance page bloat&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you a reference for comparison on blog.call.tech, our homepage weights 10 KB and an average page (image included) weights about 400 KB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do I need to download a full and bloated 3+ MB page to get simple textual information that might be just a few bits?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You and I are sitting here, probably on a modern laptop/smartphone with a decent connection. What about those who live in countries where the Internet service is poor? Most of the Internet is made of text; it should be lightweight. Why do I need to download a full and bloated 3+ MB page to get simple textual information that might be just a few bits?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;mind-the-people-using-your-websites&#34;&gt;Mind the people using your websites
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It might seem like a first world problem; in reality, it&amp;rsquo;s a terrible third world problem. &lt;strong&gt;Poorly designed websites result in the exclusion of regular people from services they could benefit from.&lt;/strong&gt; Moreover, the unnecessary data usage bloats the network creating congestions, higher demands and eventually pushing the price of the service up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let us go as far as stating this: &lt;strong&gt;publishing an unnecessary dynamic website in 2019 is an abuse of a common good.&lt;/strong&gt; The Internet network is a shared resource, why don&amp;rsquo;t we try to avoid another tragedy of the commons using nothing more than common sense?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;slow-websites-are-lonely&#34;&gt;Slow websites are lonely
&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let us merely ask a question to those who design those websites 12-times more massive than they should be: why so much hate? In perfect conditions, &lt;strong&gt;the average Internet user with his 7.2 MB/s average connection will need more than 3 seconds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; to get one page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s the impact? Neil Patel, a well-known figure in the SEO community, produced a very comprehensive info-graphics covering this topic.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; He estimates that &lt;strong&gt;40% (53% on mobile) of users abandon a website that takes more than 3 seconds to load.&lt;/strong&gt; So crossing the two numbers, you get the following absurdity:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News, media and other sites are loosing up to 40% of their potential traffic because of their poor performance stemming from their baseless choice of a dynamic rendering engine. This figure does not include the organic traffic lost because of a lack of SEO-compliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s skim the fat. Do we need this many scripts? How could having a dynamic engine continuously regenerating the same static content have become the standard of the Internet? Is this really this hard to implement proper handling of images (resizing, compression, load order) in 2019?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could having a dynamic engine continuously regenerating the same static content have become the standard of the Internet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Florent Chauveau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started-with-the-static-web&#34;&gt;Getting started with the static web
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are convinced that static websites will become commonplace shortly. In the meantime, it&amp;rsquo;s super easy to beat a bloated dynamic website at the SEO-game using a static one: now it the time to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo was a fit for our tech blog as it helped us streamline the content editing process while achieving impressive organic results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2019/staticweb/searchconsole.png&#34;
         alt=&#34;Blog.CALLR.tech Organic performance&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, the offer of static website generators and other related services greatly expanded since the release of Jekyll in 2008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering a static engine for your next website, please check our &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/p/the-edge-of-the-static-web/&#34; &gt;follow-up article covering the main frameworks and tools you can use as well some tips and best practices to develop killer static websites.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://kinsta.com/wordpress-market-share/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;WordPress Market Share&lt;/a&gt; — Kinsta.com, 2019&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1/ Cache/Minification plugin, 2/CDN, 3/ Image Compressor, 4/ SEO (YoastSEO, RankMath), 5/ Redirect, 6/Security, 7/ Comment Spam Management, 8/Formatting (Code Syntax, Shortcode, External Links, etc.) Any other common feature will require yet another plugin, including: multilingual, social share buttons, markdown import, footnotes, table of content, carousel…&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://speedcurve.com/blog/web-performance-page-bloat/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The average web page is 3MB. How much should we care?&lt;/a&gt; — Tammy Everts, Speed Matters, August 2017&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_Internet_connection_speeds#Average_connection_speeds&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;List of countries by Internet connection speeds&lt;/a&gt; — Wikipedia&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://neilpatel.com/blog/loading-time/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How Loading Time Affects Your Bottom Line&lt;/a&gt; — Neil Patel, Neil Patel Blog, August 2018&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exploring and Industry &amp; Finding Content Ideas: a matter of tools?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/exploring-and-industry-finding-content-ideas-a-matter-of-tools/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 13:21:53 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/exploring-and-industry-finding-content-ideas-a-matter-of-tools/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Exploring and Industry &amp; Finding Content Ideas: a matter of tools?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Knowing the audience is the key to successful content; it’s the key to successful marketing itself. Yet, for a start-up and moreover at an early stage, &lt;strong&gt;it’s damn hard&lt;/strong&gt;. I tried a lot of different tools before finding the one I’m happy with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The theory is known, and well documented online: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://backlinko.com/skyscraper-technique&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Skycrapper Technique&lt;/a&gt; is now commonplace. Yet, I find that jumping from theory to field tests and implementation is probably the toughest step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/explaining-seo.gif&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Explaining SEO - Source: webconfs.com | Check it out for more SEO-related comics&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Explaining SEO - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.webconfs.com/seo-comics.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Source: webconfs.com | Check it out for more SEO-related comics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I’ll walk your through the basics of exploring an industry using a mix of free and paid tools in order find content ideas and insights to improve your web presence&lt;/strong&gt;. To make it less abstract, I’ll use insights gathered with SEMRush on the telecommunications industry, during the March-April 2017 period to demonstrate my case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;exploring-and-analyzing-seo-strategies&#34;&gt;Exploring and analyzing SEO strategies
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The SEO Arms race&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to spot top organic performing content, you’ll need tools. Some free tools can do, but you’ll find yourself using &lt;strong&gt;dozens of them&lt;/strong&gt; in order to match the possibilities offered on a premium SEO service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was looking for my SEO all-in-one dream tool, I put MozPro and SEMRush to the test for a month since both offer a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;//www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34; &gt;free trial&lt;/a&gt;. To sum it in one sentence, the difference between the two lies in the &lt;strong&gt;accessibility versus exhaustivity dilemma&lt;/strong&gt;. While MozPro is easy to on board, SEMRush can be intimidating; yet it offers more features and add new ones at an impressive rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEMRush was particularly useful to track the results of your SEO efforts, be it search position or backlinks. Its usefulness doesn’t stop here as you can use SEMRush on any domain. &lt;strong&gt;Looking at competitors’ metrics&lt;/strong&gt; helps to discover opportunities and to &lt;strong&gt;confirm hunches you may have on potential strategies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true value of SEMRush to me lies in two things. First, it does in one single tool what would require 15+ free tools. Also, the data given by free tools won’t be as &lt;strong&gt;detailed, precise, and easy to access&lt;/strong&gt;. Second, the depth and the scope of the data provided is arguably unmatched by other paid services and nonexistent in free services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dig into the Rolls Royce, &lt;strong&gt;let’s see how far some free tools can get you&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free SEO tools and services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sheer amount of tools, web-services, chrome extensions and such made for SEO and Content is overwhelming. The following tools list is just &lt;strong&gt;a partial, and ultimately biased selection&lt;/strong&gt; that should help you get started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The essentials toolbox&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/screaming-frog.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Checking a blog sitemap (Screaming Frog)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Checking a blog sitemap (Screaming Frog)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.screamingfrog.co.uk/seo-spider/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Screaming Frog SEO Spider&lt;/a&gt;: It’s a &lt;strong&gt;swiss-army knife tool&lt;/strong&gt;, used for anything from finding broken links to checking for duplicate content or analyzing pages titles and meta descriptions. It’s one of the few free tools I find myself using frequently, even when I have access to a premium tool.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.alexa.com/siteinfo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Alexa Ranking&lt;/a&gt;: Very basic, but it still gives you an idea of the current traffic flow to a given website and its recent trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.spyfu.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Spyfu &lt;/a&gt;— This tool is very valuable to get an idea for the AdWords strategy of your competition, including CPC, keyword and creatives.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.dareboost.com/en/home&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Dareboost&lt;/a&gt;: Check your websites and your competitors for web performance, security and on-page SEO optimizations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keyword Exploration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://adwords.google.com/home/tools/keyword-planner/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Keyword Planner&lt;/a&gt; — very useful tool for keyword discovery and CPC/volume estimations. You can also mix and match words to produce new keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://trends.google.com/trends/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Trends&lt;/a&gt; — easily compare volumes between different keywords, see data on volume such as interest over time, where are the search made, or related topics and queries. + &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.google.com/trends/correlate&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Google Trends Correlate&lt;/a&gt; — Find keywords correlated to yours. Here are two Google Trends I like to use to showcase the potent of the tool: queries on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” (with the New Year’s Eve impact) and queries on “gift” and “present” (with Christmas’ impact).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends1.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A somehow famous Google Trends: volume on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” reaches its peak just after New Year’s Eve&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A somehow famous Google Trends: volume on “running”, “fitness” and “diet” reaches its peak just after New Year’s Eve&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;A similar dynamics is observed for “gift” and “refund”. “Gift” peaks a week before Christmas while “Refund” peaks mid-February.&#34;
	
	
&gt;
A similar dynamics is observed for “gift” and “refund”. “Gift” peaks a week before Christmas while “Refund” peaks mid-February.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Trends is one of the most basic tool there is, yet it can give you invaluable insights. &lt;strong&gt;Trends are strongly correlated with the real world&lt;/strong&gt; and now used for literally anything such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://qz.com/1052656/bitcoin-price-google-trends-can-help-you-figure-where-bitcoins-price-is-headed/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;to estimate prices evolution of cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;, measure volume distribution for similar keywords, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://searchengineland.com/google-trends-election-hub-offers-deep-dive-search-trends-2016-candidates-political-issues-258784&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;gauge the efficiency of political communications.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a last one with Hillary vs Trump over the last 9 months of the campaign. Ignoring the massive spike on the Election Day, Trump was consistently generating more volume that Hillary months before the election. &lt;strong&gt;Even if the election was a surprise to most, the data doesn’t lie: it clearly hinted a Trump victory for a long-time before he was elected.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/gtrends3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Searches about Hillary and Trump, between the 01/01/2016 and the 11/30/2016 (the election was the 8)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Searches about Hillary and Trump, between the 01/01/2016 and the 11/30/2016 (the election was the 8)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ubersuggest.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ubersuggest &lt;/a&gt;— Find new keywords with suggestions based on one keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://keywordin.com/keyword-generator.php&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Keywordin’s Keyword Generator&lt;/a&gt; — Mix and match different words or groups of words together to create more long trend variations of your keywords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/relatedkw.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Level 1/2/3 related keywords for “content promotion” using SEOChat&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Level 1/2/3 related keywords for “content promotion” using SEOChat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://tools.seochat.com/tools/related-keywords-tool/#sthash.PVTTGKHQ.HntdXy5H.dpbs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SEOChat Related Keyword&lt;/a&gt; — Find level 1/2/3 (long trend) related keywords based on one given keyword.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SEMRush insights’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of this article, I’ll show what kind of insights a premium tool can land. The insights presented below were gathered using SEMRush ($99/m) during the &lt;strong&gt;March-April 2017 period&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEMRush works as an “SEO search engine”. In the top bar, you can input any domains (yours or competition’s) and get precise metrics on it including backlinks, top keywords, paid vs organic distribution… Here’s how it looks like on a sample domain query (twilio.com):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/domain-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Domain overview for twilio.com (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Domain overview for twilio.com (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;domain overview&lt;/strong&gt; include metrics about backlinks, their types, anchors… Every entry is accessible in a dedicated and exportable full report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/img/2017/seo-tools/backlinks.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Backclink section of Twilio’s domain overview (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Backclink section of Twilio’s domain overview (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also search keywords. The overview tab will give you data about organic and paid volumes, search results and copies. Two other tabs are dedicated to keywords: phrase match and related keywords. &lt;strong&gt;The amount if data available on any keyword is really vast, this where SEMRush shines; as long as the search volume is sufficient.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/keyword-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Keyword overview for “SMS API”: Twilio is clearly dominating for now (SEMRush)&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Keyword overview for “SMS API”: Twilio is clearly dominating for now (SEMRush)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together, the tools provided by SEMRush let you conduct true &lt;strong&gt;surveys of your competitors’ digital activities and estimate the success of their strategies&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a quick overview of the insights gathered during the first round of competitor’s analysis for &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.callr.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CALLR,&lt;/a&gt; a voice and SMS API and SIP Trunking provider (03–28–2017) using SEMRush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A voice and SMS API essentially allows computers to interact directly with phone networks. Services such as Twilio’s, CALLR’s, or Nexmo’s are behind the text messages you get to confirm your authentication on websites (2FA), the notification texts you can get from services such as Uber or Amazon, etc. and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://customers.twilio.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;em&gt;many other use cases&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;involving automated phone calls and text messages.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Over 12% of Twilio’s organic traffic comes from a single article&lt;/strong&gt;, not strongly related to their expertise. Indeed, it’s a &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.twilio.com/blog/2017/02/an-easy-way-to-read-and-write-to-a-google-spreadsheet-in-python.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;tutorial detailing how to handle (read and write) Google Sheets with Python&lt;/a&gt;. 12% of Twilio’s organic entries is around 15K monthly sessions according to SEMRush. It could be surprising but it makes sense: people using Voice/SMS APIs find themselves interacting with huge sheets quite often, contact lists for instance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 10% of Sinch’s organic traffic come from keywords related (or matching) &lt;strong&gt;flash call&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the business use case they put forward. ~38% of their organic traffic lands on their tutorials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still on Sinch, &lt;strong&gt;41/500 of their top queries were due to an extensive tutorial&lt;/strong&gt; (with 700+ comments) on how to build a messaging app on Android. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sinch.com/tutorials/android-messaging-tutorial-using-sinch-and-parse&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Now the page returns a 404&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nexmo’s present a sensibly different organic traffic profile than the rest of the competition. While most providers get the bulk of their organic search traffic from brand or even exact query, &lt;strong&gt;Nexmo’s top entry points are their products pages&lt;/strong&gt;, especially the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nexmo.com/products/sms&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SMS page&lt;/a&gt; (25% of organic sessions) and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nexmo.com/products/chat&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Chat app page&lt;/a&gt; (another 12%). At CALLR, we studied them extensively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The American competitor CallFire is deploying &lt;strong&gt;a smart strategy to increase their organic presence&lt;/strong&gt;. They have seemingly auto-generated page to match every US area code. A large part of their traffic comes from people looking for “XXX area code”. Conversion on this traffic must be low though.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, SEMRush helps you find an already field-tested, working strategy used by your competitors. While your chances of achieving the same success by purely replicating them are slim, it gives you an idea of what works in the industry and what people are looking for. &lt;strong&gt;Just as a note, it’s the first time I share this unexploited list, and even though the tips are 6 months old, they might still be valid&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the list above, the first one I would address would be Sinch 404’s as it’s the most straightforward: your job would be to &lt;strong&gt;produce a tutorial on the same topic&lt;/strong&gt;, better than Sinch, and then reach out to all those who still links to Sinch’s 404 to offer your own tutorial instead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the page is now a 404, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160408195857/https://www.sinch.com/tutorials/android-messaging-tutorial-using-sinch-and-parse/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;using the Internet Archive you can still access the original tutorial&lt;/a&gt; to see what you’ll have to overtake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can try both SEMRush and MozPro for free to make up your mind&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moz.com/products/pro&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MozPro&lt;/a&gt; offers a free one month trial and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;you can get a free trial of SEMRush&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-content-performing-on-social-network-withbuzzsumo&#34;&gt;Finding content performing on social network with BuzzSumo
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://buzzsumo.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BuzzSumo&lt;/a&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;social analytics and monitoring tool.&lt;/strong&gt; Before I dig in, it’s time for a disclaimer. BuzzSumo is $99/month with a 14-days free trial. Because of the price, I decided to opt out of it, but I did use it for the duration of the free trial. It helped me get a better understanding of the dynamics in my industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering my limited experience with the tool, I won’t go into too much depths. If you’re considering paying for BuzzSumo and using it extensively, I recommend you to read these comprehensive resources: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://raelyntan.com/buzzsumo-tutorial/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Raelyn Tan’s BuzzSumo tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://buzzsumo.com/knowledge/getting-started-with-buzzsumo/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;BuzzSumo’s team itself densely document its product&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can search for topics or keywords and see the most shared (social) content. You can go even further and see, for any given post, &lt;strong&gt;the accounts who shared it allowing you to understand how each post got&lt;/strong&gt; its reach. This is also particularly useful is you are publishing similar content: it gives you a list of people potentially interested in sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/buzzsumo.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;The results of a search on BuzzSumo&#34;
	
	
&gt;
The results of a search on BuzzSumo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set up the BuzzSumo trial in February, to find the top-content addressing VoIP, SIP, and telco APIs. Back then, I recently joined CALLR and was in a reading spree to get a better hang of the main themes to address. Thanks to BuzzSumo, I &lt;strong&gt;compiled a list of the top-performing content&lt;/strong&gt; of the industry. I sorted them according to varied factors: topics, quality of content, approach, tone, targeted audience… Then, looking at sharers, I tried to &lt;strong&gt;correlate these factors to the article’s performance&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BuzzSumo’s main strength is that it’s a &lt;strong&gt;must-have tool if you want to use the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://backlinko.com/skyscraper-technique&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;&lt;strong&gt;skyscraper technique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; It facilitates the process of finding people potentially interested by your content. Indeed, BuzzSumo’s main strength is that it lets you see the list of sharers of a given content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2017/seo-tools/buzzsumo-sharers.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Preview of the sharer list feature&#34;
	
	
&gt;
Preview of the sharer list feature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yet, the metrics it gives you can be hard to interpret&lt;/strong&gt;. For instance, in the telco industry I found basic heavily-shared 500–1000 words articles, sometime even just basic product pages from competitors, not particularly qualitative. The gist? Most of these shares are on LinkedIn, and it turns out &lt;strong&gt;a lot of these shares comes from the company’s own employees.&lt;/strong&gt; If a 2000+ employees company manage to get them to share their own content, it can really skew the results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My advice with BuzzSumo is to &lt;strong&gt;dig deeper.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t stop at what BuzzSumo gives you. This is also part of the reason I decided to not subscribe to it: it facilitates the research of content performing on social and influencers, but &lt;strong&gt;it’s not sufficient by itself&lt;/strong&gt; as it relies on indicators that are easily fooled (shares, likes and such are easily bought or automated).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;From theory to practice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the most actionable insights are sadly gated behind heavily priced tools. While BuzzSumo has its flaws due to the shaky nature of social media, it can prove itself useful from a company investing on social medias. On the other hand, a SEO/SEM tool seems to be a must have for any business in for the long-haul, looking to build a &lt;strong&gt;durable online presence&lt;/strong&gt;. Whatever tool you choose, you’re essentially looking for two major benefits:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/ Ability to fetch SEO and SEM data on your competitors / partners / any 3rd party website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2/ Greater tracking capabilities of your own and competitors domains metrics and content performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are just looking to &lt;strong&gt;facilitate your tracking efforts,&lt;/strong&gt; there are some tools cheaper than SEMRush or MozPro. For simple keyword position tracking, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.serplab.co.uk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;SERPLAB&lt;/a&gt; offering free version with the paid version starting at $5/m. For backlink tracking, check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.linkody.com/en/plans&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Linkody&lt;/a&gt; starting at 13€/m.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are serious about building a long-lasting web presence, you’ll eventually need one of the shiny big tools. Good luck finding your dream SEO toolbox, I’m still constantly tweaking mine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moz.com/checkout/freetrial&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Free trial on MozPro (1 month)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.semrush.com/sem/?ref=9864882220&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Free trial on SEMRush (7 days)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
