<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fleek.co on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fleek.co/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Fleek.co on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 14:53:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fleek.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hello, World!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/hello-world/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 14:53:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/hello-world/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/hello-world/infrastructure-fr.png" alt="Featured image of post Hello, World!" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my humble domain,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to take this project live. As often with me, what started as a simple project ended up becoming&amp;hellip; something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I started preparing this blog with a straightforward goal: I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing content on the web for a while, I wanted a place for all of it to live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I was at it, I looked at the different solutions available and realized it could be much more: it could turn into &lt;strong&gt;a minimalistic yet sufficient approach to deliver content online, no strings attached.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, introducing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenbricexyz-a-blog-respecting-your-privacy&#34;&gt;Tokenbrice.xyz, a blog respecting your privacy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made this blog as a callout: I&amp;rsquo;m no dev, I can barely code, and yet I was able to respect my reader&amp;rsquo;s privacy, to an unprecedented level in the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, TokenBrice.xyz relies on open source frameworks and solutions such as Hugo (rendering of the blog) or Matomo (privacy-conscious analytics).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those interested, this blog implements full IP anonymisation, cookies non-propagation, in full compliance with the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cnil.fr/sites/default/files/typo/document/Configuration_piwik.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CNIL guidelines&lt;/a&gt; - an independent French&amp;rsquo; administrative body acting as a privacy watchdog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tokenbrice.xyz is deployed on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ipfs.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;IPFS&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely happy with the infrastructure just yet, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s significant progress compared to most existing websites:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/hello-world/infrastructure.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;tokenbrice-xyz-infrastructure-overviewe&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dont-compromise-when-asking-for-more-privacy-conscious-solutions&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t compromise when asking for more privacy-conscious solutions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nothing will be done, ever, even in the DeFi industry, unless us users make our concerns heard. &lt;strong&gt;So, check your favourite projects&amp;rsquo; websites - and let them know how dirty they&amp;rsquo;ve been!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use tools such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://privacybadger.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Privacy Badger&lt;/a&gt; to see how many trackers they have &amp;amp; block them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/hello-world/privacy-badger.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;privacy-badger&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A basic CoinTelegraph page has 14 trackers.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, please, assume best intentions: trackers and other privacy-intrusive devices are embedded in many systems, sometimes insidiously.  Do not assume a malicious intent as soon as you see a tracker. This tracker can be here for other reasons, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of knowledge (I know nothing and made it)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of care for your privacy (probably)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of resources (so to them, privacy is not a priority)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s spell it out in case it&amp;rsquo;s not clear enough: there are no valid reasons for someone to ship a privacy-intrusive website nowadays especially if the site is &amp;ldquo;read-only&amp;rdquo;, like this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet there are still too many out there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So &lt;strong&gt;let&amp;rsquo;s call these potentially — ignorant, if not — careless, if not — lazy, if not — not-giving-a-fuck-about-privacy developers out.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can barely touch an HTML file, and I did it — &lt;strong&gt;so if you truly care, quit your bullshit and get to work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ♥ love,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TokenBrice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
