<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Unstoppable DeFi on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/unstoppable-defi/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Unstoppable DeFi on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/unstoppable-defi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/jr-strategist/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2023/jr-strategist/jr-strategist-cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Hiring a Junior DeFi Strategist to help foster the growth of immutable protocols" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a Junior DeFi Strategist to join me on my daily DeFi adventures, learn and grow. The fundamental missions are governance proposals, liquidity management, business development, and partnerships, but the scope is quite flexible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a unique opportunity for a passionate DeFi curious to jumpstart his/her career in crypto. Be the first hire for a community-led effort to cater governance-minimized and immutable protocols to achieve the mission of DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll be working closely with me and learn my tactics to successfully grow liquidity and utility for immutable DeFi projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-activities&#34;&gt;Your activities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seek and find new partnership opportunities for DeFi projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collaborate with other DeFi protocols and DAOs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write governance proposals, and support proposals submitted by third parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage strategies enforced on the various liquidity-driver tokens owned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimize Protocol Owned Liquidity strategies across main net and L2s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write and tweet about partnerships and liquidity opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-experience-and-skills&#34;&gt;Your experience and skills
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensive DeFi on chain track record - who cares about diplomas? Show me a wallet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actively involved in DeFi, owning some key governance tokens, knowledgeable about the main models (Liquity, Curve, Aave, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solid understanding of DEXs like Curve, Uniswap, Balancer and voting protocols I.e.  Convex, Aura as well as ve(3,3) models like e.g. Velodrome&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Well versed in the differences of cvxCRV, yCRV, sdCRV, uCRV, and aCRV
Solid understanding of the top DeFi protocols and good overview of the promising newcomers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You’re already active on various governance forums or DeFi-related Discords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Written and spoken English proficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work independently as well as team up with your peers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-i-can-offer&#34;&gt;What I can offer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exciting part time position (~50%) with a monthly retainer in FIAT (for the beginning)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drive a community-led initiative (more to be announced soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be part of a top notch and proven DeFi team&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work remotely (ideally in Europe or US timezone)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested? &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forms.gle/6qaXgkczuhiaqNTV6&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Please apply via this form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ll get back in touch shortly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Announcement: Joining Liquity to bolster the growth of unstoppable DeFi</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/joining-liquity/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/joining-liquity/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/tokenbrice-liquity/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post Announcement: Joining Liquity to bolster the growth of unstoppable DeFi" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little less involved in the DeFi discussion lately  and you might righfully wonder why. First, I needed to slow down and take some time for myself, and the timing could not be better. While I was off, I had the time to reflect on what drew me to DeFi in the first place and how the space has evolved since I started getting involved about four years ago. Watching protocols with massive design flaws blowing up is reassuring, especially to those who anticipated it, but not exactly what I dreamed of when I discovered DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;has-defi-lost-its-way&#34;&gt;Has DeFi lost its way?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To me, it seems like we&amp;rsquo;ve lost our ways. TradFi turned into the non-sensical monster we know not on purpose nor by design: it was simply the result of every person and entity trying to pull the blanket to themselves: &lt;strong&gt;an accumulation of individual&amp;rsquo;s greed&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The developments during this last year in DeFi felt very similar to TradFi&amp;rsquo;s avarice: in terms of building a resilient and self-sovereign financial system for all, close to nothing was achieved. Instead, most of the releases were focused on delivering yet another flavor of ponzinomics to sustain the greed of apes for a few weeks until they move to the next shiny farm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remain convinced that what &lt;strong&gt;we need in the end-game are systems able to resist the (potentially coordinated) attacks of states, organized crime, and whales&lt;/strong&gt;. Most of the current protocols available in DeFi would not stand a day against structured attacks of significant magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large share of &amp;ldquo;DeFi&amp;rdquo; protocols are vulnerable to the good old wrench attack because of their reliance on multisigs: identifying, locating and threatening a dozen individuals is not an arduous task, especially when billions are at stake. Economic attacks can also seriously affect another significant share of DeFi protocols, especially if perpetrated by an actor willing to burn money in the process. Finally, governance attacks are so commonplace it&amp;rsquo;s not even exciting to cover them anymore. It is not the DeFi I signed up for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve built a platform and shed light on the projects that brought something new and relevant to the table during the last few years. Complimentary to my analysis and commentaries, I&amp;rsquo;ve supported several projects, shared my insights with creative and sensible teams, and sometimes been involved in the governance processes. Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt ready to assume a more active role within the ecosystem: today is the day! I&amp;rsquo;m confident my honest, sometimes brutal, yet always informed approach was and still is something lacking in the industry where shills are king.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;announcing-tokenbrice-x-liquity&#34;&gt;Announcing: TokenBrice x Liquity
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m delighted to announce that I&amp;rsquo;ve joined &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/liquity/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Liquity&lt;/a&gt; as Head of Marketing to support the growth of protocol, mainly focusing on a yet-to-be-announced project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the Liquity protocol is just over a year old, the team has already been active and building for much longer. What has been achieved is truly unique, remarkable, and needed. Liquity is the &lt;strong&gt;first and still only lending service available in DeFi that is  unstoppable&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; likewise, LUSD is the only stablecoin capable of resisting all kinds of censorships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What always amazed me is that this feat is delivered without compromising on the protocol&amp;rsquo;s efficiency: Liquity is extremely cost-efficient, and the protocol&amp;rsquo;s design is one of rare elegance. Liquity is &lt;strong&gt;built like mission-critical software&lt;/strong&gt;: failure is not an option. I&amp;rsquo;m glad such a protocol, truthful to the root spirit of DeFi, exists, and I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled to get the chance to help it grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar yet with what Liquity does and why it matters, feel free this intro:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/liquity-protocol.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;⚖️ Liquity: an unstoppable, efficient and innovative borrowing service&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-will-i-do&#34;&gt;What will I do?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Liquity, I&amp;rsquo;ll spearhead the growth efforts through all relevant channels: documentation, content strategy, media, events, and more, without forgetting, of course, to fuel the memetic. While I&amp;rsquo;ll mostly focus on an upcoming and yet to be announced product, I&amp;rsquo;ll also support the existing one in all relevant ways. With my efforts to craft and grow Liquity&amp;rsquo;s narrative, the community&amp;rsquo;s support, I&amp;rsquo;m confident Liquity&amp;rsquo;s prime time is yet to come!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still entirely convinced that great things are built from the bottom-up: I&amp;rsquo;ll be in close touch with the Liquity&amp;rsquo;s community to incorporate its insights and feedback at every possible level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I&amp;rsquo;m excited by the mission, my latest time-off taught me a lot about work/life balance: therefore, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to keep my involvement with Liquity part-time. It lets me make sure I still have the time for a healthy personal life and hobbies, including DeFi, such as conducting my research and sharing them with you on this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my live shows on Twitch, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to the weekly rhythm I used to have, but I&amp;rsquo;m not excluding some occasional shows to discuss relevant protocols and topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m thrilled for this next step of my journey and eager to share more with you regarding what is coming next for unstoppable DeFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🤗 Thanks to all my readers and listeners for your support so far. I have several upcoming blog posts with unique insights to share with you in the coming months, so stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
