<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Maker on TokenBrice</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/maker/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Maker on TokenBrice</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>Example Person</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/maker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Mar 2022 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/defi-vs-inflation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/defi-vs-inflation-tokenbrice-cover.jpg" alt="Featured image of post How to build an inflation-proof DeFi portfolio?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation is more than ever at the center of discussions and concerns: no one understands much about it, no economist has really anticipated it, but we all have an opinion about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we leave economics and politics aside to focus on what matters for your wallet: in decentralized finance, all kinds of protocols are developed, and a good part of them &lt;strong&gt;provide credible and innovative tools to preserve and develop the purchasing power of a portfolio&lt;/strong&gt;, even when the macroeconomic context is most uncertain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I propose to evaluate strategies involving different assets and protocols, all with the same goal: to preserve and develop the effective purchasing power of a given portfolio. Nevertheless, we have to start with the basics, level 0: what is inflation and why should we, DeFians, care about it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The cover image was made by a generous anonymous contributor and features the majestic &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rarible.com/valkyre/created&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Valkyr-E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;α-tutorial-understanding-the-impact-of-inflation-on-a-crypto-portfolio&#34;&gt;α/ Tutorial: Understanding the impact of inflation on a crypto portfolio
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t venture into the details of inflation for fiat currencies here, but the basic concept is known to anyone familiar with cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty, let&amp;rsquo;s start with the term: here is how the INSEE (Institut National de la Statistique et des Études Économiques) defines inflation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation is the loss of purchasing power of money that results in a general and lasting increase in prices. It must be distinguished from the increase in the cost of living. The loss of value of money is a phenomenon that hits the national economy as a whole (households, businesses, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just remember that, &lt;strong&gt;just like in DeFi where each token is associated with a protocol and potentially even an ecosystem, each fiat currency is also based on an economy as well as a set of rules&lt;/strong&gt; (legal system).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-macro-point-of-view-scale--country&#34;&gt;Inflation, macro point of view (scale = country)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation corresponds to the production of new money, the important thing is not so much the quantity of money created, but more &lt;strong&gt;what is done with&lt;/strong&gt;. We all understand this rather well with two caricatural examples at each extreme:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country A issues a large amount of money in order to invest massively in its transport infrastructure and its energy supply (= long-term investments).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here, inflation can be controlled because the new money issued is used to finance investments that develop the country&amp;rsquo;s economic potential in the long run (-&amp;gt; compensation).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central bank of country B issues a large amount of money to finance an emergency plan to compensate for the foreseeable consequences of previous pseudo-sanitary measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In this second scenario, the new money is used to cover a &amp;ldquo;current expense&amp;rdquo; of the government. The personal equivalent would be to go into debt every day to pay for lunch. This is obviously unsustainable in the long run. In this scenario, inflation can only be massive as a large amount of new money is issued, while the economic potential of the country in question stagnates or deteriorates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;evaluating-future-inflation&#34;&gt;Evaluating future inflation?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enough about the macro, let&amp;rsquo;s go back to our scale, with things we know well. Here is the evolution of the M1 money supply on the dollar, this allows us to visualize its &amp;ldquo;marketcap&amp;rdquo; in a way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/USD-m1-supply.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;USD M1 Supply&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we only look at M1 for simplicity but the trend is similar on M2 and M3.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are interested here in the dollar which, although challenged, remains the fiduciary currency that sets the tone. As you can see, the curve has been going vertical since the beginning of the Covid crisis. The curve is now much scarier than the worst shitcoins I have ever seen. Doubt it? Consider the same information, presented in this light:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The dollar has been around since 1914. 20% of all dollars in circulation were created in 2020. At the current rate, the total amount of dollars in circulation doubles about every 4-5 years.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To compare with crypto, many are concerned about inflation / new token issuance on Curve Finance (CRV). The 4 year issuance curve looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/crv-release-schedule.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;crv-release-schedule&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m no economist, but I know my shitcoins. The official US inflation figure we are given is 7.5% per year. Like unemployment figures, it&amp;rsquo;s a highly political metric that&amp;rsquo;s hard to really appreciate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7.5% figure may seem high, but it is still low when compared to the unprecedented money creation to deal with Covid. So I expect to see this inflation rise further, or else to be sustained over an extended period of a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So inflation is here, at 7.5% minimum for several years at least. Enough with boomers&amp;rsquo; macro, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the range of tools that the DeFi offers us to face it and overcome it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-beating-inflation-with-classic-stablecoin-returns&#34;&gt;I/ Beating inflation with &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; stablecoin returns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first approach is as always the simplest, &lt;strong&gt;the brute force method&lt;/strong&gt;: an inflation of 7.5% means that USD left as is will lose 7.5% of their value over the year. The point here is to find a source of return higher than inflation: the difference between the two is the effective return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With inflation at 7.5% on the USD, I think it is prudent to make sure to &lt;strong&gt;reach at least 1.5x this figure in yield&lt;/strong&gt; to really consider yourself inflation-proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the game is simple and the rules fairly easy to understand:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You start with a position in a given stablecoin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The goal is to make it productive, without assuming IL risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With a return that exceeds the inflation figure, once the gas costs have been amortized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;simple-stablecoin-deposit&#34;&gt;Simple stablecoin deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we would aim for &lt;strong&gt;a 10.875% annual return on stablecoin $ at the very least&lt;/strong&gt;. With recent declines and yield compression this is increasingly difficult, but still findable even with a single stablecoin deposit without IL risk. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://coindix.com/?kind=stable&amp;amp;sort=-apy&amp;amp;chain=ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Coindix&lt;/a&gt; can help you find the vault of your dreams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/coindix.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;coindix&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be careful though, &lt;strong&gt;not all vaults are created equal&lt;/strong&gt;! For example, we see nice returns on Bancor on the screenshot: don&amp;rsquo;t forget to consider the volatility of these returns as well as the fees in gas to deploy the position (a Bancor LP is notoriously more expensive than a Yearn deposit for example).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mention it here only to forget it just as quickly afterwards: the &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.anchorprotocol.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Anchor protocol&lt;/a&gt; also offers you a &amp;ldquo;fixed&amp;rdquo; return close to 20% on UST stablecoin. Such a guaranteed rate does not come, of course, without serious compromises that raise real questions about the sustainability of this whole ecosystem (Terra/Luna).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;provision-of-liquidity--time-commitment&#34;&gt;Provision of liquidity + time commitment
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Still in dollars, but a bit riskier, we can consider different types of commitments, with very controlled / no IL risks. For example, a liquidity provision between FRAX and DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-dai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/DAI LP opportunities on Frax&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here it is at &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax Finance&lt;/a&gt;, the prime rate (x1) is just our minimum target, but it is possible to reach up to x5 with two types of commitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X3 by locking LP tokens for 3 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;X2 by using your veFXS (much harder to reach)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The effective return on a position locked in for three years corresponds to about 3 times our minimum target, thus offering a credible protection against the loss of value due to the consequences of inflation, but you still have to be able to assume the three-year commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example is taken here on DAI, but the situation is similar on the other major stablecoins; for example, here are the FRAX/USDC pools:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/frax-usdc.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;FRAX/USDC LP opportunities&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convex for Frax is coming (optimizing Frax LP farming via Convex), if you don&amp;rsquo;t have your own veFXS, it&amp;rsquo;s probably pertinent to wait until the service is released to make a decision with all the cards in hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tokenizing-and-speculating-on-future-yields&#34;&gt;Tokenizing and speculating on future yields
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To beat that famous 10% return on the dollar, there are still many other options. I present you one last one here to help you consider the other possible strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this one, we rely on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;, a protocol that allows the tokenization of future yields on productive assets. The principle is both simple and complex: depositing an asset on APWine allows to separate its future yield (FYT: Future Yield Token) from the underlying principal (PT: Principal Token).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, different strategies are possible, such as immediately selling the future yield (FYT) in order to increase the quantity of the productive principal. Such a tool enables better risk management considering the volatily of yields observed in DeFi&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s keep it simple and still well above the 10% requirement: let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on the aUSDT vault of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.apwine.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;APWine&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apwine-USDT-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine aUSDT vault&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I automatically exclude the PT/FYT pool which is more complex to understand and has much higher risks than the PT/Underlying offering a 44% return in APW anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here the strategy is simple, but you have to &lt;strong&gt;keep in mind the important gas costs linked to the use of APWine&lt;/strong&gt;. To implement the strategy using USDT in the wallet, you need to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit a part of them on Aave (I&amp;rsquo;d recommend 55% of the total maximum for this specific strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Deposit the aUSDT obtained in 1 on APWine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow (x2) + Deposit the PT and Underlying (USDT) tokens as liquidity providing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow + Stake of the LPs PT/Underlying tokens to obtain the return in APW&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t forget also the gas fees related to the APW claims + unwinding of the position at the end of the period (or before).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is therefore better to wait for a day when the transactions clear under 30 gwei so as not to suffer too much from the gas costs on such a strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantage here, compared to Frax for example, is that &lt;strong&gt;the position is much more liquid&lt;/strong&gt;. APWine works with an epoch logic that lasts 90 days. Thus, to more easily amortize the costs in gas it is preferable to deploy the strategy at the beginning of the epoch: this is also when the returns are generally the highest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third winelisting (where the next tokens supported on APWine are decided) has just ended, so don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to prepare for it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/apw-winelisting3.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;APWine - Winelisting 3&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;APWine is still a young protocol, but the governance is dynamic. The next step is approaching: as on Curve, it will soon be the veAPW holders (locked APW) that &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gov.apwine.fi/t/apgp-2-enable-gauges-for-apw-rewards/171&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;will decide on emissions&lt;/a&gt; for each given vault. A redistribution of the cards is to be expected, plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-hedged-productive-positions-with-various-alternative-stablecoins&#34;&gt;II/ Hedged productive positions with various &amp;ldquo;alternative&amp;rdquo; stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have stayed for now on the dollar, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to begin with. Although dollar stablecoins are still largely dominant, there are now &lt;strong&gt;many stablecoins based on other fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt; such as EUR, JPY (Japanese Yen), CHF (Swiss Franc), KRW (Korean Won) or even CAD (Canadian Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides the few centralized stablecoins (EURS or EURT), this market is mostly covered by protocols that offer to create synthetic stablecoins backed by other stablecoins. This is the case for example with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://jarvis.network/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jarvis Network&lt;/a&gt;, which uses USDC to collateralize different types of stablecoins: jEUR, jCHF, jKRW, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;single-deposit&#34;&gt;Single deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yield opportunities with no/low IL for such stablecoins are still quite rare, and usually found on Curve: providing liquidity against other stablecoins based on the same fiat currency, if any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/curve-chf.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;CHF pool on Curve Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only a few stablecoins have lucrative single deposit options jEUR, jCHF, jJPY. They are based on the corresponding Curve pools, with additional incentives offered by Jarvis and other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via Jarvis (also available farmed by Harvest), it is also possible to generate a return without IL on jCAD and jJPY.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;fiatafiatb-liquidity-providing&#34;&gt;FiatA/FiatB Liquidity Providing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a slightly different approach, more risky, but also potentially more protective against inflation: providing liquidity on two stablecoins representing two different fiat currencies, for example EURT/3pool (USD) still on Curve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More interestingly, especially for smaller portfolios, many alternative stablecoins are available on Polygon or Avalanche, with a fairly dense ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jarvis offers jCHF-USDC, jEUR-USDC or jCAD-USDC pools with returns above 20%. Tools like &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://harvest.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Harvest.Finance&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://beefy.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Beefy.Finance&lt;/a&gt; can also be used to automatically compose the returns obtained:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/harvest-jarvis-2-stables.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Harvest Network Jarvis jFIAT&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning: depending on your base asset (e.g. USDC), exposure to EUR (or other currencies) can be lucrative or costly - depending on the evolution of the USDC/EUR exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, for the more adventurous among you, you should know that APWine is also available on Polygon and already supports several Jarvis tokens, such as the MooJarvis_4eur:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquidity contribution on Curve (4eur)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managed by Beefy Finance (moo)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which compounds return that Jarvis offers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, the addition of tokens voted during winelisting 3 will open new doors with the upcoming arrival on APWine/Polygon of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooKyber_USDC-jEUR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MooMai_USDC-MAI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;forex-borrowing&#34;&gt;Forex Borrowing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if liquidations don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, know that a Fuse pool on Polygon (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://polygon.market.xyz/pool/7&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Pool7 - Jarvis Forex Market&lt;/a&gt;) allows you to use different jFiat as collateral as well as to borrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/fuse-pool7.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Fuse pool 7&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With such a service, almost anything is possible, here are some examples to inspire you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long USD + short EUR = MAI in collateral, borrow jEUR then sell jEUR and potentially loop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short GBP via CHF = jCHF in collateral, borrow jGBP then sell and potential loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice tip&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#tip-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Tip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also note that the productive stablecoins m2CAD and m2JPY are available as collateral while keeping their yield: they can be interesting for more traditional leverage strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finding-your-balance&#34;&gt;Finding your balance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than just one magic position, what I like about Jarvis stablecoins is the ability to &lt;strong&gt;diversify easily into different types of fiat currencies&lt;/strong&gt;. Thanks to the low transaction fees on Polygon, it is quite possible to mix several different currencies and positions to make a coherent whole and well protected against its local inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, for a European (= spending €):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in stable productive € without IL, for example MooJarvis_4eur (+APWine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25% in jEUR/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;20% in stable productive dollar (e.g. aUSDT APWine strategy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;amp; Diversification: 15% jCHF/USDC + 15% jGBP/USDC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, while we&amp;rsquo;re on the subject of &amp;ldquo;exotic&amp;rdquo; stablecoins, you should know that there are also a few that track gold or silver - they can be relevant from this perspective too. For example XAUT (with Pool Curve XAUT/3crv). Gold and silver remain &lt;del&gt;barbaric&lt;/del&gt; boomers&amp;rsquo; relics, personally I see very little interest in them for a competent DeFian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-inflation-resistant-stablecoins&#34;&gt;III/ Inflation resistant stablecoins
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beating inflation is nice. Hedging it? Even better. But &lt;strong&gt;why not just abstract it&lt;/strong&gt;, using products that are naturally resistant to it? There are still very few stablecoins that are not tracking fiat currencies, but the supply is growing rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-the-first-dollar-free-stablecoin&#34;&gt;RAI, the first dollar-free stablecoin
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast, the very first &amp;ldquo;unpegged stablecoin.&amp;rdquo; Launched at a value of Pi in USD (3.14) in 2021, it has been moving between 3.02 and 3.06 almost since its launch. Given its recent arrival (just over a year), it&amp;rsquo;s hard to see how RAI will perform in a period of prolonged inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, diversifying a portion of your stablecoins into RAI may be an attractive option. In addition, there are different return options available on RAI:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple deposit without IL risk: Idle Finance deposits your RAI in Fuse/Aave to optimize the native return + incentives in FLX from Reflexer + incentives in IDLE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle-0.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/rai-idle.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Additional FLX incentives for RAI on Idle Finance&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By assuming IL risk via liquidity provision on Curve vs. 3pool, a better return is possible. The crvRAI can then be staked directly on Curve or via Convex or Yearn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is based on a mechanism inspired by Maker MCD but with many modifications to make it possible. To understand how it works, I invite you to read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;my dedicated article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;🚧 Signals that the mentioned protocol is still under development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;-an-inflation-resistant-stablecoin-the-frax-fpi&#34;&gt;🚧 An inflation-resistant stablecoin? The FRAX FPI
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Frax Price Index is a new protocol that should arrive soon within the Frax ecosystem. The goal is to offer a new stablecoin, which would follow the CPI (Consumer Price Index) to protect against inflation. Just like Frax, &lt;strong&gt;the system is based on two tokens&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the stable - Frax Price Index (FPI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and the governance token - Frax Price Index Share (FPIS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/frax-price-index/inflation-hedge&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Frax documentation&lt;/a&gt; offers some information about the upcoming token. &lt;strong&gt;An airdrop of FPIS is planned&lt;/strong&gt; for veFXS or cvxFXS holders. Thus, the protocol will be independent of FRAX/FXS, although a value capture mechanism to FXS is planned beyond the initial airdrop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is hard to project solely on a mere design, but it is clear that a stablecoin that would maintain its value despite inflation is a very desirable product. &lt;strong&gt;There are several questions as to whether the peg on FPI can be maintained&lt;/strong&gt;: to keep its equilibrium, people will have to take the opposite trade to FPI, i.e. &amp;ldquo;short inflation&amp;rdquo;. However, in the current context of galloping inflation, it is hard to imagine who could assume such a position and massive incentives might be required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the arrival of the FPI is imminent. Traces of the token &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://etherscan.io/token/0xdb68c6264e9d0f8a6df1fa5a89f205da38698d15&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FPIS on EtherScan&lt;/a&gt; can be found as early as early March. I look forward to seeing the Frax team&amp;rsquo;s proposed design to address these consequential issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-inflation-resistance--degen--volt&#34;&gt;🚧 Inflation resistance + degen = VOLT
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI, there is another project I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely, waiting for a long time and holding high hopes for. The high-level concept is very simple: an Abracadabra-like product that would not be a walking security loophole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, Abracadabra allows borrowing from various productive collaterals, which makes the service desirable. Nevertheless, the infrastructure is close to a hack and the actions of the team members make Abracadabra a second or third grade money market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea here, with Volt, is to cover the same vertical using a proven infrastructure: the base offered by Reflexer (RAI). Three main changes are expected on this model:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike Reflexer, which only accepts ETH as collateral, Volt will diversify the available options, notably with productive collateral such as wstETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The value of VOLT, the system&amp;rsquo;s stablecoin, will be indexed to Frax&amp;rsquo;s FPI. The Reflexer infrastructure will be reused (PID controller adapted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Volt team is also working in collaboration with Fuse and Olympus.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To follow Volt, as always, the alpha lives on &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://discord.gg/dGhvDmCNGr&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the Discord&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I describe here the initial design of Volt Protocol, which has since evolved. The vision of creating a borrowing service with an inflation-proof stablecoin remains, but the technical choices have evolved. Read &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/volt-protocol/whitepaper/blob/main/volt.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the whitepaper available here&lt;/a&gt; for the latest information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;iv-beating-inflation-with-returns-on-volatile-assets&#34;&gt;IV/ Beating inflation with returns on volatile assets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In a world where nothing holds and value leaks, what&amp;rsquo;s left? How about good, proven DeFi assets backed by protocols with massive, recurring revenues shared directly with their holders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few of them, very few. We will detail them one by one, as well as the different options available on them to produce a return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;eth-the-origin-and-the-end&#34;&gt;ETH: the origin and the end
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is of course ETH, which has many different sources of return - just like stablecoins, there is nothing to stop you from diversifying your ETH exposure with several sources of return, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH staked with &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://lido.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Lido Finance &lt;/a&gt;(low yield, but a priori the safest) [~5%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LP &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://rocketpool.net/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;rETH&lt;/a&gt; on Curve (more innovative, more lucrative, more risky) [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vault covered call options on ETH via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stakedao.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stakedao&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ribbon.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Ribbon Finance&lt;/a&gt; [~25%, risks!]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross-chain liquidity on a Bridge, for example &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cbridge.celer.network/#/liquidity&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Celer&lt;/a&gt; [~10%]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A position balanced in this way tracks/exceeds inflation slightly with the returns obtained on ETH. The profitability of the position over the long term depends of course mainly on the average entry price on ETH and its evolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;crv-cvx-and-fxs-the-three-fates-of-the-defi&#34;&gt;CRV, CVX, and FXS: The three Fates of the DeFi?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the Romans, the Fates are three goddesses who govern the lives of humans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clotho weaves the thread of life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lachesis unwinds it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Atropos cuts it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DeFi also knows these Fates: three protocols that play a critical role in the survival and growth of potentially any other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, in addition to ETH, there are several DeFi projects that have already proven themselves, control substantial revenue streams, and offer a truly relevant service in a macro context of prolonged inflation; I see three essentially:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Curve Finance - CRV&lt;/strong&gt;: the mother of all yields in DeFi + peg machine and liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convex Finance - CVX&lt;/strong&gt;: an option on CRV, which controls almost 50% of all locked CRVs and adds real value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frax Finance - FXS&lt;/strong&gt;: innovative stable project, native DeFi, very productive via AMOs + arrival of FPI + Frax has a big position on CVX &amp;amp; some other protocols.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being tokens backed by key protocols in DeFi, there is no shortage of return options on these three tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CRV -&amp;gt; Deposit on Convex in CvxCRV then stake or LP cvxCRV/CRV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CVX -&amp;gt; Locked vote on Convex in vlCVX -&amp;gt; Return in cvxCRV + bribes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FXS -&amp;gt; Direct deposit on Frax (veFXS) or management via Convex (cvxFXS).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-promising-tokens&#34;&gt;Other promising tokens
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, there are still other projects that have not yet reached the profitability of Curve or Convex but represent credible bets. In a world where inflation is here to stay, the tools that will allow us to protect ourselves from it can become very popular: I propose you some other theses related to what has been already mentioned in the article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;apwinefi-apw-betting-on-the-advanced-defi-infrastructure&#34;&gt;APWine.fi (APW): betting on the advanced DeFi infrastructure
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;When inflation goes up, everyone is looking for yield. Let them run behind the %, and instead target the pick sellers in this gold rush. This is the main thesis behind a bet on APW.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you could see in the article already, APWine offers interesting products to bet on the evolution of yields or even realize a future yield immediately. As DeFi develops, the demand for a product like APWine will keep growing. Will it be APWine, or another one? It&amp;rsquo;s up to you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the APWine Wars coming up, it&amp;rsquo;s not a stretch to envision bribes similar to what we see on Convex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;reflexer-flx-a-bet-on-degovernance&#34;&gt;Reflexer (FLX): a bet on degovernance
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the very interesting technical approach, Reflexer also innovates on another level. Indeed, since the launch of the protocol, the team has presented a &amp;ldquo;De-governance Plan&amp;rdquo; aiming at progressively minimizing the team&amp;rsquo;s control over the protocol through two main means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of everything that can be automated&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Management by FLX holders for situations still requiring manual analysis/decision making.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;strong&gt;Reflexer now exceeds RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. The Money God League is a set of projects building using the Reflexer infrastructure, with the support of the team. So it seems quite natural to consider an airdrop of the governance token of these new projects, including VOLT, to FLX holders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last tip: the stakers of the FLX/ETH LP in the Reflexer Safety Module are the last resort to guarantee the solvency of the protocol. If I were to consider an airdrop to thank the Reflexer community, I would probably target them first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;looksrare-looks-bet-on-nfts&#34;&gt;LooksRare (LOOKS): bet on NFTs
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Think of LOOKS as an option on the NFT market. In fact, LooksRare is the first NFT marketplace that shares revenue. This translates into &lt;strong&gt;an ETH yield for stakers on LOOKS that reached 3 digits sustained during the first few weeks&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2022/defi-vs-inflation/looks-eth-farm.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;ETH yields on LOOKS staking&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, trading volume has dropped and the ETH yield with it, but &lt;strong&gt;the staking LOOKS is still one of the biggest ETH yields out there&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll stop with these three suggestions, but of course there are other options - you be the judge. For example, the QI Wars have started and the protocol has good traction. Be careful, however, not to fall into the trap of thinking that all protocols that adopt the ve + bribes model will be as successful as Curve and Convex. ve tokenomics will multiply: it&amp;rsquo;s about making the right choices!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-luck-and-happy-harvesting-&#34;&gt;Good luck and happy harvesting 🚜
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d be tempted to apologize for the length of this article, but I remain confident that it&amp;rsquo;s worth a read and will be informative even for the most knowledgeable DeFians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have considered other useful strategies or protocols for protecting against inflation, please feel free to suggest them to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For further reading, here are some recommended related articles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/crv-wars/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Curve Wars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/reflexer-rai/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding the Reflexer RAI model&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally, for the practice, which remains ESSENTIAL, your best bet to warm up is to try with small amounts on inexpensive sidechains/L2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The APWine protocol on Polygon to familiarize yourself with these mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minting jFIAT / Liquidity contribution on Curve + farming to discover Jarvis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long/short on Forex with jFiats + Fuse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure: I have invested in APWine pre-sale and I am a big user of the protocol. I am a user and frequent holder of almost all the protocols mentioned in this article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article does not constitute investment advice, I&amp;rsquo;m just sharing my research to help you do yours!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Thanks to &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/C53300&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Charles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/disiaque_eth&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Disiaque&lt;/a&gt; for their careful proofreading and their suggestions to help improve this article.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🗿 Reflexer Labs (RAI) : the What, How and Why</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/reflexer-rai/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Sep 2021 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/reflexer-rai/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/cover.gif" alt="Featured image of post 🗿 Reflexer Labs (RAI) : the What, How and Why" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a strange beast that many people still don&amp;rsquo;t understand or care about, including people who are really knowledgeable about DeFi. So it was time to offer you a rather exhaustive article dedicated to its subject. I&amp;rsquo;ve included everything I thought was relevant to understand why an asset like RAI is needed, what it does and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So get a cup of coffee and hang on, we&amp;rsquo;re in for a great ride!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-rais-context&#34;&gt;Understanding RAI&amp;rsquo;s context
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we even begin to get into the nitty-gritty, I think it&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand the context around RAI, i.e. the main stable assets used today and their limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The context for understanding RAI is quite dense, but the good news is that this is not the first time I have covered this topic on the blog. So I&amp;rsquo;ll refer you to some relevant reading to go deeper into the subject :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/pegged-assets.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Exploring stable assets on Ethereum: approaches &amp;amp; endgame&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-innovations.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Understanding innovations in money markets to envision their future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have time to explore the concept in depth with the articles proposed above, here are the two essential points to remember to fully understand the rest:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, &lt;strong&gt;the overwhelming majority of the stablecoin demand is covered by centralized solutions requiring trust&lt;/strong&gt;, the most used being USDT (~66 billion) and USDC (~27 billion).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whatever your preferred economic theses, especially in terms of inflation, I think we can easily agree on the need for stable assets that are not correlated to a fiduciary currency (= managed by a state).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-wusdc-trick&#34;&gt;The wUSDC trick
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I use the term &amp;ldquo;wrapped USDC&amp;rdquo; (wUSDC) to describe a situation that is common in alternative stablecoins: it is used to concisely and appropriately describe &lt;strong&gt;solutions that essentially use USDC as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;, a trusted stablecoin guaranteed by a central agency (Circle).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a situation, there is no need to go further, not even to analyze the details of the system: since their main collateral can be frozen or seized, &lt;strong&gt;stablecoins produced&lt;/strong&gt; in this way cannot be considered decentralized or trustless.**&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This kind of assets has a surprisingly large following, the main ones being Maker and Frax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;maker--a-majority-of-collateral-requiring-trust&#34;&gt;Maker = a majority of collateral requiring trust
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.defiscan.info/protocols/sky/ethereum&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker (DAI)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;approximately 60% of DAI are minted with USDC as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;, to which figure we need to add those minted from other collaterals requiring trust: wBTC, TUSD, GUSD, PAX, USDT, renBTC + all UniV2 pairs involving at least one of these tokens + all collaterals from the real world such as Centrifuge: New Silver. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://daistats.com/#/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Details on DAIStats&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/dai-collateral.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;dai-collateral&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: PSM is a module that prevents excessive price volatility of DAI. It is therefore automatically minted by the PSM when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first version of Maker, before the Multi Collateral DAI update (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@MakerDAO/update-the-road-to-multi-collateral-dai-2d4c48092270&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;MCD - 18/11/2019&lt;/a&gt;) used only ETH as collateral and thus presented much more credible guarantees. This is no longer the case at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🙏 Nevertheless, I warmly thank the MakerDAO team for their very many contributions to the ecosystem - the Maker MCD model is even used as a basis by Reflexer!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;frax--guaranteed-by-usdc-or-nothing-algorithmic&#34;&gt;FRAX ? Guaranteed by USDC or nothing (algorithmic)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On the FRAX side, only USDC is used as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;, in various forms - either in Yearn/Compound/Aave to produce a return, or via &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.frax.finance/amo/overview&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;AMOs (Algorithmic Market Operations Controller)&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the details of the assets that are used to collateralize FRAX, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.frax.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;available on the official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/frax-collateral.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;frax-collateral&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Frax and DAI are developing a myriad of interesting approaches, but since their basis is centralized, &lt;strong&gt;they cannot be considered anything more than a mechanism for amplifying the liquidity available on USDC, at best&lt;/strong&gt;. They do, however, make &lt;strong&gt;interesting contributions in terms of fundamental research&lt;/strong&gt; that may help establish a more optimal solution that does not require trustlessness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;are-there-relevant-alternatives-to-rai&#34;&gt;Are there relevant alternatives to RAI?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To date, RAI is a unique asset with no comparable alternative. However, there are systems that share certain characteristics with RAI, such as &lt;strong&gt;the exclusive use of ETH as collateral&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if you are ready to expose yourself to the dollar, Liquity offers a very relevant alternative which also has &lt;strong&gt;the merit of being totally unstoppable&lt;/strong&gt; (which is not yet the case with RAI): the contracts have no administrative function, exactly like Uniswap V1/V2. However, there are still the oracles (necessary for a loan service) and the associated risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the stage is set, let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the main course: it&amp;rsquo;s time to study the underlying mechanisms of RAI. We&amp;rsquo;ll start by how to mint it from a user&amp;rsquo;s perspective before going into more detail about what RAI actually is and how it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-the-rai-created-&#34;&gt;How is the RAI created ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s RAI is in some ways &lt;strong&gt;both the primary and final form of Maker&amp;rsquo;s DAI&lt;/strong&gt;. First, in the sense that it returns to the promises of the original DAI (the SAI): only the ETH is used as collateral, and final in the sense that RAI manages to extricate itself from the dollar dependency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflexer is based on a Maker MCD with several changes, including the incorporation of the PID controller, protection against liquidations and many others. We will slowly unfold all this but let&amp;rsquo;s start by seeing how the system works from the user&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like on Maker, RAI is created directly by Reflexer users. Users can open &lt;strong&gt;a safe that allows them to stake ETH and mine a proportional amount of RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. Each user can choose the amount of RAI minted for the same amount of ETH at stake (-&amp;gt; different risk levels) and must manage his position. &lt;strong&gt;Liquidation is possible and necessary&lt;/strong&gt; because it ensures that there is always enough ETH in the system to guarantee the RAI issued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the system here is innovating compared to Maker thanks to its &amp;ldquo;Savior&amp;rdquo; function. It allows &lt;strong&gt;to use a RAI/ETH liquidity position on Uniswap V2 as a guarantee for a safe&lt;/strong&gt;. Thus, if the ETH price were to fall suddenly, which could put an open safe protected by this function at risk of liquidation, &lt;strong&gt;the Savior automatically withdraws the quantity of liquidity necessary to bring the safe back to the desired collateralization level&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This allows users who mint RAI and then use it to provide liquidity to sleep much more peacefully!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;but-what-is-rai-exactly-&#34;&gt;But what is RAI exactly ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is a new asset class in its own way. It aims to be &lt;strong&gt;low volatility, without relying on another stable asset&lt;/strong&gt; (fiat currency or gold are the most traditional sources). To do this, RAI relies on a system that reacts dynamically to market conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of RAI, there are two key parameters to consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The redemption price&lt;/strong&gt; = value of a unit of debt in the system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The market price&lt;/strong&gt; = everything is in the name !&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the system has no control over the RAI price observed in the market, which is determined by buyers and sellers. Nevertheless, it can gradually adjust certain parameters to modify the redemption price and &lt;strong&gt;converge the two prices in the future&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are therefore faced with a situation that can be generalized quite easily, embodied by an entire field of engineering and called &lt;strong&gt;control theory&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/control-theory.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;control-theory&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of RAI, &lt;strong&gt;the controller is algorithmic&lt;/strong&gt; and again quite standard: it is the famous &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;PID controller &amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong&gt;. It is based on a fairly dense mathematical formula that it is not necessary to understand in order to understand the relevance of the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, one essential point must be understood: the inherent inertia of the system. The controller cannot afford to make sudden changes in the parameters (which would be detrimental to its relative stability), so it must operate in a more iterative and progressive logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this is understood, let me remind you that the system by itself cannot affect the price of RAI. All it can do is vary the redemption rate, which modulates the incentives of system participants. This creates &lt;strong&gt;arbitrage opportunities&lt;/strong&gt; for those participants whose execution brings them closer to the equilibrium between the redemption price and the market price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look at this in practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a logic here that is reminiscent of &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;algorithmic stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;, although the end product of the system is totally different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-market-price--redemption-price&#34;&gt;When market price &amp;gt; redemption price
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We start with this situation because I think it is simpler to understand. In the case where the market price exceeds the redemption price, that means anyone with ETH available could potentially generate a profit by arbitraging the market:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ETH deposit and RAI mint;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sale of RAI in the market for a profit;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(When market price &amp;lt; redemption) repurchase of RAI to pay off debt and release ETH. The difference between the 2 prices on RAI - fees in gas is the profit generated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/marchesupredemption-en.PNG&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;marchesupredemption&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This situation is all the more interesting for those who already have safes with available capacity: they save themselves a step in the scenario presented above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, there is therefore an incentive to mint RAI (-&amp;gt;increase supply) and to sell it on the market (-&amp;gt;bearish pressure) which gradually reduces the price on the market, making it converge towards the redemption price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;when-market-price--redemption-price-1&#34;&gt;When market price &amp;lt; redemption price
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the opposite case, the redemption rate becomes positive, making the existing debt more expensive. Users with active safes have an interest in paying off their debt, which reduces the available supply of RAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/marcheinfredemption-en.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;marcheinfredemption&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, if they had converted their RAI to another asset (e.g. ETH for leveraged exposure), they will have to acquire RAI in the market (-&amp;gt;bullish pressure) in order to be able to repay their debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, it is in the best interest of the Reflexer system players to monitor the redemption rate and react accordingly. If you have an active safe, I invite you to consult it regularly - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://stats.reflexer.finance/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;it can be seen on the Reflexer website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rate impacts simple RAI owners less directly, especially if they use them to produce a return (which can offset a negative rate) but it is still a metric to keep in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dynamic-adjustment-of-the-redemption-rate&#34;&gt;Dynamic adjustment of the redemption rate
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic adjustment of the redemption rate is one of the essential features of Reflexer / RAI&lt;/strong&gt;. To better understand why this is critical, let&amp;rsquo;s analyze the situation on Maker pre-MCD:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The demand for DAI is (part of) the demand for stablecoins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, DAI are created by leveraging ETH, so they depend on the need/appetite for leverage on ETH, which is independent of the demand for stablecoins, which mostly depends on general market conditions (bear or bull and others).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If demand is higher than supply, on Maker, there is no dynamic adjustment. You have to wait for a vote of the governance (and the delays that go with it) to lower the Stability Fee. And it&amp;rsquo;s the same in the other direction (too much supply).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, &lt;strong&gt;the balance between the supply and demand side of the equation is almost impossible to maintain&lt;/strong&gt;, which is why the pre-MCD DAI could often end up above its peg. Maker solved this problem by adding many types of collateral, including non-trustless stablecoins and then the PSM which automatically mints DAI from USDC when needed. The solution proposed by Reflexer (dynamic adjustment of the redemption rate) has the merit of &lt;strong&gt;solving the problem at the level of the system itself&lt;/strong&gt;, which allows to keep ETH as the only collateral.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flx-and-rais-de-governance-strategy&#34;&gt;FLX and RAI&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;de-governance&amp;rdquo; strategy.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In addition to the RAI, Reflexer&amp;rsquo;s system also has a second token, FLX, the &amp;ldquo;ungovernance&amp;rdquo; token. It is used for system governance and also serves as a last resort liquidity mechanism (in case of bad debt), with a system quite similar to Aave&amp;rsquo;s Safety Module.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FLX token can be purchased on the market, but it is mostly &lt;strong&gt;distributed to the main actors involved in the system&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://app.reflexer.finance/earn/incentives&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;the exhaustive list of FLX incentives&lt;/a&gt; is available on the Reflexer website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who are eligible for FLX (claimable on the Reflexer website, monthly distribution) are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Safes owners who bring their RAI in liquidity on the UNIv2 ETH/RAI pair (migration in progress, end soon) or UNIv3 RAI/DAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But also the liquidity providers on FLX/ETH (migration in progress, end soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally the FLX stakers in the equivalent of the Safety Module at Reflexer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are also incentives in FLX related to the use of RAI in various DeFi services, detailed in the last part.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.reflexer.finance/incentives/flx-staking&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FLX staking (Uni V2 FLX/ETH)&lt;/a&gt; serves as both an incentive mechanism to provide liquidity as well as a guarantee for the system. If the system is under-collateralized, the stakers will be diluted (-&amp;gt;token LP liquidated) so that the module acquires RAI and brings the system back to equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a normal situation, the stakers simply enjoy a rather attractive return. Just like Aave&amp;rsquo;s Safety Module, this module has a time limit for unstake, to avoid liquidity drain in critical periods: it is 21 days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we have the basics on FLX, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss its long-term issues a bit more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-gouvernance-exit-plan&#34;&gt;The gouvernance exit plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Reflexer system is intended to be &amp;ldquo;governance-minimized&amp;rdquo;. This has been the case since its inception, since decisions that are made by governance in Maker (Stability Fee of vaults) are automated in Reflexer (PID controller).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision is simply to automate everything that can be automated in the long term, once the system is mature, and to give the keys to the subsystems that cannot be automated to the FLX holder community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team has set three main levels related to this objective &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/introducing-flx-20755214a465&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;detailed in the FLX presentation article&lt;/a&gt;. Each level is linked to a date:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14 months after launch - April 17, 2022: minimization of governance on the main subsystems (liquidation, auction and taxation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;18 months after launch - August 17, 2022: minimization of governance on all main contracts, except for the PID controller, oracles and the Savior mechanism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3rd step (date incoming): handover (to FLX holdeurs) of the remaining mechanisms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this overview is enough to understand the interest of RAI and how it works. So let&amp;rsquo;s see how RAI is already used in various DeFi protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-defi-ecosystem-around-rai&#34;&gt;The DeFi ecosystem around RAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;RAI is gradually being adopted within the DeFi ecosystem, and that&amp;rsquo;s great to see! So I&amp;rsquo;ll end with a quick overview of the different RAI integrations in DeFi protocols, starting with money markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-on-fuse-rari-capital&#34;&gt;RAI on Fuse (Rari Capital)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuse is a rather innovative money market since it allows the creation of pools by players who are not the team, and eventually anyone. It is therefore quite logical that Fuse was one of the first money markets to support RAI. Depending on the pool, it is also possible to &lt;strong&gt;use RAI as collateral on Fuse&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RAI is currently available in 3 asset pools with different risk levels and borrowable tokens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2021/reflexer-rai/fuse-rai.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;fuse-rai&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-on-aave&#34;&gt;RAI on Aave
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After adding support for RAI already a few weeks ago, Aave recently allocated a (very moderate) amount of StkAAVE to incentivize borrowing and depositing on RAI. It was necessary to shed light on one of the main contradictions of the platform: Aave is a decentralized money market that (still) uses the vast majority of its budget to encourage borrowing/deposits on stablecoins that are not stablecoins at all (USDC and USDT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: for the moment &lt;strong&gt;the max LTV of RAI is 0: RAI cannot be used as collateral on Aave&lt;/strong&gt;. No discrimination here, this is pretty standard on Aave&amp;rsquo;s part - this is the &amp;ldquo;classic&amp;rdquo; and prudent procedure when adding a new type of collateral. Governance can vote to increase this value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-on-cream&#34;&gt;RAI on Cream
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cream was one of the first money markets to support RAI. However, it is an extremely risky and non-value-added, even deleterious, second-tier money market over the long term. So I&amp;rsquo;ll stop there, and &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2021/money-market-risks.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;invite you to read this article if you&amp;rsquo;re wondering why&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai-on-idle-finance&#34;&gt;RAI on Idle Finance
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idle Finance is a service that allows, as the name suggests, to set up passive return strategies. In the case of RAI, Idle leverages the returns available on Fuse as well as Aave. Initially, there was also Cream but the governance chose to refocus the strategies to contain the risk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the native RAI return, a deposit on Idle Finance also allows you to benefit from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From a FLX output, visible here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A StkAAVE yield (corresponding to the share of RAI deployed on Aave)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And finally, also a yield in IDLE (soon - voted by the governance but not yet implemented)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you want to own RAI over the long term to hedge against dollar/euro risks, the Idle deposit is rather attractive to produce a totally passive return. Be careful though, this means compounding several smart contract risks: Reflexer + Aave + Fuse + Idle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rai--fei-protocol&#34;&gt;RAI + Fei Protocol
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fei is another stablecoin that seeks to maximize decentralization. Here the approach is different and is essentially based on the notion of Protocol Controlled Value (PCV). In short, the bulk of liquidity in EIF pairs is controlled by the protocol itself. The funds come from the genesis of the protocol where users have committed ETH in order to acquire FEI as well as TRIBE (governance token) at their creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a stablecoin that shares a characteristic with RAI and LUSD: it is fully collateralized by trustless assets (ETH). Nevertheless, FEI is much closer to LUSD than to RAI in the sense that it remains pegged to the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Fei DAO voted to &lt;strong&gt;diversify some of the protocol cash flow to RAI&lt;/strong&gt; to make it more sustainable. Thus, up to $6M (~2M RAI) will be acquired and deployed on Aave and Fuse to produce a return.  Other DAOs are also considering diversifying some of their cash to RAI (Moloch, DxDAO, Metagame, etc.), so I expect more similar initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I hope you&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things from this fairly comprehensive presentation of RAI. As always, keep in mind that I choose my topics carefully and this article is not intended as investment advice. In this case, Reflexer/RAI was chosen here because it is an elegant system whose analysis allows to discuss many essential notions to better understand DeFi as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope that reading this article has been informative for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;🙏 Huge thanks to HHK, Charles, Thomas, Erwan, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/phil_h&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;PhilH&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; FrenchTony for proofreading the French version of this article and translating it integrally into English.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t get enough? Well, the Reflexer team has some very well written articles to explain the system in more depth - in English. Here are the ones I particularly recommend reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An article &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/securing-the-money-god-ef21453a299b&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;to understand the approach developed to secure the protocol&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/reflexer-labs/rai-system-simulations-part-1-safe-owners-876a6bd55385&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;series of three simulation articles, perfect for articulating your understanding of RAI in practice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, for the brave among you, you can &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/reflexer-labs/whitepapers/blob/master/English/rai-english.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;refer to the original RAI whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The state &amp; future of algorithmic stablecoins</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/the-state-future-of-algorithmic-stablecoins/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/the-state-future-of-algorithmic-stablecoins/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins/cover.png" alt="Featured image of post The state &amp; future of algorithmic stablecoins" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of December, a new trend has been shaping up in DeFi: algorithmic stablecoins. Several projects launched and saw significant growth, attracting even more interest for this subset of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into what they are and what they entail, let&amp;rsquo;s first discuss the addressable markets. Stablecoins on Ethereum are massive: they are around 20B USDT circulating, 3.5B USDC &amp;amp; 1B DAI. As you can see, right now most of the volume is served by stablecoins requiring some forms of trust, such as &lt;strong&gt;USDC or USDT: the emitting company has the power to freeze assets and manipulate balances.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maker explored another approach with DAI that has significantly fewer compromises - however, the scalability is lowered. Besides, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to consider DAI &amp;ldquo;sufficiently trustless&amp;rdquo; today when the majority of the collaterals used to mint it are not (USDC, wBTC, TUSD, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the recap here would be that so far, there is &lt;strong&gt;an obvious unsatisfied demand&lt;/strong&gt; in stablecoin - the ones that scaled did it with significant compromises, which enabled them to satisfy markets despite being services requiring trust, and more or less worthy of it (especially USDT).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I&amp;rsquo;m writing this piece today is that after following developments on the stablecoin space for years - it seems like we&amp;rsquo;re reaching an exciting breakthrough with a new generation of stablecoins able to offer &lt;strong&gt;both scalability and credible trustlessness&lt;/strong&gt;. The topic is neither simple nor easily accessible, especially for newcomers. I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best to walk you through the thought process step by step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-do-we-need-uncompromisingly-trustless-stablecoins&#34;&gt;Why do we need uncompromisingly trustless stablecoins?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into what project does what to what end, let&amp;rsquo;s take another step back. We&amp;rsquo;ve established that there is a significant demand for stablecoins, and none of the current leading offers are sufficiently trustless. But what does it mean exactly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;trustless means that the whole system does not require any central point of trust to operate smoothly&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s often mentioned with &amp;ldquo;censorship resistance&amp;rdquo;, a different property that stems from trustlessness. So from a practical perspective, here are some question to help you assess trustlessness: the more permissive the permissions, the less trustless the project tend to be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can token balances be seized or frozen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the protocol&amp;rsquo;s code or parameters be updated? In which conditions? By who?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is the protocol dependant on 3rd-party services, such as price feed (oracle) that could be manipulated?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who/what can print new tokens? Is that user-initiated (someone takes an action) or protocol initiated (a decision the protocol makes based on given parameters)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last question is particularly insightful, as it highlights a core component of algorithmic stablecoins: &lt;strong&gt;their &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; is a smart contract&lt;/strong&gt; — no one controls it, it simply reacts to the system parameters. We&amp;rsquo;ll dive more into this right below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with this piece, we&amp;rsquo;ll examine the main models available: Ampleforth, Basis Cash, Empty Set Dollar, and Dynamic Set Dollar. I&amp;rsquo;ll not dive into the history of the space and the specificities of each model, feel free to check this article from Deribit Insights if you need more context:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉 &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://insights.deribit.com/market-research/stability-elasticity-and-reflexivity-a-deep-dive-into-algorithmic-stablecoins/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Stability, Elasticity, and Reflexivity: A Deep Dive into Algorithmic Stablecoins&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So instead of diving into each system&amp;rsquo;s details, I&amp;rsquo;ll draw &lt;strong&gt;a sketch showing the core principles this generation of stablecoin is built upon&lt;/strong&gt;, based on the common parameters and design approaches shared in all projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;central-smart-contract&#34;&gt;Central Smart Contract
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first interesting dimension is the &amp;ldquo;central bank&amp;rdquo; of the system - aka who/what can print new tokens and under what conditions? &lt;strong&gt;USDC &amp;amp; USDT pretty much replicate a central bank&lt;/strong&gt; - one entity is in charge of the project and emitting new tokens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Maker is just a smart contract enabling its users to mint DAI from certain collaterals, the approach is different here. Essentially &lt;strong&gt;Maker/DAI enables you to be your own central bank&lt;/strong&gt;. So the central bank of Maker is a smart contract, but it requires human input to mint DAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The algorithmic stablecoins go even further, as &lt;strong&gt;the human input is removed from the minting process.&lt;/strong&gt; In these systems, no one has the capacity to mint tokens - only the smart contract operating it can. It&amp;rsquo;s very elegant and minimal, but it requires a carefully designed set of incentives to make sure the stablecoin will eventually hedge towards its peg. To put it simply, &lt;strong&gt;with algorithmic stablecoins, the central bank is an autonomous smart contract.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-army-of-stabilizers&#34;&gt;An Army of Stabilizers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With algorithmic stablecoins, especially in their early days, peg breaks are frequent. To push the stablecoin back to the peg, the protocols have different kinds of incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the stablecoin is worth over $1, &lt;strong&gt;the protocol mints new tokens and distribute them as an incentive&lt;/strong&gt; to users providing liquidity or locking their token, which helps to push the price back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the stablecoin trades below $1, the coupons (or bond) system kicks in: &lt;strong&gt;users can burn their stablecoins for a coupon&lt;/strong&gt; representing it + a premium. However, they will only be able to redeem the coupon once the price is back over the dollar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, at a high level, these mechanisms are simple. They have intricacies that you need to master if you want to partake in the system. &lt;strong&gt;Users understanding them and following them can help the protocol stabilize&lt;/strong&gt;, and if it does they might earn in the process. So these simple rules lead to the emergence of an army of stabilizers, who make use of all the mechanisms to stabilize the price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design pushes both game theory and the meme-game to another level:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins/dsd-meme.jpeg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DSD Meme&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;aggressive-expansion-phase&#34;&gt;Aggressive Expansion Phase
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the supply of algorithmic stablecoin is elastic, their mechanism is quickly battle-tested. Indeed, at launch, the circulating supply of the stablecoin is usually low and the attractive incentives create a lot of demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, &lt;strong&gt;Basis Cash launched with 50 000 BAC tokens&lt;/strong&gt; distributed to the first stakers. Roughly a month after, there are now &lt;strong&gt;40M BAC circulating&lt;/strong&gt;: they were produced because BAC has been trading &amp;gt;$1 most days since the launch. So far, there was no phase where BAC&amp;rsquo;s TWAP &amp;lt; $1, so the Basis&amp;rsquo; coupon system (BAB) has not been tested yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;.notice{padding:18px;line-height:24px;margin-bottom:24px;border-radius:4px;color:#444;background:#e7f2fa}.notice p:last-child{margin-bottom:0}.notice-title{margin:-18px -18px 12px;padding:4px 18px;border-radius:4px 4px 0 0;font-weight:700;color:#fff;background:#6ab0de}.notice.warning .notice-title{background:rgba(217,83,79,.9)}.notice.warning{background:#fae2e2}.notice.info .notice-title{background:#f0b37e}.notice.info{background:#fff2db}.notice.note .notice-title{background:#6ab0de}.notice.note{background:#e7f2fA}.notice.tip .notice-title{background:rgba(92,184,92,.8)}.notice.tip{background:#e6f9e6}.icon-notice{display:inline-flex;align-self:center;margin-right:8px}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice svg{height:1em;width:1em;fill:currentColor}.icon-notice img,.icon-notice.baseline svg{top:0.125em;position:relative}&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;svg width=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;0&#34; display=&#34;none&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;tip-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.967-111.033 248-248 248S8 392.967 8 256 119.033 8 256 8s248 111.033 248 248zM227.314 387.314l184-184c6.248-6.248 6.248-16.379 0-22.627l-22.627-22.627c-6.248-6.249-16.379-6.249-22.628 0L216 308.118l-70.059-70.059c-6.248-6.248-16.379-6.248-22.628 0l-22.627 22.627c-6.248 6.248-6.248 16.379 0 22.627l104 104c6.249 6.249 16.379 6.249 22.628.001z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;note-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M504 256c0 136.997-111.043 248-248 248S8 392.997 8 256C8 119.083 119.043 8 256 8s248 111.083 248 248zm-248 50c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;warning-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M569.517 440.013C587.975 472.007 564.806 512 527.94 512H48.054c-36.937 0-59.999-40.055-41.577-71.987L246.423 23.985c18.467-32.009 64.72-31.951 83.154 0l239.94 416.028zM288 354c-25.405 0-46 20.595-46 46s20.595 46 46 46 46-20.595 46-46-20.595-46-46-46zm-43.673-165.346l7.418 136c.347 6.364 5.609 11.346 11.982 11.346h48.546c6.373 0 11.635-4.982 11.982-11.346l7.418-136c.375-6.874-5.098-12.654-11.982-12.654h-63.383c-6.884 0-12.356 5.78-11.981 12.654z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;symbol id=&#34;info-notice&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34; preserveAspectRatio=&#34;xMidYMid meet&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M256 8C119.043 8 8 119.083 8 256c0 136.997 111.043 248 248 248s248-111.003 248-248C504 119.083 392.957 8 256 8zm0 110c23.196 0 42 18.804 42 42s-18.804 42-42 42-42-18.804-42-42 18.804-42 42-42zm56 254c0 6.627-5.373 12-12 12h-88c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h12v-64h-12c-6.627 0-12-5.373-12-12v-24c0-6.627 5.373-12 12-12h64c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v100h12c6.627 0 12 5.373 12 12v24z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/symbol&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice info&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#info-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Info&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Expansion/Contraction are phased in &amp;ldquo;epochs&amp;rdquo;. Basis Cash has 24h epoch. ESD is 8h and DSD is 2h.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, ESD and DSD already saw several cycles of expansion and contraction each, with the protocol operating as intended:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/algorithmic-stablecoins/dsd-mktcap.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;DSD Market Cap over the last 7 days&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;harnessing-defi-composability&#34;&gt;Harnessing DeFi composability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another key principle of algorithmic stablecoins is composability. We often think of it as &amp;ldquo;how can I plug my finished product/service into others?&amp;rdquo;. These projects go much further, as &lt;strong&gt;they use other protocols like Uniswap as a central part of their system.&lt;/strong&gt; Basis, ESD and DSD all have three main components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An internal locking/staking mechanism for expansion phases (DAO or Boardroom)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A burn&amp;amp;redeem mechanism for contraction phases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Uniswap pair (/USDC or /DAI)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their very structure demonstrates an understanding of DeFi and its composability. By placing the Uniswap-pair(s) at the core of the protocol, it helps on so many levels - since &lt;strong&gt;Uniswap is staple DeFi users are familiar with.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Uniswap is the main pool, the liquidity on other DEXes is increasingly looked at. With the launch of Omakase, Sushi added two new incentivized algorithmic stablecoin pools: ESD/ETH &amp;amp; DSD/USDC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Composability is key for algorithmic stablecoins and several projects are already taking steps to get more integrated within the ecosystem. Within the next few months, we should see the next steps of this with the arrival of some algorithmic stablecoin as collateral on lending platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;oracle-minimalism&#34;&gt;Oracle Minimalism
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oracle are used as a base parameter in the algorithmic stablecoin system:: they are the &lt;strong&gt;source of truth for the price of the stablecoin&lt;/strong&gt;. Making sure the oracle is resilient and cannot be gamed is critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do so, the previous generation of projects, especially Maker, tended to overengineer things. In the early days, Maker&amp;rsquo;s input parameter was almost the pure &amp;amp; raw price of ETH. However, to make the system less prone to &amp;ldquo;flash liquidations&amp;rdquo;, Maker built their own oracle, and use several delays and averages with the liquidation price to &lt;strong&gt;add some inertia to their system&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, as we&amp;rsquo;ve seen before our algorithmic stablecoins tend to be minimalist and harness the composability of DeFi. &lt;strong&gt;With their Uniswap pairs, they already have a decent price feed with significant liquidity, making it hard to manipulate&lt;/strong&gt;. So the Uniswap price is used as the based, but generally computed as a TWAP (Time Weighted Average Price) to avoid price manipulations right before rebases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While being minimalist, the systems are efficient and elegant: as these stablecoins projects grow, so should their liquidity on Uniswap, making the oracle more resilient and the price harder to manipulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I for one am excited as to where this subset of the space is heading. Whether you intend to partake or not in the bootstrapping phase of such stablecoins, I think it&amp;rsquo;s highly valuable to document yourself on them as they are a good tell of the main trends of the space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-algorithmic-stablecoin-toolbox&#34;&gt;🧰 Algorithmic Stablecoin Toolbox
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Before we part way, allow me to share some useful tools to track the evolution of these stablecoins. First, each project has its own tracker providing the main metrics for the current epoch:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://bc.tools/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Basis Cash Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://esd.tools/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ESD Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://dsd.tools/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DSD Tools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, you can view more granual details about the ESD and DSD system on this dashboard: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://duneanalytics.com/tongnk/esd_1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ESD/DSD Bonding&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer&#34;&gt;Disclaimer
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;notice warning&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#warning-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Warning&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS ARTICLE DOES NOT CONSTITUTE INVESTMENT ADVICE.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a qualified financial advisor, but who gives a fuck really? This is DeFi we&amp;rsquo;re talking about.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve felt legitimate to write this piece because I&amp;rsquo;ve been following closely Basis Cash, Empty Set Dollar, and Dynamic Set Dollar closely, as well as Basis Dollar &amp;amp; Share less attentively. Frax is another hybrid project that is worth looking at - I did not discus it as I&amp;rsquo;m not familiar enough with it yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;notice note&#34; &gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;first notice-title&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon-notice baseline&#34;&gt;&lt;svg&gt;&lt;use href=&#34;#note-notice&#34;&gt;&lt;/use&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;💰 Bag Disclosure&lt;/strong&gt;: I own BAC/BAS (Basis Cash), ESD (Empty Set Dollar) and DSD (Dynamic Set Dollar).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this read was insightful for you. If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/tokenbrice/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;follow me on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or this blog through RSS (at the very bottom of the page 👇) to get notified when the next article is published.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:1313/p/eth-exposure-or-defi-yields-why-choose/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Aug 2020 01:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
        
        <guid>http://localhost:1313/p/eth-exposure-or-defi-yields-why-choose/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/leveraging-ETH.png" alt="Featured image of post 🎚 ETH exposure or DeFi yields: why choose?" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the Ether giant seems to be waking up, you might be considering your &lt;strong&gt;options to recenter your exposure on ETH&lt;/strong&gt;. This is precisely what I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking at and executed on lately, and now is the time for the feedback session!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, DeFi is heating up and yields are attractive. However, &lt;strong&gt;even crazy liquidity mining returns (on stablecoins) might not beat the ETH price appreciation once its time comes.&lt;/strong&gt; So, instead of having to choose, why not have not both?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this one goal in mind, the most obvious solution was &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://makerdao.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Maker&lt;/a&gt;. The position can, of course, be achieved using other services; I consider them at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there you have the base idea: instead of investing directly in ERC20 or stablecoins and putting them to work, you maintain an ETH base, use it to generate DAI and then diversify into your positions. This way, you maintain a healthy ETH exposure - the tradeoff being the additional risk, including liquidation that are discussed below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;re-investing-the-minted-dai&#34;&gt;Re-investing the minted DAI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The options to re-invest your DAI are pretty much infinite, so I will focus on these that make the most sense - aka the best at harnessing the current DAI premium. Feel free to check my previous publications covering incentivised liquidity pools investment opportunities &amp;amp; the useful tools to harness them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/yield-farmer-tier-list.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;💦 The Yield Farmer Tier List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://tokenbrice.xyz/content/posts/2020/defi-farmer-toolbox.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;🧰 The DeFinancial Farming Toolbox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So essentially when it comes to what makes of the DAI, you have several options, here are the broad categories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIMPLE STABLECOIN RETURNS&lt;/strong&gt; - Put your DAI to work, with a simple deposit on Compound or Aave, or using a yield optimiser.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ADV. STABLECOIN RETURNS&lt;/strong&gt; - Invest in Curve Ypool for decent returns + extra earning opportunities on your pool tokens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ERC20 EXPOSURE (+LP)&lt;/strong&gt; - Purchase ERC20 tokens and hold or purchase ERC20 tokens and provide liquidity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MORE ETH LEVERAGE&lt;/strong&gt; - Use the DAI to buy more ETH. Can be potentially repeated for more leverage (CAREFUL). This obviously makes the most sense when you&amp;rsquo;re expecting positive price action on ETH.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DAI is currently trading at a premium ($~1.03), some strategies are better than others to harness the impact of this spread. I detail them in the last section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vault-management-how-to-increase-gas-efficiency&#34;&gt;Vault Management: How to Increase Gas Efficiency?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it comes to making sure you&amp;rsquo;re not burning yourself on the gas costs, I&amp;rsquo;ve already covered several critical tools that we won&amp;rsquo;t detail again, such as &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://zapper.fi/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zapper.Fi&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://paraswap.io/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ParaSwap&lt;/a&gt; for some token swaps. Today, I want to discuss services that are helpful to manage Maker vaults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While interacting with your vaults, you&amp;rsquo;ll find yourself make series of transactions (deposit ETH -&amp;gt; mint DAI -&amp;gt; do something with the DAI). To reduce your gas costs, you can &lt;strong&gt;use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://furucombo.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FuruCombo&lt;/a&gt; to build your series of operations and execute it in one transaction.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You might find yourself in need of a &amp;ldquo;flash capital&amp;rdquo; to close a position somewhere and re-open it somewhere else. If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, an Aave flash loan will be useful. Now for the best part: &lt;strong&gt;flash loans are available on FuruCombo!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/furucombo.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Collateral swap using Furucombo&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that in these times of high gas cost, each interaction is costly. To reduce the impact of gas on your strategy, try to minimize the amount of operations you&amp;rsquo;re doing - FuruCombo is simply amazing for that!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have many positions to close/open, you might also want to wait for an opportunistic time to do so, where gas costs are low. The weekend evenings (Europe time) are usually best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-please-read-how-to-not-get-liquidated&#34;&gt;🚨 PLEASE READ: How to not get liquidated?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;understanding-makers-liquidation-mechanism&#34;&gt;Understanding Maker&amp;rsquo;s Liquidation Mechanism
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you get liquidated, (a part of) your collateral is seized to cover your debt. &lt;strong&gt;The existence of liquidation on Maker means you could lose potentially all of your ETH&lt;/strong&gt; if you are careless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my tips and recommendations to make sure this does not happen to you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are just starting with leverage, maintain a very healthy collateralization ratio&lt;/strong&gt;. I’d recommend &amp;gt; 300 % for new users, simply for peace of mind during your discovery phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t put all of your eggs in one basket&lt;/strong&gt;: on Maker, you can open as many vaults as you want. While you don’t want to open hundreds of positions to keep the gas costs in check, you might also want to consider splitting your stash to not put all of your ETH under the same risk and be able to more gradually manage the positions as they grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Vault Management&lt;/strong&gt;: if you&amp;rsquo;d like a less stressful approach, you can use &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt; to make sure your vault is automatically kept at a certain ratio with the Save function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/defisaver-automation.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Automating Maker Vault Management with DeFi Saver&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advanced-vault-management&#34;&gt;Advanced Vault Management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have several vaults, you can use a tool to re-distribute capital between them in one transaction, again with FuruCombo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Mint DAI on Vault1 (currently safe) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; Burn DAI on Vault2 to lower its risk
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Using a flash loan, you can even fully close a vault “into” another vault for instance:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;lntable&#34;&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;1
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;2
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;4
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;lnt&#34;&gt;5
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;lntd&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Flash loan DAI (=debt of Vault-1) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt; Burn on Vault-1, to free the ETH 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Deposit the ETH in Vault-2 (the one you keep) 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Mint DAI on Vault2 
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; Pay back the flash loan.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be mindful with what you do with the DAI you mint: it&amp;rsquo;s a debt.&lt;/strong&gt; Prefer safer investment options. If you invest in something stupid &amp;amp; get rekt at the same time the ETH price is depreciating, you could be putting your ETH at risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-maker-is-the-best-service-to-leverage-eth-right-now&#34;&gt;Why Maker is the best service to leverage ETH right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I decided to focus this article on Maker only, considering the angle is to leverage ETH and Maker is currently the best platform to do so, as well as probably the safest (running track record). Here are my main three reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fits the bill&lt;/strong&gt; - It enables you to keep an ETH exposure while generating extra DAI to re-invest.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;0 fee if not liquidated - (⚠ gas costs)&lt;/strong&gt; The current stability fee is 0 (on ETH) - it costs you nothing but gas to open a position on Maker.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DAI Premium -&lt;/strong&gt; DAI is frequently trading at $ 1.02-1.03 meaning minting DAI can result in a 2-3% instant profit on the amounts reinvested (more on this later - DAI premium section).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please keep in mind that &lt;strong&gt;this is NOW&lt;/strong&gt;, several weeks from now there might be better options for such positions, as Aave implements its new tokenomics for instance. A similar position could already be achieved today using Compound, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem profitable to do so right now (vs Maker).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-this-strategy-for&#34;&gt;Who is this strategy for?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since it&amp;rsquo;s quite a flexible strategy, &lt;strong&gt;it can be used by pretty much anyone owning ETH and looking for a way to put them to work.&lt;/strong&gt; However, allow me to highlight some use case scenarios that should give you ideas:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve entered the markets recently (2019), and made profits but not really on ETH. While your ERC-20 positions are up, you might be wary about missing on ETH gains. To increase your exposure to ETH, you could settle some of your positions to ETH, open a vault, and reopen up to ⅔ of the closed ERC-20 positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve been harnessing neat gains on the stablecoins farming lately, but even the best yields can&amp;rsquo;t beat a waking giant. You might consider buying ETH with your stablecoins, to then open a vault and reopen part of your stablecoin position - you keep some of your yields while adding a sweet exposure to ETH&amp;rsquo;s price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;harnessing-the-dai-premium&#34;&gt;Harnessing the DAI Premium
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To conclude, let&amp;rsquo;s consider the best options if your goal is to make the most of the current DAI premium - what does it impact most?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it&amp;rsquo;s very nice for ETH-leveraged long. Indeed, if DAI trades at $1.03, buying ETH from DAI is more efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are considering investing in the Curve y pool, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend going 100% from DAI. You&amp;rsquo;ll save gas cost massively on the swaps that are not required (+ less deposit and approve tx). On top of these savings, entering the Curve y pool fully in DAI usually has a positive price slippage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently it sits ~1.5% over 5000 DAI: that is 1.5% instant profit as you enter the position, quite attractive right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/img/2020/leveraging-ETH/curve-dai-premium.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Curve DAI Premium&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending on your risk preference and your capital, you might want to time your entry. I was able to harness up to a 3.5% positive bonus entering the ypool, so waiting can be worth it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to Grégoire for proof reading this content &amp;amp; &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/jimmyragosa&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Jimmy&lt;/a&gt; for suggesting &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;, try it out!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-takeaways&#34;&gt;Key Takeaways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://oasis.app/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;put your ETH to work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, without selling them! Try out with a first safe (&amp;gt;300%) position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liking it? Start exploring other strategies but remember to account for gas costs. Use &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://furucombo.app&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;FuruCombo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to build more complex flows.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using vaults more and more? It might be a good time to consider &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://defisaver.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;DeFiSaver&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; to reduce your risk and manage your vault without stress.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://twitter.com/MakerDaiBot/status/1290243544670785536&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The Stability Fee is now = 0&lt;/a&gt; for all collaterals on Maker.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
